With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE BATTLE IN THE WHITE GARDEN
So you managed to survive.
That's not entirely correct.
In fact, I died once.
But, I was given the Dragon Blood
that flows in Master Baran's veins.
It resurrected me from the brink of death.
Dragon Blood?!
What he used to resurrect Popp
after his life ended!
Master Baran shared his Dragon Blood
with us three Dragon Masters,
and laid us down in the forest
near the Fountain of Miracles.
But Dragon Blood doesn't guarantee
the resurrection of all who drink it.
Only in those with the willpower necessary
to crawl back from the brink of death
is this effect observed.
I was the only one of us three
who made it back.
I see. So it was Popp's strong will
that allowed him to resurrect.
I awakened from my long slumber
in my coffin just a few days ago.
I almost missed this final battle.
Thank you. If you hadn't saved me, I...
I don't recall ever saving you, Hyunckel.
I merely disposed of an enemy in my way.
I have no interest in rescuing losers.
W-What?!
I know how soft you are.
Those wounds must be from
protecting that enemy there.
An action unfitting of a Warrior,
a professional in combat.
Of course you lost.
You bastard!
You may be right.
Huh?!
Hyunckel!
To coldly analyze a situation
and defeat enemies like a machine...
If that's what makes a Warrior,
then it's something I can no longer do.
I'm no longer worthy.
No matter what happened,
I couldn't abandon Hym!
It appears that leaving the fates of
Master Baran and Master Dino in your hands
was a mistake on my part.
Looking at you like that, I doubt
you'll be of any use to Master Dino!
W-What do you think you're doing?!
This man is too pitiful to let live.
I'm going to finish him myself!
L-Larhart...
The Warrior Hyunckel is dead.
I just killed him right now.
Therefore, there is no reason why
I shouldn't take the Dark Armour Spear.
Yes. Go ahead.
A corpse has no use for armour.
Amudo!
Farewell my friend. May you rest in peace.
Larhart...
You were too kind
to continue fighting forever.
Dammit! That Darkling pisses me off!
Let him go.
That was his own brand of kindness.
I think he was sent
to protect Dai in my place.
A savior that Baran sent from the heavens.
He's a savior?
By passing judgment on me,
he took on my will and duty.
We both watched each other die.
What a strange twist of fate.
I've done all I could.
I even managed to rescue Hym.
Maybe now... Maybe now
no one will scold me...
Mas... ter.
Yeah, but it's that sort of "We've got a
special bond" attitude that's annoying.
I'm going to have to
kick his butt someday, too.
Whoops. But first, once we're healed,
I need to settle things with you.
Are you listening, Hyunckel?
Hyunckel, thank you for using your body
to protect Master Dino until now.
You can leave the rest to me.
For I am the sort of
battle machine you spoke of.
Oh! Look!
Is that Hyunckel?!
You're from the Royal Guard!
Why are you here?!
Hyunckel! What happened to Hyunckel?!
Shut up. Keep it down.
He's finally getting the rest he deserves.
Probably for the first time in his life...
he can forget about
fighting and destinies...
and rest his weary body and soul.
Right... Hyunckel?
It appears they were wiped out.
The King's Orichalcum Army.
Huh?!
But of course they were.
Maximum was just a delusional blowhard.
Maximum did not have King Ban's favor.
That fool didn't know hunting a mouse
from finishing off a wounded beast.
So who took care of the Orichalcum Army?
It must have been
the ones not present, Hyunckel or Aban.
I'm right here!
Master Aban!
It must have been my first student
who took care of them!
You're late, Master!
We were worried!
Master!
Oh come on! It's not just Master Aban!
I'm here, too!
That's right!
I mean. It's not like we weren't
worried about you, Princess.
Honestly!
So you're Aban.
I see. You went ahead
into the Tower of Supremacy.
That's right! We've already scouted
most of the structure ahead!
And we took care of
most of the Reaper's traps, too.
Using my special item!
Huh?! M-Master,
you don't need to show them...
Hup!
These Mieru Glasses
I found in the Cave of Trials
enable me to see through any trap!
HAKENDISUTORU
ABAGAMU
Swish, swish, swish!
With my Mieru Glasses and hammer,
I crush traps with a swish, swish, swish!
So much for Master's cool image.
If he had just kept quiet...
Master's in some kind of mood.
Yeah. He could never let
any lame bit go to waste.
Did we waste our time worrying about him?
-Huh?
-H-Hey...
-It looks like Mystban finds it funny.
-That's impossible!
I understand now. What a fascinating man.
I've never encountered
a human like you, Aban.
I've known about you ever
since you defeated the Dark Lord Hadorra.
But to actually see you
is something else altogether.
You act in such a way
to hide your overwhelming talent.
And that profound integrity
I sense from within you...
No wonder your disciples
continue to look up to you.
Princess Leona has filled me in on
what's happened these past three months.
The current Dark Commander Mystban
is apparently the greatest, most powerful
barrier in the fight against Ban.
It seems what I was told is true.
You would be right.
Seeing as there's no word from Zaboera,
I can only assume he's been defeated.
The self-proclaimed
"most powerful" king also fell.
I am the only one left who can
exterminate the nuisances in Ban Palace.
I, Mystban, alone!
All the other former Six Legion Commanders
have been defeated!
Looks like it's almost over!
The Six Legion Commanders?
What's so funny?!
The Six Legion Commanders.
That was just a little amusement
King Ban created on a whim.
He could have always wiped out
the surface world with me alone.
But King Ban didn't want to
just destroy the surface world.
By creating legions that would
compete to carry out that purpose,
he wanted to gain the ultimate army
that would last into the future.
That's why he welcomed Hadorra, the most
powerful being in the surface world,
and placed me under his command.
Baran and Hyunckel were chosen
for their spirit and hatred of humans.
Crocodine, for his loyalty.
Flazzard and Zaboera,
for their ambition and wisdom.
They were chosen for
the potential King Ban saw in them.
In order to create a powerful army,
the tension between such varying
personalities is essential.
But you managed to shatter that plan.
It was an unfortunate turn of events,
but ultimately meaningless.
The Dark Army was but a fleeting dream
of the last few decades.
Its loss doesn't hamper our goal
of wiping out the surface world at all!
I alone, have been here
for thousands of years!
I alone, have protected King Ban!
He's...
He's the most dangerous of all of them!
It's like he's on a whole different level
from the others!
Now, come at me all at once!
I shall make this White Garden your grave!
Watch out, Dai!
He has a hidden face! An unknown power!
Yeah! I know!
We fight at full power!
Hold on!
I will fight that man!
By "you," do you mean by yourself, Aban?
That's crazy, Master!
That's right, Master!
If we fight together...!
Master...
Will you accept my challenge, Mystban?
I refuse.
What?!
I had forgotten about him.
He tends to be very vindictive.
Who knows what he'll do
if I try to take his prey?
Master!
A scythe?!
It's Kilban! Kilban got Master!
I knew it was you, Kill.
The Reaper lives up to his reputation.
That's...
Myst... sorry, but I leave
the others to you.
I've barely even started!
Master!
No!
The Reaper took him and vanished!
You have lost him again, Dai.
Not just once, but twice.
How does it feel to lose
your master before your eyes?
I imagine your heart must be overcome
with frustration and loss.
You did this together!
You worked with the Reaper
to assassinate Master!
That wasn't an assassination.
It's something much more interesting.
That was a duel.
A duel?!
The scythe that attacked Aban
wasn't Kill's favorite Reaper Flute.
That was a guide to drag Aban
to the place of their duel.
Aban wasn't killed.
But he's about to die.
Where...
Where is this?
Huh?
It-It's not moving.
That thing isn't targeting me?
Is this strange robot thing
what dragged me into this place?
Bingo!
Kilban!
Hello Aban. Welcome to
the field of my revenge.
Normally, I'd prefer to immediately
repay you for humiliating me,
but I couldn't decide
which mask to wear.
I really liked the last one,
so finding a similar one was quite a pain.
But...
I managed to find
the perfect mask for the occasion!
A... A Mask of Anger!
As you can see, this mask
represents my emotional state.
No man has ever wounded my pride
and caused me such anger as you.
If anyone, that little Mage student
of yours was close.
But as his master, you annoy me even more!
As promised, I'm going to kill you myself!
So you're going with your anger
and giving up the smug facade?
So? What sort of dirty trap
have you prepared this time?
Consider that a left-hand glove.
This time there are no traps.
Fair and square,
I challenge you to a duel!
A duel?
That is what this field is for.
Take a look at that robot.
It's part of my collection
from the Underworld, called a Judge.
Its scythe has the ability to
tear reality and drag a target here.
How did the residents
of the Underworld use it you ask?
They used it as a dueling machine against
those they had a score to settle with.
Basically, as the name implies,
the Judge serves as overseer,
presiding over the duel
between the individuals trapped here.
Here, isolated together
in this empty field,
they fight and fight and fight
until one finally falls!
And in the end, the Judge
passes its judgment!
It takes the loser's head.
What a terrifying machine.
A fitting thing for the Underworld
where conflict never ends.
I got it because I rather like the design,
but I never imagined
I'd be using it myself.
You never know
what can prove useful in life.
So, Aban, will you accept my challenge?!
What do you mean "accept"?
The fact that I'm here
means I have no choice but to accept!
Don't talk about "fair and square."
This is the definition
of "trap," Kilban!
That attitude!
I can assume you accept this duel!
Now we fight, Aban!
What?! Kilban's using a sword?!
Aban versus Kilban. Battle start.
Kilban draws first blood.
65 damage to Aban.
Care to make a wager, Dai?
Which of us will come back here alive?
Obviously, I place my bet on Kilban.
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Aban was dragged into
another dimension by Kilban.
It was the wrathful Kilban's way
of challenging him to a duel.
Dai and his friends are shaken
from losing Aban again.
Just as it seems
that Mystban has broken their spirit,
a single Feather strikes
the ground at their feet.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Successor of Justice"
The adventure continues!