With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE NIGHT BEFORE THE BATTLE
There isn't a single scratch!
It looks brand new!
I'm glad you're okay.
Now we can fight together again.
This time it really could be
the final battle.
I'm going to use all the power I can.
I hope you'll support me.
Thank you, Ron Berku.
Congratulations, Dai!
That's a huge boost to your strength!
Now you can use your Dragonic Aura and
the Sword of Dai's been enhanced, right?
The Sword of Dai doesn't get stronger.
Huh?
I'm the one who has to get stronger.
About that, Dai.
I did a little tinkering of my own.
Huh?
Your sword remains as it was before.
But, in battle, you should exhibit
far greater power.
The secret isn't in the sword itself.
It's in the scabbard.
The scabbard?
I've written the details down here.
Read through it before the battle.
Okay, I'll read it for you.
I've enhanced
the Dark Armour Spear, but...
I hear Hyunckel was captured?
I see.
I understand the situation.
I'm amazed you still decided to invade
Ban Palace under these circumstances.
It seems more reckless than brave.
I suppose that's humans for you.
Who is this guy?
I've made weapons for Dai's companions,
so that should make fighting easier.
For my companions?
Right! Hold on to your seats!
This is the new Dark Armour Spear.
This is an axe and this is a staff...
Wait. Where's Popp?
Huh? I haven't seen him in a while.
Apparently he went to the forest
behind the Fort.
Oh. I guess Popp's training, too.
So this is mine?
Yes. That's your new weapon...
the Dark Armour Fist.
The Dark Armour Fist?
It'll work better on
your non-dominant hand.
Oh man. Everybody else gets new weapons.
There's one for you, too.
What?! A new weapon from
the craftsman of the Underworld?!
No. I made this one!
The Barbed Nunchaku!
Here!
This'll shred any enemy!
It looks like it'll shred my hands, too.
But I appreciate the thought.
Ouch!
There's no need to get emotional!
Ron Berku, why are you
helping us humans so much?
I was never really
on the Dark King's side.
I merely did what I was asked to.
As a result, the Kōmanotsue
became the strongest weapon in the world.
But that's because
the Dark King himself is so powerful.
Simply put, even a knife
becomes more powerful in his hands.
He's the most boring customer
a weaponsmith could have.
Why am I helping you?
Helping the weak seems more interesting.
Does that answer your question?
He's such a weirdo.
Pretty much.
But he's actually not a bad guy.
Okay! Let's rescue Crocodine
and Hyunckel, and deliver these to them!
Right, everyone?!
Then I'll take this axe to
Mr. Crocodine...
or so I thought.
Ursula!
My troop member can carry it.
Then I'll take the spear and staff...
Miss Amy?
Let me take this spear.
I want to personally deliver it
to the man I love.
She's serious.
I'm in love with Hyunckel.
At first, he seemed so menacing.
He's the Legion Commander
who destroyed our country, after all.
But I slowly came to realize...
that he's actually pure and delicate.
That his heart is like glass,
sharp yet fragile.
I found myself slowly drawn to him.
Before the last battle,
I took this spear from him.
I didn't want for him to fight.
For him to be hurt.
I never knew!
But I realized I was wrong.
All I did was add to his suffering.
If living in battle is what he desires...
If he is destined to writhe in hell...
then I will embrace it!
I will join him in hell!
Maam, you don't mind
if I give this to him, do you?
Then I guess I'll go take this to Popp.
Maam...
We've got your back,
so make sure you hand that to him.
And tell him how you feel when you do.
I already did, but he turned me down.
Why would he turn down
someone as beautiful as you?
What should we do?
What a turn of events! How exciting!
That's not what I meant.
Does it matter?
People can love who they please.
Besides, Maam is far too oblivious
about her own charisma.
This is a good chance
for her to grow as a person.
Your words and expression don't match.
Oh?
What's going on?
Nothing! Don't worry about it!
If Meruru gets involved,
it'll make things even worse.
Queen Flora, the food
is now ready for everyone.
Once we eat,
check your weapons one last time!
Then get as much rest as possible.
Tomorrow, we go to war!
I never knew...
Miss Amy felt that way about Hyunckel.
What about me?
How do I feel?
According to the Ancient Tome, five types
of soul power are required for Minakator.
The five types are Courage, Love,
Fortitude, Justice...
and a fifth one
which was too faded to make out.
Dai is Courage and Maam is Love.
Leona is Justice...
"Fortitude" is like a word
that was invented for Hyunckel.
And mine remains a mystery.
Do I really deserve such a word
to begin with?
I only got this far
by the skin of my teeth.
It was just for everyone,
no, especially for her.
Popp.
Maam?!
MEDOROA
ABAN STRASH
Maam?!
Sorry to interrupt your training.
Nah, it's fine.
I can't let her know.
The fact that I'm mediocre.
That I'm not like everyone else.
Here's the staff Ron Berku made for you
and its instructions.
Ron Berku?!
He repaired and brought
Dai and Hyunckel's weapons.
He also made weapons for us and Crocodine.
Wow. That's pretty thoughtful.
With the Sword of Dai
we'll be in great shape.
Let's see what sort of weapon this is.
Um... Popp.
Hm?
Can I talk to you about something?
What's this about all of a sudden?
It's about... Hyunckel.
I don't really know how I feel about him.
I told you I don't know how
I feel about Hyunckel as a man.
I never really thought about men
that way before.
But when Miss Amy said
she was in love with Hyunckel
my heart started pounding.
Could I be jealous of her?
Or am I just confused because
someone other than us understands him?
Maybe I really...
Shut up.
I said shut up!
How the hell should I know
what you don't know yourself, idiot?!
You don't have to be so...
We've got a battle tomorrow
that we might not come back from
and you're suddenly talking about love?!
I don't care whether
you love Hyunckel or whatever!
I'm sorry, Popp.
I didn't consider how hard
you were training for tomorrow.
You're the only one
I can talk to about this stuff.
I'm sorry!
I'm the real idiot!
She came to me because she trusted me,
and I threw it back in her face!
This is exactly why I can't get
one little rock to shine!
Dammit!
My new staff?
This is for me?
"Black Rod."
"This staff absorbs Magic Power
and converts it to physical energy."
"It can also extend and change shape
according to the user's will"?
Wow! This thing is amazing!
It's basically the same as
Ban's Kōmanotsue!
And it can change shape, too!
I must have imbued it with Magic Power.
If that little Magic Power
becomes that much destructive power...
this should be useful
for physical attacks.
I'll have to do it. All or nothing.
Nothing I did
made my Insignia of Aban glow.
My only hope is to figure out
something during the battle!
Everyone is counting on me.
I can pull something off
at the last minute.
I have to believe that!
My friends, the time of battle approaches.
I hope you all will try your hardest!
With that...
some soldiers have said that
monsters like us
will be difficult to distinguish
from enemies in the heat of battle.
So I've made Beast King Commando badges!
I have one for each of you.
And Otoad is number ten.
Wait, that's strange.
There's 11 of you.
Hi!
M-Master?!
You're Master Brokin!
Master? That's not who I am.
I'm the Beast King Commandos 11th helper!
The mysterious monster, Mr. Beast!
You don't need a disguise.
Helping my students in secret seems cool.
Also, I'll need to have a badge, too!
Just like everyone else!
Oh boy...
The execution will be in Loroi Valley.
We saw Dark Army monsters gathered there.
There are mountains on all sides.
If we're surrounded, we can't escape.
The terrain is an issue, but the biggest
problem will be when Minakator is cast.
The five Disciples of Aban
won't be able to fight.
We have to fend off the enemy
with everything we've got.
That will be my job.
I'll command all the soldiers...
Will such a patchwork army be enough?
What are you asking?
I'm asking if you'll be able to
hold your ground.
If the line is breached
while they're defenseless, you'll all die.
Who asked you?!
We're not here on a whim like you are!
I'm willing to risk my life...
Don't assume you'll win
by risking your life.
You'll just die in vain.
What?!
Enough, Nova!
Relax, kid. I'm not trying to insult you.
I'm asking if you need a helping hand.
A helping hand?
You yourself would fight?
I thought I'd follow you all
to the very end.
Oh, Dai.
What are you doing?
Preparing medicinal herbs for everyone.
I couldn't relax enough to sleep.
I really should, shouldn't I?
Then why don't you try this?
This is a Dream Seed.
It will help you sleep and heal fatigue.
Huh.
It is said that
those who are pure of heart
will be able to dream
what they truly wish to dream.
I'm sure you'll have a nice dream.
Thanks Meruru. Goodnight.
Goodnight, Dai.
May you have a good rest tonight.
For tomorrow, you will face a battle
far beyond my imagination.
Don't be sad, Mom.
I've made up my mind.
I'm going to risk everything
for this fight.
I promise I won't lose.
Dai!
You look chipper.
Did something good happen?
I dreamed about my mom.
Your mother?
My mom was so beautiful.
I wanted to thank Meruru for the Dream Seed
she gave me, but she's not here.
She left early with everyone else.
She's going to fight, too.
Even Meruru?!
I argued against it, but she was adamant.
If the world is going to end, she'd rather
fight with us even if she's weak.
I see.
Where's Maam and Popp?
I'm not sure what they're doing.
Maam, you there?
Popp?
Sorry about yesterday.
I lost my temper and yelled.
I didn't consider your feelings.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry. It was my fault.
Let's forget it happened.
And let's focus on today.
You can't tell Hyunckel how you feel
if you don't rescue him first.
Right.
While you're praying for Hyunckel,
pray for me, Maam.
Pray that I don't fail
in that vital moment.
Oh?
They look normal.
You're disappointed?
Sorry to keep you waiting!
It's finally time.
I know you all know this,
but I'll say it anyway.
Failure is not an option for us.
If you assume we'll have
a second shot at this, we will lose.
This will be our final battle! Got it?!
Okay! Let's go, everyone!
Right!
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
To be honest I was clumsy
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
And it took me forever to get here
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I used even loneliness as a weapon
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
I just want to be there for you
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
To call out your name
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Is harder than any magic spell
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
Even though you're so close to me
aishiteiru
I love you
imasara kizuitanosa
I finally realized it
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
To call out your name
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
Must be the reason I was born
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
I shake off the clinging night
ai ni iku
And go to see you
ima sugu kimi no moto e
Right now to where you are
Hyunckel and Crocodine are
set to be executed in Loroi Valley.
The time comes, Ban Palace appears,
and Mystban approaches Hyunckel.
Mystban uses Dark Aura
to try to make Hyunckel his servant.
Can Hyunckel and Crocodine
escape this peril?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Dark Hyunckel"
The adventure continues!