With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE DARK HYUNCKEL
It's arrived.
Ban Palace!
They kept them tied up there all night?
They're inhumane!
Hyunckel...
Mr. Crocodine, we'll get you out of there!
It stopped.
The sun...
is now...
at its zenith, shining at its brightest.
It is noon.
Meruru, are those
all of the enemy's forces?
Yes.
The Shadow Legion Commander
and armoured monsters...
There's 36 of them!
I sense a great amount of pressure
coming from Ban Palace...
but that's all for the ground.
We should be able to handle
such a number...
excluding Mystban.
Hyunckel, I'm sure you haven't forgotten.
Will you drink the Dark Aura in
this chalice and serve me or not?
What do you choose?
If you want an answer, then free me!
Very well.
Remember, once you drink this it is done.
You will have sold
your soul to the devil again.
Don't do it, Hyunckel!
Hyunckel!
Crocodine...
don't forget... what I told you... please.
Hyunckel, I know you.
I'm sure you thought you'd pretend
to submit as a way to trick me.
Unfortunately, my Dark Aura is
not so easily overcome.
No matter what you intended,
you belong to me now.
What's going on?!
What happened to Sir Hyunckel?!
He drank from that strange cup
and completely changed!
It's Dark Aura!
What?!
I sense an evil presence from Hyunckel!
He's likely being affected
by the enemy's Dark Aura!
He accepted an evil influence?!
How could a Disciple of Aban do that?!
Hyunckel!
It feels good, doesn't it?
If told to behead someone,
you feel you could do it easily,
as if picking a flower, don't you?
As you should.
At last you are back where you belong.
Don't be ridiculous! He wouldn't lose
his righteous heart so easily!
Oh Crocodine.
Limited as it is, you have
the ability to manipulate Aura, too.
Looking at him, don't you sense it?
I can't sense his Aura of Light!
He's completely enveloped in Dark Aura!
E-Even now, the last of Hyunckel's
Aura of Light is being consumed!
It appears he underestimated my Dark Aura.
He assumed if he pretended to submit
and accepted my Aura,
then he could overcome it
with his own Aura of Light.
Such a fool!
There are some things in this world
that cannot be overcome!
The power of darkness has no limits!
Hyunckel, it appears your final gambit...
has ended in failure.
You still seem sluggish, Hyunckel.
The power of darkness
has healed your wounds.
The sluggishness is because
you still retain a shred of conscience.
Let me tell you how to become
a complete warrior again.
Take this and execute Crocodine.
Killing a former friend
will extinguish your conscience.
You'll lose your Aura of Light and again
become a true Dark Swordsman of Evil.
Now do it!
Hyunckel!
No! You can't go out there yet!
But Hyunckel is...!
We know that!
We're not supposed to charge
until Dai and the others rescue those two!
They can't rescue them like that!
Dammit!
What can I do?!
Hyunckel is now an enemy!
Wait!
Crocodine.
If you consider me a friend...
I need you to trust me no matter what.
That's right! He's still fighting!
There's a desperate battle
raging inside of him!
I have...
I have to believe in him!
Hyunckel! Hang in there!
Don't let the Dark Aura take you!
What's wrong? Kill!
Kill him!
I believe in you!
Even if I'm cut to shreds,
I'll believe in you to the very end!
So fight! Fight that evil within you!
Kill him, Hyunckel!
Don't listen to his nonsense!
Hyunckel!
What?!
He's... dead.
What a fool.
If he had just accepted it,
he could have returned to the Dark Army.
He couldn't endure the conflicting Auras
and it killed him.
Hyunckel's life energy has disappeared!
And now we can no longer gather
five Disciples of Aban.
What is Dai doing?!
I've waited long enough!
What are you doing?! Let go!
Don't you get it, boy?
The reason they haven't appeared
is because they understand Hyunckel.
What?
That's just who he is.
Life itself is but
one more weapon for him to wield.
Disappointing, but so be it.
Let me give you a companion
to take to the afterlife.
Hyunckel!
W-What?!
Impossible!
I feel really good, Mystban.
Right now I feel like
I could behead you easily.
As if...
picking a flower!
BLOODY SUKURAIDO!
TOMAKUGUTSOSHO
Hyunckel...
He's back!
Impossible! I'm sure I felt
your life energy vanish!
Why are you still alive?!
It's really very simple.
Two opposing Auras
were battling inside of me.
And...
one of them won!
What you felt was the Aura that lost!
It can't be!
Hyunckel!
How is this possible?!
Why is your Aura of Light so powerful?!
It's true that my Aura of Light
was suppressed by your Dark Aura.
Overwhelmed by your evil power,
it was almost extinguished.
But, as a result,
my Aura of Light grew stronger!
My will not to give in to evil
made my Aura of Light even more powerful!
And in turn, it suppressed your Dark Aura!
How dare you!
That was your intent from the start!
You used my Dark Aura to
help boost your own power!
You once told me that abandoning
my Aura of darkness had made me weaker.
But it wasn't because I couldn't use
both opposing powers at the same time!
When evil, I hated the power of light
that Aban had bestowed upon me.
When good, I sought to overcome
the power of darkness within me.
This rapidly boosted both Auras!
When you told me to accept your dark power
I took it as a final chance
to shine even brighter than before!
That's absurd!
You're saying your Aura of Light
has actually suppressed my Dark Aura?!
There's no way you could do that!
Surely you already sense it.
The Dark Aura within me that has been
completely enveloped by my Aura of Light!
Silence!
Taking out Restless Armours bare-handed?!
Oh wow!
It's the power of Aura.
What?!
His overflowing Aura
has made his body harder than steel.
It seems he's powered up
beyond imagination.
You knew that was
Hyunckel's plan all along?
Pretty much.
It was a risky gamble,
but fortunately it worked.
I'm sure they think so, too.
Huh? Who's they?
How dare you...
My face shall not be touched!
Honestly, you're always
pushing yourself to the extreme!
How do you intend to make up
for scaring me half to death?!
Crocodine, I'll take care of these guys
and get you out of there.
How dare you!
I'm going to tear both of you apart
here and now!
"Both of you"?
Mystban, it looks like your senses dull
when you get emotional.
D-...
Dai!
So he still lives.
What did I tell you?
My fortune telling has never missed.
I sense spirit within him.
Like he's a whole different person.
Renewed your resolve?
Dai!
Oh! Popp! Maam! And even Princess Leona!
We tunneled in like you do, Big Guy.
We had to use
my fire magic instead, though.
Let me get those!
Dai, I'm surprised
you didn't jump the gun.
I knew right away.
I sensed the Aura of Light inside you
growing stronger.
We were worried at first, but we quickly
switched to an attack from underground!
I see. Thank you.
You believed in me, too.
It wasn't only Dai who
believed in you, Hyunckel.
Maam...
We wanted to charge the moment
you went all dark.
But she stopped us.
Hyunckel would never accept Dark Aura
if he didn't know he could beat it.
Let's trust him and see what happens.
Got it?
But I was right.
Yes. I made a vow.
I'd only ever fight with
the power of light.
Some of them can still fight!
Nova!
We've run out of patience, Dai!
Everybody's set to explode!
It's game time!
Everyone, charge!
We'll use them to blow off some steam!
Wait, why are you
leaving the fighting to them?
Well, it's all a little complicated.
Hyunckel, do you still have
your Insignia of Aban?
Of course.
They could kill me
and I wouldn't let go of it.
Hold it in your hand
and focus your will!
Focus... my will?
It's not anything difficult.
Just focus your thoughts
on what gives you the will to fight.
I'm just the worst!
For a moment I actually hoped
that Hyunckel's Insignia wouldn't glow.
That if Hyunckel couldn't do it,
it'd let me off the hook.
Whoa! The Insignia of Aban is glowing!
The Insignia must be responding
to your fortitude!
We're all set now!
We have five Disciples and five Insignias!
The Great Purification Spell
Minakator is ready!
Hup!
Curse you Dai! Curse you Hyunckel!
You've humiliated me time and time again!
What's wrong, Mystban?
My Dark King!
Why are you so agitated?
With your power you could
wipe out all of them easily.
It's not as though their resistance
will gain them entry into Ban Palace.
Take your time and show
those who would resist me
what true suffering really is.
Yes, my King! Forgive me!
As you command, I shall offer you...
the sight of them writhing in agony!
I shall tear you all apart!
Dark Puppetry Aura Decimation Field!
They've got... other things to do.
They don't have time for you.
If you want to play...
then I'll play with you, Mystban!
Y-You!
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
imasara kizuitanosa
I finally realized it
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
To call out your name
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
Must be the reason I was born
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
I shake off the clinging night
ai ni iku
And go to see you
ima sugu kimi no moto e
Right now to where you are
The five Disciples of Aban gather at last.
The ritual of Minakator begins,
with Leona at its center.
Mystban tries to stop the spell,
but Ron Berku thwarts him.
Crocodine and the others fight to protect
the five Disciples from the Dark Army.
With everyone counting on them,
will the Great Purification Spell succeed?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Five Colors of Light"
The adventure continues!