Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE HERO'S TUTOR
Dark Army, advance!
Charge! Charge!
This looks very grim. Speed it up, Popp.
Yes, Master.
Woo-hoo! Go, go!
What's wrong with you?!
Are you okay, Gomechan?
What's wrong with everyone?!
Grampa, emergency!
Get a grip, Grampa!
Dai?
Grampa!
Are you okay?
It feels like black blood
is coursing through my veins!
If I don't stay focused,
I think I'll go berserk!
Everyone suddenly became violent.
What's wrong with them?
There's only one possible reason.
The Dark Lord has returned!
What?!
This urge to go berserk
can only be the Dark Lord's evil will.
He wants to gather us with his dark power
to try to overthrow the world again!
No way...
Dai, you must leave this island!
Otherwise we might kill you!
Hurry!
But...
It was my good heart that let me raise you
after you drifted here on this boat.
At this rate, I might harm you
with my own hands.
Grampa...
Just go!
No!
Listen to me!
I can't run by myself!
That's not what a Hero would do!
Dai...
Precisely!
Well said. You must be...
Dai.
How do you know my name?
Why don't you leave this to me.
Look out!
Don't worry. Master's got this.
Master?
Dark influence, begone!
Mahokator!
Oh wow.
It's a miracle.
Who are you?
How rude of me. I...
I CAN TRAIN YOUR HERO!!
A 15-YEAR VETERAN OF THE TRADE
am a Hero trainer.
Basically a tutor for Heroes.
A Hero's tutor?
Yes. Agents of peace who uphold justice
and defeat evil! Heroes, Sages, Mages...
It is my job to train them
into first-class warriors!
It is I, Avan De Zinuar III.
Where have I heard that name?
And this is my student, Popp.
He is currently training to become a Mage.
So why is such a tutor here?
Perhaps you've noticed
that the Dark Lord has returned.
I knew it.
Monsters under his control are everywhere,
and people in places
like Romos and Papnica are in danger.
No! King Romos and Leona, too?!
The Papnica royal family
asked that I come here.
They want me to train the future Hero
on Dermline Island to be a true Hero.
Dai, will you undergo my training?
This is to defeat the Dark Lord,
so it will be exceptionally hard.
I'll do it! If Leona is in danger,
I have to go help her!
Plus, if we don't defeat the Dark Lord,
Grampa and the others can't live in peace!
Please train me! I'll become a true Hero
and defeat the Dark Lord!
Very good!
What's that?!
Gargoyles!
I see humans!
Kill them!
What the hell?!
Check it out!
A magic circle of light
has sealed off the entire island!
They appear to be
scouts for the Dark Lord.
Popp, take care of them.
Huh?! By myself?!
I used the purification spell, Mahokator,
so I am very, very tired.
Aww. No fair, Master.
Don't push!
I get it already!
Hey! I'll fight you!
You brat!
Don't make me laugh!
Merazoma!
He trained that boy to be
such a powerful magic user!
It seems this man is the real deal.
You bastard!
I'll roast you into fried chicken next!
Mahoton!
Ka... Ka...
Take that, brat!
Oh... Oh crap!
How disappointing.
I told you that Gargoyles can use
the magic impairment spell, Mahoton.
What the hell?!
Servant of the Dark Lord...
get off of this island!
Darn it!
Look out!
You may use that.
It's a distinguished legendary sword.
It'll take more than improvised swordplay
to defeat a soldier of the Dark Army!
Don't get cocky!
I did it!
You did it!
That's really an amazing sword, Master!
Hmm. It's actually a cheap sword
I bought at a used goods store.
It seems this boy may be quite the find.
Master, what's my next training?!
Now, now. Don't get ahead of yourself, Dai
Popp, you're the older student,
so look after Dai.
Nice to meet you, Mr. Popp.
It's just Popp.
Now then, I have various training courses,
but we're short on time.
And so, Dai, you will be taking the
one week hero-making Special Hard Course.
What?! I can become a Hero in a week?!
There's no way you can!
Don't do it! You'll die!
Popp...
You can join, too.
No thank you, Master!
I'm fine with the normal training!
I'll do it!
I need to get strong and save Leona
as soon as possible!
Very good.
We'll begin your hard training tomorrow.
Huh? Not right away?
Sir Avan is tired from a long journey.
He's also expended much Magic Power
casting such a powerful spell.
Precisely.
Let's all get some proper rest today.
I understand!
There's no way you could
become a Hero in just a week.
BAGIKUROSAI
VORTEX-TYPE SPELL
HYADARUKO
ICE-TYPE SPELL
Right. The Special Hard Course.
Dai, slice this with a sword.
Huh?! This?!
This is the first day's objective.
Oh no! I broke the legendary sword!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Don't worry about it.
Use your knife instead.
Okay!
This sword only cost ten gold coins,
so it's only natural.
It's no good. I can't cut it.
I guess you're not ready yet.
In that case, go run a little more.
Now we'll begin
the normal training course!
Hey, are you okay?
First is Avan Style Basic Training!
Next is Avan Style Unarmed Combat!
Don't forget the basics of magic!
Popp, what sort of training is this?
It's meditation
to increase your Magic Power.
Now for magic practice.
Hyadaruko!
The wave froze! Amazing!
Of course, I've been training
with Master for over a year.
Huh?!
You fail to see things through as usual.
Magic is about focus. Focus.
Yes sir.
Now Dai, it's your turn.
Hyado!
Not much potential for magic, I see.
I don't have to worry
about him overtaking me.
Hard training! Sword practice!
Very good.
He does show promise in swordplay.
Don't worry.
That man possesses unfathomable skill.
Besides, I've never
seen Dai train so seriously.
Now Dai.
Let's give it another go.
Master, I'm completely beat.
Just trust me and give it a try.
Okay.
I cut it?
When people are thoroughly exhausted,
their movements become simple.
In other words,
their most natural movements.
You tended to move too much
with your sword.
You've always had the strength
to slice a boulder like this.
Master, you really are amazing!
He really sliced it in one day!
Well done, Dai!
He really must have been exhausted.
Master, are you really going to continue
with the Special Hard Course?
Of course. His grand objective
is to save his friends, so he'll be fine.
Popp, you can join us with the morning
and evening training if you'd like.
Well done. You made me use
both hands in only two days.
Dai, you amaze me.
To improve this much since yesterday
is astounding progress.
As a reward, let me show you
my special move.
Huh?
This is my super special attack.
Try to master it as soon as possible.
Master, are you...
Avan Strash!
Master just went and showed him
his best attack!
It's this strong with just a wooden stick?
That's an amazing attack!
Popp, you can join
the Special Hard Course anytime.
Huh?! No thanks!
I'm fine with the Normal Course!
AVAN STYLE SWORD TECHNIQUE THEORY
EARTH, SEA, AIR
The theory
of the Avan Style Sword Technique.
Earth, sea, and air. You will learn
to slice these three things.
Earth? Sea and air?
Yes. Let's start with
the earth slicing attack, Earth Slash.
The key to this attack is power.
In other words, strength.
Avan Style Sword Technique!
Earth Slash!
Very nice.
You've almost mastered Earth Slash.
But Earth Slash is the most basic attack.
I wanna learn Avan Strash.
No, no. Everything has its proper order.
AVAN STYLE SWORD TECHNIQUE THEORY
EARTH, SEA, AIR
Slice the earth, slice the sea,
slice the air.
And what slices everything is Avan Strash.
Oh. I've got a long way to go.
Popp.
If you're watching, tend to Dai.
Y-Yes sir!
There. Get some rest until dinner.
Thanks.
Are you really going
to continue this all week?
Yeah. I am.
That's insane. Do you really like
that Papnica Princess that much?
Pretty much.
You're so naive.
I do apologize for dinner being so late.
N-Not at all.
I get so excited watching Dai's progress
I get caught up in the training.
And Popp too.
Popp?
Oh, he would never
take his training seriously.
Every time I gave him a hard task,
he'd always give up.
But recently, he's been curious about Dai
and keeps spying on him.
I see.
By the way, tomorrow's training
could get a little chaotic.
Is there a place we can use
where we won't trouble others?
A place that won't cause trouble?
You managed to learn Earth Slash
in two days, Dai.
Therefore, your third day training
shall be to learn an even harder skill.
Yes sir.
It won't be easy.
If you aren't careful...
you will die.
What sort of training is it?
Very simple. You will fight me.
That's all?
However, I will be using a special spell,
so you may use your knife.
My knife of Papnica?
That's right. My skin will
be harder than steel after all.
Here we go, Dai.
Doragoramu!
Master turned into a Dragon!
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
To learn the Avan Style Sword Technique
Dai bravely faces Avan, who changed
into a Dragon using an ancient spell.
Through Avan's training,
Dai rapidly grows stronger.
But an evil presence closes in.
Next time on
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Dark Lord Hadlar's Return"
The adventure continues!