With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE SECRET SPELL OF FROZEN TIME
You're rather peculiar.
But no simple clown could know
the name of that spell.
Just who is that guy?
Wait, isn't he here just for healing?
That's crazy, Grand Master!
Grand Master...
I'm counting on you...
Popp.
This movement...
Oh wow!
It's like he's fighting against a feather!
For anyone who can move like that,
being close is actually safer.
He fights like straight from
a martial arts textbook!
Stop clinging to me!
Popp!
Now's your chance!
Right! I know that!
Medoroa... Medoroa... With my Medoroa...
Popp, why are you casting
two Hyado spells?!
Huh?!
Well...
there's just a lot of pressure
on my shoulders.
You know how everything's always
ended up coming down to Dai or Hyunckel?
I'll do what I can and end up
on the ground, which has been fine
because I've never had everyone count
on me as the last hope like this.
I know it's pathetic...
but I just can't move like I usually do.
You idiot! That just proves
how strong you've become!
How can you not use the power
that you've worked so hard to gain?!
-Even Grand Master is doing his best!
-Whoa!
A direct hit?!
Whoops!
Are you kidding me?!
With this well-trained, dried,
withered body of mine
I can float like a leaf in the wind
and absorb the force of enemy attacks!
It's one of the ultimate skills
of my fighting style.
And that one hit confirmed my suspicions.
Your body is abnormally cold.
Just like back then.
Over a decade ago, when we fought
Hadorra, the Dark Lord!
What?!
Hadorra?! How do you know Hadorra?!
I once fought the Dark Lord long ago...
with Aban.
What?!
Back then, Aban cast a legendary spell
for the first and last time.
That spell was...
the Secret Spell of Frozen Time!
That was 17 years ago.
Back then, Aban, the Hero traveled with
Roka, the Warrior and Leira, the Priest,
on a journey to defeat the Dark Lord.
ROKA, THE WARRIOR
The Secret Spell of Frozen Time?!
ABAN, THE HERO
LEIRA, THE PRIEST
Just what is that?
It freezes time.
In other words,
it's a spell that stops someone's time
and holds them in place indefinitely.
Whoever it's cast upon becomes immobile
as though Asutoron was cast,
and they become impervious to any force.
But unlike Asutoron,
their biological functions stop, too.
After all, you've stopped
their time itself.
And it's not just a spell
to protect oneself.
It can seal an enemy, too.
So you plan to defeat Hadorra,
the Dark Lord with that, Sir Aban?
Defeat him. But I can't kill him.
However, he will be sealed away forever,
so peace will be restored to the world.
Peace to the world...
I've researched this spell using
ancient tomes so it should work.
But today is our only chance to cast it.
During today's once-in-centuries
total solar eclipse.
Once-in-centuries...
Okay! Good going, brainy Hero!
Nice find on that spell!
I've always held your intellect
in high regards! Right?
Then let's get this thing going!
Let's all grasp that
once-in-centuries chance!
Unfortunately...
it won't be all of us.
Roka... Leira...
I can't drag you two
into this fight with me.
W-...
What?! What are you talking about?!
I said exactly what I meant.
I mean that this party
must be temporarily disbanded.
Sir Aban, why are you saying that?
This secret spell is not fully understood.
It uses the power of nature
so it should work on the Dark Lord.
But...
I don't know if I can hold off
the spell's backlash.
In the worst case...
...you'll be caught in the frozen time?!
Even if we should win peace,
it's pointless if
no one's there to enjoy it.
I need you to leave this to me.
You moron!
Oh my. Are they fighting?
They're always fighting. But this time
is a little more serious than usual.
Why can't we all work together
to fight like we've always done?!
Like always!
I'm not going to sacrifice you
just to win!
I can't allow that, Roka.
What?!
You really can be so thick.
You need to survive to look after
the woman you love.
You knew about us?
You're wrong! I'm not serious
or anything about this girl!
-"This girl"?!
-Yeah!
Wait! I didn't mean it like that!
Hmm.
So you weren't really serious?
Let me explain.
That's no good.
You need to take responsibility...
since you'll be a father.
W-Why you...
Sir Aban, you knew that I'm pregnant
with our child?
I hadn't even told Roka.
Roka can be quite awkward.
Even if he knew,
he'd still try to hide it.
He was always saying "I live by the sword"
or "I'll never fall in love with a girl."
I know he can be a handful,
but please look after him.
I believe a child born in war
deserves to live in peace.
Do give it a good name, Leira.
Sir Aban.
That's just who he is.
Matorif!
He's going to risk his life
to protect one that will be born.
And he's one to talk about awkward.
He's just as thick as anyone.
Just leave him to me.
I don't have a family to mourn me.
I'll try to make sure Aban doesn't die.
I make it a point not to let women cry.
-Let's go, Brokin.
-Oof!
ABAGAMU
TIGER SHATTER FIST
I'm sorry, Grand Master, for dragging you
into such a perilous fight.
Don't you worry about me.
With my illness,
I don't have long anyways.
Not again.
I'm counting on you.
Just distract the Dark Lord.
Even an instant will do.
That's a feat only you, the best martial
artist in the world, can accomplish.
Am I famous or something?
Yeah. Like myself, you're one of the few
famous old geezers in the world.
I'll take care of the riffraff.
Good luck to you.
My Strash and Sword Technique
are still incomplete.
This is the only way to obtain peace
here and now!
Begirama!
Bagikurosai!
IORA!
Secret Spell of Frozen Time!
No!
I'm not yet strong enough to...
Hadorra and Aban both stood frozen,
not even blinking an eye.
For a period of over a year,
their time remained stopped.
And so, the Hero brought a brief peace
to the world.
When you came to me seeking training,
I truly felt the hand of fate at work.
That's right.
The child born between Roka and Leira...
was you, Maam.
Grand Master...
I see.
So the Grand Master
was a member of Master Aban's party.
I knew he was more than he seemed.
Now I see.
If you were an ally of Aban's,
then it's no mystery that you know
this secret spell.
But Grand Master,
isn't that Secret Spell of Frozen Time
supposed to freeze its target?
If it's cast on him, then shouldn't
Mystban be immobile?
That's not it.
He's utilizing the power of
that Secret Spell for combat.
That's what I believe.
I'm not sure how he's doing it,
but he can still move while the Secret
Spell of Frozen Time is cast upon him.
His very time is frozen
and his body has,
as it were, become indestructible.
So he takes no damage and is immune
to any physical attack.
It's like still fighting while under
the effects of a Asutoron spell.
That's correct.
But don't you see?
You're declaring your own death sentence.
I can fight while my time is frozen.
That means...
that I am invincible.
He's right!
An enemy who could still attack
under the effects of a Asutoron spell
would be unbeatable!
Not to fear, Popp.
The spell that Matorif passed down to you.
That is an exception.
Huh?!
On that day,
Matorif could do nothing
as he saw Aban sacrifice himself.
Wracked with guilt, the spell he created
for the final battle was...
...The Extreme Annihilation Spell!
Medoroa!
Yes.
You're just a dry leaf.
If grabbed, you can be torn.
If dodging is all you can do,
then Larhart would be a more worthy foe.
Be torn to shreds, clown!
Grand Master!
An instant is all I need!
Give me back the strength I once had!
Here once again!
To save the next generation!
Oh wow!
If it wasn't Mystban,
that first strike would have ended it!
I never knew Grand Master
was this powerful at full strength!
Popp!
I'm burning to go!
I won't miss this shot!
Popp!
They really were all amazing.
All of Master's old friends!
We're all here now thanks to
the great people who came before us!
If I can't hit this,
I ain't no Disciple of Aban!
I'll do it!
I'll hit him with this Medoroa
even if it kills me!
He's already back on his feet. That
tenacity is what makes a Disciple of Aban.
Enough with your futile resistance!
Curse you!
Okay!
Grand Master!
Warrior Master Style
Earth Wyrm Eruption Strike!
Popp, now!
That attack controls the ground!
The floor will explode, lifting Mystban!
Okay!
It was a dud!
Grand Master!
I see.
It's possible that spell could defeat me.
I can only last
about a minute at full power.
Age certainly takes its toll.
It's even shorter
than when I fought Hadorra.
Your miracle plan
to turn the tide of battle... is over.
Or will you cast your spell
and sacrifice him?
Grand Master!
It doesn't matter, Popp. Cast the spell.
I don't have long to live anyways.
It's better than all of you dying!
I know that, Grand Master!
Popp!
Stop bluffing.
You disciples of justice
could never do that.
Yes I can!
I know I can now!
And this time...
we're going to let Grand Master
and Master enjoy the peace we've won!
What?
Here goes!
Medoroa!
Rura!
He can't dodge that!
Hit him! Evaporate him!
We've won!
Grand Master!
Popp!
They're gone!
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Popp and Brokin disappeared in
the Medoroa that Mystban reflected.
Hyunckel realizes Mystban's secret,
but Kilban appears
and Aban's defeat becomes apparent.
As despair descends upon the heroes,
the centuries-old relationship between
the two who bear Ban's name is revealed.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Myst and Kill"
The adventure continues!