With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
RETURN OF THE GREAT HERO
Hadorra...
Hadorra.
In your last moments, you were one of us.
You were...
our friend.
Up you go!
I see you've matured well, Popp.
It's been quite a while.
Sh-Shut up!
Oh my.
You're not... You can't be Master!
The real Master wouldn't
suddenly return after all this time!
This is a dream or an illusion
or that dirty Zaboera in disguise again!
That's not possible, Popp!
That's a Magic Circle of light.
Even a perfectly disguised
dark sorcerer couldn't cast it!
Then, Leona, is that...?!
Is... Is it really?!
Then...
That's right.
Forgive me for
causing you all such concern.
I am neither ghost
nor imposter nor illusion.
And obviously not an identical stranger.
It's really the real me.
Master Aban!
Master!
Howl, Inferno!
Take this! Northern Grand Blade!
Is something wrong, Queen Flora?
I sensed something...
up there.
-Master!
Master!
Dai.
Maam.
Popp.
Master!
Oh my! My good clothes!
I can't help it!
I just wanna hug you right now!
That's it! Down you go!
Popp, I sensed your Magic Power
from a long distance.
Your power was most impressive.
I've grown a lot, you know!
Master!
Those clothes... I never expected you
to become a Martial Artist, Maam.
Dai.
You have truly become an impressive Hero.
You all have changed so much.
Even without me,
through your own strength,
to see you all come so far
makes me sincerely proud.
And...
Hyunckel.
I know you've devoted yourself
to a never-ending battle.
But you're allowed to express
your honest emotions sometimes.
These are... my honest emotions, Princess.
I suppose this is what it means...
to be unable to show one's face.
Bartos was the strongest knight
of the Dark Army...
and my father!
The malice you sense in my blade is
my hatred towards you, my father's killer!
Wait, Hyunckel!
Not all students of Aban
respect their teacher and love justice.
Some of them love violence
and have embraced the darkness.
After seeing just how weak...
justice really is!
But...!
I am Hyunckel!
One of the Six Legion Commanders
of the Dark Army!
Hyunckel, the Undead Legion Commander!
I don't deserve your forgiveness.
Hey, I bet this is our chance
to see Hyunckel be all weepy!
It's a rare sight!
Popp, don't be like that!
Can anyone blame me?
Huh?!
Let him be for now.
Master, Hyunckel was...
It's alright. You don't need to explain.
Hyunckel.
You're here now,
giving your strength to help the others.
That alone brings me...
It brings me great joy.
Master Aban.
Princess Leona. You're here, too?
I was given this by Queen Flora.
I see. If she deemed you worthy,
then I trust her judgement.
Master Aban, please explain.
How did you come back after dying?
I was told you died on Dermline Island
during your battle with Hadorra.
Back then, Master...
A spell?! Impossible!
You should be out of Magic Power!
This spell requires
very little Magic Power.
Instead, it turns life energy
into explosive power to defeat enemies!
Wait! This spell is...!
Stop! Don't do it!
Popp, Dai! I leave the rest to you!
Stop!
Megante!
That's right.
Master tried to protect us...
...and cast Megante.
If anyone other than a Priest
casts Megante,
their body is obliterated
and they can't be resurrected.
I don't mean to doubt you...
but please tell us what happened.
Well...
it's very simple.
I never really died!
What?!
DORAGORAMU
FIRE DRAGON TRANSFORMATION SPELL
REAPER FLUTE
I've been alive this whole time.
B-But, back there...
I didn't die.
But we saw you...
I was told you died!
I didn't die!
W-Wait just a minute.
How is that even possible?
Like yourself, I too was given
something by Queen Flora.
This... is what saved my life.
This is...
This is the Amulet of Carl.
Take this as well.
It's the Amulet of Carl
that's passed down in the royal family.
I'm sure it will help you someday.
Back when I went to face Dark Lord Hadorra,
Queen Flora gave me this treasure
of her royal family.
Megante!
In the explosion from my Megante spell,
this was damaged in my stead.
It's basically a kind of protection item.
As a result, I managed to survive,
though only barely.
Then...
Then why didn't you show up
to help before now, Master?!
We risked our lives to fight
because we believed you had died!
Are you saying
you knew this whole time and did nothing?!
That's right! Do you know how much
I grieved when I heard you'd died?!
We all fought desperately for you!
There must be some reason, right Master?
It's because...
Everyone, I will explain in due time.
But first...
I want you all to run
to the central palace as fast as you can!
Huh?!
Why do we have to race
at a time like this?!
Just answer the question and...
Shut up!
All I have to say right now is this.
Trust me when I tell you that I am here
to defeat the Dark King like all of you.
That is all.
I am no longer your Master.
I am a new ally who will fight with you.
W-Wait a minute!
I-I haven't regained the stamina...
Thank you, everyone.
Oh my. You seem alright.
Unfortunately for you, I'm quite immortal.
Immortal! Immortal!
Piercing my heart
isn't nearly enough to kill me.
I was interrupted earlier
by Hadorra in his dying moments
but I won't be stopped again.
I'll be sure to kill you!
My instincts tell me that
I can't afford to let you live.
Go ahead... if you can.
Why did Master suddenly
tell us to run to the palace?
How should we know?
But if Master says to run,
we obey and run.
It may seem meaningless or unimportant,
but there's always a reason for it.
That's always been Master Aban's style.
Go ahead if I can, you say?
You knew I was alive,
yet you sent the others off regardless.
You seem to be quite confident.
That sort of attitude will cost you.
You impressed me by thwarting
my Nine of Diamonds,
but that wasn't my only Kill Trap.
The others won't be able to
proceed unharmed.
Besides...
no matter what powerful spells you have,
I doubt you can do anything now.
Mr. Reaper... or whatever they call you...
do those Kill Traps of yours activate
automatically when someone snares them?
Those sorts of traps tend to be activated
by the creator's Magic Power.
But your hands appear full at the moment.
Y-You...!
Was this your plan all along?!
By keeping me here, all the Kill Traps
to King Ban's palace won't activate!
That's why you sent them ahead!
You're quite sharp.
You're more dangerous than I thought.
Enough chit chat. It's time to die.
After that, I'll wipe out the others
with new Kill Traps.
Most of my Kill Traps
are in the palace anyways.
Oh? That's useful information.
I'll keep that in mind down the road.
Enough!
W-What?
You can't move?!
I don't need a shave, thank you.
I already had one before I came here.
W-Why?!
My arm, no, half my body won't move!
W-Where did this feather come from?!
When you first fell,
I still sensed malice,
so I took precautions.
How does it feel to be caught
in a magical trap yourself?
Hadorra was once a cruel man.
He did terrible things to people.
But he always did it himself.
When fighting me,
he always came forward to fight.
But you are far lower than that!
You sit back and enjoy watching
the people you trap suffer!
You're lower than cruel, you're barbaric!
A warrior takes pride...
in upholding the basic rules of fighting.
At least Hadorra understood that!
With this blow, feel the anger
of his departed soul!
Remember this.
Though I don't enjoy using it,
I'm also well versed in such spellcraft.
If you continue using such dirty traps
against us, I will fight back in kind.
I will not forgive you!
And you would be wise to remember this.
I am going to kill you!
I swear... I swear I will kill you
with my own hands!
I swear it!
He's gone.
And now.
So King Ban is in here.
W-Whoa. It's even
more impressive up close.
You're right.
Wow. It's quite big, isn't it?
M-Master?! Where did you come from?!
We ran here at top speed!
Actually, I was just a step
behind you the whole time!
He's lying.
I never sensed him behind us.
I know he remained back there for a while.
I used my new skill,
Sneaky Step Stealthy Step Aban Step.
What the hell is that?!
Why not Sneaky Step
Stealthy Step Popp Step?
I guess if you used it,
you could call it that.
Something about him
is different from before.
It's like he possesses
a completely different power.
That glow...
I get it! So that's it!
This man...
And now, everyone, for your next task...
Enough.
Huh?
I can see the extent of your power.
Hyunckel... the extent of my power?
You're weak.
Far too weak!
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
I finally realized it
imasara kizuitanosa
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
Must be the reason I was born
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
I shake off the clinging night
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
Hyunckel voices his objection to Aban.
The others continue hesitantly
but their way is barred by a giant gate.
Its door is like the one
Dai and Baran barely managed to breach.
Yet Aban tackles it alone.
The mystery behind Aban's activities
after his fight with Hadorra are revealed.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Secret Way of Purification"
The adventure continues!