Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
HYUNCKEL VERSUS HADORRA
Hyunckel... you're alive?!
You...
Is this a dream? Or am I dead?
You're not dreaming. And you're not dead.
Hyunckel!
Maam.
You're alive! You...
Thank goodness!
Hey, Hyunckel!
I'm wounded over here! Help me out!
Have some medicinal herbs.
That bastard!
What happened to equal treatment?!
Explain this to me.
You were supposed to have died
with the fall of the Underground Palace.
That's right. I should have.
But I was saved
at the brink of death by one man.
Truly, at the brink of death!
So you survived...
...Crocodine.
My steel body is my one defining trait.
Plus your servants patched me up well.
I was barely alive
when this Garuda saved me.
I was the one who tried to kill you.
Why save me?
It was a warrior's mercy
that you ordered my treatment.
Mercy must be repaid in kind.
Besides, you must continue
to help Dai and his friends from now on.
If mercy was your intent,
you should have let me die.
Hm?
I ignored my own weakness
and turned my hate to my master, Aban,
and towards humanity.
My death would have
at least made up for my crimes!
Now, I have to live on in my shame!
Hyunckel.
I believe the worth of a man lies in
how much they can let go of the past.
Be it a life in shame, hated by all,
so long as you walk the path you believe,
isn't that enough?
The Garuda tells me Dai
and his friends have headed north.
Probably to Valge Island.
I'm going to go help them.
It's the least I can do after they
reminded me of a warrior's honor.
Wait!
You're right. My crimes aren't so small
that my death absolves them!
And you and Maam were the first people
to ever shed tears for me.
In order to repay those tears,
I must... I must...
I must continue to fight!
What's that?!
The Dark Armour Blade?!
It was lost in the fall of
the Underground Palace! How is it here?!
And it's completely restored!
They say a true weapon
chooses its wielder.
Perhaps this Dark Blade was drawn here
by your renewed Aura.
Amudo!
That's it!
So long as you have the will to fight,
that armour shall never die!
Thank you, Beast King!
Unbelievable!
I never trusted you, but for Crocodine
to betray us and join Dai!
You'll believe it when you hear him
destroy the Dark Flame Spire.
Maam, can you stand?
Yes.
Leave this to me.
Head to Valge Tower with Popp.
Dai should be on his way there.
Yes, but...
Well, okay then! Thanks!
Best of luck to you!
What are you doing, Popp?!
Forget him! He said go, so we're going!
Like I'll let him touch you
a second longer!
Traitors must die!
That's the law of the Dark Army!
I'll make your death slow and painful!
Now, how do you want to die?!
Hadorra, are you looking down on me?
Or are you too stupid to tell
how strong your opponents are?
What?
These scrubs aren't worth my time!
If you want to kill me,
do it by risking your own life!
Y-You brat!
Don't let him any closer
to the Dark Flame Spire!
Get back, old man!
Beast King Anguish Blast!
No! The Dark Flame Spire!
I feel lighter! The Curse Field is gone!
What an astounding attack!
But "Anguish Blast"
sounds a little too ominous.
Why don't you call it,
"Beast King Redemption Blast"?
That's not half bad! Thanks, old man!
Oh, man. After all that trouble,
there goes my Curse Field.
What is Master Hadorra doing?
The Dark Flame Spire has fallen.
It's your turn now.
Lord Hadorra!
Stay back, all of you!
I'll show him my true power!
I'm no longer worthy
to call Aban, "Master."
To claim to avenge my master
would be impudent.
However, for taking the life
of my father, Bartos,
I cannot allow you to live!
You snotty whelp! Watch your tongue!
Like father, like son, you both defy me!
Begone!
Impossible! My Ionazun spell...?!
Have you forgotten?
My armour repels all attack spells.
Prepare yourself, Hadorra!
Die!
There's nothing in this world
my Hell's Claws can't penetrate!
Good! That's more like it!
Dai!
Popp! Maam!
It was Hyunckel! Hyunckel saved us!
Talk about an oasis in a desert!
That's great! So Hyunckel
is a Disciple of Aban after all!
I'm sure Master Aban must be proud.
Let's go! To save Leona!
Right!
Be careful, Hyunckel.
They're evenly matched!
No, Lord Hadorra seems at a disadvantage!
He's not the Dark Commander for nothing!
He has the power to back it!
He's stronger than I imagined!
No wonder Dark King Ban likes him!
And without my spells,
I'm at a disadvantage!
If I can do something about that armour...
I see...
He's coming for the final showdown!
Bloody Sukuraido!
That was rather disappointing.
It's over, Hadorra.
No!
Lord Hadorra lost?!
Impossible! How can you move
with your vitals pierced?!
Unfortunately for you, I have a heart
on both sides of my chest.
I was waiting for you to lower your sword!
Now let me fill your armour
with my flames of hell!
Merazoma!
Hyunckel...
BLOODY SUKURAIDO!
FIVE FINGER FLARES
How do you like my flames?
Agonizing, aren't they?
They won't go out
until your body is burned away!
Curse you and your dirty tricks!
I can't... I can't move my body!
So much for your mighty sword.
Meanwhile, I still have my secret weapon!
Now watch as I unleash the full power
of my greatest spell!
Can your punctured armour withstand it?!
Take this!
Begiragon!
I've won!
Stubborn little brat! He's finally dead!
Lord Hadorra has won!
Lord Hadorra, are you hurt?
It's nothing.
I merely lost one of my hearts.
Is this all that survived?
Yes, Lord!
Good! We're going after Dai
and we'll slaughter them all!
Yes, Lord!
No! Dai and the others are in danger!
I have to stop them!
But I don't have any way to fight!
What can I do? What weapon can I use?!
Life itself.
Aban?!
Life energy. Basically, your Aura.
What is this attack?!
I just focused my Aura.
As a Warrior, you cannot cast spells.
If your sword is lost,
the only weapon left is life itself.
In such a situation, use your life energy.
In other words, you fight with your Aura.
My Aura...
But an Aura is offensive life energy.
It's very, very difficult to control.
If your heart is full of malice,
it can put your own life at risk.
I don't need such a skill.
All I have to do is defeat my enemy
with my sword, right?
Back then, I laughed at Aban's teachings.
But now, I understand.
Now I know I can do it!
It's almost impressive how stubborn
the Students of Aban can be.
Wait a minute, Lord Hadorra!
We can take a half-dead enemy like him!
Huh? Has he given up?
What is that? An extreme amount of energy
is gathering at Hyunckel's forehead!
Wait, is this... his Aura?!
If it means stopping Hadorra here,
then I'll gladly use all of my life!
Aban, my master! Give this ungrateful
student his final strength!
N-No! Get away!
Grand Cross!
Dai, that light!
Yeah!
What is it, you two?
It's just like back then.
The light from when Master Aban
fought Hadorra and died!
Megante!
It was just like that.
Like the final flash of life itself.
No...!
Hey! Where are you going, Dai?!
Where do you think?! To go help Hyunckel!
Hold on!
We don't know if that was him or not!
Besides, he can't use spells!
He can't cast Megante and die!
But that's no ordinary light!
Win or lose, he won't be alright!
Isn't that right, Maam?!
What are you thinking?!
What about Princess Leona?!
There's still time until sundown!
Stop it! There's nothing you can do now!
No! At the very least, I have to go!
You can't, Dai!
We're going to Valge Tower! We have to!
Why?! Are you abandoning Hyunckel?!
That's what he wants!
Hyunckel and Crocodine
came here to help us.
It's all so you can save Princess Leona!
If you turn back now, all they've done,
their very lives will be for nothing!
Besides, Hyunckel is a Disciple of Aban.
He'd risk his life to save his friends
no matter what!
Just as our Master did!
They're strong... They're so strong,
both Hyunckel and Maam.
I can't compete...
All right, Maam.
Right now, our purpose is
to save Leona as soon as possible!
Let's go! The tower is right there!
Hyunckel, Crocodine, thank you!
I promise I'll save Leona!
So please, please don't die out there!
I somehow managed to withstand it.
How lucky I had these minions
to use as shields.
Is this the power
of that Grand Cross attack?
What terrifying power!
Hyunckel!
I see.
I get it now!
Grand Cross was an incomplete attack!
As a result, it drew upon
all the Aura Hyunckel had!
All that's remains is this soulless husk!
After all your trouble, it looks like
I get the last laugh, Hyunckel!
I'll just cleave your head off,
and massacre Dai and his friends,
and there'll be no one left in my way!
You can grind your teeth in the afterlife!
Along with Aban, Bartos,
and your friends that follow you!
Aban...
Bartos...
Master!
Dad!
This is the end! Die, Hyunckel!
I-Impossible!
He had spent all of his Aura completely!
Even unconscious, he still retains
the last of his will to fight!
Well done, Hyunckel.
You are indeed, a true...
warrior...!
Man, Master Hadorra is useless!
He can't even beat a few brats...
Oh well. I guess this means
Dai's head will be worth even more!
The Hero's Party that the Dark Army
working together couldn't beat.
If I obliterate them,
the more glory for me!
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
Saved by Hyunckel and Crocodine,
Dai's party reaches Valge Tower at last.
But again, they are at the mercy
of Flazzard's powerful attack.
When all hope seems lost, Dai
remembers the words of his master, Aban!
Next time on
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Final Aban Style Technique"
The adventure continues!