Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE WORLD SUMMIT
Princess Leona is planning a world summit
to plan the battle with the Dark Army.
A world summit?
That's right.
She's gathering kings and leaders from
all over the world for a world meeting.
Leona's planning that?
Until now, leaders didn't work together,
something the Dark Army has exploited.
As a result, Orzam, Ringaia,
and Carl have fallen.
But, with the call of
the young leader, Princess Leona,
the remaining leaders have decided to work
and plan together to face the Dark Army.
Amazing!
That's huge!
That's what Leona meant by
something only she can do.
When and where will
the world summit be held?
In a few days, at a location in Papunica.
I plan to depart tonight, but Dai...
would you like to join me?
Listen, if important people
from all over will be there,
maybe someone will know
about other legendary weapons.
That's true!
Your Majesty, we'll leave for Papunica
right away with Popp's Rura spell!
Very well.
-In that case...
-Wait a minute.
Thank you. Without you,
we would all have died.
You're a true Hero indeed.
You showed me
there's always a bigger fish.
We'll train to prepare for the upcoming
showdown with the Dark Army.
Why?! After my
amazing performance out there...!
All of you! Why won't you praise me?!
-Stop that!
-Ow!
Who did that?!
Enough. You're making a fool of yourself.
How dare you, you little ghost!
I don't think you have the right
to talk down to me like that!
Oh? Are you sure?
What?!
Can't you tell?
That's Grand Master Brokin.
What?!
Uh...
Hi!
Eep!
Grand Master!
This old man is the Grand Master?!
Sir Brokin, the Holy Fist!
G-Grand Master!
Why were you disguised?!
I was curious to see
how you two had improved.
You two are students of
Brokin, the Holy Fist?
I didn't expect all that to happen,
but in the end, I got to see
the results of Maam's training.
I'm gonna get chewed out!
The experience was good for you,
wasn't it, Chiu?
For three years since I took you in,
the reason you never improved
was because you always tried to show off.
But that attack you used when you were
desperate was quite impressive, wasn't it?
You've grown.
Grand Master!
You're a proper hero, too!
You've got the biggest guts in Romos!
Everyone...
That's how it is, Chiu.
Fame follows after.
You mustn't seek it out.
Grand Master!
He's a pretty good master.
Yes.
Let's get going.
Grand Master,
I'd like to travel with Miss Maam.
Go ahead. If they give you permission.
Well, thank you for everything!
Hold on, you three!
Chiu?
If you insist,
I would be willing to help...
Rura.
Huh?! Hey!
Wait! Wait for me!
Popp...
That was mean.
Well, he hasn't learned
his master's lesson.
Still, he's an interesting guy.
Wait!
Looking at him,
my worries about being human or not
seems almost insignificant.
I suppose we could use a guy like him.
Wait! Let me join your party!
Mystban?! How did you find this place?!
So your hideout was on this island
so close to the Field of Death.
Where is Hadorra?
Well...
Where is he?
Zaboera, let him in.
Lord Hadorra?!
It matters not. I need to speak to him.
Pathetic, isn't it?
This is the man who failed at his
last chance to kill Dai and was defeated.
Mystban, you're King Ban's
most trusted vassal.
I know you serve under me,
yet you wield more authority.
If you wish to inform King Ban
of my defeat, so be it.
I know I'm in no position to ask,
but I must beg a favor!
While I'm converted into a Superior Being,
would you fight the humans?
The conversion is almost complete,
but the humans are up to something big.
I've learned leaders from around the world
are quietly gathering in Papunica.
You want me to crush them for you?
To buy you time?
Will that serve King Ban?
I know of Zamuza's defeat.
Superior Beings are flawed creatures
that can't cast spells after transforming.
We have already found
a solution to that flaw.
Magic Power is lost in the process of
changing from Darkling to Superior Being.
The solution to that is to turn this body
into a Superior Being from the start!
What?
Hadorra, you would abandon
your Darkling body?
You would live on as a monster?
Indeed.
You would lose your immortality.
Would you allow that?
The Disciples of Aban are enemies
worth that sacrifice. I now realize that.
I no longer want status or honor
or even this life!
I must defeat them, even if it costs me
my body, or my life will mean nothing!
Very well.
Hadorra, despite having
the strongest body and abilities,
the reason the Disciples of Aban
continued to beat you,
was your weakness of will
and your pride.
But you have cast those aside.
Having overcome your greatest weakness,
you shall become the greatest warrior.
King Ban will be pleased.
Leave Papunica to me.
Thank you.
Can he really be trusted?
We have no choice.
I need time more than anything.
I don't care who gives it,
so long as I can have one last chance!
Hmm. This is a pretty lovely country.
Yo, you're back!
What the heck is this behemoth?!
Crocodine!
Maam! I heard you fought admirably!
Your return is like
giving a metal club to an ogre!
Don't talk about metal clubs
and ogres to a girl!
Sorry about that!
Hm?
What's that thing?
That's my fellow student, Chiu.
He just joined us.
Hmm.
Are you sure this little rat
is up to being a party member?
Is he another male friend of Miss Maam's?
Now, now, Big Guy. He actually helped out.
Miss Maam has pretty poor taste.
So where's the Princess and other leaders?
The world summit is being held... there.
The Papunica Grand Chapel.
They're gathered there.
How surprisingly considerate of Myst
to show such leniency to Hadorra.
You said it!
But, if he's holding the Key of Ban,
it means King Ban
is allowing this attack.
REFRACTOR FIST
TOMAKUGUTSOSHO
All of you, welcome back.
And Maam!
Leona!
I see you've gotten stronger.
We're counting on you.
You're impressive, too, Leona.
To unite leaders from around the world.
Unfortunately, it's not all of them.
We've heard nothing
from leaders of the fallen countries.
At Ringaia, we only managed
to rescue General Bowson.
We couldn't find anyone in Orzam.
And Queen Flora of
Carl Kingdom is still missing.
Don't worry. She's well known
for being a bold, courageous woman.
I know she's all right.
Huh. More bold than the Princess?
She could even be stronger than Dai.
I heard that, Popp!
Hey, does anyone in the world summit
know about legendary swords?
Why don't you ask King Volken of Teran?
He's known for his great knowledge.
A sword stronger than
the Sword of Champions
likely doesn't exist.
What?!
The metal used in that sword,
Orichalcum, was made my the gods.
A small bit was given to humans
and made into legendary equipment.
What about the Demon Dragon Blade?!
That sword was forged by the gods.
It's not a sword of the human world.
I see.
Are there any other powerful swords?
Summon Meruru.
Huh?! Meruru's in Papunica?!
I get to help Popp and the others already.
Now Dai, visualize the object you seek.
When I tell you, drop that flame.
Now.
Ra... n... ka... ku... su...
Huh?!
What's that?
Rankakusu Village.
A small village that lies east
of Teran and Bengana.
How will we get there?
Maybe borrow Leona's Balloon Ship?
Or use Rura to somewhere close by?
We could use Rura to get straight there.
Huh?! Really?!
Popp, you've been to that village?
I didn't go there. I left it.
It's my place of birth.
It's your home village?!
Your family runs a weapon store, right?!
That might be it!
You know, I ran away from home
to be Master Aban's student...
Ow, ow, ow...
What a terrible landing.
Don't blame me. I'm carrying a lot.
Sorry about this.
For making you come with us.
We figured you being here would help.
It's okay. I want to help all of you.
This way.
Thank goodness.
She's nothing like that fake one.
She's kind and warm.
I can see why Popp likes her.
It seems like a nice place.
It's a tiny village.
Nothing's changed at all.
The shop's up ahead. I'll be waiting here.
Are you really sure?
If Dad sees me, it'll be bad.
Does that lady work in the weapon shop?
Huh?!
Mom!
Huh?! Popp?!
Is that really you?!
Huh? Uh...
Popp!
Mom!
Mom, I'm sorry!
-I'm sorry!
-It's okay, Popp!
Popp...
He must have really wanted to see her.
Dad?!
Honey, Popp is back!
Popp...
Dad!
You run off without a word
for over a year!
You think you can just waltz back
like nothing's happened?!
-You ungrateful son!
-Honey, stop!
Mister! Calm down!
Why you...!
I didn't realize we had customers.
Sorry about that.
I can't believe my idiot son
is actually helping the Hero.
But he's helped us so much.
It's thanks to Popp that we're even alive.
He's our most reliable friend!
Seriously?
So, mister, about what we said...
Right. A legendary sword.
You won't find one in my shop.
But you might find something
at Ron's place.
Ron?
He's a Darkling I met recently.
Dad! Is that Darkling's name, Ron Berku?!
Sure. So?
You know him?
I heard from Hyunckel.
The legendary craftsman who made his
Dark Armour Blade and Spear was named...
Ron Berku!
Then...!
Yeah, if we ask him...!
Don't be so sure.
Huh?
He lives in the forest like a hermit.
He doesn't like meeting people.
Go away.
I will never put my heart into
making a weapon again.
Much less a fool's errand like
the world's greatest sword.
But...!
My interests lie solely in
how the weapons I make perform.
But recently, there's been
a lack of decent wielders.
No matter how powerful the weapon,
if the wielder is a dud,
then it's nothing but an ornament.
Those swords over there.
I forged them for drinking money,
but they're better than a normal sword.
Take one and leave.
Better than normal isn't enough.
Even your Dark Armour Blade couldn't
endure my power and crumbled.
What?
Please! Make a sword
stronger than that Dark Sword!
Otherwise, I can't hope to beat
the Demon Dragon Blade!
The Demon Dragon Blade?!
You fought that weapon?!
And?! What was the result?!
It was a draw.
I broke their sword,
but mine disintegrated.
So I guess I lost.
You broke it? You broke
the Demon Dragon Blade with my sword?!
Yeah.
Wonderful! That's magnificent!
Hey, Ron, what's so funny?
How can I not be overjoyed?!
The Demon Dragon Blade was forged
by the gods as the world's greatest sword!
It's the ultimate weapon
that I spent over a century pursuing!
To hear that the Dark Sword I forged
out of an inferior metal broke it!
You've impressed me, boy!
With you as its wielder,
I can forge the world's greatest sword!
If I make it out of the same material,
it will beat the Demon Dragon Blade!
Then please! Hurry!
Calm down. I said, "the same material."
The same as the Demon Dragon Blade.
Orichalcum.
Find me some Orichalcum.
What?!
I'm no Metallurgist.
Without material, I can't forge a weapon.
Great. So we're back to square one.
But we just need to find some Orichalcum.
Easier said than...
Hm?
Oh!
The Crown of Champions!
King Romos said it's made of Orichalcum!
To Dermline Island!
Grampa! Where?! Where is it?!
What's this all about?
My Crown of Champions!
It should be back there.
Where?! Oh! This!
Whoops! That's not it!
Wait! I found it!
So that's our Orichalcum!
Let's go!
-Bye, Grampa!
-Excuse us!
Rura!
Clean up after yourselves!
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
As embers that keep me burning
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
A single transparent beam of light
me no mae wo terashite yuku
Lights the way before me
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
There is little that I can do
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
Ron Berku, the Underworld's greatest
craftsman will forge a sword for Dai.
Back in Papunica, Leona's
summit of world leaders is held,
but not everyone sees eye to eye.
As an ominous fog brews, the giant
footsteps of the Dark Army approach.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Landing of Sovereign Rock Castle"
The adventure continues!