With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
You're The Bravest
THE SURVIVORS
TOWN OF POLTOS, ROMOS KINGDOM
What is that?!
Look!
-Everyone run!
-Run! Faster!
The town of Poltos!
Forgive my lack of manners,
but there is no time.
I bring news from Queen Flora
of Carl Kingdom.
Isn't this place a little too cold?
Don't blame me!
The Dark Army's been rampaging
all over the world!
Is that so?
Hey!
We caught some fish!
Nice!
What is that?
Bird bones?
Run!
Where the hell is the real Hero?!
Such impressive destructive ability.
King Ban truly is great!
Ah, if it isn't my master,
Dark Commander Mystban.
Take a look at that crater.
I, Zaboera, am truly in awe of
King Ban's power!
And he even granted me the position
of Dark Army Second-in-Command.
I'm glad I cut ties with
that fool Hadorra when I did.
Zaboera.
Yes?
When you converted Hadorra
into a Superior Being,
did you not notice the Black Core
implanted in him?
Oh, I noticed it. But I left it alone.
I figured he'd die
for King Ban eventually anyway,
and so long as I wasn't
caught in the blast, it didn't matter.
Excuse me?
You filth!
You're not worthy to speak ill of Hadorra!
I recognize your part
in saving King Ban,
but I will never trust gutter rats
who care only for their own success.
They always turn on their masters
when it suits their needs.
When you do,
I won't hesitate to kill you.
Hmph! Say whatever you will!
Strength is not about possessing power.
It's about being the last one standing.
I promise I'll find a way
to have the last laugh.
I...
I made it.
Did I wash up here?
You swam all this way
while carrying me?
You never cease to amaze me.
A Grisly?!
Without my Magic Power this is bad!
But I have to protect her at all costs!
Hey! Over here!
I'll take you down even if it kills me!
What?!
Oh! You found them, Troop Number Eight!
Sir Popp!
Miss Maam!
You morons. Don't scare me like that.
Hang in there!
We'll take you to the Forest Fort!
Good job finding them!
The Forest Fort?
We were rescued by the Order of Carl.
We're stationed there now.
The Order of Carl survived!
As well as Queen Flora!
Huh?!
So it's been four days.
The Dark Army has been using
their flying Dark Citadel
to drop bombs all over the world.
On one target every day.
At first, I wondered why
they weren't attacking capitals,
but after hearing your accounts,
now I know.
It doesn't matter where.
The Dark King wants to destroy
the Surface World, not invade it.
But at least you two made it back safely!
I'm sure Dai, Hyunckel,
and Crocodine also...
I sure hope so.
We saw it.
The legendary Holy Mother Dragon
took Dai away.
Hyunckel and Big Guy took a direct hit
from the Dark King's attack.
If Hadorra hadn't shown up,
me and Maam and Gome would be dead.
We got our butts kicked.
Seriously.
It's no good.
Popp and Maam have both felt
the terror of the Dark King up close.
There's nothing we can say
to lift their spirits.
I guess... there's nothing we can do
to stop them.
You mustn't say things like that.
You're both Disciples of Aban,
are you not?
Huh?
Queen Flora!
Huh?! Then this person is...
That's right. She escaped the fall
of Carl with a handful of knights
and has been waiting for a chance
to strike back at the Dark Army.
She brought us here to this fort.
Popp. Maam.
I heard what happened.
But if you really carry on
the will of Aban,
you mustn't voice such weakness.
Did you know Master Aban?
Aban was a member of our Order.
He risked his life to protect us
with the lead knight, Roka.
Yes. With your father.
Back when Hadorra led his forces
on an attack on our world...
my father fell ill.
As princess, I had to lead my army
to fight against him.
To boost my subjects' morale,
I had to put on a strong face.
But I was unsure if we really could fight
the supernatural powers of the Dark Lord.
I was terrified.
It wasn't just me.
Everyone in the palace was scared.
It's no good! There's no way
we can beat the Dark Lord!
At this point, we'll gain nothing
by scampering around.
That's when Aban spoke up.
Non, non, non!
What are you all talking about?
If we do nothing
then we really will gain nothing.
If all we can do is scamper around
then our course is clear.
My friends, let us scamper around!
I broke out into laughter.
There, in front of everyone.
That's when I realized...
this man is a natural-born Hero
who can give everyone hope.
That's why
whenever I find myself losing hope,
I dedicate myself to
scampering around as much as I can.
I still believe in what he said.
Um... Your Majesty...
Master Aban...
I know. He's dead, isn't he?
If he were alive somewhere...
he would never stand still
and let his home be ravaged as it has.
I know he would save us if he could.
I get it. She...
She was in love with Master Aban.
I would like... to scamper around!
Me too.
I know I can't be Master Aban.
Though incompetent, I am his student.
Thank you.
But now is not the time. Get some rest.
I have a plan of my own.
Recuperate your strength for now.
Understood?
She's a great woman.
There's something reassuring...
almost overpowering about her.
Isn't there?
I can see why
you respect her so much, Leona.
So she and Master Aban were together.
She's got a sort of
mature allure to her that...
You lech!
Princess Leona! Come to the command room!
The Dark Army is moving against Ringaia!
CASTLING
BEHOMA
HEALING-TYPE SPELL
How boring it is...
for things go so smoothly.
I agree wholeheartedly!
I wouldn't be so sure.
An unfortunate card.
This card comes up every time.
You're saying those
who would resist me are still out there?
I'm not sure.
Whatever it means,
it's definitely trouble.
I've never been wrong with my cards.
Then let us draw them out.
That's why we have those two held captive.
TERAN KINGDOM
Your Majesty! Outside! Look in the sky!
The Holy Mother Dragon!
Here in Teran, where we worship
the God of Dragons,
the life of a Dragon Knight
is coming to an end right now.
Could it be the Hero?!
Where am I?
Did I... make it?
No. You have died.
Who's there?!
I am the Holy Mother Dragon.
I preside over the life and death of
Dragon Knights as a servant of the gods.
The Holy Mother Dragon?
I remember.
When a Dragon Knight dies,
to pass on the power of the Crest,
a legendary Dragon appears.
You have taken an astral form
and have merged with me.
Soon your soul shall be led
to the world of the gods.
Then...
a new Dragon Knight
is going to replace me?
There will be no new Dragon Knight.
You are the last Knight.
Huh?! W-Why?!
The gods of Humans, Darklings, and Dragons
created the Dragon Knights
to defeat any evil that would
tip the balance of the world.
But over a long, long time,
the power of such evil has grown.
Dark King Ban possesses a power
greater than a god.
Even with a Dragon Knight's power,
evil can no longer be punished.
In fact, overcoming the Dragon Knights
may be what drove evil
to become so powerful.
But...
That is why I am ending
the history of the Dragon Knights.
I no longer have the power
to birth a new Knight anyway.
A dark force is bringing
my life to an end.
Then there won't be anyone
who can stop Dark King Ban?
You can forget your trying battles now.
Your soul can return
to the heavens with me.
Something's wrong.
You have two souls.
D...
Dad!
Mother Dragon.
I am the true last Knight, Baran.
This boy, Dai, was born between myself
and a human woman.
The death you sensed was mine.
What?! That's not possible!
This boy's life has not yet ended.
Please, I ask that you grant this boy
one more chance.
Dad...
No one can defeat the Dark King,
no matter how powerful.
Even if I resurrect him,
he will only face a cruel hell again.
I do not agree.
This boy has a power
no normal Dragon Knight has.
Something beyond power.
But...
Dragon Knights can only last
for one generation.
So how could a Dragon Knight sire a child?
The gods must have sensed the limits of
the Dragon Knights and gave us this hope.
In this world where power
rules over everything...
he can defeat evil with his soul.
Perhaps that is why the gods
allowed this boy to be born.
Please, Mother.
Very well.
I shall grant the very last
of my power to Dai.
Dai.
From now on, you will write
the history of the Dragon Knights,
raising a child with the woman you love.
And to do so, you must defeat Ban.
I know you can do it.
I can't!
I'm...
I'm not that amazing!
I'm not strong like you are!
You are not alone.
You have your friends.
Dad!
And Soara and I...
will always be with you.
Wait! Don't go!
Dad!
Dad...
please don't go.
Fetch someone who can use Rura!
Get him to Queen Flora!
My King!
Let's give them some space.
Thank goodness.
Thank you... for being alive.
Queen Flora.
Dai is asleep.
His wounds have been healed.
I see. That's a relief.
Truly good news.
But I'm afraid I have some very bad news.
Huh?!
A message from the Dark Army
was sent to countries across the world...
using a communication spell with mirrors.
This is the translated message.
"To the foolish humans of the world.
In a few days, our Dark Army
shall vaporize this Surface World
where you dwell.
You have no way of stopping us.
Accept this as fate
and die with your world.
To celebrate this grand achievement,
the traitors who aided
the defeated Hero and his party,
Hyunckel the Dark Swordsman and
Beast King Crocodine, shall be executed.
Those interested may witness this
as a memory to take to the afterlife.
They die at noon in two days,
in the northern mountains of Carl Kingdom.
That is all."
Executed?! The bastards!
So Hyunckel and Crocodine
are being held by the Dark Army.
We will have a meeting at once!
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
I finally realized it
imasara kizuitanosa
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
Must be the reason I was born
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
I shake off the clinging night
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
The missing Hyunckel and Crocodine
are being held by the Dark Army.
And Dai has returned after
parting with his father, Baran.
While Dai's wounds have healed, memories
of his defeat by Ban torment him.
Even so, Popp and the others
believe that Dai will stand once more.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Dai and Popp"
The adventure continues!