nakama tono kizuna wo
With your bonds with your friends
sono mune ni idaite
Embraced in your heart
hikari no you ni isshun ni
Like a flash, in an instant
subete wo kaketeku
You risk it all
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
tachimukatte ikunnda to
You will face it again
kakugo wo kimetanara
If that's what you choose
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even when hurt
Oh tsumazuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
susume kono tabi no hate
Continue on
To your journey's end
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Again and again
To the future you make
Oh Oh
tachiagareru
You're The Bravest
You can stand up
Oh Oh
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
ON THIS BOND
Just as Dai, the Hero is the only one
who can defeat the Dark King,
the only one who can unlock
Dai's full potential...
is the one who has been with him
since the very beginning of this fight.
Popp... That's you.
Work together... and achieve victory!
Master!
Master, please watch us!
I promise...
we'll get the Dark King for you!
What a joke.
What are you doing?!
Ban's going to attack!
Hurry and ready yourself!
Nah. Don't worry.
Ban will never attack first
in that stance,
the Demonic Guard of Heaven and Earth.
It's not that sort of skill.
I understand now.
It's the ultimate defensive skill.
Basically, it's for countering.
While it lets him use
three skills at once,
used offensively,
it's just a triple attack.
And Ban's skills are great enough
to defeat most enemies without it.
I bet the Tenchimato
is a stance Ban only uses
against truly powerful enemies.
By letting an enemy attack first,
he can hit them with his super skills
of attack, defense, and magic,
completely obliterating them.
It's unbeatable!
But he must charge a massive amount
of energy in order to unleash these.
They're not normal attacks.
Hitting his opponent
with these three super attacks
is what brings such devastation.
That immovable stance isn't
just to make his enemies attack first.
It probably lets him conserve energy,
storing it in his body
and then unleashing it all at once.
It appears Aban's parting words
weren't said out of desperation.
A fledgling like you
saw through my ultimate skill.
But, knowing that, what can you do?
How do you intend to fight?
Once I take this stance, it's over.
No one can break it.
And buying time is meaningless.
Dai's wounds were inflicted by Dark Aura
and can't be healed by healing spells.
That's the problem!
Dai's not healing at all!
I can only think of
one way to attack Ban.
Hit him in the brief moments
following an attack.
Before he charges for the next.
But with everyone in this state...
And I can always initiate
an attack as well.
Don't forget that!
-He dropped his stance!
-Here he comes!
Larhart! Hym!
I hate to ask this
from complete strangers, but...
give your lives to me!
They say ancient humans thought thunder
was the gods fighting in the heavens.
You can feel the terrifying power
from way down here!
Dai and the others must be fighting
Dark King Ban right now!
Unbelievable.
There's no ifs or buts about it.
Either the Dark King falls,
or the Surface World ends.
It's one or the other.
It's hopeless!
He's on a whole different level!
Please! Please just stop it!
I can almost hear the anguished cries
of your friends, Dai!
They might as well have stayed behind
and left you here with the Princess!
This game...
is mine.
-D-Darn it!
-It's no good!
I can't move my body!
So much for my plan.
It looks like it was worthless.
You asked us to give our lives to you.
So tell us.
If there's any hope of winning,
tell us what to do!
We've reached our limit!
If you can't hold out, then all is lost.
My plan wasn't anything complicated.
It's what you said before.
Be a shield for Dai!
We're all beat to hell here.
None of us can face Ban directly.
That's why I wanted the three of us
to take his blows and create an opening,
allowing Dai to focus on the offensive!
"Wanted"? You're talking past tense?
It looks like I underestimated him.
At this rate, we won't even be able to
take more blows for Dai!
P-Popp...
I shall end this now.
I'll wipe you all out
with my Calamity Wall.
It looks like some poor little Eyes
will be disintegrated as well.
He means me!
I'll make this one move slowly.
You can enjoy your fear longer.
Calamity Wall!
Dammit! He's laughing his head off!
I won't give up!
I will never give up!
I swear I'll survive this Calamity Wall!
There's no point if we can't withstand it!
I need him to use
that ultimate skill one more time!
What?!
You fool! Didn't you see
the three of us fail against it?!
The Demonic Guard of Heaven and Earth
can't be beaten head-on,
not even with ten people!
But the moment he unleashes that ultimate
skill is when he's most vulnerable!
Popp, you had the same idea as me!
I thought that was the only way, too!
Withstand all three super attacks
and then attack immediately after!
That's the only way
to defeat that unbeatable skill!
But I knew that it would kill me
if I tried it alone.
So you saw through it, too.
Nice going, partner. That settles it!
You're not alone anymore!
You've got allies here who will suffer
those super attacks in your place!
Even if it means getting hit by all three,
I'll give you the chance to strike back!
So that was the plan.
These guys are crazy.
It's an impossibility
within an impossibility.
And we haven't even gotten him
to take his ultimate stance yet.
First we need to take care of
the big problem at hand.
But it's still a gamble whether
the Dark King will take his stance or not!
Stay back!
Little Hym!
That sounds fun!
You can count me in
on that hopeless gamble!
Sadly, I don't think
I'll be able to see how it turns out!
Hym!
You've gained my respect
for the first time.
But I can't let you beat me
in terms of dedication to Master Dai!
I can't see anymore!
Which way is Ban?!
Ban's this way!
Come on!
-You can have it!
-My life!
Larhart! Hym!
They actually did it!
AURA KNUCKLE
HAKENDISUTORU
In this condition
I doubt anything I do will work on him!
In that case...!
We'll be living bullets!
We'll use our bodies as weapons
and charge him!
So you're prepared to die.
Their intensity...
No simple attack can counter them!
Tenchimato!
W-What?!
Medoroa?!
Phoenix Wing!
You surprised me, boy!
Not only did you once again
force me to take this stance,
but by using a delayed Medoroa,
you even managed to scare me!
But, unfortunately for you,
you're now out of options.
What? I can't drop my stance!
Something inside of me senses a threat!
Do they still...?!
Hym, Larhart, thank you!
You used to be our enemies,
and yet you've done so much for us!
You've given us a chance at victory!
We can't waste it!
Your final attack?
Very well. Come on!
Are you sure about that, Mister Dark King?
What do you mean?
This final attack we're about to unleash
will break through your precious
Tenchimato!
Don't make me laugh!
Gigastrash and Medoroa.
You already know that
your most powerful attacks won't work!
Don't you get it, Ban?!
Popp didn't cast Medoroa
to try to defeat you!
He did it to show me the perfect timing!
Oh?
I was right.
Right after you use Tenchimato,
there's a slight delay
until you're ready to counter again.
I cast Medoroa in order for
Dai and I to see the timing for ourselves!
Just as I thought,
you froze for an instant!
And on top of that, you couldn't properly
deflect the Medoroa back at me!
Even though Mystban could do it!
In other words,
if we strike at that timing,
even wounded as we are,
we have a chance at a comeback!
That's interesting.
I see. So that's the reason why I froze.
No wonder you never knew about it.
The Tenchimato has never failed to
beat your enemy, has it?
Of course not.
Tenchimato is my ultimate skill!
To use it means to
absolutely erase any enemy.
That's why you have that weakness!
Being your greatest and final skill
causes that opening!
No matter how great a skill it is,
you shouldn't show it off so many times.
If you want to secure a victory,
you should attack normally.
Mister Dark King!
This is a gamble!
With their stamina drained, having Ban
attack normally would be worse.
Pop is purposely provoking Ban
to get him to use his ultimate skill.
He's betting on the Dark King's
absolute confidence in his ultimate skill!
Very well.
I accept that challenge!
Yes! Now it's all or nothing!
I'm interested in seeing if that
little provocation of yours pays off.
I never imagined
that I had such a weakness.
But first...!
And then there were two!
Dai! Popp!
This is grim!
I don't know what Popp's planning,
but those two are too wounded
to break Ban's ultimate skill!
Dammit! I can't even be a shield for them
in their moment of need!
From what I see, Dai doesn't have
the stamina to use Gigastrash anymore.
And if you plan to finish things
with your Medoroa, I can deflect it again,
whether back at you or not.
Neither attack can be used to finish me.
That's what I'm interested in.
There's no way you two can possibly
pull off that plan by yourselves.
You can't even withstand
my ultimate skill!
So how do you intend to hit me
with a deciding blow?
I must see this!
Which of us will use the deciding blow?
Isn't it obvious?!
The Hero is the one
who always defeats the Dark King!
I'll be the shield
against your ultimate skill!
Popp!
I did it!
I remember Mentor once used
two spells at the same time.
I thought maybe I could pull it off now.
You're very talented, boy!
That may be better than a single Medoroa...
but I thought you were smarter than that.
Can't you do simple math?
What?!
Let's assume that Explosion-type spell
is as strong as a Ionazun spell.
And that you can cause
a great deal of damage
with the rest of your Magic Power
focused in that staff.
That adds up to two!
So what about my third attack?
If a frail human like you
takes a direct hit unguarded,
you won't even serve as a shield!
First, I'll deflect your spell
with my Phoenix Wing.
Then I'll shatter your weapon
with my Calamity End.
That'll leave you defenseless.
And you'll be hit by the combined force of
the deflected spell and my Kaiser Phoenix.
You'll be incinerated in an instant,
and Dai will be hit by my spell
before he can exploit any weakness.
You'll both be reduced to ashes.
That's how it will end.
Things might be different
if you only had a few more people.
Here goes, Ban!
And yet... you still try.
Ban...
Popp may have been
a little unreliable at first.
But he's been with me in this battle
since the very beginning.
He's a friend I trust.
He's saved me time and time again!
If Popp says he'll make
an opening for me, then he will!
All I have to do is trust him
and focus my power!
You should remember this.
The two of us aren't alone.
We may have started
this adventure together,
but we've met numerous people
on our way here!
We've fought against
and been saved by them!
If even one of them hadn't been there,
we wouldn't be facing you now!
Even if they're far away,
even if they can't move,
we're all connected
by the bond of our souls!
It's the strength of this bond!
You can't see it,
but I know it's gonna surprise you!
I said it once.
Don't make me say it again.
You can't kill me with your soul!
Here goes, Dai!
The rest is up to you!
Right!
Tenchimato!
Burn to ashes!
Popp!
It's no good! It's just as Ban said!
I was right!
The Mirror of Shahal?!
Reflect it!
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Thanks to the desperate charge
by Hym and Larhart, Popp found a way.
Popp reflects Ban's magic
with the Mirror of Shahal,
consuming Ban in flames.
Using the chance that everyone has
given him, Dai readies a desperate attack!
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Greatest, Final Comeback"
The adventure continues!