boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
are itsukarada?
Since when was it?
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Being honest became whining
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Standing firm became strength
naa mitsukaranai?
Have you found it yet?
jishin janaku jibun jishin
Not confidence, your true self
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
I smolder because I've actually burned
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
tada me wo mihiraite
I'll just open my eyes
yume wo miru
And dream my dream
yume wo shiru
And know my dream
THE GRAND SORCERER MATORIV
Please! You have to help us!
I don't want anything to do with anyone.
Y-You!
Hm?
Uncle Matoriv!
Hmm?
Oh! You!
Maam?!
Look how you've grown!
You're ripe for motorboarding!
As if!
Calm down.
I've changed your diaper, remember?
Give me a motorboard greeting.
You haven't changed at all, you lech.
Wait, you know this guy, Maam?
I don't just know him. This is...
Matoriv! Now I remember!
A Mage who fought the Dark Lord with the
Hero and served the Papnica royal family!
His name was the Grand Sorcerer Matoriv!
By Hero, you mean Master Avan?
That's right. Uncle Matoriv was
in Master Avan's party.
How's your mother, Maam?
If she's still single, I can marry her.
He used to visit our home a lot,
but I had no idea he was hiding here.
This old lech was in the Hero's party?
Normally, I wouldn't want to
see him, but not today.
That's right!
No one could be more helpful
than the Grand Sorcerer Matoriv!
Please, Sir Matoriv!
Help us rescue Princess Leona!
Princess?
That's right. The Princess of Papnica
is being held on Valge Island.
I'm sure Sir Matoriv can overcome
the enemy's strange spell!
Please!
No thanks.
What?!
I said no thanks.
I'm done helping the stupid royal family.
The royal family? Stupid?
It's not just the royal family.
It's people in general.
When the Dark Army was attacking, they'd
butter us up so we'd fight for them.
But once peace came, they all suddenly
turned their backs on us.
Sure, I got to be advisor to the king
after the battle was over,
but I was constantly badgered
by the other officials.
I guess they were all
jealous of my skills.
That's people for you.
They think about nothing but themselves.
I grew tired of all of them
and decided to live in this cave.
I saved you all out of a whim,
but that's as far as it goes.
Besides, even if I help you, once it's
over, you'll just forget about me again.
Shoo! Shoo!
That's...
That's not true.
Dai, you...
Not everybody thinks
about nothing but themselves!
If you were Master Avan's companion,
you should know that!
Those eyes...
Avan?!
They have the same eyes.
And you are?
I'm Dai! Master Avan's last student!
His last?
Master Avan gave his life to save us!
I see. So Avan is dead.
That's why we want to avenge his death
by defeating the Dark Army!
Please! Lend us your strength!
I'm listening.
That's Legendary Forbidden Magic.
I think Flazzard mentioned
something like that.
Forbidden Magic is magic so dirty
that its use is banned.
Anyone who uses it
becomes a pariah among Mages.
How can we save Princess Leona?
First, you break
the Blizzblaze Curse Field.
To do that, you have to approach outside
the field and destroy these two Spires.
You'll need bombs that pack a hefty punch.
Then leave that to me!
Good. You can use
whatever you like for materials.
Don't forget they need
to pack a hefty punch.
We don't need any silly bombs.
I can blow them away with my magic.
He's not a Student of Avan, too, is he?
He is. This is Popp, the Mage.
Lend him to me.
Huh? Does he show promise?
Just the opposite. I've never seen
a Mage who looked so weak.
If I don't do something,
he's going to die out there.
O-Oh really?
Leave it to me. I'll train him with
a Special Hard Course worse than Avan's.
What?!
What did you just say, Lord Hadlar?!
A full-on assault.
They're sure to attempt to destroy
the Dark Flame and Dark Ice Spires.
When they do,
they'll split up their forces.
We will gather all of our armies
and wipe out Dai and his companions.
Oh?
But Flazzard is sure to complain
about not being able to take credit.
He's a monster that I created
using Legendary Forbidden Magic.
He's basically my son.
He won't disobey his father.
Interesting. At last,
my Dragon Legion can play a role.
Wait, Baran. I have something else
I need you to do.
What?
Mystvearn is fighting Carl Kingdom,
but they're proving quite resilient.
I'd like you to take down Carl.
You just said "all of our armies!"
And defeating the Hero should take
precedence over other invasions!
Isn't that why the Six Legion Commanders
were summoned?!
Or is there some other reason
you don't want me to face this boy, Dai?
Say what you will, the order still stands.
Very well. I'll let you give the orders
this time, Dark Commander.
I'm off to Carl Kingdom!
What's so special about Baran that Lord
Hadlar gives him preferential treatment?
Not even Baran can
overthrow Carl that easily!
We must kill Dai before that happens!
We shall make Valge Island their grave!
W-What the hell?! This is Nayle Village!
This is the
Instant Transmission Spell, Rura!
You think of your destination
and it takes you there instantly.
Popp!
Matoriv, you...
Yo, Leira, long time no see.
I ran into Maam.
Maam?
She's gotten all curvy,
just like you when you were young!
Why are you here with Popp?
It's complicated. I figured
I'd give his butt a well-deserved kick.
Come on!
Ow, ow, ow!
Popp...
-Get over here.
-I get it, I get it!
Shut up.
He seems like a mean old man.
He is.
But if he's teaching,
I know Popp will grow stronger.
He was once called
the greatest of all Mages.
But he can be a little quirky.
Is this really going to
let me use powerful magic?!
Idiot, this is basic stamina building
before training. It's a warm-up.
Better pick up the pace
or you'll get trampled!
See? You can do it.
Mera doesn't work well under water!
Find another way out or you'll drown!
Wanna know how? You don't use a spell!
You release your Magic Power itself!
From your entire body!
Whoops. Did I read him wrong?
Dai!
Let's stop.
Your wounds haven't fully healed.
You're pushing yourself.
I'm fine. I can't rest
when Popp is out there training!
Besides, Matoriv said this training
would help me to fight Flazzard!
I'll never forgive Flazzard!
Just when I finally found Leona!
I'll defeat him!
And I swear I'll rescue Leona!
I've never seen Dai so emotional before.
Princess Leona must
really be important to him.
All right! Here we go!
Come on!
MAGIC BULLET GUN
FIVE FINGER FLARES
No more!
How pathetic.
A whole day together and
your Magic Power increased just that much?
You should be ashamed a hundred year-old
like me beat a youngster like you.
A hundred?!
I guess that's all for today.
I'm heading back to Papnica.
Use your own Rura spell to come back.
What?! There's no way I can do that!
It's easy. You flew from the river to
the shore by releasing your Magic Power.
If you have a clear image of your
destination, Rura's a piece of cake.
But from the river to the shore and
from here to Papnica is totally different.
Beside, even if I learn Rura,
it's useless in battle!
Get your head out of your ass!
A Mage's magic is
for protecting his companions!
Thwarting danger using numerous spells
and knowledge is what a Mage does!
Don't you realize,
if you could have used Rura,
you could have rescued your companions
from the burning Balloon Ship?!
Don't talk like you're anything more
than a novice!
If you can't clear a challenge this easy,
you'll just drag everyone down.
Even if you join the fight,
you'll just end up dead.
You can just wander around
the Dark Forest for eternity!
Wait!
Dammit! You bastard!
Ah, Sir Matoriv! I've completed the bombs!
No good. Do over. The design sucks.
The design?
Go for a more sophisticated shape.
They're going to get blown up,
so who cares about the design?
Yo! Looks like you're making progress.
Matoriv!
Once you can cut the unseen,
your blade will become
three, or even five times more powerful.
Keep it up.
Wait, where's Popp?
Him? He's probably dead by now.
What?!
That little brat. What a pampered weenie.
His type never try
unless they're desperate.
That's why I left him
on the other side of the world.
Avan was always too soft for his own good.
He could never properly train
a crybaby like that.
He needs my kind of tough love.
Sadist...
Can you hear me?!
Little Disciples of Avan!
How long do you think
you can hide from me?! Huh?!
You don't think your Princess
is safe all frozen, do you?!
Unfortunately, her life force
is getting drained in this ice!
Your Princess's life ends
tomorrow at sundown!
Hurry on back! Come on!
Leona's going to die?!
I won't let that happen!
Get real! I'm not dragging everyone down!
Unless you defeat Flazzard
by sundown tomorrow,
the Princess's life force will be drained
by the Forbidden Magic ice and she'll die.
But charging in during the day
is just what the enemy wants.
We strike tonight.
Light the fuse,
and in five seconds... Boom!
We only have two, so be careful.
I guess we'll have to use
the ugly bombs after all.
If these don't work, we'll have to
destroy them by sword or magic.
What are you talking about?!
I made them! They're foolproof!
That's why we're worried.
How will we get to Valge Island?
Our Balloon Ship has sunk.
I have a small boat I use for fishing.
I'll fly it across with my magic,
just above the ocean.
That'll get us over the whirlpool.
Exactly. But the boat only holds four.
Then it'll be me and Maam and...
Me, of course! I built the bombs!
Of course I'm going!
I'll go, too!
Fighting for the Princess is
what the Papnica Troika are for!
Wait, Amy.
Apollo, you shouldn't move yet!
I cannot let Dai and his friends
carry our burden.
I shall go in your stead.
No! I will!
Hold on a second, you two.
The fourth seat is already taken.
Popp!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I couldn't get a clear image of the cave.
I made it to the Papnica temple
with my Rura spell,
but from there it was a real pain
and it took a while.
But I made it back.
Good. You're the fourth.
Nothing beats Maam's Behoimi!
This is the last help you'll get from me.
It'd be easy with Rura,
but I've never been to that island.
If Popp does it, he'll take you to the top
of Valge Tower inside the field.
It's enough, Uncle.
Thank you for everything, Matoriv.
Save the thanks for when you win, idiot.
Right! I swear we'll win!
Everybody onboard!
Listen...
if I survive this,
I'd like to continue my training.
If I quit after all that,
it'd look like I ran off like some coward.
Like I'd let you run.
I'm still not finished with you.
Later, Mentor!
What do you mean by "Mentor"?
Master Avan is my one and only master.
A master and mentor are different!
Why are you splitting hairs like that?
Here we go.
When did Gomechan sneak onboard?
Go with the blessing
of the great gods of Papnica.
Don't die out there,
forgotten mementos of Avan.
This is fast!
We'll make it to the island in no time!
I guess they don't call him
a Grand Sorcerer for nothing!
Listen, I was just thinking...
how do we stop?
Oops.
Is something wrong?
I forgot to think about how they'd stop.
W-What do we do?!
D-Don't ask me!
We'll crash! We'll crash! We'll crash!
Bagi!
That's it! A Bagi spell as a brake!
Cast Bagi, Popp!
Don't you have Bagi
in your Magic Bullet Gun?!
Use Bagi! Use Bagi! Use Bagi!
Bagi!
Ow, ow, ow...
Oh come on, Mentor.
He talks big, but he always
screws up where it counts!
I tried to cast Bagi and it worked!
Let's split up.
I'll go to the Dark Flame Spire
with Baduck.
Right.
Then Maam and I'll take
the Dark Ice Spire.
Once the two Spires are destroyed
and the field is down,
we charge into Valge Tower!
Sorry about that. Come with us, Gomechan.
Let's go.
Stay safe, you two!
Here they come. The sad little flies
into the spider's web.
Mystvearn, are your soldiers ready?
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
Dai and his friends managed
to reach Valge Island.
They split up
and headed for the two Spires.
But, waiting for them there
is the full force of the Dark Army
that anticipated the attack.
As Dai and his friends fall into peril,
an unexpected individual appears.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Death-Defying Savior"
The adventure continues!