With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
RISE, KNIGHT OF DESTINY
What is that?!
Is it alive?!
Darn it!
Stop!
Stop it! Hey! What's with you?!
Stop it! Please!
Hey!
Wh-Who the heck are you?!
I'm Dai! Who are you?!
Dai?! You're Dai?!
Answer me! Who are you?!
What is that thing?!
Why did it capture Leona?!
I-I can't answer all that at once!
I'm Goroa, the Drumbler.
I oversee the heart of Ban Palace.
You fly Ban Palace from here?
Then what is this monster?!
Why did it take Leona?!
That's not a monster.
It's true that it's based on an organism,
but it's a Dark Force Reactor
that's half machine.
Wait. That controls Ban Palace?
That's right.
The Dark Force Reactor
is the heart that drives Ban Palace.
draws on my Magic Power
and transmits it
across all of Ban Palace.
It's a living engine. But...
thanks to that spell
the girl cast, Minakator,
it has lost the ability
to draw on my Magic Power.
Starved for Magic Power,
it's gone berserk.
That's why the Dark Force Reactor extended
its tentacles to search for Magic Power.
So it went after Leona
because of her high Magic Power?
But... me and Popp are also here.
That's it! Master Aban's Feathers!
With Master Aban gone, Leona currently
holds the greatest source of Magic Power!
Leona! That thing is drawn
to the Magic Power
of the Feathers Master gave you!
Try to drop all the Feathers!
I can't! I can't move!
Darn it! I'll have to destroy it!
If you do that, King Ban will punish me!
Then you stop that thing!
I'm trying to!
In order to control
the Dark Force Reactor,
King Ban gave me the power
to control super gravity!
I'm using it as we speak!
But it's not stopping at all!
That shows how wildly
the Dark Force Reactor's rampaging!
If I stop the Gravity Pulse
from my belly, it's over!
That girl will be eaten
by the Dark Force Reactor and die!
Normally, any creature caught by
those tentacles would be absorbed!
Really, you should be thanking me!
Forget it! I'll do it!
Dai!
What was that?!
It's like an invisible wall!
Out of the way!
He seems to be incredibly strong.
At this rate, he'll destroy
the Dark Force Reactor.
If that happens,
King Ban is sure to execute me!
I know...
It's no good! Nothing's working!
In that case,
there's some risk to Leona...
but I'll have to cut it in two
with an Aban Strash!
Leona!
I'll get you out of there!
Aban...!
What's going on?!
I feel so heavy!
Sorry, but I hit you with a Gravity Pulse.
Now that I think about it,
I'm under no obligation to help that girl.
If I can kill the Hero,
I'll be rewarded for my achievement!
It's my chance to get out of
life in the bilge!
Oh no! If he's directing
his Gravity Pulse at me...!
Dai!
Leona!
Darn it!
You're quite powerful. But...
I was tasked with holding
that giant Dark Force Reactor in check.
Your power can't beat mine!
Darn it!
That said, how am I supposed to
finish him of?
Ah, that's it!
Darn it! Get up! Get up!
Hurry or Leona will be... Leona will be...
It's too late!
It'll only take a few more seconds
for her to be absorbed and die!
And if I stab you with this sword,
not even you can survive!
If I defeat the Hero,
King Ban will commend me!
I can do things if I set my mind to them!
To be killed by a little grunt like Goroa
only moments before the final battle...
For a Hero,
that's a rather pathetic ending.
No.
It's not over until it's over.
And now, with this...
it's over for you!
You're still trying to resist?!
Just sit still and die already!
Darn it!
Darn it.. Dragon Crest...
Is this... Is this really...
all the strength that I have?!
Even while I'm using
all that I have within me?!
Is this all a Dragon Knight can do?!
Are Dragon Knights... really this weak?!
I want to protect someone I care about!
Don't I have the power to do that?!
Tears of frustration.
But it's not your fault.
I just happened to be smarter!
Now die by your own sword!
Goodbye!
Huh?
Dad?!
This is...
when Mom died?!
Soara!
The life of a Dragon Knight
is one of unending battle.
Dad!
Caught in that bloody path...
it seems many a woman
has met a tragic ending.
Sadly, your mother was one of them.
But...
whatever the past may be, you are you.
By your hands...
see if you can end the sad fate
of the Dragon Knights, Dai!
Remember when you first rescued Leona!
You are no normal Dragon Knight!
You carry my soul.
You are a new Super Knight!
Stand! Stand up! Dai!
Dad!
That's right!
The first time the power of my Crest awoke
was when I rescued Leona!
Draw it out!
That unknown power within me!
Just like back then!
My power and that of Dad's...
are much more than this!
What is that?!
GIGA STRASH
GIGABRAKE
Th-This is...!
Dragon Crests... on each fist?!
The power in my left hand...
is Dad's!
I will be with you
in the battle ahead.
We shall always be together,
never to part again.
At that time,
the power of Dad's Crest entered me!
That why I saw Mom,
even though I've never met her!
It was Dad's soul reassuring me!
Inside me... all this time!
Dad was always there!
I see. Baran's power.
Two Dragon Crests.
They are... Twin Dragon Crests!
Dammit!
My Gravity Pulse isn't working!
Crest Beam!
Even the Dark Force Reactor's barrier...!
The Twin Dragon Crests are a threat.
Ah, the fortune telling of a Reaper.
The predictions always come true
in a bad way.
Leona!
No...
Was I too late?!
Thank goodness!
She's okay!
Her clothes may be all torn up,
but she's completely unharmed.
Leona, wake up!
Dai...
I...
You're okay.
Goroa said that thing would absorb
your body, so I was really worried.
You took care of it, didn't you?
Thank you!
But my clothes are ruined.
And when I was first grabbed,
I felt really weak.
The Dark Force Reactor really does absorb
creatures for their Magic Power.
So how...?
I dunno.
Dai, could you turn around?
Huh? Why?
Just turn around!
R-Right!
Dai!
Huh?!
Gomechan shrunk?!
Gomechan was inside my clothes.
Inside your clothes?! Where inside?!
I-It doesn't matter where!
Gomechan must have protected me.
It could be that while I was inside
the Dark Force Reactor,
Gomechan was emitting
Magic Power the whole time.
That's what kept me from being absorbed.
That's what caused the shrinking?
But Gomechan's helped us
in numerous battles up to now.
Could Gomechan have some mysterious power?
healing Dai's stamina,
and allegedly calling Popp back
from the brink of death.
And with Chiu,
attacking with a hardened body.
As for me, emitting Magic Power.
Just what is Gomechan's true power?
Let's forget it.
Let's not question
someone who saved our lives.
Besides, Gomechan
is kind of cute this small.
Let's just let Gomechan rest for now.
I said don't look!
I just wanted to make sure
I knew where Gomechan would be!
Goroa?!
You've left me with no choice!
I'm going to pour all of my Magic Power
into the Dark Force Reactor
and take you down with me!
Stop it! It won't work!
I don't have any other option!
I swear I'll destroy you!
Enough.
King Ban?!
That's enough.
Even if the Dark Force Reactor is lost,
I will not hold you responsible.
It seems that the great wheels of fate
have sided with the Hero.
If he had climbed
the Tower of Supremacy unchallenged,
Dai would have been no threat to me.
There are other Dark Force Reactors
in the Underworld.
Don't provoke Dai any further!
It may be your order, King Ban...
but I can't turn back now!
Leona, get back!
Two Dragon Crests?!
That stance!
I'm warning you!
This isn't just some ordinary spell!
It's my Dad's...
It's the Dragon Knight's...
greatest and strongest...
ace in the hole!
Doru Aura!
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
The Doru Aura fired from the Twin Dragon
Crests obliterated the Dark Force Reactor.
At last Dai and Leona reach the top
of the Tower of Supremacy.
There awaits Dark King Ban
brimming with deadly intent.
Dai's fears resurface
with his rematch against Ban,
and the Kōmanotsue closes in.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Ban, the Dark King"
The adventure continues!