boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
are itsukarada?
Since when was it?
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Being honest became whining
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Standing firm became strength
naa mitsukaranai?
Have you found it yet?
jishin janaku jibun jishin
Not confidence, your true self
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
I smolder because I've actually burned
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
tada me wo mihiraite
I'll just open my eyes
yume wo miru
And dream my dream
yume wo shiru
And know my dream
THE FIELD OF DEATH
Here.
Jank.
Have a drink.
How generous.
Growing older has changed you.
You're one to talk.
The life of a Darkling is uneventful.
We live much longer than humans,
so many of us are lazy.
Some lives can last centuries
yet still be empty.
Delicious. Not many
can feel what I feel now.
Right now, I feel truly fulfilled.
That sword was well forged.
A true Hero!
He did it!
What an incredible power.
That sword has a soul.
It chooses when and where it fights.
I get it. A weapon this destructive
shouldn't be used just anywhere.
That's why you seal yourself away.
I'll only borrow your strength to fight
truly powerful enemies or save everybody.
Glad to have you with me, my sword!
Dai!
Huh? What?!
Oh come on, Dai!
He must have gone
to help the others fight.
There's still one more
source of evil energy.
The enemy leader wasn't in the castle?
What's wrong?!
I sense something horrible
is about to erupt forth!
Wait, Meruru!
Dai, hurry!
They're all...
Popp and the others are in danger!
You may have lost your trump card,
but this is unlike you!
You're wide open, Mystban!
Air Strike!
He didn't even try to dodge!
That's his Dark Aura!
What a... disgraceful failure!
King Ban's
Sovereign Rock Castle in ruins!
This is because I failed to realize
the power of Dai's new sword!
It's my...
It's my fault!
How do you like that?!
That's what you get
for underestimating us!
Now to finish you with my spell!
Wait! Wait, Popp! Don't attack recklessly!
Burn to ashes!
Begirama!
Ow, ow, ow!
Yow, yow, yow!
He reflected my spell?!
No, it was like he amplified it
and fired it back!
Its impact was closer to
that of a Begiragon spell.
Dark Puppetry Aura Decimation Field
and Byut Deathstringer...
Are they just a fraction
of his true power?!
So be it!
I must shed my Shadow Raiment
and erase Dai and all of you right here!
That's when you shall realize
being crushed by Sovereign Rock Castle
or being torn apart by my Dark Aura
would have been a far better way to die!
What is that power?!
Compared to that giant castle,
the pressure coming from Mystban is...
It's way bigger!
I've always assumed the source
of Mystban's power was his Dark Aura.
But that Dark Aura
wasn't his greatest weapon.
Could it just have been a veil
hiding his true form?!
Now witness my true power...
The power of Mystban!
...And stop.
That's enough right there, Myst.
Kill...
That's Kilban, the Reaper!
What?!
The Reaper?!
Him?!
Bad boy! Bad boy!
King Ban's gonna be mad!
That's right.
Your true form,
no matter the circumstances,
can only be revealed
with King Ban's permission, can it not?
Disobey that and, friend or not,
I'll be forced to intervene.
You're right.
Apologize! Apologize!
Exactly.
Sovereign Rock Castle is only
one of King Ban's many toys.
With a sincere apology, he's sure
to forgive his precious little Myst.
Better that than
adding to your shame here.
Understood. I will never fail again.
And it's back to silent mode, is it?
Well then...
Now everybody, with that...
He's coming!
...we'll be excusing ourselves now.
Huh?!
You're running?!
Dai's sword was quite impressive,
destroying Sovereign Rock Castle and all.
Tell him congratulations on completing it.
Now he doesn't have to worry
about his friends being useless.
What?!
Oh, especially you. You couldn't
do a thing to Sovereign Rock Castle.
Yeah! Useless!
Well then. See you again.
Hey! Wait!
After all that...
After all you did to this country...
Don't think you can insult us
and get away with it!
Wait, Popp!
Don't!
Popp!
You won't get away!
This time, I'm finding your stronghold!
That idiot!
Hey!
Dai!
Are you okay? I sensed a huge power here.
That can wait!
Popp flew off alone
chasing after the enemy!
You're the only one here
who can catch up to them!
Please! You have to bring Popp back!
He's lost his cool!
Got it!
They went northwest!
Will they be okay?
Hyunckel, you know that
the power of Dai's crest is limited.
Yeah.
You'd expect Dai to have flown back here
after destroying Sovereign Rock Castle.
But he came on foot.
That's right!
He must have spent a lot of energy
destroying Sovereign Rock Castle.
He was subunconsciously
conserving his power.
I didn't have a choice.
Popp was heading to certain death.
What?!
Kilban is the one tasked
with killing us Legion Commanders!
What?!
No one in the Dark Army
has ever seen him before.
If he ever appeared before anyone,
it would mean their death was certain.
He's that dangerous?!
Hyunckel!
Dai, you have to bring Popp back...
Just don't fight... head-on!
Hyunckel!
W-Where am I?
This place is...
north of Orzam!
I was so focused on flying.
Could this be...
The Field of Death?!
Is this the stronghold of the Dark Army?!
HYADARUKO
ICE-TYPE SPELL
TOMAKUGUTSOSHO
There's no mistake.
This is the infamous Field of Death.
Some call it the world's edge
or the last unexplored land.
It's a dark island devoid of any life.
No one has ever approached it
and returned.
I get it. It's the perfect place
for the Dark Army to use as a base.
I bet Ban, the Dark King, is here.
I may have gotten in over my head.
I need to learn to control myself.
A flute?
Kilban!
B-Both of you?!
Foolish little boy.
Did you really think you could
keep up with us if we were serious?
We flew slow enough so you could
and you fell for it.
Dummy! Dummy!
Oh yeah?! Then why reveal
where your stronghold is?!
You Disciples of Aban
have grown rather strong.
I figured I should get around
to doing my job.
Your job?! What's that?!
What was that?!
Something felt very wrong!
Surely you've guessed by now.
The way I'm dressed, my title of Reaper,
and everything I've said and done.
As-sas-si-na-tion.
Whoa!
What the...?! His scythe
wasn't even close to me!
Strange, isn't it?
Wow!
How's that, dumb reaper?!
Burn! Burn!
You missed!
What?! What's going on here?!
Am I dreaming?!
Oh, it's something far more grave.
An illusion! He's somehow
making me see illusions!
How?! How is he doing it?!
I didn't see him cast a spell
and he didn't use any items!
This high-pitched, whistling noise.
It's like... a flute!
Could it be...?!
Bingo! That's correct!
If only you'd realized it
a few seconds earlier.
What the...?! I can't see!
I can't move either!
What's going on?! Dammit!
I'll tell you before you die.
My Reaper Flute isn't just
for playing sweet melodies.
I use it like this for my work.
When I swing my scythe,
air flows through the flute,
which emits a high-frequency tone
that can barely be heard.
Upon entering the ears,
this sound disrupts my opponents' vision.
In the end, it robs them
of all of their senses.
That's why it's called the Reaper Flute.
It's the perfect weapon
for assassinations.
Lovely, isn't it?
You pathetic dummy! Serves you right!
Don't mock him too much.
Weaklings like him who improve a little
become the heart and soul of their team.
He's the first of the Hero's party
you'd want to get rid of.
That's why we lured him here alone.
Then kill him already!
You're right, Piroro.
Good idea.
You followed us, Dai.
Popp, are you okay?!
Dai!
Aww! We almost got to kill him!
Hold on, Myst.
Even you need to be careful of
Dai, the Hero, when he has that sword.
I'll take this.
Dai, be careful! His Reaper Flute...!
Huh?! The Reaper Flute
isn't working?! Why?!
Oh! The Reaper Flute is cracked!
He did it when he blocked me earlier.
Good going, Dai! He uses that flute
to create illusions to kill his enemies!
By cracking it, you prevented him
from controlling the sound!
Really?
That was lucky!
We shouldn't pursue them any further.
Let's find an opening and escape.
Good idea.
That is if they'll let us go.
Looks like both sides
are out of decisive moves.
I see. They still have their trump card.
We both want to finish this,
and we both want to run.
This is frustrating.
Neither side can move.
My sword won't come out.
What now?
Popp, can you move?
I'm free of the illusions now.
It's a stalemate.
Let's attack and break through.
Okay!
They're coming!
Hadorra?!
You... You were alive?!
Sorry to have kept you waiting, Mystban.
I've fully powered up.
Now it's my turn to help you.
Hadorra...
Powered up?! Nothing's changed about him!
Dai, you will fight me here.
One on one. Fair and square.
What?! You're one to talk about fair!
I've cast aside my useless pride
and even my Darkling body for this day.
I have but one wish left.
To defeat you,
the legacy of my eternal rival, Aban!
My sword! It opened its seal by itself?!
My sword realizes that Hadorra
is far more powerful than ever before!
Hey! Don't use your crest at full power!
You need to conserve your energy!
No! He's not the Hadorra we knew!
I have to fight
with my full strength or we'll die!
An astute observation!
You truly are my rival!
I expect nothing less
from a Disciple of Aban!
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
It may just be a rationalization
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
Even now, even now I waver
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
How far will we go?
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
Exposed to love and sorrow
hokori mamire michi no tochu
On the path strewn with pride
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
Fleeting moments of cowardice
nomikonda SOS
The SOS I held back
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
I clenched my trembling fist
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
That single little promise
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
Those trivial little memories
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
They're still in my heart
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
As embers that keep me burning
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
A single transparent beam of light
me no mae wo terashite yuku
Lights the way before me
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Hadorra appeared before
Dai and Popp with new power.
Dai struggles against his awesome power,
even with his full Dragonic Aura.
Hadorra's power and his resolve
are beyond anything ever before,
forcing Dai to wield his sword once more.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Clash of Powerful Swords"
The adventure continues!