With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE OTHER HERO
Ron Berku overwhelmed Mystban!
And yet his blade...
...doesn't work!
Of course it didn't!
Zaboera?!
The body of this Superior Being Zombie
absorbs impacts!
No weapon can cut it!
It's truly invincible!
My brain is a terrifying thing indeed!
It truly is the mind of a demon!
Never fear!
We have the Superior Beings'
weakness on our side!
What?!
Now, Master, I mean, Mr. Beast!
Give him a taste of your Refractor Fist!
I can't!
Huh?! Why?!
The Refractor Fist doesn't work on Zombies
because they're already dead!
What?!
Remember this, rat!
It's called an "upgrade" because
it's overcome all previous issues!
The idea for this Superior Being Zombie
came from that attack.
If it has a weakness,
it would be cutting off my Magic Power...
but I just hide myself
deep inside like this...
and its weakness disappears!
Everyone, use magic attacks!
Howl, Inferno!
Fools!
Such pitiful attacks won't work on me!
That old weasel.
Cornering him finally
made him reveal his hand.
All that remains...
Dammit!
Not even my Great Axe has any effect!
Even with all those spells
and weapons stuck in it, it's fine!
What a success!
Not again!
Here!
Futile, futile!
Ron Berku couldn't cut it!
There's no way you humans can!
-Dammit!
-Calm down!
Unfortunately, he's right.
No attack will work.
But...!
Not even my force and speed worked.
There's nothing we can do here.
If we had an ultimate weapon
that used more force and speed,
then maybe...
You mean like the Sword of Dai?!
I'll get rid of
that annoying Magic Circle!
Your majesty!
Hm?
Crocodine...
I'm the only one
who can fight you hand to hand!
How small! How weak! How persistent!
I suppose this is what
I used to look like to you.
It feels magnificent to be a giant!
Beast King Commandos, attack!
Rescue Mr. Crocodine!
We can't just wish for what we don't have!
Defeating him and protecting
the Magic Circle is our task!
Now's the time for us to unite
and unleash a power
that rivals Dai's own!
That's theoretically impossible.
Besides, you don't have a weapon
that can defeat him.
A weapon that can defeat him?
A weapon...
We do!
What?
We have... my life!
Your... life?!
I told you, kid.
If you think you can win
by risking your life, you'll die in vain!
I'm not just risking my life.
I'm using it as a weapon!
My life itself can be powerful weapon!
What?
Swords won't work on that monster.
I know!
Nova!
Here goes!
I will use all of my life power!
It's like his sword is draining his life!
At this rate...
Nova! Don't do it!
A Life Blade?!
I'll cut him with his!
If I can expose Zaboera even a little bit,
it should be possible to defeat him
and stop the Superior Being Zombie!
Stop! Don't do it, kid!
Out of my way!
No!
I acknowledge your bravery...
but I can't let you use an attack
that has no hope of succeeding!
Sadly, I can tell.
Even with that Life Blade,
the damage you inflict will be minimal.
The power to cut it...
and expose Zaboera is beyond you!
Now stop that blade!
At this rate, it'll drain
all your life energy!
It doesn't matter if it does.
I never assumed I could win with one blow.
But a Life Blade cannot be broken!
I'll hit him again and again
and again until I fall!
If I can leave even a single scratch,
then that's enough!
That's dying in vain!
It's not in vain!
Even if I die, it will leave something
for everyone else!
I once called myself a Hero.
It's my duty!
A Hero?!
What's wrong, Nova?
There's... There's such
a difference in our power.
And yet I was so full of myself,
trying to compete with you.
You were the real Hero.
And I was just jealous.
Forgive me, Dai.
Forget about it.
Besides, difference in strength
doesn't matter.
It doesn't make sense if
only the strongest person could be a Hero.
Then what sort of person is a real Hero?
Huh?
Hmm...
Forget it! Sorry! That was too difficult!
I'm not sure,
but it's not about
who's stronger or braver.
Oh!
Everybody calls me the Hero.
But back in your home of Ringaia,
you're the Hero of the North, right?
Y-Yeah.
Then isn't that enough?
If we're helping save people,
then I'm a Hero and you're a Hero!
We're both Heroes!
Thank you, Dai.
You've giving me confidence.
And a new spirit.
That's it! This is...!
That's when I realized...
a true Hero is more about
inspiring courage than just being brave!
Even if I should die...
if I can leave even a scratch...
and inspire the others
that remain to attack...
I may not be a good as Dai...
but I can still serve as a Hero!
Nova... You used to be so selfish.
Look at how you've grown!
Your majesty! I leave the rest to you!
Give the call!
"Everyone, follow that attack!"
Nova!
NORTHERN GRAND BLADE
DARK INCENSE
Enough. You can relax, Nova.
Why? Why go so far?
Until now, I looked down on you.
You impressed me, and at the same time...
I couldn't let you die in vain.
Our blood may be of different colors,
but we value life the same.
Ron Berku!
If a life must be spent,
it might as well be mine.
I've lived at least
ten times as long as you.
If I had the sort of resolve you did...
I could have defeated that enemy easily.
I summon you! The ultimate weapon
I've dedicated my life to!
What?!
W-What is that?!
A-A new enemy?!
Stand back! It's dangerous!
This is the ultimate superweapon?!
No matter what kind of weapon
you bring out now,
it won't work on
my Superior Being Zombie!
I'll pulverize that little rock
before you can use it!
What?! My blades?!
Inside that hunk of stone,
there is something incredibly powerful!
Thanks. You're a real help.
You saved me the trouble of opening it.
Swords?!
Two of them?!
I call them...
The Star Emperor Swords!
The Star Emperor Swords?!
So these two swords
are his ultimate weapon?!
The Star Emperor Swords?!
What a pretentious name!
This is the ultimate weapon
that I've spent over a century creating.
It's the only weapon in the world
made exclusively for me!
Dual-wielding?!
What intensity!
But will it work on
the Superior Being Zombie?!
It just looks like
a clumsy pair of swords!
If it's swords, then it doesn't matter
how hard they are!
I have nothing to fear!
W-Why you...!
Now I see, Ron Berku!
You boast about those swords,
but you're unsure of their strength!
You're scared, aren't you?!
H-He...!
Indeed, I am scared.
I'm terrified.
Not because they might be weak.
But because
they are overwhelmingly powerful!
What?!
I will swing these swords only once!
Right and left! Once strike apiece!
When I do, even I won't be left unscathed!
That's why I'm making certain my attack
can hit you and cut you into four!
This is the most powerful
Ron Berku Style sword skill...
The Star Emperor Cross Slash!
L-Look! It was as I expected!
Nothing! Not a single...!
You can brag in the afterlife...
about that parting cross slash I gave you.
He did it!
Ron Berku!
What happened to his arms?!
Looks painful!
I did it again.
"Again"?!
I knew this would happen.
When I use the Star Emperor Cross Slash...
it shatters both the swords and my arms.
Nearly 200 years ago,
I lost the use of my arms the same way.
The Star Emperor Cross Slash
is too powerful an attack.
The moment I tried it,
it ruined my arms and swords.
Like you just saw.
More than my own strength,
I cursed the weakness of my weapons.
I became a weaponsmith to create
weapons I could use at full strength.
That was the Star Emperor Swords.
But it's an incomplete prototype.
I should have completed it sooner.
Ever since I forged the Sword of Dai,
I've been focused on helping his party.
The reason I worked so hard
on the Sword of Dai...
was likely because I knew the frustration
of being too strong to wield a weapon.
Then, you've been holding back
your strength until now?
Because if you hadn't
you would only destroy yourself?!
And yet...
for me... for us...
you used an incomplete superweapon,
knowing what it would do to you!
I told you.
It's better than having
a young man like you die in vain.
My one regret...
is that I won't be able
to make weapons for you.
My arms won't heal for a while.
Probably not in your lifetimes.
Then... Then use my hands.
Until the day your wounds have recovered.
You saved my life.
I swear I will complete
your shattered Star Emperor Swords.
Nova!
You're not just strong.
You're worthy of respect.
If you will let me,
I wish to learn from you!
Then, for starters...
Huh?
Could you open my bottle for me?
Yes sir!
Nova, you've finally found them.
Someone you can call Master
and a path to walk on.
H-Huh?
Oh dear. I guess I should start
by teaching you how to open a bottle.
C-Crocodine?!
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Ron Berku cut down Zaboera's
Superior Being Zombie,
and the battle of Loroi Valley
ended in victory.
Meanwhile, in Ban Palace, Hyunckel
fights a horde of Underworld monsters.
Eventually, one person appears,
mowing down the monsters.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Survivor From Hell"
The adventure continues!