Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
DAI'S SECRET
The Dragon Knight is approaching.
He's close!
The Dragon Knight?!
It's Baran!
They're connected by their crests.
He'll reach this castle soon!
We must ready our defenses!
Got it!
You and I will be the defense!
Madam Nabara and Meruru
will stay here with Dai!
It's too dangerous!
You can't fight Baran and leave unscathed!
You'll need my healing-type spells!
Very well.
You're not one to be
talked out of your decisions.
Exactly. Let's get going!
Madam Nabara, Meruru,
don't let Dai out of his cell!
What is it, miss?
What?! What are you doing?!
Stand still.
Huh?! What is this?!
A weapon! Use it to defend yourself!
D-Defend myself?
Isn't it obvious? You use this to fight!
No way! I can't! It's too scary!
Take it off, miss!
Dai, I've told you before. You're a Hero!
You're small but brave
and bright and sincere.
That's the real you!
This cowardly you isn't a Hero!
It isn't who Dai is!
That's not true. I can't be a Hero.
Besides, if we wait,
someone will come to protect me.
He instinctively senses
that Baran is his father after all.
You're wrong.
That's the enemy!
The enemy?
That's right! He took precious
memories of us from you!
He's a terrible enemy!
Don't be happy that he's coming!
Princess Leona...
Fight, Dai! Fight to regain what's yours!
Your memories and courage!
Courage...
Come, Crocodine.
Understood.
Come to think of it...
I think... something like this....
happened before.
I see you aren't quite dead yet.
But I will not finish you off.
You can wallow in shame
and feel regret as you bleed out.
I must hurry and regroup
with Master Baran to reclaim Master Dino.
"Dino"? Does he mean Dai?
You still bother to resist?
Father or not...
I can't let him... take Dai.
Dai is...
the hope of all humans
living in this world!
What rubbish!
The filthy humans of this world
don't deserve such a thing!
What?!
Very well.
I shall tell you before you die.
The reason why Master Baran hates humans!
The only woman Master Baran ever loved,
in other words, Master Dino's mother...
was murdered by humans!
The ones who killed Dai's mother
were humans?!
Why would humans...
Just who was Dai's mother?!
Normally, only one
Dragon Knight exists at a time.
The power of a Dragon Knight
can reshape the heavens and earth.
Thus only one in a generation
can possess it in this world.
When a Dragon Knight's life ends,
the Holy Mother Dragon descends.
It is said that she caringly cradles
the battle-weary knight's body.
And the Dragon Crest,
having fulfilled its duty,
is passed on to the life
the Mother Dragon carries within her.
A new knight now within her,
she gives birth in a distant land.
The humans there worship the child
as a divine child and raise it.
And when the knight is fully grown,
it awakens to its duty.
Thus, no Dragon Knight ever knows
parent or offspring.
They are destined to a life
of never-ending battle.
But something unusual happened
in Master Baran's generation.
Fifteen years ago...
When Hadorra laid waste to the world,
the Dragon Knight did not appear.
It was a human Hero who defeated Hadorra.
Aban...!
At the time, Master Baran
was fighting a greater threat.
For it is a Dragon Knight's duty to punish
those who disrupt the world's balance.
Compared to the threat of
Veruza, King of the Abyss,
who was the last intelligent Dragon
seeking to conquer this world,
even Hadorra was trivial enough
to be ignored.
Having vanquished Veruza and his kin,
Master Baran was mortally wounded.
Master Baran used the last of his strength
to reach the Fountain of Miracles
said to heal Dragon Knights.
I...
I was so close...
Drink this.
It is said to ease wounds and illness.
A human woman?
That was Master Baran
and Lady Soara meeting.
Weary from battle, Master Baran
found the sun in Lady Soara.
Eventually, love between them blossomed.
Lady Soara was princess of Arukido Kingdom
and when Master Baran came to the palace,
the two grew even closer.
But there were vassals
who found this displeasing.
They couldn't stand a stranger
winning claim to the throne.
Your Majesty, there are rumors
that knight is not human.
W-What?!
He may be a surviving servant
of the Dark Lord.
The fear of Hadorra being a recent memory,
the humans banished Master Baran.
Soara...
It seems life with a human
was never meant for me.
My time with you was a happy one.
Farewell.
Baran!
Please! Don't leave us!
"Us"?!
Soara, are you with child?!
Unbelievable!
The Dragon Knight...
A bloodstained Slayer has sired a child?!
Then that child...!
It is Master Dino.
Dai is the child of
a Dragon Knight and a human?!
The three of them...
lived quietly,
deep in the forests of Teran.
Soara, what shall we name him?
How about Dino? It means
"Strong Dragon" in the Arukido language.
Dino, the Strong Dragon. A good name!
Dino!
Oh dear...
Dino, don't worry.
That was scary, wasn't it?
But the humans...
did not let them enjoy
their days of peace for long.
A monster kidnapping their princess
would shame their country.
Enraged, the king hunted them down
and surrounded them with a battalion.
My love!
I mustn't kill any humans.
Master Baran made his decision.
Wait, my love!
I surrender.
But do not harm Soara or my son.
Very well. He may be a monster's spawn,
but he's still my grandson.
He cannot stay here,
but I shall send him to a foreign land.
Master Baran allowed
the Arukido soldiers to capture him.
And Master Dino was taken from Lady Soara
and sent to a foreign land.
You are sentenced to death!
Soara... Dino... May you find happiness.
Fire!
No!
Soara?
Soara!
M-My love...
How foolish! Why would you do this?!
I-I couldn't bear...
to see my father and the others...
continue... such cruelty.
Soara!
But... please don't hate humans.
They're all just scared.
Enough! Don't speak!
Please...
Find... Dino...
And live together... in peace...
Soara?
Soara!
That fool! To die for a monster?!
What a disgrace!
A disgrace?!
Just who do you think you are?!
Begone! Begone, humans!
Arukido Kingdom vanished from this world.
What hopelessly selfish creatures!
To think I fought the King of the Abyss
to protect such swine!
If I knew humans were such filth...
I never would have protected them!
Master Baran searched the world,
but he never found Master Dino.
Apparently, the ship was lost at sea.
It was in his deepest despair
that Ban, the Dark King approached him.
He said, "Don't you think the humans
should be wiped out first?"
This is Master Baran's sad past
that he has told only me.
What?! You still...?!
Larhart, you are indeed powerful.
I doubt I even have
the strength left to stand.
But, after hearing that story,
I realized I had to get back up.
For Dai...
and for Baran!
BEAST KING REDEMPTION BLAST
ABAN STRASH
For Master Baran?!
I know very well how Baran feels.
What?!
I, too, once lost faith
in the human world.
I sold my soul to the Dark Army,
and sought to destroy everything.
But I realized...
No, my friends made me realize...
that there was still hope
for the human world!
And now, I want to
help Baran realize this.
I might be able to...
What could you possibly know?!
You think Master Baran's pain
is something so light that you can ease?!
Don't make me laugh!
Impossible! I aimed for your heart!
I can see through your attacks!
What?!
To be honest,
I was fighting you
while saving myself to fight Baran.
That's why I tried to keep my distance
when dodging your attacks.
But now, I don't care
if you hit me or not!
This is what allows me
to barely dodge any mortal blows!
Cocky bastard!
Where does this strength come from?!
And you're faster than before!
This is the power a human wields
when risking his life!
I won't accept that!
You were wise to bring the fight in close.
But once distance is gained,
a sword cannot beat a spear!
I doubt you can even move now.
I could end this with a single thrust...
but that won't satisfy my anger!
His Hakendisutoru!
Feel the sting of my claw once more!
Die a ghastly death!
As punishment for your nonsense!
Hakendisutoru!
I've got you! You fell for
my final life-risking trap!
What?!
Take a good look at the shape of the Aura
our weapons create!
A cross?!
Grand Cross!
Impossible!
He was hiding a weapon
charged with his Aura?!
But he was completely defenseless!
W-Where did you hide such a weapon?!
This was the only weapon I had left!
That flimsy little chain?
This chain is unbreakable.
It is a symbol of
the bond of the Disciples of Avan!
The bond...
Using Grand Cross
leaves me weak for a while.
You're still alive?!
Very well.
This time I'll pierce your face!
Can you?
Popp!
Drop your weapon!
Otherwise, I crush the boy's skull!
You dirty...!
Don't!
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
I clenched my trembling fist
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
That single little promise
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
After a fierce battle, Larhart entrusts
Hyunckel and Popp with his last wish.
Meanwhile, Dragon Master General Baran
finally arrives at Teran Castle.
Crocodine risks his life to face Baran,
but Baran eventually reveals
his true power full of grief and rage.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Baran's Rage"
The adventure continues!