With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
You're The Bravest
THE UNLIKELY SAVIOR
Now! Take this!
King Ban!
Yes! Dai actually pulled it off!
Now, Maam!
This is our chance to heal up!
The light of a Behoma?!
Hurry! Right now!
Legends say a phoenix is resurrected
from its ashes, but...
That was more than I expected.
The Dragonic Aura.
A terrifying ability
in both attack and defense.
I cannot win bare-handed.
I must use my own.
My precious legendary weapon.
The heavens are trembling.
Dark King Ban is going to wield
the most terrible weapon at last.
How can you tell?
It's obvious...
because I made it.
That's...
This is my weapon, Kōmanotue.
Kōmanotue?
The outcome is decided.
Now that we both wield weapons
made by Ron Berku,
our individual strength
will decide this fight.
Ron Berku made it?!
You're lying!
The man is a Darkling.
Considering how difficult he can be,
the fact that he gave you humans weapons
is the more unlikely scenario.
Long ago, I presented him with several
weapons, like the Dark Armour Sword.
Ban chose
the Kōmanotue as his own.
What sort of weapon is it?
You've heard of a Somatic Staff, right?
Yes. It converts Magic Power
into its equivalent in attack power.
It functions on the same principle.
But, whereas a Somatic Staff is limited
in how much Magic Power it can convert,
Kōmanotue suffers
no such limitations.
When Dark King Ban wields it
with his tremendous Magic Power,
it becomes the greatest and
most terribly destructive weapon.
Now observe...
his greatest masterpiece.
Drink! My Magic Power is yours!
Now... try it again.
It broke?!
The invincible Sword of Dai,
made from Orichalcum?!
You've lost your will to fight.
Hardly anyone has ever
fought me this long.
You can be proud...
in the afterlife.
Dai! What's wrong?! Get up! Move!
Get up! You have to get up!
I don't want to see you like this
before I die!
This is the last thing you will ever see!
Calamity Wall!
Feel it for yourselves!
Hyunckel! Crocodine!
You're with me on this, Crocodine?
Yes! My life already belongs
to Dai and his friends!
You two!
You're not...!
Both of you, move!
Where we are doesn't matter!
If we're going to die,
we'd like to die here...
protecting you for one more second,
one more moment!
At least let us choose where we die!
But...!
Hyunckel!
Big Guy!
Dai!
It's futile. Futile.
Once let loose,
no one can stop the Calamity Wall.
Maam...
I have a request.
Your hand...
Would you hold my hand
until the very last moment?
I-It can't be!
Him?!
He rescued us?!
This is a surprise.
Not just that you still live,
but that you sided with the Hero...
Hadorra.
I haven't sided with him.
I just didn't want anyone else
to kill Dai and his friends.
If Dai had perished...
it would have made my transformation
into a monster meaningless.
And I would have no reason to live.
Then fear not. For your death is imminent.
The Black Core has already
fused with your body.
Now that it's been removed,
you don't have long to live.
But the primary reason you will die...
is because I am going
to execute you here and now.
I may have been generous, giving you
chance after chance over the years,
but I'm not so forgiving as to smile
when my prey is stolen.
Therefore, you need not worry about
a reason for living.
We're finally free.
Lord Hadorra's presence...
is that way!
Okay!
Huh?!
Why are King Ban and Lord Hadorra...?!
We must help Lord Hadorra!
You will not!
Dark Puppetry Aura Decimation Field!
Move and I pierce your Core.
Those four...
What's going on here, Mystban?!
Hadorra rescued Dai and his friends
from King Ban and let them escape.
As such, he is going to be executed.
What?!
You will not intervene.
Witness the end of your master.
No!
Lord Hadorra!
He's fast!
Die, Hadorra!
Dammit! Is everything going to end here?!
Without fighting the Disciples of Aban?!
Right here?!
Dammit!
W-What?!
I'd rather not be killed by you twice.
If you want to take my life so much...
then I have no choice
but to defeat you here!
Don't underestimate me, Dark King!
ULTRA COMBUSTION SLASH
KAISER PHOENIX
Impossible!
He repelled my attack?!
I gave him a body that would grow more
powerful each time he was resurrected.
But he couldn't be resurrected
without my Dark Aura.
Now that he has become a Superior Being,
I assumed that this power was lost!
But he brought himself back
from the brink of death.
And now it seems he may actually
be becoming strong enough to rival me!
Stop, Hadorra!
Don't you care
what happens to your servants?
I don't.
Do what you will.
If I die, they die as well anyways.
The Hadorra Royal Guard stands united!
Our sole objective is to defeat
the Disciples of Aban!
None of my servants fear death
if it serves our purpose!
Oh wow.
That was well said, Lord Hadorra!
Ban! You're the one dying today!
Do you really think you can defeat me
with a meager power increase?!
If it were just that,
I doubt I could defeat you.
But, in your current condition,
it's another story!
I assume that staff absorbs Magic Power
and converts it into attack power!
That means, simply holding it
drains your Magic Power continuously!
I could break the Sword of Dai,
but not this Orichalcum blade...
I see now!
Fighting Dai and his friends
drained my Magic Power!
It seems you've caught on!
With your Magic Power waning,
in a clash of might, I have the advantage!
No!
Watch it!
There's no telling what we'll do
if you release these bindings.
There you have it!
You can assume that the instant you move,
you'll be burned to a crisp...
Mister Reaper.
Hmph. Arrogant little doll.
Kaiser Phoenix!
Normally, this would reduce me to ashes.
It seems your Magic Power
really is weakening!
I won't miss this opportunity!
Your Ultra Combustion Slash?!
Prepare to die!
That's...!
Zaboera?!
You dare ignore your debt
for being made into a Superior Being?!
Don't bother.
This spell immobilizes me,
but binds you as well.
That little parasite!
Now's your chance, Dark King!
Well done, Zaboera.
Hold him right there.
My King!
Lord Hadorra!
And now the tables have turned.
Dammit!
Block?!
Where's Hadorra?!
W-What?!
Block!
Everyone...
Look after... Lord Hadorra...
Block!
You idiot!
What do you mean,
"Look after Lord Hadorra"?!
How can those be your first words?!
Block...
So they've escaped.
Who knew that rook had such an ability.
A rook...
I see.
A castling maneuver.
Castling?
In the game of chess,
there is a move where
the king and rook can be rearranged.
That warrior was born from a rook.
It's no surprise that
this piece would possess such an ability.
But I was just about to finish Hadorra.
If this were a game of chess...
castling after a check is cheating!
Dai?! Where's Dai?!
I thought he fell with us!
Could he still be...?!
Is that what Hyunckel talked about?!
The Holy Mother Dragon.
Ah. So that's what is said to appear
when a Dragon Knight's life is over.
This battle...
belongs to me!
Popp, look!
Dai?!
Wait!
Dai isn't dead yet!
Dai would never die!
Wait!
Don't take him away!
Look!
Their weapons?!
They returned not to their masters,
but to Sir Ron Berku?
Could Dai and the others...?!
I doubt anyone else will come
to try to thwart my plans.
Even if the Mother Dragon
gives birth to a new Dragon Knight,
it will take decades
before it is fully grown.
Meanwhile, it will take less than ten days
for me to reduce the Surface World to ash.
We only need to be careful of
any desperate resistance from Hadorra.
Come, my subjects.
It's time to bring ruin to the world.
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
I finally realized it
imasara kizuitanosa
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
Must be the reason I was born
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
I shake off the clinging night
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
Defeated by Dark King Ban,
our heroes escape thanks to Hadorra,
but are all separated.
Dai is suddenly taken away
by the Mother Dragon,
while Popp and Maam
wash up in Carl Kingdom.
As Popp prays for his friends' safety,
he learns that Ban has begun
his attack on the world.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Survivors"
The adventure continues!