nakama tono kizuna wo
With your bonds with your friends
sono mune ni idaite
Embraced in your heart
hikari no you ni isshun ni
Like a flash, in an instant
subete wo kaketeku
You risk it all
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
tachimukatte ikunnda to
You will face it again
kakugo wo kimetanara
If that's what you choose
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even when hurt
Oh tsumazuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
susume kono tabi no hate
Continue on
To your journey's end
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Again and again
To the future you make
Oh Oh
tachiagareru
You're The Bravest
You can stand up
Oh Oh
tachiagareru
You're The Bravest
You can stand up
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
motto Make you strong
You're The Bravest
Make you more strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
motto Make you strong
You're The Bravest
Make you more strong
THE SHADOW RAIMENT
And another!
D-Did it work?
Yeah.
Dai!
I'm okay.
I just feel a little sluggish.
I knew using Doru Aura twice in a row
would take its toll.
But I was able to do it because
you understood what I was thinking.
Thank you.
I can't believe you planned to use
Doru Aura twice in a row.
When I realized that Ban used his
Kōmanotsue to survive my Doru Aura,
I figured that he wouldn't be able to
withstand it twice in a row.
I thought it might be possible
if you healed my Magic Power.
I see.
It wouldn't work if he had dodged it,
but if he was using his staff to block it,
if you fired a second one while
the energy of the first one remained,
that would be two Doru Aura's worth.
There's no way... he survived that.
It was all so quick
the reality hasn't sunk in yet.
There was always only one Dragon Knight.
To hit something with
Doru Aura twice in a row...
It's a destructive force
that should normally be impossible.
It's because it's Ban.
Huh?
Nobody but Ban would be able to
block a Doru Aura spell.
Because Ban is too strong...
His strength is the reason he ended up
being hit by an attack that powerful.
I guess being too strong
isn't all it seems to be.
Come on! Stand proud, Hero! You've won!
You've defeated the Dark King!
That was pretty big.
It was the biggest shock I've felt today.
Either it was caused by Dai... or...
We should hurry!
Hey! What about him?
Just leave him.
We know he can't resist.
There's no need to kill him.
Right, Hyunckel?
We don't need to finish him off, do we?
You're too forgiving, Maam!
How many times have we fought this beast?!
We should finish him here
or we'll regret it!
You know I'm right, don't you?!
But if Dai loses to Ban
it'll be meaningless!
Even if we kill Mystban...
You're infighting?
Your teamwork sure sucks!
The Royal Guard was much...
He shouldn't be able to move a muscle!
He's immortal?!
See?! Do you still want to
show him mercy now?!
Hey, Hym!
You don't need to tell me!
I'm finishing him off now!
King Ban...
forgive me.
Please forgive me.
Stop your useless babbling!
Forgive me, King Ban.
For the first time...
without your permission...
I have revealed this face.
Th-That's...
Mystban's face!
A human? No. A Darkling.
The true face that even Ron Berku feared
is that of this slender young man?
This presence... I recognize it.
All this force... from just a push?!
How terrifying.
I have done something truly terrifying.
Not even I can escape the severe
punishment from King Ban this time.
Even execution may be unavoidable.
Showing this face
is that great of a crime!
And to do it without
King Ban's permission...!
Bastard! Are you trying to provoke me?!
What's so great about that pompous face!
Stop! Hym!
What overwhelming malice!
You're not as thick as I thought.
You've sensed my power.
What?! I'm... I'm being
overwhelmed by his pressure?
By... By this normal-looking...
ordinary guy?!
His Dark Aura was much stronger
when he had his mask on!
Very good. Be afraid.
I'm afraid, too.
S-Screw you!
Babble all you want after you eat this!
Stop! Don't do it, Hym!
Aura Knuckle!
What?!
Are you kidding me?!
Hym's Orichalcum arm!
He twisted it off! Forcefully!
And so casually!
And not by using his opponent's strength
against them like I would!
He tore it off with brute strength!
Hey! My arm!
Hmm. Very impressive, Larhart.
A normal hit would have caused
that arm to break or dent.
These shattered fragments of Orichalcum
are proof of your strength.
However...
You and that pawn...
may be warriors of the highest level
on this Surface World.
But you cannot hope to
match me in this form.
This is the face of
the strongest man in the Underworld.
What?!
W-What about Ban?! Isn't Ban
supposed to be greater than you?!
King Ban is a great man.
His wisdom and Magic Power
are indeed unparalleled.
But in terms of a powerful body,
I am currently above him.
That's right.
I am stronger than King Ban.
I am the strongest of the Dark Army.
DARK AURA PUPPETRY HAND
AURA KNUCKLE
There! I cast Behoma on you.
Thanks!
I'm worried about the others.
Let's hurry back to the White Garden.
Huh? Huh?
W-What's wrong, Dai?!
It's just, my body feels a little weak.
I should be healed more than I was before.
You're not fully healed?!
With a Behoma spell?!
I guess so.
But I'm better than when I cast Doru Aura.
What are you talking about?!
Then you've only recovered
what you would naturally!
To not fully recover your stamina
from a Behoma spell is impossible!
Wait. It could be possible.
Huh?
Hyunckel mentioned it.
Damage from Dark Aura
can't be healed with Heal-type magic.
It could be possible that
the Dragonic Aura is similar.
If the rebound from that double Doru Aura
has left residual damage to you
that is unaffected by Heal-type magic...
What do we do about it?
Well...
We've already defeated Ban.
We either let it heal naturally,
or wait until Heal-type magic works.
All we can do is give it time.
How long do you think it'll take?
There's no need to rush.
Mystban may be strong,
but he can't be stronger than Ban.
If Larhart's working with the others,
they'll be fine.
Getting your power back fully comes first.
We can think about Popp,
Master Aban and the others after that.
If you go to help in that state
you'll only drag them down.
You're always so blunt, Leona.
But I guess that's
what makes you reliable.
Hey! What kind of compliment is that?!
Hmph!
Why is it?
I still feel a trembling in my heart.
I still have...
this terrible feeling...
that something bad is going to happen.
What?!
You're stronger than Ban?!
Don't be ridiculous!
What? Are you saying you're
the real big boss of the Dark Army?!
That you're above Ban?!
Say something!
With your meager intellect,
you wouldn't understand even if I
explained my relationship with King Ban.
But I'll answer your first question.
You are correct.
Then... you're really...
He could... actually be stronger.
That power is beyond human comprehension!
It could be greater than Ban's!
Be grateful as you die.
You could live for centuries
and never have the chance
to be killed by one like me.
This gift of death is far beyond
what you deserve.
Nothing will work!
But we won't go down so easily!
It may seem that
we're powerless against him,
but if we can slow him down...
We still have our last option!
Medoroa!
I feel an abnormal amount
of expectation on my shoulders!
Talk about pressure!
If I use it head on, he might reflect it.
And he ain't slow either!
I need to cast it at the perfect time!
Hey!
Heal me so I can fight again.
I'll get him in a hold somehow.
When I do,
just cast that big spell of yours.
-I couldn't do...
-You idiot!
There's no time to hesitate!
Can't you see?!
He'll kill every one of us!
You still seem ready to fight.
Your bravery is commendable.
Even against such overwhelming power
none of you have lost hope.
You did manage
to fight King Ban once after all.
Thanks!
Now for your finishing move.
Don't forget what I told you.
You may be a metallic life form,
but I can't sacrifice you!
Hesitate like that and you'll end up dead
with that girl you love.
If my life is all it costs,
consider it a bargain.
Why does a random enemy like you
know about that?!
Buddy, talk about obvious.
Stop squabbling and get ready!
We're all counting on you!
Everyone...
There you have it.
I don't know what they're planning,
but I guess I'll join in on that gamble.
Here goes! It's round two!
Everyone but us, keep your distance!
Stick to ranged attacks!
Whoa! Larhart and Hym's
simultaneous attacks...
...aren't hitting!
It's not that they aren't hitting!
Just like before,
some attacks are hitting home!
And yet!
Dammit! In that case!
How about this!
That was quick.
Dammit! I can't even hold him in place!
My Beast King Indomitable Blast
isn't even slowing him down!
Crocodine!
-Are you okay?
-Yeah.
I never expected to be saved by you.
If only I could move freely!
He's too strong!
I hate to disappoint everyone,
but there's no time
to ready a Medoroa spell!
What a clean face.
Huh?!
What are you talking about
at a time like this?!
You've always had a thing
for handsome guys, haven't you?!
That's not what I meant!
He's been hit numerous times
even when he had his mask on.
I even hit him in the face
with my Refractor Fist.
And yet he doesn't have a scratch!
You're right.
It's too clean!
Maam.
Grand Master!
No, right now I'm Mr. Beast.
Huh?
Is this guy...
More importantly, is that true?
You hit him in the face
with your Refractor Fist?
Yes.
I see. I understand.
I believe I've uncovered
the secret of his immortality.
Immortal and indestructible
are two different things.
Mystban may be powerful
and seemingly immune to damage,
but the Refractor Fist
overcharges biological functions.
Normally, he should retain
some sort of mark.
There's only one explanation.
His body isn't alive.
It has no biological functions.
What?!
Popp, I will give you a chance
to cast Medoroa.
-Wait! That's crazy!
-Don't worry.
But, as you know,
I suffer from Glossy Ankleitis.
I can't fight for long,
so make good use of that chance.
Wasn't Brokin's illness something else?
Forget about that!
I don't have time to think about that!
What's this?
Now a clown is going to buy time?
The secret of your immortality...
must be...
the Secret Spell of Frozen Time.
You know of the Secret Spell?
You!
Who are you?!
Mr. Beast!
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
We act tough and follow our hearts
hajimeta monogatari
And we began this tale together
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
We've been seeking something certain
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Brokin realizes the secret
behind the unmasked Mystban.
As he confuses Mystban
with his flexible movements,
Popp looks for a window to cast Medoroa.
What is Mystban's secret
that Brokin explains?
And can Popp achieve victory
with his Medoroa Spell?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Secret Spell of Frozen Time"
The adventure continues!