Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
A FATHER AND SON CLASH
I won't give in!
I'm me!
I'm Dai, the Hero!
You still resist your father?! You fool!
You're not...
You're not my dad!
What?!
He struck me while I was shielded
by my Dragonic Aura?!
What?!
Dai's crest is on his fist?!
What?! Impossible! This can't be!
In thousands of years
of Dragon Knight history
for the light of the crest to appear
anywhere other than the forehead...
It's never happened before!
Could it be...?!
The human spirit?!
Is this Soara's will?!
Dai...
W-What's going on?!
Why is the Dragon Crest on his fist?!
I think Dai did it by his own will.
What?!
To escape Baran's mind control...
and to gain greater power than him...
he realized he had to move
the power of his crest from his forehead.
His full Aura power may be weaker,
but when it's focused in a single point,
each attack is stronger!
Is such a miracle possible?!
I doubt a normal Dragon Knight can do it.
Even Baran seems taken aback.
Prepare yourself, Baran!
What?!
You've taken so much from me!
My...
My dearest things!
Even if you are my dad,
I'll never forgive you!
I'm going to crush you!
Watch your tongue, boy!
Amazing!
I'm speculating, but...
I think the blood of Dai's human half
brought on this miracle.
His feelings for his friend
ignited a fire in his human heart,
driving the Dragon
and Darkling powers into his fist.
And this gave Dai control of his power!
You mean right now, Dai is...?!
He should have full control
over the power of the Dragon Crest.
Soara...
Even you... Are you saying I was wrong?
Curse you!
Dragonic Aura!
Impossible!
Yes! You're right!
Every one of Dai's attacks is stronger!
But...
This is ridiculous!
As if a child could beat his father!
It's time to back down
or I'll open a hole in your body!
If I fire my Crest Beam at full power,
it can carve a mountain!
So what if it can?!
Are you sure, Dino?!
My name...
My name is Dai!
Take this!
Your Majesty, what was that?!
The Dragon Knights.
Stop holding back.
What?!
The others are fair game...
but I'm not?!
Don't get cocky, you little brat!
No, Dai! Don't anger Baran any further!
He hasn't shown his full power yet!
Amazing, Dai...
We might have a chance.
Meruru!
Princess Leona, let me cast Hoimi.
Forget me. See to Crocodine and Hyunckel.
Okay. But... Um...
Leave Popp to me.
Huh?
I've never used it before,
but I want to test a spell on him.
It-It's beginning!
The greatest battle in the world
beyond anything we can fathom!
They're gone!
Up there!
Did he do it?!
No! Look out!
It's over!
Don't mock me!
Your Majesty!
Amazing. So this is
the ferocity of Dragon Knights.
Will we be okay?
We must make a decision.
Huh?
Which Dragon Knight we believe is right.
Dai?!
I was right. Dai's doomed at this rate!
What do you mean?!
Until now, Baran's been holding back
so as not to kill Dai.
Even with us, he probably held back
because we used to be allies.
But now he's a Dragonoid,
a Killing Demon Beast!
If provoked enough,
he'll kill anyone, no matter who they are!
You mean...?!
Even if it's his own son!
Burn away!
Along with this country!
No!
That's Doru Aura?!
ABAN STRASH
GIGABREAK
Baran's hands...
It's a Dragon's mouth!
What energy!
I get it! Doru Aura compresses
massive amounts of Dragonic Aura
and fires it as a spell!
Take this!
Look out! Dai, dodge it!
I won't let you!
Doru Aura!
What power!
This isn't even a spell anymore!
Where's Dai?!
Did he get him?!
I see. You dodged with a Rura spell.
You have good instincts.
He escaped the Doru Aura energy field
with a sudden short Rura spell!
I won't miss a second time!
Toberura!
Dai, you can't beat Baran in the air!
He has wings!
Why is he choosing to fly?
Because of us.
Huh?!
If Baran fires that Super Spell down here,
we and the people of Teran
will be reduced to ash!
That's why Dai took to the sky!
But...!
Even in his anger,
Dai is still our Dai inside.
He's not a monster like Baran!
Dai!
Hurry and heal us!
All I need is to stand!
I can't just do nothing!
Okay!
I see you've given up.
This will end it!
What do you think you're doing?!
I'll withstand it!
Even you can't cast a spell
that strong more than twice!
If I withstand this...
I'll win!
What?!
That's crazy, Dai!
You fool!
No being can withstand
a Dragon Knight's Doru Aura at full power!
It's never been used on a Dragon Knight!
I'm a Dragon Knight, too!
Save your nonsense, boy!
Dai, dodge it!
It's too late for that!
Take this and begone!
Doru Aura!
Dragon within me,
now's the time to awaken!
Focus everything I have to defeat him!
Dragonic Aura!
Dai?!
Dai!
There's nothing left!
What's so funny?!
You monster!
H-He withstood it! That Super Spell!
Impossible!
Baran!
You've got nothing left now!
Take this!
Aban...
Strash!
Leona's knife?!
What a pity.
When Dragon Knights fight
with Dragonic Auras at full strength,
normal weapons and armour
can't endure the power and burn up!
In your case, you've focused
all of your power in your right arm.
No weapon in the world
can endure such immense power!
No!
But...
this!
My Demon Dragon Blade is different!
This is the only sword in the world
that can endure the Dragonic Aura!
Dammit!
Only this sword can endure
a full-powered swing of a Dragon Knight!
I may not have the Magic Power to cast
Doru Aura, but victory is in sight!
I'll slice you in two!
You?!
I won't let you!
I was known as the Beast King!
I don't intend to just lie around!
Hang in there, everybody!
I'll see to Popp!
His heart's stopped.
I don't know if I can cast
such a major spell.
But if I don't succeed, Popp will...
Gods, bless us.
In thy name, let the soul of this one
whose life has burned out be restored!
That spell...!
Zaoraru!
It's Zaoraru! The resurrection spell
said to bring back the dead!
Then Popp can be saved?!
I don't know.
Even with an experienced Cleric,
the success rate is less than 50 percent.
So it's up to the Princess's magic level.
Come back to us, Popp!
If you want to cut my arm
you'll have to use Gigabreak!
Curse you!
A Raiden spell?!
Crocodine!
Fool! Die quietly
like the bag of bones you are!
Not even the gods can interfere
in this battle between father and son!
Prepare yourself, Dai!
I'm not finished!
I can't just sit around.
If I can move, it's enough.
Crocodine, wake up! Get up!
Hyunckel.
We have to help Dai.
Lend me your strength. I have a plan.
What?!
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Dai is on the defense, but thanks to
backup from Hyunckel, he holds out.
Meanwhile, Leona continues
to desperately cast Zing on Popp.
The battle's conclusion approaches.
Will Dai be able
to defeat his father Baran?
Lightning shall sever
the ties of father and son.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Farewell to the Father"
The adventure continues!