Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
NOW I SLICE EVERYTHING
Why am I alive?
I thought Hyunckel pierced both my hearts,
killing me.
And this...
That is due to Dark Aura.
I see. You used your Dark Aura power
to resurrect me.
Is my body even more powerful than before?
That is the secret of the body
King Ban has bestowed you with.
Should you die,
so long as the Dark Aura of King Ban
or myself remains, you can be resurrected.
And with far greater power than before.
Is that why you were placed under me?
Hadorra, your body belongs
to the almighty King Ban.
You can no longer choose your own death.
Should you die, you will return
only to fight on.
For your master, King Ban.
Gladly.
Where are you going?
Back to the battlefield.
For a silent man of shadows,
he's certainly become quite chatty.
It's done.
I've hit...
my target!
The power of that core keeps the hot and
cold sides of Flazzard's body together.
With it now gone...
Crap! I can't maintain my body!
If I remain together I'll vaporize myself!
Now, Popp!
Right!
Begirama!
Take that!
Well done, Dai!
So, what about him?
I'll pulverize him
so he can't rebuild himself!
Wait! Please don't!
Prepare yourself!
The Shadow Vizier...
Mystban!
Mystban, you've gotta help me! Please!
I can't just die like this! Do something!
What the hell is that?
The ultimate armour of my Shadow Legion.
If you would become burning Dark Aura,
in other words, a Dark Fire Energy,
it can be yours.
What?! That would mean
becoming your servant!
I'm not doing that!
If... If I really merge with that,
I can beat them?
You will be unrivaled.
Fine!
Do it!
The power! The power is overwhelming!
Such unbelievable, extraordinary power!
This is amazing!
Stand back! I am
the great swordsman of Papunica...
W-What is that?!
Baduck! Gomechan!
Oh no! They chose
the worst time to show up!
W-What?!
Crocodine!
Old timer!
Hyadaruko!
My spell's not working!
This body is amazing!
It's stronger and faster
than I used to be!
And it's immune to spells!
I'll be taking you out later. But first...
I need to crush this little brat!
He's coming!
Get back, Maam. He's after me.
You can't! You don't have the strength!
You've got some guts, kid!
You're begging me to send you
to the afterlife with one punch!
Dai!
What...?!
It's okay, Maam. I can win.
I don't know why,
but I don't feel like I can lose to him.
You can't lose to me?!
You do nothing but
spout your annoying words!
That's why I can't stand you,
you little brat!
Why you...!
He's reading the movements
of all those powerful attacks!
And with his eyes closed!
It's complete.
By obtaining Air Slash, Dai's completed
his Aban Style Sword Technique.
It means that super attack
is also complete.
By super attack, you mean...?!
Dai subconsciously understands
its destructive power.
That's why he knows he can win!
You're kidding! This is impossible!
I'm supposed to be invincible!
I've got the ultimate body!
I can't lose to this brat!
With this power and this durability...
if I lose now...
I'll look like an idiot!
Slice the earth...
Slice the sea...
Slice the air...
And slice everything...
I was able to do Air Slash.
I know... I know I can slice everything!
Here it comes!
Watch me, Master Aban!
This is... This is a true...
Aban Strash!
He did it!
Magnificent.
Oh wow! So that's the power
of the complete Aban Strash!
It rivals Aban, no,
it might be even more powerful.
Well done.
Dai!
Y-You lied to me, you bastard!
How is that the ultimate armour?!
That was indeed
the ultimate armour of my army.
If it was destroyed,
it merely means your foe's attack
was that much stronger.
Please! Give me another chance!
Mystvear--
Who does such a thing to their own ally?
Did Mystban use Flazzard
to test Dai's strength?
It looks like he's truly
the most dangerous among the Dark Army.
Let's hurry! To the Princess in the tower!
Oh! That's right!
Now that that monster is dead, the ice
of his Forbidden Magic should be gone!
He was a right bastard, but that was
a pretty horrible way to go.
Should we gather the fragments
and make a grave?
No need.
That's his gravestone.
ABAN STRASH
TOMAKUGUTSOSHO
Huh?! Why?!
What's the meaning of this?!
It hasn't melted at all!
No, it's started to melt.
Then why?!
It seems we were too late.
Too late?!
Flazzard is dead
and his Forbidden Magic is dispelled.
But it appears the Princess doesn't have
the strength to break free of its effects.
What?!
Princess! Princess!
Your Princess' life ends
tomorrow at sundown!
Gira!
It's barely melted!
In that case... Begirama!
Popp, hang in there!
You can do it!
It's no good!
A normal spell can barely melt it!
Then I'll have to risk it
and try shattering it with this!
A-And what if you
shatter the Princess, too?!
Is there anything else we can do?
I know!
This contains a Gira spell.
If we charge it with a Begirama spell,
maybe it can fire an even greater heat?
I've never charged
more that one spell, though.
If you do that,
your Magic Bullet Gun might break!
What are you talking about?!
This is the Princess' life here!
The Magic Bullet Gun isn't just some item!
Master Aban made it.
It's all that's left of him!
Let's try it.
Master said this weapon
was for helping people.
I'm sure he made it for times like this!
Okay. Fine.
Hand it over.
Huh?
What's wrong, Popp?!
He's out of Magic Power!
Hey Popp! You can't give up!
You're the only one who can use Begirama!
If I really do have a mysterious power
like everyone says...
then let me use that power,
not to fight...
but to save a life.
To save Leona's life!
What is that mark?!
That's the mystic power within Dai!
But it's not coming from anger!
It's responding to something
other than battle!
Begirama!
It's charged!
Maam!
Right!
Please...
Leona!
Leona... She's alive!
She's alive!
Thank goodness!
Thank goodness.
I'm sorry, Magic Bullet Gun.
But it's okay, right?
Thanks to you, a person's life was saved.
Thank you for everything.
Hey, you lot! Are you alive?!
That voice...?!
Mentor!
Okay! The food's ready!
Where does this...
A feast! A victory feast!
Food goes there! Fruits over there!
The Papunica soldiers who were scattered
have begun to gather.
They heard you rescued the Princess.
You really saved us by fixing
the Balloon Ship and coming for us.
-Princess!
-The Princess!
Princess!
Leona!
Thank goodness you're all better!
Your face was all pale like a King Squid
so I was worried about you!
W-What, Leona? Have you forgotten me?
Honestly! Give me a break, Dai!
It's supposed to be the emotional reunion
between the Princess and her rescuer!
Try to read the room!
Huh? Huh?!
Cheers!
You have all fought bravely.
Especially Dai and the other
Disciples of Aban.
No words can express our gratitude.
My father was right to send
Master Aban as a Hero's Tutor.
The King of Papunica was killed
during the Dark Army's attack.
Since then, the Princess has united
the people and continued to fight.
Tell me, Dai, is that swordsman also
a Disciple of Aban?
Huh?!
Oh crap!
Uh, well, of course he is!
Then I should thank him.
Princess Leona, there's something
I have to tell you.
Uh, Leona, he's, well...
I am...
The Undead Legion Commander
of the Dark Army, Hyunckel!
The Dark Army?!
The Undead Legion Commander?!
That idiot!
Is that true?
Wait a minute!
He's not in the Dark Army anymore!
That's right! He's awakened to his duty
as a Disciple of Aban and helped us!
No matter how I may have atoned for it,
the fact remains that, as Undead Legion
Commander, I destroyed this country.
I must be punished.
Princess Leona, I ask that you judge me.
You can cut me down now if be it.
Hyunckel!
I was blessed to be saved
and to lend my strength to Dai.
I can die fulfilled.
Hyunckel...
as you wish, I Leona, Princess of Papunica,
shall pass judgment upon you.
You will spend the rest of your life,
serving your duty as a Disciple of Aban.
You will risk your life to fight
for friendship, justice, and love.
And you must never disparage yourself
or become lost in the past
and cease from moving forward.
Leona!
That is all. Is that understood?
I accept this.
Let us all move forward together!
She's more capable than she looks.
Papunica just might rise from the ashes.
Ah, there you are.
You.
We were looking for you.
What are you doing drinking alone here?
A monster shouldn't
be drinking with humans.
Don't be ridiculous! A hero
is a hero no matter their race!
Now drink up!
Cheers to the Princess' savior!
Delicious.
This is the most delicious drink
I've ever had!
Mentor! I can't breath here!
I'm sorry, Princess. I didn't know
Uncle Matorif would cut loose like that.
There's no need to be formal.
You can call me Leona, not "Princess."
Otherwise, I'll start
calling you "Ms. Maam."
Please don't!
Hyunckel! What's wrong!?
Where are you going?!
We were going to leave unannounced...
to Sovereign Rock Castle.
Sovereign Rock Castle?
The fortress of the Dark Army.
It's north of Papunica,
deep in the mountains of Guildmain.
Crocodine and I are going
to check their movements.
Why don't we all go together?
It'll be easier with just us.
Please trust us.
I had a wonderful time today.
Give my regards to Dai
and the people of Papunica.
We'll meet again, Maam.
Take care.
This man is a monster!
Even Carl Kingdom,
with its dozens of powerful knights,
is on the brink of ruin
after only five days!
I see.
That boy Dai seems quite impressive.
He managed to fight off
the whole Dark Army.
He's a strange boy
with a mysterious power.
When this mark shines on his forehead,
he exhibits this amazing power...
A mark?!
Zaboera, does that mark
resemble the face of a dragon?
A dragon?
Now that you mention it,
it does seem similar.
Damn you, Hadorra!
I know what you're up to!
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
Dai and friends defeated Flazzard
and rescued Leona.
As they prepare for their next battle,
her broken Magic Bullet Gun
leads Maam to a decision.
Meanwhile, Kilban the Reaper
appears before Dark Commander Hadorra.
And Sovereign Rock Castle, the fortress of
the Dark Army, shows its true form.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Maam's Decision"
The adventure continues!