With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE SURVIVOR FROM HELL
Star Emperor Cross Slash!
C-Crocodine!
You found me, Crocodine.
I know just how tenacious you can be.
But you were foolish
to come after me alone!
I could still have a plan up my sleeve!
No you don't.
Knowing you, after all that
you'd disappear somewhere far away.
The fact you're crawling here is proof
that you're out of Magic Power and items.
That means Ron Berku's attack
drained your Magic Power
and you barely made it out.
Now you're truly out of options!
Curse you, you damn crocodile!
When did you get so smart?!
I have to do something!
There must be a way!
I can't lose in a battle of wits
to this blockhead!
He's just a rube! This is my chance!
There must be something!
Zaboera... it's over.
Crocodine.
You're right. I'm out of options.
I have no choice but
to die by your hand here.
Considering all I've done,
it's only natural.
But I did it because I was scared!
Compared to the other
Legion Commanders, I was so weak!
Resorting to schemes
was the only way I could survive!
Zaboera...
With the defeat of
my Superior Being Zombie,
I realized I can't survive
without relying on others.
Now that I know that, I beg of you...
Please spare me!
I swear I'll never help
the Dark Army again!
You're the only one I can trust!
The Dark Army has abandoned me
and the humans won't accept me!
I'm begging you!
That's it, you naive twit.
Feel conflicted.
True, I have no Magic Power
or stamina left.
But I still have the hundreds of toxins
that flow in my body.
I've just mixed a poison
that will turn him into my puppet.
Just a scratch and I've won.
Come on! Fall for it, Crocodine!
All right, Zaboera.
Come.
You fell for it, you fool!
You really are hopelessly naive,
you blockhead!
No, you're a stepping block
towards my new life!
Got you!
The handle of his axe...?
You bastard! You were pretending!
Crocodine!
Zaboera.
I may not be smart,
but I have learned one thing from you.
And that's...
In this world, some people
are truly beyond all hope!
Wait a minute! Crocod--
Oh! Crocodine!
So you finally defeated this old gremlin!
He wasn't in the zombie
so we were searching for him!
Well! Good for you!
Hm?
Crocodine?
Old man...
Back when there were
six Legion Commanders,
Zaboera's great Magic Power made him
a respected individual.
But, blinded by his ambitions,
and doing nothing but use others,
he eventually became this lowly parasite.
If only he was like Dai
and had even a shred of desire
to grow through his own strength...
Greed is a terrible thing.
If I hadn't been the first to fight Dai,
who knows how I might have ended up?
Zaboera was a true piece of filth.
And for that, I pity him.
You're a decent man, my friend.
But he's not like you.
Even if my friend, Beast King Crocodine
had remained an enemy,
he would have risked his life to better
himself and would be worth respecting.
At least I think so.
Old man...
Thank you.
Let's go... back to the others.
Is he a demon?!
We can't win! He's too strong!
Even with all these numbers...
We'll have to rush him together!
Give it up. It's useless.
What?!
Who said that?!
This one's mine.
No matter how many of you there are,
you can't win.
He's my prey. No one can have him.
Hym?!
What's wrong, Hyunckel?
You look like a bird hit by a peashooter.
I thought seeing my face
didn't make you feel anything.
Are you really the pawn Hym?!
Hadorra created his Royal Guard using
Forbidden Magic on Orichalcum pieces.
In other words, now that Hadorra is dead
and the flow of his Magic Power stopped,
you shouldn't be able to remain alive!
So why?!
I don't know.
After you defeated me,
I fell from Ban Palace to the ground.
I definitely should have died.
I sensed my consciousness
slipping into darkness.
I felt the sense of my own death.
But...
through that darkness,
something rang out within me.
It was the dying cries of my friends
and Lord Hadorra in their final battle.
I knew my friends were dead.
That Lord Hadorra was dead.
We had all lost.
In that moment,
from the bottom of my heart...
I felt I couldn't die!
Even if I was the only one left...
I had to live on and carry on
the will of Lord Hadorra and my friends!
I had to strike back at you
or my death would have been in vain!
So that's it.
When I came to,
the hole in my chest was gone.
It's a miracle!
A miracle caused by an undying spirit!
So Hym is no longer a puppet
controlled by Hadorra's Magic Power?
Could it be...?!
For a moment I wondered who it was.
It turns out it's that loser,
Hadorra's little slave!
So this barely-alive failure wants
to take our place? What a joke!
We'll take care of you
before the Disciples of Aban!
Die, you piece of scrap!
Fools. I would have let you live
if you stayed out of my way.
But now, it looks like I can't!
Sure you got in my way.
But to have garbage like you
talk down and insult Lord Hadorra...
It's completely unforgivable!
S-Silver hair?!
Hym's almost like...
Hadorra!
This is...
Why do I have this?
This is almost like Lord Hadorra's...
Hym...
I think you resemble me the most.
It's like Hadorra reincarnated!
And that energy Hym just emitted
was definitely Aura!
Aura is life energy
that a doll imbued with
artificial life shouldn't be able to use.
That's right!
Hym is now a new individual life form!
Hadorra's life must have entered Hym!
Simultaneously, it's the birth
of a powerful enemy!
Air attacks won't work anymore.
And attacks of Aura
from its Orichalcum body...
will be as powerful as Dai's Aura Blade!
And now...
let's get started, Hyunckel.
Though it looks like you can barely stand.
Weak as they were, you fought
all those enemies. You must be drained.
But I won't be holding back.
For me, you're an obstacle
that must be overcome!
I've felt it from
the first time we fought.
Just as Lord Hadorra
gave everything to defeat Dai,
I have one goal left in this world.
And that's you, Hyunckel!
Take this!
From me and all of the Royal Guard.
All of our pride and anger...
in this fist!
STAR EMPEROR CROSS SLASH
BEAST KING REDEMPTION BLAST
Thanks.
You did well, Garuda.
We managed to defend this Magic Circle.
Well done, all of you.
With this Magic Circle, we can send help
to Ban Palace at any time.
And if anyone from Dai's party is hurt,
we can bring them back here.
Oh, that's right!
Ban Palace no longer has its barrier!
That means anyone who can fly
can get to Ban Palace!
Even so, we're in tatters from
the battle defending the Magic Circle.
There's no one healthy enough
that we can send.
Okay!
Leave this to me!
-That's right.
-He still has plenty of spirit.
My friends! We face Dark King Ban!
Sending the wounded or weak
will only lead to more casualties!
And of the Commandos, only Terry,
Rumbles, and Drack-Drack can fly!
He's probably the weakest of us.
True that.
Obviously, as captain
of the Commandos, I'll be going.
So two more!
Once we select two more members,
we'll leave this place to you all!
Mr. Crocodine, you'll go, right?
Of course! Need you ask?
Sorry. I wish I could go, but...
Oh, that's okay.
You need to look after Ron Berku.
One more person.
Preferably someone who can heal...
Me! Me! Me! Me! Me! Me! Me! Me!
I'm not sure why,
but I sense incredible pressure...
I choose Mr. Beast!
But...
Okay! That makes three!
Oh, right!
Everybody!
Toss whatever
healing items you have in here!
Mr. Crocodine, hurry!
Right!
We're counting on you!
I guess I can't stop healing Meruru.
It's unfortunate, but...
Hyunckel...
Again, I've returned here.
But this time I won't lose!
So this is Ban Palace.
Chiu.
We should send these three back.
You're probably right.
Good work guys!
Go back to Loroi Valley
and await our return with the others!
Don't worry! I promise we'll win
and return to you!
I never lie!
I swear on my Commando badge!
He's still weak, but he's big-hearted.
This little runt just might end up
being someone great someday.
Okay then!
I wonder where everyone is.
That was a good hit, wasn't it, Hyunckel?
I couldn't react to that at all!
Hym's speed and power are incredible!
So this is Aura. What a wonderful ability.
It's like my rising anger
channels directly into power!
Don't tell me it's over already.
What else have you got for me?!
I guess it really is over...
even for you.
It's impossible!
With all the Aura I've spent fighting,
I'm no match for Hym with
that amount of overflowing, newborn Aura!
How can I fight? How?
No! I'm losing sense of my body!
I can't afford to lose here!
Dai... Popp...
Maam...
Hyunckel... Hyunckel...
Hyunckel...
Come on! Just stand up!
Hyunckel!
Hyunckel.
You still aren't doing what I told you to.
What you... told me to?
That's right.
A defeat after trying everything
is nothing to be ashamed of.
But there's still something
that you can do.
If you're going to lose,
try everything first and then lose.
Otherwise, you'll never
become a stronger you.
Give everything you have
and fight to the end.
That's what makes a true warrior.
That's right.
That's more like it, my eternal rival.
It's so strange.
I used to despise him.
I even wanted to kill him once.
Master...
Whenever I fell,
something made me get back up.
It was always you!
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Hym returned from the brink of death
to appear before Hyunckel.
Hym has been imbued with Hadorra's spirit
and evolved into a mighty warrior.
Having spent all his Aura,
Hyunckel struggles,
but eventually goes for a final gambit.
Hyunckel or Hym.
Who will have the stronger will?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Silver-Haired Hym"
The adventure continues!