With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
You're The Bravest
THE GOD OF THE UNDERWORLD
So I shall give you a chance.
These two will not intervene.
I shall fight you alone.
That is your reward.
So?
Surely you won't refuse.
Of course not!
We would have fought even if you had
Mystban and the Reaper!
That's why we've all come this far!
Very well then.
Let us begin.
Ah, I almost forgot.
That man.
His ability to fight was magnificent
and he truly lived up to the legends.
But sadly, it seems his heart
was far too human.
At least let me give him
an ending befitting a human.
Everyone, run!
It's a Merazoma spell!
Dad!
Was that unsatisfactory?
Or did you wish to send him off yourself?
Don't, Dai!
Oh my. Your precious Hero
was the first to fall.
And now there's no one left
with the power to harm me.
He took down Dai with one blow?!
What was that power?!
What a disappointment.
And after I gave him a chance.
You would follow your father, Hero?
Everyone move!
I won't let you!
Merazoma!
Now! Heal Dai
while I hold him off with my spell!
Dai!
Popp!
N-No way! He burned these clothes
that were sewn with magic!
With such a tiny ember!
Is the Dark King's Merazoma spell
that much stronger than mine?!
A Merazoma spell?
That was no Merazoma spell.
It was Mera.
Mera?!
Even with the same spell,
depending on the caster's Magic Power,
the effects can vary greatly.
In other words, comparing my Mera spell
to your Merazoma spell,
my spell is far more powerful.
What?!
Such a difference in strength.
You managed to break the Dark Army's
assault time and time again.
So I assumed you were
a little more powerful, but I was wrong.
Even with that blow to Dai,
I merely shot a little of my Aura
to match his attack.
Just like this.
Super-pressurized Dark Aura?!
He hit Dai with that?!
This doesn't look good!
We must fight as one if we want to win!
How's Dai?! Is Dai alright, Maam?!
His heart is beating.
But he took so much damage...
He was hit where
he'd already been wounded!
Just heal him already!
I am!
Enough.
As much as I enjoy
watching you weaklings struggle...
don't bother anymore.
It seems I was wrong
to give you a taste of hope.
Even if Dai was in your ranks,
it would change nothing.
As recompense,
allow me to kill you painlessly.
This is my Merazoma spell.
From its unimaginable power
and graceful form...
it has its own ancient name
in the Underworld.
Kaiser Phoenix.
Hyunckel!
My armour should be able
to withstand it for a bit!
Hurry and heal Dai!
Crap!
A second one?!
Impossible! He's too fast!
I don't have time to heal!
Everyone! Switch to the offensive!
Dark King, prepare yourself!
Bloody Sukuraido!
Such bright eyes.
How revolting.
You used to be far more magnificent.
Curse you!
Crocodine!
Look out!
Hyunckel!
Stop, Ban!
Oh?
Please work!
If I can't beat him with this,
I'll be out of spells that'll work on him!
Please work!
Medoroa!
What?!
This is Mahokanta.
I'll have to cancel it out!
Popp?!
Popp, are you okay?!
Dammit! He reflected my spell
with a Mahokanta spell.
I can't use Medoroa anymore!
When did he cast a Mahokanta spell?!
His magic is on a whole different level.
His magic doesn't have a charge.
He can cast spells without
taking the time to charge them.
That lets him do two things
in the time it takes us to do one.
While we're attacking,
he can attack and defend at once.
Maam, can you carry Dai?
Huh?
I'm taking us over to Big Guy.
Then we'll Rura out of here.
Popp...
I won't hear any arguments this time.
No wonder he's called
the God of the Underworld.
He's on a whole different level from us.
If we are to fight him again,
we'll need to regroup first or we'll die!
Got it.
Here goes! Come here!
Bye!
Rura!
What?!
W-What happened?!
Poor thing.
Now things are even more hopeless.
Did you not know?
No one escapes the Dark King.
MEDOROA
KAISER PHOENIX
Ban Palace is shielded
by King Ban's Magic Power.
You can't escape it with a Rura spell.
Bleah!
Moving within Ban Palace
may be possible,
but no one can enter
and no one may leave.
No one but warriors of the Dark Army
blessed with a special spell.
Dammit!
Had you tried to fight instead of running,
maybe you could have lived longer.
But I guess it's all the same.
Either way, there's nothing you can do.
You're all done for! Done for!
What's your problem?!
I said you're all done for!
You're! All! Done! For!
It's over.
Now to finish it.
I grazed him...
back then...
with my Refractor Fist!
I see! Back when you all attacked!
What a shock. It's a miracle.
It worked!
Dark King Ban is still
a living creature!
If I can hit him with my Refractor Fist...
Care to try?
This is indeed
a one-in-a-million opportunity.
My servants won't intervene
and I'm wounded.
My attacks will be slower.
But, surely you know
that Darklings can regenerate.
If you don't hurry,
your opportunity will disappear.
We can't escape
and I'm the only one who can fight.
What will you do?
I have to give it a shot!
Don't!
You can't, Maam! Do you really think
he can be defeated so simply?!
How very sharp.
The little Mage is definitely
the MVP of this battle.
You were toying with me!
You could have regenerated any time!
How cruel! Do you enjoy
playing with us like that?!
I do enjoy it.
When you use the awesome power
you've gained to toy with the weak,
is it not pleasurable?
Do you not feel superior?
What are you talking about?
Power is the purest, most simple,
and most beautiful fundamental law.
"Might makes right"
is how all creatures live.
Darklings... Dragons... All creatures.
Only humans use their
pompous reasoning to deny the truth.
Power is the truth that rules all.
Even if you have power, that doesn't
give you the right to disrupt peace!
The peace that everyone
on the Surface World desires!
You are ignorant.
The truth is that peace is maintained
by a greater power.
Indeed.
By the power of the gods.
My home, the Underworld, is a world
that lies far beneath your lands.
Everywhere you look is
boiling magma and barren land.
What's more, the sun,
the source of all life,
does not shine in the Underworld.
The sun... Such a magnificent power.
But the gods granted the sun
and the Surface World to the humans,
banishing the Darklings
and Dragons to the Underworld
simply because the humans
were weaker than us.
If that is justice,
than our power, too, is justice.
That is why I spent
thousands of years building my power
in preparation to annihilate
the Surface World.
Soon, the Surface World will be gone.
Then, in our Underworld...
the sun shall shine.
When that happens, I...
I shall truly be God of the Underworld.
The folly committed by the gods...
shall be rectified.
W-We can't win!
He's thinking on a whole different scale!
For thousands of years, he's thought of
the Surface World as nothing but a lid!
We're just...
We're just mere humans!
There's no way we can hope to win!
You've finally given up.
That was more enjoyable than I expected.
You've done well,
Heroes of the Surface World.
I won't give up!
D-Dai?!
Even if everyone in the world does,
I won't give up!
I'll never give up!
What impressive vitality.
But what was that?
I don't think I heard you correctly.
I'll never give up.
Even if everyone loses hope!
I can't give up until the very, very end!
So I heard you correctly the first time.
I thought it inconceivable that you would
say such a thing when faced with my power.
I know just how overwhelming
your power is.
But that doesn't matter!
You said that power is justice,
but you're wrong!
That's not what Grampa taught me...
Or what Master Aban taught me...
Or what Dad taught me about justice!
You're wrong about everything!
Dai!
They stand again?!
After they were on the verge of death?!
Very well.
I recognize the power of your soul, which
gave your despairing friends strength.
But you can't kill me with your soul.
If you wish to change
my mind about justice,
then use your power and not your words.
Then here you go!
This is all of my power!
Kaiser Phoenix!
Aban Strash!
He pierced it!
Too slow!
Dai!
King Ban!
He was able to counter my second attack.
Not only that, his force overpowered
my Kaiser Phoenix and reached me.
Very well!
Iora spells?!
Whoa! It's like a storm of Iora spells!
Ban's using weaker spells
and fighting with numbers!
Even so, each spell is
as destructive as a Ionazun spell!
Dai!
King Ban, perhaps you should
stop playing and let us all fight.
What? Ridiculous.
You actually believe that
he will wound me further?
Dai!
Now! Take this!
King Ban!
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
I finally realized it
imasara kizuitanosa
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
Must be the reason I was born
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
I shake off the clinging night
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
Dai's Aban Strash blasts Ban.
Recognizing Dai's power, Dark King Ban
summons a legendary weapon to counter him.
Its power shakes
the heavens and the earth.
Ban easily drives Dai back
and unleashes a finishing blow.
Can Dai and his friends find hope
in the face of certain doom?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Unlikely Savior"
The adventure continues!