Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE DARK LORD HADLAR'S RETURN
So that's the island.
That crafty little...
Doragoramu!
Master turned into a Dragon!
Dorogoramu! It's an ancient
mythical attack spell!
I never thought I'd see it used!
He's much bigger than the last one!
Among all monsters,
Dragons are the most powerful!
Only a true Hero can fight one
and overcome it!
Now face me, Dai!
This is going too far!
Get back, Grampa!
I told you.
A Dragon's skin is harder than steel.
Then I'll use Avan Style Sword Technique,
Earth Slash!
You cannot win simply with brute strength!
Dai!
Hmm. That's not it.
What the hell?! Don't scare me like that!
L-Listen, I wasn't training
to compete with Dai.
I want to be perfectly clear about that.
I don't know what sort of
heavy training he's doing's, but...
Master Avan?
What about Master...
What?!
He didn't!
How could he do something like that?!
Dai can barely use Hyado! How is he
going to stop a Dragon's flames?!
Dai!
That's enough!
I'm fine, Grampa!
Earth Slash is a strength-based attack.
I can't face a Dragon's flames with it.
Slice the earth, slice the sea,
slice the air.
The Avan Style Sword Technique
is based on these three skills.
Yesterday, you attained Earth Slash,
the ability to slice the earth.
Now I shall explain the next skill.
Slice the sea.
The key to this attack is speed.
In other words, agility.
WAVE SLASH
SPEED
Beating a Dragon's flames
requires an attack that slices the sea!
Wave Slash!
Avan Style Sword Technique...
I see you've caught on.
But will it work?
Oh no!
Don't do it, Dai!
Wave Slash!
Dai!
He sliced... the flames!
Master...
Dai!
I did it.
Master, are you okay?
It stings.
It's your own fault, Master.
Using Dorogoramu for training is crazy.
What if you burned Dai to a crisp?
Well, remember when Dai split the sea
when he faced that Gargoyle?
I thought he might be able
to pull off Wave Slash right away.
Don't do things like that on a hunch!
You seem rather upset.
Were you really that worried?
N-No I wasn't.
If Earth Slash is a strength attack,
Wave Slash is a speed attack.
With the strength you already had, your
speed has increased these last few days.
So he was able to slice the flames
with the pressure from his quick slash.
Yep. Wave Slash is for slicing
formless things like fire and water.
Precisely!
If you master this skill, you can slice
flames and blizzards to attack enemies!
And Dai has already figured out
how to do Wave Slash!
At this rate, completing the
Special Hard Course could be a reality...
It stings.
Maybe a light Hyado spell to cool it?
In that case, perhaps Dai should do it.
That might be perfect.
Hyado!
A very nice size!
What do you mean by "nice"?
This is quite embarrassing.
But Popp, why are you here?
Huh?
I was forced to come here.
Huh. Popp was training alone?
Hey! Don't!
Huh? To compete with me?
Knock it off! I wasn't training!
An earthquake!
What is it? A volcanic eruption?!
No. It's something else.
This shaking...
is from someone trying to
breach the island's magic circle!
What?!
Who is it?!
A servant of the Dark Lord of course!
This island is protected
by a magic circle that repels evil!
Only bad guys can't come in!
But a normal monster
wouldn't be able to set foot inside.
Could it be...?!
D-Did they give up?
It's coming!
What?!
Something really powerful is coming!
I can feel its evil energy!
Grampa, what's wrong?!
I-I know this intense energy!
It appears my fears were correct.
Your magic circle was quite an annoyance.
So you're really back, Dark Lord!
Dark Lord?!
D-Dark Lord?!
Hadlar!
THE RESURRECTED DARK LORD
HADLAR
DORAGORAMU
FIRE DRAGON TRANSFORMATION SPELL
BAGIKUROSAI
VORTEX-TYPE SPELL
The Dark Lord Hadlar?!
There's no mistaking it.
It's the Dark Lord!
And that face and body...
He looks younger than I remember!
He's overflowing with vitality!
It's been a while, Avan, the Hero.
Hero?!
Master is the Hero?!
Long ago, you thwarted
all of my ambitions,
and even took my life!
I will never forget
that pain and humiliation!
You've already taken
hundreds of human lives!
Compared to a Darkling like me,
humans are nothing more than chattel!
My life is worth more than thousands,
if not hundreds of millions of them!
You're still the same.
No. You're even more
disgusting than before.
And I've grown tired of your Hero antics.
That's right! Avan, the Hero!
The name of the legendary Hero
who fought and defeated the Dark Lord,
and brought peace to the world
was Avan!
Is it true, Master?!
That was a long time ago.
Now stay back!
No! I'll fight with you!
You idiot! Come on!
You too, gramps!
What are you doing, Popp?!
I have to fight, too!
You moron!
We'll only get in the way!
I can't believe Master
was the Hero who killed the Dark Lord!
I chose the wrong person to learn under!
So those are your students.
I hear you're going about as a Hero tutor
training warriors of justice.
I didn't expect that you'd return, though.
How futile.
IORA!
I'm glad that you came here yourself.
I can defeat you here
and clear the darkness clouding the world!
What rubbish!
Begirama!
Yes!
What farce is this, Avan?!
It didn't work?!
Heat and explosion-type spells
are my forte!
Did you think you could defeat me
with an ember like that?!
Watch!
This is a true Begirama!
Begirama!
Wave Slash!
Master!
What power...
You're even stronger
than when we last fought.
How?!
You want to know?
You'll regret hearing the answer.
I see you still believe
that I'm the Dark Lord.
What do you mean?!
I was resurrected through the power
of a mighty ruler!
He gave me
a more powerful body than before!
What?!
There's someone stronger
than the Dark Lord?!
Who is it?!
Vearn, the Dark King.
The Dark King...
Vearn?!
That's right!
It was Vearn, the Dark King!
A mighty god of the Underworld
who resurrected me after my defeat to you!
A god of the Underworld?!
I had to sleep for over a decade
to replenish the power I lost,
but after my return,
I swore loyalty to Lord Vearn,
and was granted rule over his entire
Dark Army as his right hand man!
I am now supreme commander
over Lord Vearn's armies!
I am Hadlar, the Dark Commander!
Unbelievable!
There's someone stronger than him?!
It's over! This world is over!
Vearn, the Dark King is my master
and an omnipotent Dark God!
His armies are far greater than
mine ever were!
No matter what you do,
you humans have no hope!
What...
Avan, do you remember
our battle 15 years ago?
I offer you the same choice
I did back then.
Join me! Do so and I shall grant you
half of the world!
Well?
Now that you sense your defeat,
perhaps you'll be more reasonable.
I refuse!
Still the same answer.
You still can't see my mercy.
You don't know what mercy is!
Even if I agree,
you'd eventually take my life.
Don't be so sure.
Besides, I doubt you have the authority
to offer half of the world.
Now that you're just
a servant of your Dark King.
W-What?! A servant?!
You dare call me
a servant of the Dark King?!
I see I've struck a nerve.
Silence!
So much for sparing you!
Your students can watch you turn to ash!
That's the strongest
explosion-type spell there is! Ionazun!
Master, look out!
That stance!
Eat this!
Ionazun!
Avan Strash!
Master!
A draw?!
Ah, the attack that took my life,
Avan Strash.
It cuts deep.
However!
It appears it lacks the edge
over my resurrected power!
Master!
Idiot! What are you doing?!
I'm gonna fight!
Don't be stupid! How can we
fight someone even Master can't beat?!
Master used Dorogoramu in our training!
He barely has any Magic Power left!
That's right!
I've heard Dorogoramu takes three or four times
the Magic Power of a normal spell!
Master...
Hey!
You've grown weak, Avan.
No. I suppose this is
the limit of a human's power.
Let me ease your suffering.
Stop!
Do you want to die that much,
student of Avan?!
Dai...
Dai!
Darn... it...
You mean nothing to me.
If you want to live, get out of my sight.
Th-Thank you.
Excuse us!
What?!
Blood?! Impossible!
That little brat's blade
drew blood from me?!
Stop, boy.
Y-Yes sir?
I've changed my mind.
I suppose no student of Avan
can be left alive after all.
I'll slaughter you all!
Popp! Dai!
Begirama!
Master!
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
The resurrected Hadlar's power
was overwhelming.
Even Avan, who had once defeated him,
is forced into a corner.
When Avan shows his willingness to die
to protect Dai and for peace,
once again Dai's power awakens!
Next time on
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Insignia of Avan"
The adventure continues!