A Hero. A bringer of peace
who battles monsters and protects people.
The young boy, Dai,
was raised by monsters.
He decided to fight the Dark Army
after being trained by the Hero, Avan.
Traveling with Popp, the Mage, they were
later joined by Maam, a Warrior Priest.
Monsters of the Dark Lord Hadlar's Six
Legions attacked these Disciples of Avan.
They defeated Crocodine
of the Furfang Legion,
and were victorious against
Hyunckel of the Undead Legion.
Dai continues on the path of a Hero.
His next adversary is
Blizzblaze General Flazzard.
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
BLIZZBLAZE GENERAL FLAZZARD
What's wrong, Maam? You seem blue.
I'm fine.
I was just thinking.
About Hyunckel?
Yeah.
Did you, well, like...
Did you like him?
Huh?!
I don't know.
But, when I looked into his sad eyes,
I wanted to help him.
I wanted to be by his side.
I just got that feeling.
Don't worry! It's okay. He's not dead.
After all Dai and I threw at him,
he was fit as a fiddle, remember?
Popp?
He was even Undead Legion Commander.
He wouldn't die so easily.
You're right. Thank you, Popp.
Uh, sure.
He must be alive.
He was a Disciple of Avan, after all.
Oh man! What the hell am I doing?!
Here I am, talking up my rival
for some reason!
Ow!
Finished!
Wow, it's like new! Amazing!
They used to call me
the Papnica Inventor King!
What happened to being
"the greatest swordsman in Papnica"?
Now we're all set! Let's go rescue Leona!
The problem is just where is the Princess?
He's right. She's missing, isn't she?
Where to look
in this vast continent of Holkia?
I guess we'll have to take it slowly.
But if we don't hurry, the next Legion
Commander of the Dark Army might show up.
Leona...
That's it!
What's it, old timer?
The temple! We should go to the temple!
The temple?
Hey, old timer,
what's in this ruined temple?
The temple has a basement warehouse.
Try to find the entrance.
This won't be easy.
What's in that warehouse?
Signal flares!
Signal flares?
Papnica has flares that use
gunpowder to send signals during battle.
Huh. With gunpowder?
If we find and launch one, the Princess
is sure to see it wherever she is.
I see.
If we launch
a red signal flare of victory,
I'm sure the Her Majesty will feel
it's safe enough to show up.
Found it!
Ooh! This might actually be it!
It's no good!
We can't get in.
But... I don't think we can move all this.
Leave it to me! Everybody get back!
He seems excited.
He probably can't wait
to test his strength.
Since I told him he beat Hyunckel
without the power of his mark.
Let's test out whether I can
use that skill or not!
Mera!
You moron! Don't!
Fire Earth Slash!
Yes! I really did it!
You moron! Of all the attacks to use!
There's gunpowder down there! Gunpowder!
Oh crap!
They've ignited! Run!
A total loss.
All the signal flares were blown away.
Hey dummy, why couldn't you use Hyado
for an Ice Earth Slash or something?
Hmm?
Sorry.
Well, at least the flares were launched.
Don't you think Princess Leona
got the message?
I dunno. With that crazy display, she
might get suspicious and stay hidden.
Sorry.
Huh?
What's that?
It's not a bird.
Is it a monster?!
No, that's...!
That's...
The Papnica Balloon Ship!
Balloon Ship?
It's a vehicle that travels by air!
The royal family uses it!
What?!
Take us down.
That's Baduck!
Hey! Hey!
Hey!
Wow.
That's impressive.
Hey!
Lady Amy!
Baduck, did you send up those flares?
You know her, old timer?
Introduce me, will you?
Fool! Show some respect!
This is Lady Amy,
one of the Papnica Troika!
A woman that young? I was thinking...
We're the Papnica Troika!
Those strange flares went up,
so we came to check it out.
I left the Princess with Apollo and Marin.
By Princess, you mean Leona, right?!
Is she okay?! Where is she?!
Who are you?
I'm a friend of Leona's! My name is Dai!
Dai? You're Dai?!
That's right. This young man is
the Hero Her Majesty always talks about.
This young man and his friends
have already vanquished the Undead Legion.
You can all rest easy.
What?!
Vanquished the Undead Legion?!
Are you really Dai, the Hero?
This is a weapon
of the Papnica royal family!
Leona gave it to me. It's my treasure!
I understand. Come with us.
The Princess waits at Valge Island.
Valge Island?! The Princess is there?!
Wow!
Holy cow!
This thing is amazing!
Of course.
It's the only Balloon Ship in Papnica.
Man, what a surprise.
When you came from the sky,
I thought you were the Princess, Miss Amy.
Oh no. The Princess is far more beautiful
than I could ever hope to be.
Ooh. I can't wait to meet her!
Gross. You're such a creep.
Oh come on! This is a princess
we're talking about here.
Who wouldn't be interested?
I bet she's gentle and cute,
unlike someone I know.
What?
Leona's cute, but she's not really gentle.
Huh? R-Really?
She's brutally honest.
She could be worse than Maam.
If she's worse than Maam,
is she really okay?
What's that supposed to mean?
If she's worse than Maam,
she must be an ogre.
Why you...!
Hey! Behave yourselves!
HYADARUKO
ICE-TYPE SPELL
HELL'S CLAW
There's the island!
So that's Valge Island?!
The sea is spinning!
That's the Valge Whirlpool.
Because of that,
most people avoid Valge Island.
To get there by boat requires taking a
long route to avoid the whirlpool.
Plus Valge Tower
is the only thing on that island.
I never would have guessed
Her Majesty was there.
It's all thanks to this Balloon Ship.
We used it as a message ship while we
planned for a counterattack at the tower.
That must be the tower
in the middle of the island.
It used to be used as a lighthouse.
That's where Leona is!
At last... At long last I can see Leona!
Let go, you bastard!
Shut up! It's mine!
It's mine!
That's enough!
What is it?! What is going on?!
Sir Apollo! Lady Marin!
They're fighting over rations!
Over rations?
That's enough!
You're embarrassing yourselves!
It's his fault!
He tried to take more than his share!
I've been on guard for three days!
I deserve to eat this much!
I haven't eaten anything in a whole day!
Shut up! Let go!
You let go!
Hand that over!
Princess!
Your Majesty?!
What are you doing?!
Throwing it away!
What?!
But it's the last of our valuable food!
Valuable or not,
if it sparks conflict, I don't want it.
All of you...
The reason we're in hiding
and preparing for a counterattack...
is to thwart the Dark Army's evil.
How can we fight amongst ourselves
over our own greed?!
That's no different from the Dark Army!
If the alternative is to live as monsters,
then let us starve to death as a humans!
I'm so ashamed.
You've barely eaten, too, Princess.
And here we are, the first to complain.
Forgive us!
We're sorry.
Have you calmed down?
Yes!
Then talk it over and share.
Very well!
We just need to hold out a little longer!
I know the Hero will come to save us!
You mean the young man
you always speak of?
I believe his name is Dai?
Right!
He's a little short,
but he's got the Hero spirit.
I sent him a tutor,
so he should have gotten stronger by now.
That's not a very nice way
to speak of our savior.
But do think such a boy will really come?
Let us believe he will.
At the very least, the Princess believes.
If the Princess believes,
then so should we all.
Sorry, but that's
a pipe dream right there.
The Hero and company
are at the bottom of a pool of lava.
Who's there?!
Such leadership and charisma
for a little girl.
I may have scored
a bigger fish than I thought.
Over there!
You! Who are you?!
Blizzblaze General Flazzard.
Sorry I ain't your Hero, little Princess!
The Dark Army!
Curse you!
One was burned and one was frozen...
He can control both heat and cold?
Time to die now.
Today the Papnica royal family dies out!
Don't be ridiculous!
We won't let you lay a finger
on the Princess!
Die, monster!
We can stand this flame!
Too hot for you?
Then let me cool you down!
With one blow?!
The temperature difference.
The rapid temperature difference of
the flames and ice weakened their armour!
Hmm?
Looks like we got at least one guy
with some brains.
I am Apollo of the Papnica Troika!
And I am Marin!
We shall protect the Princess
with our lives!
Ooh. Good for you.
Marin, hit his flame side
with a Hyado spell.
I shall hit the other side.
Got it!
Here goes! Merazoma!
Hyadain!
Whoops!
Goodie, goodie.
Giving me a feast as a welcome?
Stop! He's absorbing the spell energy!
Right back at you.
Fubaha!
Fubaha, huh?
Well, well. I guess that "Troika" title
ain't just for show.
Now matter how strong your flames or ice,
you cannot pierce this defensive shield!
Okay, okay, I get it.
Then out of respect for your performance,
let me show you a neat trick.
A trick?!
Me...
ra...
zo...
oo...
ma!
Five Finger Flares!
Look! Something's wrong down there!
Could the Princess be in danger?!
He fired five Merazoma spells at once.
He's an unbelievable monster!
Apollo, let me heal you!
Y-You bastard!
How could you do that to Marin?!
Don't make me laugh!
This is a battlefield!
It doesn't matter who you are!
The strong live and the weak die!
If you don't want to get hurt,
stay off of the battlefield!
Ain't that right, Princess Leona?
You're prepared to die
in any horrible way, aren't you?
Hurry! Get us down there!
Can you land on the roof?!
Yes, my lady!
Leona...
Hyado!
So much for Papnica.
When the survivors hear of your death,
they'll all lose hope.
I'm sure they'll never think of
opposing the Dark Army again.
Don't assume humans are like you monsters!
What was that?
There will always be someone
who'll stand against you!
So long as humanity has its pride!
That's some courage there.
Right when you're about to die!
Bye-bye, little Princess.
Go act tough on your way to the afterlife!
Wait... that knife...
Who's there?!
Dai?!
You?! You're alive?!
Get away from Leona!
Save it for someone who cares!
If you even touch Leona, you'll regret it!
Dai!
You little brat!
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
Dai battles Blizzblaze General Flazzard.
Flazzard uses the Blizzblaze Legion's
unbeatable strategy.
With Flazzard's obsession with winning at
any cost, Dai and friends fall into peril.
What's worse, Leona falls prey
to Flazzard's cruel intentions.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Terrifying Curse Field"
The adventure continues!