With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Never let go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Never let go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
You're The Bravest
HADORRA VERUS BARAN
Iora?!
D-Darn it!
Begira--
Dai!
This is too difficult!
We can't win like this.
Begiragon!
Defending with Dragonic Auras.
Like father like son.
Baran has realized that Hadorra's body
contains a Black Core.
Congratulations, Mystban.
Hadorra may actually have a chance.
The attacks and spells
of Dragon Knights are too powerful,
and will most likely detonate it.
Their fear of that keeps them
from fighting at full strength.
You two!
Why are you holding back?!
Don't tell me the mighty Dragon Knights
have lost their nerve!
This can't be because
you're not used to fighting together.
Baran! Where's your Gigabrake?!
Dai, you too! Don't you want
to avenge your dead master?!
Don't you want to take revenge on me?!
That's it! Hadorra doesn't know!
Maybe if I tell him, he'll stop fighting!
Listen, Hadorra! You've got...
Don't!
You mustn't tell him!
Huh?! Why not?!
A Black Core can be detonated
by its creator's Magic Power.
Once Hadorra notices the Black Core,
Ban will detonate it on the spot.
He'll do it to stop Hadorra
from revolting against him.
What's wrong?!
We'll be fine. If we focus all our energy
on defense, we should survive.
But your friends on the surface
are certain to perish!
Why are you holding back?!
At this rate...
How very suspicious. What are you up to?
We're up to nothing!
Gigaden!
We were merely holding back
to analyze the extent of your power!
As you wish, I shall face you
with my ultimate blade!
I see. So you were just testing me.
That's good to hear.
What are you doing?!
It's a risk, but I have no choice.
I'm going to have him explode here!
Huh?!
If I decapitate him,
he shouldn't detonate right away.
It should take a moment
for Ban to detonate him, too.
That's when I'll use all of my
Dragonic Aura to contain the blast.
That's a crazy idea!
We don't know if it can be contained
by a Dragonic Aura!
That's way too dangerous!
Dai...
do you trust me?
Huh?
Well?
I-I trust your strength
more than anyone's.
A good answer.
And I trust your strength, too.
Seeing you fight that Royal Guard member
and Hadorra, I realized...
you're far stronger than
when you fought me.
You impress me with how you've grown.
But this is something only I can do.
Only with my sword skills
and abundance of Dragonic Aura.
So I need you to trust me here.
Get your friends out of here just in case.
Take that hole to the surface.
No matter what happens to me
I promise I'll take care of Hadorra!
I leave the fight with Ban to you.
Promise me you'll win.
For you and for those who believe in you.
What impressive power we wield!
You have your Ultimate Blade, Gigabrake!
And I have my Ultra Combustion Slash!
Both infuse our blades
with supercharged energy
to unleash at the moment of impact
and destroy our enemies!
In other words,
the first to land a hit wins!
It'll all be decided by the timing!
So it seems.
And neither of us require a second strike.
Both of our attacks
are strong enough to end things.
Maybe... I should help out?
Maybe using my Dragonic Aura
to help contain the blast...
Don't interfere!
Hadorra's right. The timing is everything.
If you interfere,
it increases my chances of failing.
B-But...!
Didn't you say you trust my strength?
All right!
Once Popp and the others are safe,
I'll come back to help!
Promise me you won't fail!
Yes.
I promise I'll be fine.
Here I go!
Hadorra! It's time!
Show me the true power of a Dragon!
Go Dai!
Gigabrake!
Ultra Combustion Slash!
Got you!
What?!
It's over...
Hadorra!
H-He did it!
Impossible! It didn't cut through!
Look out!
D-Dai?!
Dino!
GIGABRAKE
ABAN STRASH
Move!
Dino! Hang in there, Dino!
No! The wound is too deep!
Untreated, it could be fatal!
Dino!
Dino?
Oh. You mean me.
Looks like it didn't work.
It's strange. Your Gigabrake
was much stronger when you fought me.
That's enough! Don't talk!
Let me heal you!
Why? Why is my head
still attached to my body?!
Baran attacked at the perfect range
for a fatal blow.
How could I take a fatal blow
from Dragon Master General Baran
and still have my head on my shoulders?
How?!
Allow me to answer that question.
You!
You're still alive?!
It'd be pretty sad if a reaper
was killed. Of course I'm alive.
Yo! The undying man!
How can you be alive
after I cleaved you in half?
That's it. Cleaving me in half
was the problem, Baran.
What?!
The blood in my veins has the same
composition as Underworld magma.
It's super-hot and contains
a powerful acid.
You went and cut me in half
getting my blood all over
your Demon Dragon Blade.
So now you see.
My blood corroded your sword,
dulling its sharpness.
Even the Demon Dragon Blade
can't regenerate that damage quickly.
Against someone as strong as Hadorra here,
it loses its effectiveness.
This is my curse, Baran.
A reaper always kills its target.
You may evade me,
but there are consequences.
So there you have it, Hadorra.
I doubt you'd like me taking your prey,
so I leave the rest to you.
Be sure to take care of Baran for me.
I didn't know you were ordered
to assassinate Baran, Reaper.
Everything's a mystery with you.
That's an ugly wound.
Piroro, heal him will you?
It'll heal momentarily.
Now, now. Don't be like that.
Learn to accept
people's generosity, Hadorra.
So long as Baran dies,
my job will be complete.
One more thing.
I'd advise against showing any mercy.
You should crush them at once.
You may want a fair fight, but his sword
won't regenerate for a while.
Do you have that sort of time left?
How did you...?!
Hooray! It's all healed!
Oh? There's another small wound here!
Let me take care of that!
They know!
They're backing down
not so that Hadorra can have the glory,
but to avoid the Black Core's explosion!
Goodbye and good luck, Hadorra.
You too, Baran.
Not that it'll help.
I'd prefer not to win a fight
with the Reaper's help.
But I don't have the luxury of waiting
until you're both ready to fight.
I won't be holding back, Baran!
No! If I stop the healing spell now,
Dino might not survive!
I can't let go of him,
no matter what attack comes!
So you choose
to protect your son. So be it.
I can't extend this fight any longer!
I must finish things now!
D-Dodge it!
Forget about me and keep fighting!
Ionazun!
D-Dino!
Y-You fool! How could you be so reckless?!
I'm fine. I'm already fully healed now.
Stop pretending! Your wound...
I've had it!
What?!
All this covering for each other
and walking on eggshells while fighting...
I've had it!
We're family aren't we?
Dino...
If we're going to fight together,
let's really fight together as one!
If the two of us seriously work together
maybe we can find some new,
final power!
A final power...
Okay! Here goes, Hadorra!
Darn it!
This is nothing!
What an unlimited willpower he possesses!
Very well. I'll do as you say.
Really?
What was that?!
Dai. Who gave that name to you?
It was Grampa.
When I washed up on Dermline Island.
My crib.
There was a name plate.
Only the "D" was left on it.
Grampa gave me this name
so that at least...
I'd share the initial
my real parents gave me.
Why am I so sleepy?
I cast the Sleep Spell Rarihoma on you.
Leave the fighting to me and sleep.
Why? I'll fight with you!
Lie still and you should heal.
You're a Dragon Knight.
Your healing abilities should be strong.
N-No! H-How could you do this to me?
Children may wish otherwise,
but this is what parents must do.
You'll understand when you grow up.
Don't do this!
I... I'll fight with you!
"Dai," is it?
It's a good name.
But I hope you'll remember the name
that Soara and I gave you.
"Dino." In the Arukido Kingdom language
it means, "Strong Dragon."
Why?! Why does everybody do this to me?!
Even Master... Even Master
cast Asutoron on me and...
I see.
So Aban did the same sort of thing.
It seems that, in the very end,
part of me learned how to be human.
This can't be the end!
No!
It's not...
fair.
Come on! Good night, Dino!
Go to sleep!
Good night, Dino!
What's wrong, Dino?
You're doing it wrong.
Go to sleep, Dino. Good night.
Honestly, you never get the hang
of putting him to sleep.
It looks like you're right, Soara.
I never got the hang
of putting him to sleep.
You're a parent at heart, Baran.
You risk yourself for him.
Prepare yourself, Hadorra.
I swore I'd never use
this power again, but...
I use it now!
That's...!
I didn't put Dino to sleep
out of fear for his well being!
I once took this terrible form
when we battled before!
I never want him to see it again!
That form! The Dragonoid!
I see! So you plan to fight in
the Dragon Knight's ultimate battle mode!
Very well! I accept your challenge!
Die Hadorra!
We can go to hell together!
C-Curse you!
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I used even loneliness as a weapon
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
I just want to be there for you
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
To call out your name
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Is harder than any magic spell
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
Even though you're so close to me
aishiteiru
I love you
imasara kizuitanosa
I finally realized it
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
To call out your name
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
Must be the reason I was born
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
I shake off the clinging night
ai ni iku
And go to see you
ima sugu kimi no moto e
Right now to where you are
The battle against
the Hadorra Royal Guard begins.
Meanwhile, in Ban Palace,
Baran has put Dai to sleep
and once again becomes the Dragonoid.
With the attack against his son,
Baran unleashes his fury on Hadorra.
Dark King Ban calmy watches
the battle from his throne.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Black Core"
The adventure continues!