Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE ORICHALCUM WARRIOR
Listen up!
Dai, the Hero was lost in the waters
near the Field of Death!
While he was wounded by Lord Hadorra,
no one believes he died!
He's alive out there somewhere!
The Mystic Legion must be the first
to find Dai and kill him!
We must distinguish ourselves
for Dark King Ban's praise!
Now go! Mystic Legion, go forth!
Dai, where are you?!
Leave this to me and my nose!
Find something?!
My nose froze.
I figured as much!
Regardless, there won't be any smell
to detect in this environment.
That girl, Meruru, could have been
a real help here.
She has that strange power.
We couldn't bring her here.
She's just a defenseless Seer.
I couldn't find a single clue
looking from the sky.
In that case...
Yeah! Looks like it's
winter swimming for us!
What?!
Let's go!
Right!
Wait! Shouldn't you warm up first?!
Uh-oh. I thought that
this was my chance to shine.
This situation is very bad.
I don't know how to swim.
Huh?
What?! What's your problem?!
How dare a simple jellyfish laugh at me!
That's it!
Listen, I've got a proposal.
I'll make it worth your while.
So cold!
Th-This is hopeless!
I can barely last a few minutes!
If he's down there,
not even Dai could survive!
But if he's not here in the water,
searching is going to be near impossible.
Another possibility is that
when he hit an iceberg,
he got buried inside of it.
If that's the case...
how do we find him
from among all these icebergs?
Why you...!
Hey! How can you be fishing
at a time like this?!
This may look like fishing to a layman,
but it has a purpose.
My mind works on
a whole different level from yours.
What?
Ah, it's back!
What's that?
A jellyfish I just tamed.
I'm having it search for Dai
in return for food.
Oh? You can do that?
Of course. A Fat Rat is like
the king of the monster world.
Any monster will bow before me.
You can't be serious.
Hey, did you find Dai?
Oh! That's...!
This is Dai's! I'm sure of it!
Was that all?
Did you really search everywhere?!
Wasn't there a human?!
Dai...!
This proves that he's definitely nearby.
Huh?
Oh, the food I promised.
Hold on. I haven't caught it yet.
What a temper.
Dai... Don't die. Don't die out there.
I swear I'll find you!
No matter how many hundreds
or thousands of icebergs there are...
I swear I'll find you!
Dai!
Popp?
I thought I heard Popp's voice.
Could the others be nearby?
Okay...!
This is the last bit of Aura I have left!
Popp... Everyone...
Please... find me!
Popp!
Could that pillar of light be...?!
The Dragon Crest!
It's Dai!
Hey! Wait up!
I'm still numb.
You wait here.
Garuda!
This is pathetic.
It's just me...
Huh?
Popp!
He survived!
I knew he was all right, that rascal!
Right! Your voice must have reached him!
What is it, Big Guy?!
Our enemy has also noticed!
It must be a search team
sent by Zaboera to find Dai.
I'll take care of them!
Melt the iceberg and rescue Dai!
Will you be okay alone, Big Guy?
Don't you think it's a little soon
for you to worry about me, Popp?
All right then! I'll leave this to you!
That's far enough!
There you are, Zaboera.
Curse you, Crocodine!
Traitors have no business here!
You always hide in the shadows
and never get your hands dirty.
Yet here you are with your servants.
I'm guessing you've lost standing
within the Dark Army.
W-Why you...!
When you hide behind others,
leeching off their efforts
and never work to better yourself,
you're bound to end up
exactly where you are now!
Shut up! I'll take care of
both you and Dai!
Get him!
I guess the time apart
has made you forget...
the power of the Beast King!
Flying Flayers!
Looks like they've started.
Oh no! The light!
The light of the crest is fading!
P-Popp...
Dai!
I have to hurry! They need me out there!
HYADARUKO
ICE-TYPE SPELL
ULTRA COMBUSTION SLASH
Zaboera has discovered Dai
and headed out to the frozen sea.
The fool has gotten ahead of himself.
Hym, use force if necessary.
Bring Zaboera back.
My lord.
No one shall touch
Dai and his friends but me!
There! Found him!
I need to be careful from here.
What are you standing around for!
Leave this to me!
Huh?!
Rattus Rocket Ram!
Ow, ow, ow...
You idiot!
-Dai!
Dai! Dai, hang in there!
Popp...
I knew it was you.
Obviously. Who else
would come to rescue you?
And me! And me!
Don't forget about me, Dai!
Chiu, carry that sword!
We're getting out of here!
Huh? But what about my praise?
Tsk!
How can a sword so small weigh so much?
Zaboera?!
What?! How did he get there?!
Flying Flayers! Cast Merazoma on me!
W-What?!
This is my greatest trump card,
the convergence spell, Mahoplus!
It's a Super Spell that
lets me absorb others' spells,
add my own power
and fire the combined energy!
With the combined Merazoma spells
from me and my Flying Flayers,
I'll evaporate you and that iceberg!
Dai! Popp!
If I run with a Rura spell,
it'll hit Chiu behind me!
Can I cancel it out
with a spell of my own?!
Die!
What?! W-What happened?!
What is that?!
Who is this guy?
A man made of metal?!
Is it a new enemy?!
But why did it save them?!
Y-You!
Who are you?!
Why do you get in my way?!
Even Zaboera doesn't recognize him?!
I am Lord Hadorra's loyal soldier,
the pawn, Hym!
Hym?!
Did he say pawn?!
By Lord Hadorra's order I've come
to retrieve your disobedient hide.
He's strong!
You little brat! Take this!
Impossible! My spell didn't work?!
Come to think of it,
you already repelled my Mahoplus spell.
What are you?
Fool!
I am one of the ultimate guards created
from an Orichalcum piece by Lord Hadorra!
My entire body is made of Orichalcum!
I am invulnerable to
all attacks and spells!
Only Lord Hadorra with his Orichalcum blade
or the omnipotent Dark King can harm me.
What?!
You there!
Huh?!
Is that your sword?
The owner of that sword
might actually put up a good fight.
Then why not kill us here?!
Why bother protecting us?!
I'm not a piece of scum like him.
I'm a proud servant of Lord Hadorra!
I will face any opponent head-on!
Killing you in such a cheap way
would be boring!
I protect the Field of Death with
my four comrades by Lord Hadorra's order!
We shall cross paths eventually.
You'd better train
for when that day comes!
Don't disappoint Lord Hadorra!
Are you okay?
Y-Yeah.
I guess we were rescued by our enemy.
Big Guy, that guy said he was a pawn.
By pawn, did he mean...?
Yes. It's the name
of the weakest chess piece.
That was the weakest?
It's a scary thought, but it seems so.
Let's go back, guys.
We've got a lot to do
when we get back to Papunica.
You're right. Good point.
I completely forgot
you're wounded and half-frozen.
That's cold.
Let's go! Back to Papunica!
We can figure things out then.
Ow, ow, ow!
Do something about your landing!
Don't blame me! I'm overburdened!
Dai! Everyone!
Thank goodness you're all right!
I told you to leave it to me.
You should have seen me out there.
Dai!
Huh?
Oh! Dai! Dai!
Thank goodness!
How dare...?!
You don't have the power
to escape that cage.
You can cool your head there.
Wait! Wait!
Curse you Hadorra!
How dare you steal my glory!
It's time to see Hadorra's
newly assembled royal guard.
Giving him five whole Orichalcum warriors
was rather generous of you, King Ban.
Why shouldn't I?
Mere Gargoyles and Archdemons
wouldn't be strong enough
to be Hadorra's guard now.
At last.
Oh great Dark King Ban,
I present to you my new servants.
Five pieces born from
everlasting Orichalcum.
First is the pawn, Hym.
PAWN: HYM
The knight, Sigma.
KNIGHT: SIGMA
The bishop, Fenbren.
BISHOP: FENBREN
The rook, Block.
ROOK: BLOCK
And the queen, Albinass.
QUEEN: ALBINASS
This is the ultimate force
to protect the Field of Death...
the Hadorra Royal Guard!
Magnificent, Hadorra.
You are the king of that royal guard.
When the Disciples of Aban are defeated,
and the world is conquered,
I shall grant you the surface world.
When that time comes,
you may reclaim your title of Dark Lord.
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
There is little that I can do
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
The showdown
with Dark King Ban is decided.
The Disciples of Aban
begin their individual training.
To fight the Hadorra Royal Guard,
who are immune to magic,
Popp visits his mentor, Matorif.
In order to learn the ultimate spell
that even Matorif fears to use,
Popp begins a deadly training.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Extreme Annihilation Spell, Medroa"
The adventure continues!