boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
are itsukarada?
Since when was it?
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Being honest became whining
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Standing firm became strength
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
FAREWELL TO THE FATHER
Crocodine, do you have any strength left
to throw me up there?
What?
You trying to fight in the air
won't make any difference.
I know.
Then why?
The same as you.
What kind of man would watch
someone die like that and do nothing?
Okay!
Ready?!
Not yet! The timing is everything!
It's over!
Now!
You filthy trash!
Your pitiful attacks won't...
Dai! Use that!
It's not as strong as Baran's,
but it's still a Legendary Dark Blade!
So that was his plan from the start!
Curse you!
Hyunckel, are you all right?!
I'll heal you!
Dai, finish it in one shot.
Not even the Dark Armour Blade
can endure your power for long.
Yes! This'll work!
I could tell when our blades crossed!
That weapon isn't as strong
as my Demon Dragon Blade!
I'll shatter it in one blow...
with my ultimate attack, Gigabreak!
That's not a true Gigabreak!
The spell you just used was Raiden!
That's it!
You don't have enough Magic Power
to use Gigaden anymore!
If it's the same spell...
we'll win!
A Raiden spell!
With my power...
and Master's attack...
and Hyunckel's blade...
All his power is in the blade!
And...
the all of the memories
that Popp restored.
That's what I'll hit you with!
Silence!
Why aren't they using their attacks?
Because they both know
their next attack will be their last.
Whoever offers the slightest opening
will lose this fight.
Good luck, Dai.
For Popp, too.
It's no good.
He's not responding to my Zaoraru spell.
At this rate...
Please! Come back to us, Popp!
What happened to me?
Did I die?
Well, I used Megante, so obviously...
Megante?!
Where's Baran?!
He's not here.
So if this is the afterlife, he went
to a different afterlife or something?
Popp!
Huh? Who's there?
It's me!
You're... Gome?!
Popp!
Well, what do you know.
Gome's talking. I guess
anything's possible in the afterlife.
Wait, does that mean you're dead, too?
Popp, don't go that way!
You'll enter the Land of the Dead
and you won't be able to come back!
Huh?
Even if you say that,
my feet keep moving and won't stop.
Get a grip, Popp! You can't die here!
We've come all this way together!
If you die, I...
I...
Sorry, Gome. But it's over for me.
It's a miracle I lived this long.
My strength could only take me so far.
Popp...
Stupid Popp! You weakling!
What?!
He fell for it!
I hate you, Popp!
You haven't even avenged Master Aban
and you're giving up!
You're a weakling, Popp!
Why you little...! I'm not letting
a crybaby like you call me a weakling!
I tried as hard as I could!
You liar!
You're still a child!
You don't have my battle experience!
Dai's still...
fighting alone out there!
And yet...
you're abandoning him!
You're pathetic! You're just a weakling!
Watch your mouth, Stupid Gome.
Huh?
I...
I may be dead, but I'll...
I'll...
This is the end!
Fall to my Gigabreak!
I'll...!
I'll never abandon Dai!
Impossible! A corpse cast a spell?!
Now!
Aban Strash!
A-A draw?!
ABAN STRASH
GIGABREAK
Dai!
He's alive!
Oh!
Dai!
Thanks.
Are you all right?
Yeah. It's thanks to you guys.
The Dark Armour Blade!
Even an immortal Dark Blade
cannot be restored with its blade gone.
The Dark Blade is dead.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry. Your life is more valuable.
Thanks.
That's right! Popp!
Yes! Popp is all right as well!
No...
Leona?
Popp... can't be resurrected.
That's impossible! He just...
That's right! He cast a spell!
I don't understand why that happened.
But, my Zaoraru spell didn't work!
I'm sorry! I wasn't strong enough!
No...
Say it isn't true, Popp.
Please!
Open your eyes! Popp!
Popp!
Baran?!
Don't bother bluffing.
I know you don't have
a bit of strength left.
Like myself.
His heart has definitely stopped.
And yet, how...?
Did his feelings for his friend
cause this dead boy's body to move?
Is such a miracle possible?
How ironic.
The power of Dragons,
magic of Darklings, and heart of humans.
Of the three gifts
granted to a Dragon Knight,
for the human heart
I cast aside as useless...
to deal such crushing blows to me.
What are you doing?
Dino, I have nothing to say.
Take the path that you believe is right.
However, this world has no use
for two Dragon Knights!
Once my blade is restored
and my wounds healed...
we shall settle this!
You're returning to the Dark Army?
I no longer care about the Dark Army.
If you defeat me,
you can go on to destroy
the Dark Army for the humans.
But if I win...
I will wipe out the humans!
You're still saying that?!
It's too late to change my ways.
This is just how it is for adults.
You stubborn idiot!
Say what you will.
Popp is...!
He's alive again! He has a pulse!
Popp?!
The boy is tougher than he looks.
Did you...?!
This is the first and last time
I offer a gift to an enemy.
Next time we meet, I won't hold back.
Dino!
No...
Dai!
You've been warned!
Baran has regained his human heart.
That's why, to atone for his sins,
he wants his own son to take him down.
He truly is tragically powerful
and ever alone.
It's the worst possible outcome!
Baran survived
and Dai's powers have begun to awaken!
At this rate, I'll...
I'll...
Dark Commander Hadorra.
His Majesty, Dark King Ban summons you.
Hadorra, raise your head.
What's wrong? Raise your head.
I-I beg for forgiveness, King Ban!
Baran's failure
is my responsibility as his superior!
When he returns, I shall make sure to...
Fool!
Baran will likely never return.
Considering his personality,
I doubt he'll do anything
unless it involves Dai.
Baran's failure
is your crime for hiding that Dai was
a Dragon Knight even from me!
This is the result
of your petty little games!
Baran is the only being in the world
who has the power to resist me.
Convincing him to become an ally
was not an easy task.
I'll say it once more, raise your head.
I am a tolerant man.
I will forgive up to three failures.
However...
you've cost us Romos Kingdom
and Papunica kingdom,
allowing two of our Legion Commanders
to join the other side.
And on Valge Island...
despite leading an army,
you failed to kill Dai.
And now, this incident with Baran...
However...
I did not forget
that you slew Aban, the Hero.
Hadorra, this is your last chance.
When you next appear before me,
if Dai and his friends
have not been wiped out,
my third finger shall drop.
Am I understood?
Y-Yes, my king!
I, Hadorra, shall stake my life on it!
Very well. Go.
My king!
Shouldn't we just kill him?
I have given him the ultimate body.
If he cannot win,
then the weakness is in his mind.
Driven to desperation,
he may actually prove his worth.
We can kill him anytime.
Amazing, King Ban.
You've thought of everything.
King Ban, hooray! Hooray!
Let us sit back and enjoy...
the final charge of the Hadorra Legion.
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
It may just be a rationalization
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
Even now, even now I waver
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
How far will we go?
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
Exposed to love and sorrow
hokori mamire michi no tochu
On the path strewn with pride
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
Fleeting moments of cowardice
nomikonda SOS
The SOS I held back
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
I clenched my trembling fist
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
That single little promise
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
Those trivial little memories
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
They're still in my heart
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
As embers that keep me burning
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
After the battle with Baran,
Dai and friends stop by Meruru's house,
but the Dark Army offers no rest.
The next assassin is the desperate Hadorra,
with one last chance from Dark King Ban,
and Zaboera, the Mystic Bishop.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Zaboera's Scheme"
The adventure continues!