Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE DEATH-DEFYING SAVIOR
Dammit!
Why?! Why the hell?!
I'm the one who lured the Hero here!
So why am I left guarding the hostage?!
How'd you like to be shattered?!
Huh, little Princess?!
I guess I don't need to kill you now.
You've only got until sundown anyway.
Looks like there are guards.
Let's get rid of them!
Hey! So suddenly?!
Oh no! It's the Hero!
Aban Style Sword Technique, Wave Slash!
Run!
Baduck, hurry!
Right!
Okay, time for this!
If we can destroy this Spire
and Popp destroys the Dark Ice Spire,
Flazzard's Curse Field should disappear.
I'm going to save you, Leona!
Here we go!
Look out!
The Spire's... still standing!
Who did that?! Who interrupted us?!
Whoa! What are these guys?!
We're surrounded!
These monsters are different!
Was this a trap?!
Who are you?!
I'm Zaboera, Legion Commander of
the Mystic Legion of the Dark Army.
And this is Mystban,
Legion Commander of the Shadow Legion.
The Mystic Legion?!
The Shadow Legion?!
We knew you would split up
to come destroy the Spires.
It was the perfect opportunity
to wipe out you pesky gnats.
Then Popp and Maam...?!
Looks like we've fallen into a trap.
Do you think Dai and Baduck...?
We don't have time to worry about them!
We have to defeat...
So Dai is at the Dark Flame Spire.
How disappointing.
It can't be...!
So be it. The Disciples of Aban
will die out today either way.
I suppose I'll just enjoy
crushing you worms.
Popp?
This... This voice...
is one I'll never forget!
Hadorra, the Dark Commander!
Not even a Hero can handle
this many enemies at once.
Learn to fear the Dark Army and die!
Very well! It's time for me to show off
the Papunica Single-Blade Style once again!
Baduck, try to fight just the Mages!
Watch out for their magic
and they're pretty weak!
G-Got it!
He's... He's the one
who killed Master Aban?!
Yeah. But I didn't expect
the Dark Commander himself to show up!
I thought I'd crush
all of you annoying creatures at once.
Sh-Shut up! Don't assume everything's
going to go as planned, Hadorra!
You're that little Mage
who was there when I killed Aban.
That's right!
I'm a student of Master Aban!
W-What's so funny?!
How hilarious! No, how very pathetic!
The scrawny little student
desperately fought all this way
to avenge his master...
only to end up dying a pitiful death!
S-Screw you! I may die,
but I won't go down without a fight!
I'll make you feel even a fraction of
the pain we felt when we lost our master.
That's right! We'll never forgive you
for killing our kind Master Aban!
Who are you?
I'm a student of Master Aban, too!
A Disciple of Aban!
You seem to have the wrong idea, girl.
I'm not the one who took Aban's life.
That primitive, ape-like emotion
called "kindness" was his undoing!
Why you...!
Maam, don't!
Run Maam!
He's formidable at hand-to-hand, too!
Maam!
Die.
There's just too many of them!
In that case...!
Aban...
Dai!
H-He floats like a ghost,
but he's so strong!
Who is he?!
Th-This is...
Tomakugutsosho?!
B-But this was Hyunckel's skill!
You fool. Hyunckel may have learned
his sword skills from Aban,
but he learned how to control
Dark Aura from Mystban.
For controlling skeletons.
In other words, Mystban
is the originator of that skill!
I-I can't move!
Dai!
Whoops! You aren't
going anywhere, you old goat!
Shut up! I won't let
an old gremlin call me an old goat!
Having an old fossil like you
running around is even more annoying!
Let my words of death
lead you to an eternal slumber!
Zaraki!
W-What is this creepy voice?!
These are words of death
calling to you from the netherworld.
When you succumb to them, your life ends!
Now die, die, die!
HYADARUKO
ICE-TYPE SPELL
TOMAKUGUTSOSHO
Popp...
Dammit. Hadorra's spell
is even stronger than last time!
How?!
Isn't it obvious?
As a reward for killing Aban,
Dark King Ban granted me a new body,
allowing me to power up!
In combat, spells, and everything!
In other words, I'm even stronger now
than when I killed Aban!
No...
So, now you see that
you have no hope for survival.
I'm sure Dai has already been pummeled
by the Mystic and Shadow Legions,
and is dead by now.
It's no good.
We can't... We can't beat him!
Maybe if it was just Flazzard. But with
Hadorra and the other Legions here...
It's all over.
You insects! For the crime of
standing up against our great Dark Army,
death is not enough!
Begirama?!
Taste pain worse than death
from my inferno!
Maam!
That's right... I can't give up!
If I give up,
who's going to protect Maam?!
Burn to ashes together!
I have to protect Maam.
I have to go help Dai!
Begirama!
I can't give up! Not until the very end!
What?!
I cast Begirama!
I-Impossible!
Impossible! That brat's spell
overpowered my own?!
Lord Hadorra, are you alright?!
Shut up!
Now's my chance! They're disorganized!
What can I use?! Anything?!
Curse you, boy!
We'll take him!
All of you back off!
Begirama!
I did it! Maam, did you see that?!
It was amazing.
I can't believe you cast Begirama.
Me too. I wasn't even thinking.
It's all thanks to my mentor!
It was just one day of training,
but my attack spells increased in power!
Thank you, Mentor!
The Dark Ice Spire can come later.
Let's go help Dai and Baduck.
Yeah.
What a surprise.
How that snotty little brat has grown.
But now observe and know
that there's always a bigger fish!
No way! That's...!
Oh? You recognize this spell?
You've done your Mage homework.
Run, Maam!
Begiragon!
W-What's that?!
That is the sound of Lord Hadorra
using his most powerful spell, Begiragon.
Hadorra's here?!
The Dark Ice Spire is guarded by
Lord Hadorra himself and his minions.
Hadorra is fighting Popp and Maam?!
Darn it!
Futile! Pure futility!
No one can break free from
Mystban's Tomakugutsosho!
Now let's see which of you dies first.
Yes!
Baduck!
Gomechan!
C-Curse you and your useless resistance!
This time, we'll end it all at once!
Gomechan, Baduck...
I'm not sure if I have the strength
to defend both of you.
I'm sorry.
Fear not! If we die, we die together!
All of you! Attack!
Wh-Who was that?!
Who dares to do such a thing?!
I do!
I-Impossible!
Beast King Crocodine!
Y-You! First you disappear
without a trace,
then you show up and drop a boulder
on us?! What's the meaning of this?!
I'm helping the Disciples of Aban.
W-What?!
I couldn't just sit back
and let you ambush them.
Have you lost your mind?!
All of you!
Take care of that traitor first!
Take care of me? You're joking!
As if you small fry
could defeat the Beast King!
What the heck is this giant monster?!
Crocodine!
Dai!
You were alive!
As you can see! I'm here to help you!
That's right! Popp and Maam are in danger!
Hadorra is...
Fear not. A powerful ally
is headed for the Dark Ice Spire.
And he's even more powerful than I am!
Huh?!
L-Lord Hadorra, you're safe...
Indeed.
They still remain.
Well, I had to hold back to spare
the Dark Ice Spire after all.
She's still breathing. I should
strangle her to death just in case.
Wa...
Wait...
You survived, too?
Don't worry. You'll soon
see each other in the afterlife.
Please...
I don't... I don't care
what happens to me.
Just...
Just, please, let her go.
Is this the "kindness" you speak of?
Please... Not Maam...
I see. You're in love with this girl.
This is great!
Please...
Knowing that,
I can't possibly let her live now.
You little maggot, you scarred my body.
Now watch
as the girl you love dies horribly.
This is the most fitting
punishment for you.
Don't...
I'll impale her body
on the top of the Dark Ice Spire.
Don't!
Please don't!
Maam!
The Dark Ice Spire fell?!
You're...!
The Dark Ice Spire...
Well done, Hyunckel.
So it really is Hyunckel!
Now, Dai, I'll shatter
the Dark Flame Spire!
You go on ahead to Valge Tower!
Right!
Go kick Flazzard's butt!
Hyunckel... you're alive?!
You...
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
anata wa nannte iukana
I wonder what you'd say
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
Unlike the today that I sought
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
The one who saved Maam
was Hyunckel, the Undead Legion Commander
who vanished at the Underground Palace.
Hadorra's anger explodes
at Hyunckel's betrayal of the Dark Army.
Hyunckel seeks to avenge the death
of his father, Bartos.
Their incredible showdown begins at last.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Hyunckel Versus Hadorra"
The adventure continues!