With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE EYE JEWEL
Now you shall slowly feel my wrath.
I think I've come up
with an entertaining idea.
Princess Leona.
You must serve beside me.
W-What?!
After the Surface World is demolished,
I shall keep you alive.
You can watch this Dragon Knight,
the hope of the Surface World,
be viciously torn apart.
Then spend the rest of your life
serving me.
You shall be an Underworld songstress,
singing of my power and terror.
That will be much more entertaining
than just simply slaughtering you.
I can enjoy that for a long time.
What do you think?
I... I'll never do that!
Don't be stupid! If Dai should fall,
then I won't live long either!
I'll fight until the very end
together with Dai!
Leona...
How very brave.
For one so young
to possess such a strong will.
I've never encountered this before.
I like you even more now.
But look at your precious Dai.
He's on the verge of death.
There is no if. He will die.
If I'm going to kill him, I want him
completely and utterly destroyed!
I want him to see my greatness
and the limits of his own strength.
And to see the true nature
of the humans he so loves.
He should know true despair
before he dies.
Now, Princess, take a good look.
Watch your Hero get pummeled to death!
Dai!
What's wrong, Dai?! Can't you get up?
Are you just going to roll around
like a worm?
Perhaps my Calamity End
was too powerful?
It's no good! I can't move properly!
Get up! Fight back!
No. I must watch.
I shouldn't avert my eyes
from Dai's suffering.
I'm fighting, too!
I have to do something! Anything!
Anything against the Dark King!
Just doing that
will lessen Dai's suffering!
And now for this.
Kaiser Phoenix!
W-Well?
How does it feel to be wounded
by a little girl, Dark King?
Did you see that, Dai?!
Ban's body couldn't be cut
by even a Gigastrash,
but unless he's fully focused,
he can't maintain his invulnerability!
Even I could wound him!
Nothing in this world is invulnerable!
Nothing can be!
Don't forget that!
Leona...
If you still want to keep me alive
then go right ahead!
But I'll tell everyone
for the rest of my life
that I wounded the great Dark King Ban!
That I'm the strongest woman in the world!
No! Get up! Stand up!
If I don't stand...
then Leona will...
Leona!
You will regret that.
You can no longer resist or speak.
Leona!
Huh?!
Leona became a jewel?!
How do you feel, Princess Leona?
Huh?
Leona!
Where am I?! What happened to me?!
You decided to wound me,
so I won't kill you.
I won't be satisfied
unless you suffer a fate worse than death.
I've used my Magic Power
to turn you into a jewel called an Eye.
There are only three things
you can do now.
See, hear, and think.
You cannot move,
and your voice cannot be heard.
No matter what scenes of atrocity
may unfold before you...
you cannot look away.
Congratulations, Dai.
While heavily wounded,
you may still be worthy of fighting me.
Dai! Dai!
Leona, hang in there!
Now watch from there, Princess...
as the Hero is beaten beyond all hope.
You cannot fight with him,
nor can you take your own life.
As a leader of the Surface World,
there can be no greater humiliation.
I will change you back once you decide
to pledge eternal servitude to me.
Turn her back now!
You'll have to stop my Magic Power.
Defeat me and she'll be restored.
But that seems unlikely in your condition.
I have to defeat Ban!
If I don't defeat him here, then Leona...
But his Tenchimato is perfect.
It has no weakness!
Hm?
That's it! If there's no weakness, then...
That look... He's thought of something.
But I can't do it alone!
Well? What's wrong? Didn't you think of
some way to fight back?
It doesn't matter either way.
You will still be torn apart.
Calamity End?!
Don't be so surprised.
Tenchimato
isn't necessary for a Kaiser Phoenix
or Calamity Wall attack.
The divine power of my palm strike
can also be unleashed at any time.
Why use my ultimate skill against
one who has lost the will to fight?
I'll cut you to shreds!
Oh Dai. This isn't good.
You can barely even stand.
To be powerless at a time like this...
To be forced to just watch...
That's it, Princess! I feel your torment!
To feel it for just a minute,
for just a second longer is more fun!
You should know that my last attack
was just a simple palm strike.
Calamity End is my greatest strike.
I put all of my might into it.
Like this.
Dai!
Can you withstand a second one?!
Calamity End!
MINAKATOR
THE DEMONIC GUARD OF HEAVEN AND EARTH
Calamity End!
Sorry about that, Mister Dark King.
You...
You'll have to beat all of us.
It's not over until you do!
Popp! Everyone!
You little scrubs.
Begone!
Watch out, everyone! That eye is...!
It looks like most of you were
barely healthy enough to make it here.
Those worthy enough to fight me are...
Dai, Popp, Aban, Hym, Larhart...
Just you five.
What's going on here?!
When hit by the light
of Ban's third eye,
anyone too weak to fight
is turned into a jewel.
He got Leona, too.
Then everyone's in these things?!
What terrifying Magic Power.
To come all this way and be useless...
Dammit!
Let me out!
That's right. Hyunckel was already
in critical condition.
Maam and Brokin were still wounded
from the fight with Myst.
Sadly, I guess Big Guy and Chiu
weren't strong enough.
There's a big difference
between Big Guy and Chiu.
But I guess compared to Ban
it's all the same.
Are they still alive in there?
Yeah. But they can't do anything.
Great. That's actually better.
What?! Don't you care
that he got your friends?!
I thought you were better than that!
They can be turned back, right?
Ban said defeating him
would restore them.
He's the Dark King.
We won't be able to cover for our wounded.
Popp...
From the looks of it,
those jewels won't break so easily.
Maam and the Princess are actually safe.
We don't have to worry about
getting thrown off by them getting killed.
It's a little heartless,
but defeating him will be easier this way!
Oh?
You're always so noisy,
so I thought you'd be more sympathetic,
but you can be pretty level-headed.
It depends on the situation!
Anyway, if we lose,
the Surface World is over!
And our friends won't be turning back!
Matorif?
If it means defeating him,
and saving our friends,
I'll do anything it takes!
I see.
He's been instructing Popp
while I was gone.
It's just like back then.
It feels like Matorif
is right here beside me.
Before you know it,
they've all grown up so much.
Cool. Be cool!
Now's the time to fight like Mentor!
Now that we know he can reflect Medoroa,
I've only got one thing left.
It's this sharp mind that's got me
and my friends through numerous perils!
I suppose
the bigger the audience the better.
You have to see the fall of the Hero Dai,
hope of the Surface World.
But you should all be proud.
You are witnesses to history.
Cry, heavens!
Howl, earth!
Here and now...
the age of darkness has come!
Now... witness this!
That's...!
Heal Master Dai!
Right!
We'll use that time...
...to hold him off!
No! Don't charge into his Tenchimato!
That's the Dark King's ultimate skill!
Not even the three of you could...!
Don't!
What are you doing, Popp?!
We have to stop them!
Just sit still!
Aban Strash!
Hakendisutoru!
Aura Knuckle!
Tenchimato!
That's all the three of you
together can do?!
At least Dai's Gigastrash
managed to wound me!
I saw it! He repelled the Hakendisutoru
with the force of his palm...
took down the Aban Strash
with Kaiser Phoenix...
and shattered the Aura Knuckle
with a palm strike!
Attack, defense, and magic
all in one motion!
So that's Ban's ultimate skill!
Why?! Why did you abandon them all, Popp?!
Ban's stance is unbeatable!
I know that, which is why...
Thank goodness! They're alive!
We have to stop them from--
Why doesn't he finish them?
They're all in shambles!
He could wipe them all out
with a single extreme spell!
Is he playing with them?
No, that's not it.
He isn't giving any openings.
Could it be...?
So, what now?
Will you give up and beg for your lives?
Or will you once again
face my ultimate skill of death?
Given that choice,
there is but one answer!
We'll take our chances!
A welcome answer.
But it looks like one of you
won't be able to.
Master Aban!
Master!
I'm pleased that
you fell so quickly, Aban.
Fighting power aside,
your brain can't be underestimated.
You're unpredictable.
And the smartest man on the Surface World.
Unfortunately for you,
there's still someone smarter than me.
M-Master!
I'm sorry! I... I...!
I understand why you held Dai back
despite knowing what would happen.
Only the Hero's strike
can defeat the Dark King.
You were following the advice
that I gave to Princess Leona.
Just as Dai, the Hero is the only one
who can defeat the Dark King,
the only one who can unlock
Dai's full potential...
is the one who has been with him
since the very beginning of this fight.
Popp... That's you.
Work together... and achieve victory!
Master!
Master Aban!
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
We've been seeking something certain
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Even Aban was turned into an Eye Jewel.
Dai and his friends
are helplessly battered.
And his allies trapped in Eye Jewels
can do nothing but cry out.
Things are dire, and to overcome
the Dark King's greatest skill,
the Demonic Guard of Heaven and Earth,
Popp readies a desperate plan.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"On This Bond"
The adventure continues!