nakama tono kizuna wo
With your bonds with your friends
sono mune ni idaite
Embraced in your heart
hikari no you ni isshun ni
Like a flash, in an instant
subete wo kaketeku
You risk it all
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
tachimukatte ikunnda to
You will face it again
kakugo wo kimetanara
If that's what you choose
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even when hurt
Oh tsumazuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
susume kono tabi no hate
Continue on
To your journey's end
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Again and again
To the future you make
Oh Oh
tachiagareru
You're The Bravest
You can stand up
Oh Oh
tachiagareru
You're The Bravest
You can stand up
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
motto Make you strong
You're The Bravest
Make you more strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
motto Make you strong
You're The Bravest
Make you more strong
VICTORY OR ANNIHILATION
Begirama!
May I ask you something?
Go ahead.
Are you really a human?
Only a Darkling could be this resilient.
Don't flatter me. I'm just a human.
A cowardly, small, ordinary human.
Those who speak like that
are often dangerous.
I will not hold back!
Popp...
Popp, was it?
You are far more dangerous
than you let on.
I felt it from the first time we fought.
For example, you keep using magic
even though I keep reflecting it.
I would assume you have some sort of plan.
Am I wrong?
And you're the most difficult enemy
I've ever faced.
Everyone I've ever fought
assumed I was just a scrub.
That always let me catch them off guard.
You're using spells to find
an opening in my defenses aren't you?
You only have one spell
that can defeat me after all.
Try and use it. That Medoroa spell.
Don't be stupid. If you reflect
my Medoroa then it'll really be over.
I'm not giving you
what you want so easily!
A IO spell. Futile!
I'll just reflect it!
Counter and cancel it out!
IO!
Now! Extend, Black Rod!
Oh no you don't!
Rod, into fork spear!
I did it! I got the mirror off
and immobilized them!
It's over!
Why are you so calm?! Struggle more!
This is the end for you!
You completely exceeded my expectations.
To hide such a powerful ace
up your sleeve all this time...
How very brave.
What a shame.
You could have won if it wasn't
my right arm you pinned.
Too late!
Lightning Buster!
You weren't the only one
with an ace up your sleeve.
The Lightning Buster from my right arm
is as powerful as a Ionazun spell.
Like Hym's Heat Knuckle, it requires
physical contact to work, though.
I heard bone shatter.
You're beyond help now.
Forgive me for heading to the next battle
without offering proper rites.
My worthy adversary.
Impossible! How are you still alive?!
That's... a Behoma spell?!
You've been so resilient because you've
been healing yourself this whole time?!
Are you...
a Sage?!
No I'm not. I ain't no Sage.
I ain't no Sage.
Why not, Mentor?
You can use attack and healing
and all sorts of types of spells.
How does that not make you a Sage?
I don't like the title.
It sounds so pompous and doesn't fit me.
Besides, it lacks impact.
That's why I came up with an awesome title
that would make everybody fear me.
The title of the single most
powerful spell-caster in the world!
That's...
Daimadoshi.
What?!
That's right.
If you're going to call me anything,
call me the Daimadoshi.
Popp, the Daimadoshi...
Honestly, that doesn't seem
far off the mark.
When did you attain such a spell?
I just did.
What?
My mentor already made me bind
with almost every spell there is.
I just suddenly was able to use it.
Gaining power at the moment
you most hate yourself is pretty ironic.
I've never...
I've never been
more ashamed of myself before.
Your soul is what awakened that power.
The soul can enhance the body
beyond its limits. That's what I believe.
This soul that Lord Hadorra gave me
is my greatest pride.
But...
unfortunately, that doesn't
give you any advantage.
Healing will only lengthen our battle.
All the better for me, since I'm trying to
buy time for Lord Hadorra and Dai's duel.
Don't be... so sure!
Medoroa?!
Don't you realize
I won't just let you hit me with that?
Either way, it's the only spell
that'll work on you.
It all comes down to this Medoroa spell!
It's all or nothing...
Sigma!
You're an opponent worth respecting.
That's why I'll match that sense of duty!
I'm going back to Dai as soon as possible!
And for that...
I'll defeat you!
I could try to buy time...
but you've gained my interest!
Bring it on, Grand Sorcerer!
Give it up! That sort of movement speed
will never catch me off guard!
IO!
Got you!
It seems the goddess of victory
does not smile for you this time!
Of course not!
My goddess doesn't smile for me!
She slaps me across the face!
Too slow!
No you're too slow!
Your own weapon will send you
to the afterlife!
Allow me to offer the same line!
Your Medoroa will send you
to the afterlife!
Popp!
You're too late.
He is about to be annihilated.
Impossible!
He hasn't been annihilated?!
It looks like I win the game of deception!
Medoroa!
MEDOROA
LIGHTNING BUSTER
So that first spell... wasn't Medoroa.
Yeah. I adjusted my Magic Power
and disguised a Begirama spell.
I intentionally let myself get hit...
to catch you off guard.
Well done.
It was a satisfying fight.
Lord Hadorra will not blame me.
I shall not forget your name,
Daimadoshi Popp.
Me neither, Knight Sigma.
Give my regards to
your goddess who slaps you.
I saw a brilliant flash from Ban Palace.
Yeah. That light is from Popp's Medoroa!
The Disciples of Aban are fighting well!
So that's his Medoroa!
I guess we can't let them down!
Exactly!
Howl, Inferno!
Why'd you come to help?
Did you really have no faith in me?
That's not it.
Maam.
There's something I need to tell you.
I...
I love you.
I finally, finally got to say it
to your face!
That last confession was just the worst.
It really was the worst.
Popp...
I know you're wondering why
I'm choosing to say this here and now.
I wanted to say it properly
before the final battle.
I'm sure you were uncomfortable
with how things stood.
That's all.
Sorry. Let's get going.
Wait.
I said wait, Popp!
Don't you...
Don't you want to hear my answer?
You can't just say your piece
and end things there!
That's not fair!
You never do beat around the bush, do you?
Why did I have to fall in love with you?
Yeah, it's not fair.
I guess I've always been a coward.
Even now I'm terrified.
I'm scared you're not interested in me
or that you really love Hyunckel.
I'm shaking.
Popp...
Even back with the Minakator spell.
I wasn't scared of
getting wounded or even dying.
But to be left out of the group...
That scared me.
If I didn't have Dai or you with me,
I'd still be worthless.
When my Insignia didn't glow, I should've
just come out and asked for help.
But I was scared.
I couldn't speak up.
What if someone told me
I'm not worthy to be among you?
That fear kept me silent.
I bet it was Master Aban
who kept it from glowing.
He was saying "I won't have any student
of mine chickening out like that."
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Maam. You're right.
I should accept whatever's coming to me
or I'll never be able to face Meruru.
Besides, I guess I'm
the Disciple of Courage.
You're always like this.
Whenever I go astray, you wake me up
and put me back on the right path.
That's why...
That's why?
It's that quality of yours that...
I...
I'm in love with.
Tell me.
How do you feel about me?
How I... feel about you.
I love you. Very much.
Really?
But I thought
you were in love with Hyunckel.
Of course I love Hyunckel.
He's strong, but so alone,
and I'm always worried about him.
But the same goes for you, Popp.
I'm always afraid to let you out of
my sight. You're like a little brother.
I worry about you.
A little brother...
When I learned you're in love with me
I was conflicted at first.
But I'm grateful now.
But I'm not ready to give you an answer.
I realized something in this battle.
I never actually knew what real love is.
Miss Amy and Meruru and Albinass were all
willing to die for the people they loved.
To truly love someone
is a fierce and powerful thing.
I don't know if I'm capable of that.
I never considered how to see others
or how others saw me.
It's possible...
that you've been hurt and suffered
numerous times because of me.
Maam...
I'm sorry.
I can't give an answer to you right now.
I don't think I have that right.
But, Popp...
if you'll allow it,
will you give me a chance?
A chance?
I don't know if we'll survive this battle.
But, if we do manage to...
I'm sure that then I'll be able
to look at you as a man.
The reason I'm able to love you
is because I've seen you grow so much
through your battles.
So lend me your strength!
And let's fight for the future!
The future...
I don't know if I'll be able to love you
as a man when it's over.
I may love Hyunckel instead.
But I know I'll be able to become
someone I wasn't before.
So, for the future, let's work together
and overcome this battle...
together!
This is the best I can offer right now.
Is it... enough?
Maam!
Thank you. That answer
was far more than I deserve.
I'm... I'm so glad...
I fell in love with you.
Popp?
So, if the Dark King ends up killing us,
then that's that, right?
I guess so.
Then... can I have an advance?
Huh? What?!
Close your eyes.
You're kidding...
Popp!
Just kidding! Fooled you!
Even I'm not brave enough to do that!
But you really closed your eyes.
Could it be you might actually
have feelings for me?
You...
idiot!
Maam.
What?!
Let's win this. I want to see that future.
Even if it's the one
where I get shot down.
Idiot!
Yow!
What is this?!
Popp, Maam! You're both okay!
It looks like your fight
with Sigma was a tough one.
Y-Yeah...
Half of this is from Maam, though.
Why are you just standing here?
Where are Dai and Hadorra?
Look at that!
Look at what? I can't see them anywhere.
There's just a huge swirl of sheer heat.
So where's Dai?!
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
To be honest I was clumsy
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
And it took me forever to get here
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I used even loneliness as a weapon
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
I just want to be there for you
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
To call out your name
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Is harder than any magic spell
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
Even though you're so close to me
aishiteiru
I love you
imasara kizuitanosa
I finally realized it
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
To call out your name
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
Must be the reason I was born
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
I shake off the clinging night
ai ni iku
And go to see you
ima sugu kimi no moto e
Right now to where you are
Popp and Maam arrive to help Dai.
Dai and Hadorra's clash
rivals one from legends of the Underworld.
It is one that none may interrupt.
Dai's Aban Strash
or Hadorra's Ultra Combustion Slash...
The duel between the two
nears its conclusion.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Battle of True Dragons"
The adventure continues!