Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
MAAM'S DECISION
Hold still. Just a little longer.
Yes.
It's no good.
Even for you?
Whoever made this is a genius.
It's completely beyond me.
I see.
Everybody come check it out!
What's going on?!
Lady Marin of the Troika...!
Is that Behoma?
That's right. The greatest Hoimi! Spell
that the Princess can cast.
It can cure severe injuries.
There. You're all better.
Thank you so much for doing this.
It's nothing. A friend in need and all.
Princess.
I'm so glad, Marin.
Sister!
Leona's so amazing.
Obviously.
She's a Sage in training after all.
She can even use attack spells,
though not as strong as the Troika.
She's truly an all-around spell caster!
What's wrong, Maam?
I'm going to talk with Uncle Matorif.
Maybe he can fix my Magic Bullet Gun.
Hey! Maam?!
Looks like your Magic Power's increased.
Don't let that surprise you!
Gira!
Popp! Hang in there!
Hyado!
Iora!
Oh no!
The Flight Spell, Toberura.
When did you learn that?
It's easy if you know Rura!
Toberura!
Don't get cocky.
I may be old, but in a one-minute
one-on-one fight
there isn't a being alive
who can beat me at magic.
Nasty old geezer!
Hey, Matorif, can't you teach me
some amazing spells, too?
I'm having you do basic meditation.
But you're teaching Popp
and he's improving so much!
Fool. You don't need to know
the same spells as Popp.
Huh?!
How come?!
A Hero can do anything.
But a Warrior is stronger,
and a Mage can do more magic.
A Hero is a jack-of-all-trades
and master of none.
But a Hero does possess an ultimate weapon
that no one else has.
Huh?! What's that?
Isn't it obvious?
A Hero's weapon is courage.
Courage?
All you need is the courage
to face any enemy. That's all.
If you want magic,
this one will improve on his own.
That makes a party.
That's what companions are for.
Aw.
Courage, huh?
I suppose that's something I don't have.
A weapon of my own.
That's it. Without that...
I didn't do anything yet!
Your mere presence oozes salaciousness!
Then I'll just hide my presence.
Why you...!
Honestly, the one thing you take after
your father, Roka, is your strength.
Strength? My father's strength...
Papunica Kingdom is gradually rebuilding.
Hearing Dai beat the Dark Army,
the citizens are returning.
The temple repairs will soon be complete.
After that, we can start on the palace.
I see. Things seem to be going well.
Which leaves us.
The Dark Army's fortress is here
in the mountains of Guildmain.
According to Maam, Crocodine and Hyunckel
went on a reconnaissance mission.
What should we do?
Currently, we lack weapons and manpower.
Rather than attack,
we should focus on building our strength.
Okay. Then let's all
go look for new weapons.
That sounds good. Right, Maam?
What's wrong, Maam?
Listen, everyone. I've been thinking...
I think I should go
my own way for a while.
What?! How come?! Why so suddenly?!
With my Magic Bullet Gun broken,
I can't use spells to attack.
Plus Leona is far better at Hoimi Spells.
At this rate, I'm going to end up
being a burden.
That's not true!
Don't be so sure.
Leona?
We'll likely be facing
far more powerful enemies from now on.
Without greater power,
you really may end up being a burden.
Leona, that's a little harsh.
You never hold back, Leona.
I really like that about you.
That's why I thought
I should return to Romos to train.
To find something only I can do.
What's something only you can do?
Martial arts.
Martial arts?!
Right. I figured I'd become
a Martial Artist!
A Martial Artist?!
Hyunckel and Crocodine have betrayed us,
and Flazzard is dead.
With the Six Legion Commanders
now three, our forces are halved.
What's that?
This melody is the Reaper Flute!
See, I told you!
Hadorra's army is falling apart!
Good boy, Piroro.
You were wise to inform me.
Good evening!
Greetings, inhabitants of Sovereign
Rock Castle. Let me introduce myself.
KILBAN
My name is Kilban.
I'm Piroro!
Th-This is Kilban?!
Surely you've heard of him!
The personal assassin of Dark King Ban!
The deadly reaper of the Dark Army
that silently erases
those who cross King Ban!
And why is the reaper here
in Sovereign Rock Castle?!
Has someone's incompetence
warranted a visit?
This is surprising, Mist.
I haven't heard you speak in decades.
Surprise, surprise!
I've seen you remain silent for centuries
when there's nothing to say.
You're the one who talks to much, Kill.
Perhaps.
Do these two know each other?!
And now, Hadorra, I hear your performance
has been slipping as of late.
That's right!
He's been botching things up!
Ever since he failed to kill Dai the Hero,
Legion Commanders have fallen,
Romos and Papunica were reclaimed.
It's a whole mess!
And recently, he took the whole army
and was still beaten by Dai!
Silence!
Is it true you let
Dai and his friends beat you?
The plan to kill him
is still ongoing! In time...
Then you'd better hurry up.
King Ban is a patient man,
but even he has his limits.
If you should fail again...
If I fail, then what?!
Do I have to say it? This. Get it?
Then have no fear!
I'll wipe out those brats in no time!
By my own hand!
Not so fast!
The next to fight Dai is me,
Dragon Master General Baran!
BEHOMA
HEAL-TYPE SPELL
MAGIC BULLET GUN
Baran?!
It's too soon!
Has he already destroyed Carl Kingdom?!
It's our savior Baran! How cool!
Oh. You've been saving
Dragon Master General Baran.
Then I guess there's no issue.
Wait, Baran! In order to regain
the Dark King's trust, I should...
Dark Commander,
I grow tired of your excuses.
I know why you seek
to keep me away from Dai.
What?!
That boy, Dai,
is a Dragon Knight, isn't he?!
A Dragon Knight?! From the legends?!
He finally knows!
So, will you leave Dai to me?
No! No, No!
As Dark Commander, I order you!
You will do nothing!
Besides, there is no proof
that he's really a Dragon Knight!
I merely need to see it for myself.
And I said no!
Stop!
How dare you!
I believe I know what's going on, Hadorra.
If this Dai really is a Dragon Knight,
you can't let Baran near him, right?
Oh well, you can all squabble
on your own time.
I'd like to finish what I came here for.
That's...
the Key of Ban!
Crocodine and Hyunckel, was it?
Those two know the location
of Sovereign Rock Castle.
So King Ban ordered me
to move it immediately.
Move it?!
So that's why...
It finally stands!
Sovereign Rock Castle moves!
And now, let's all enjoy
a little globe-trotting!
Whee! Whee!
Maam...
Why doesn't she just train with us?
It's a decision she reached
after much thought.
Besides, I've heard deep in the mountains
of Romos lives a "God of Martial Arts."
Who cares about some God of Martial Arts!
Just let her go off and
be a Martial Artist or whatever!
What are you so sour about?
Popp's actually sad
because he really likes Maam.
And you can shut your mouth!
Oh really? Then why don't you
just tell her how you feel?
You won't be seeing her
for a while anyways.
For... a while...
It doesn't matter.
She's already into someone else.
And that's why you're all sour?
Is that supposed to be kindness?
Besides, if you die in battle,
this will be your final farewell to her.
She'll never know how you feel.
Are you fine with that?
This is... our final farewell?
I...
Maam! Wait!
And off he goes! What will happen now?!
Leona, you're enjoying this, aren't you?
Maam!
Popp?
What's wrong?
You're going to Nayle Village
in Romos, right?
I'll take you there with Rura.
What will he do?
Will he be able to tell her?
That was mean, Leona.
To push Popp like that.
That's not true.
I said what I said for his benefit.
It's not good for one's mental health
to keep things bottled up.
Really?
I'm sorry, Popp.
Huh? You're not going to Nayle Village?
You said Romos, so I thought...
Our battle isn't over yet.
I'm not returning there until we defeat
the Dark Army and avenge Master Aban.
Oh...
Besides, the God of Martial Arts is
said to live deep in the Romos mountains.
I trained in the Romos mountains
with Mentor!
I can get there with Rura!
But...
Oh come on. We're friends, right?
Okay. I guess I'll take you up on it.
Good!
R-Ready?
Rura!
Whoa! He even put his arm around her!
Not a bad job at all!
Good luck, Maam. We'll be waiting.
Ow!
Sorry. My landings still suck.
Huh? This isn't the Romos mountains.
Huh?
This is...
the Dark Forest?!
Why did we end up here?!
Oh! This is...
where we first met!
Oh!
That's right. A mental image
is the key to Rura spells.
I guess this place
is really important to...
I remember. The first thing we did
when we met was fight.
I'll never forget it.
The timing feels right.
This is my chance to tell her!
You know...
Huh?
You're amazing, Popp.
How?
I mean, it took us days by boat
from Romos to Papunica.
Now you can come back in an instant.
It's nothing impressive.
When we first met, I couldn't imagine
you doing something like this.
To be honest, at first I thought
you were just a selfish coward.
I-I can't argue with that.
But, through every battle,
you grew so strong and so brave.
It made me realize
how hard you were trying.
You grew strong so fast
and learned new spells,
and saved me again and again.
Even back when we fought Hadorra...
Maam...
That's why, after that battle,
I decided I wanted to catch up with you.
I can't have you rescuing me
all the time, right?
Popp?
It's okay, Maam. It was nothing.
You don't have to feel that way at all.
I'd gladly throw my life away
for you any time.
Huh?
I want to tell you that...
I...
"I..."?
I think you're the best companion ever!
Popp...
See you, Maam.
I promise I'll be back.
You'll be shocked how strong I become.
If you show up looking like
some muscle-bound gorilla,
I'll pretend I don't know you.
You're already not much to look at now.
W-What?!
Best of luck out there!
Try not to become a muscle-bound gorilla!
Thank you, Popp.
This is how it should be!
I can't tell her yet!
I'm not at strong or brave
as she thinks I am!
I need to get even stronger!
What do you think will happen?
I think there's a 70 to 80% chance
that he gets shot down.
You really are enjoying this.
W-What?!
Sovereign Rock Castle is gone!
How is this possible?!
Look there!
Sovereign Rock Castle has moved!
Are you saying the castle
sprouted legs and walked away?!
It's not entirely impossible...
considering Dark King Ban's
Supercharged Dark Energy.
Crocodine, you need to inform
Dai and the others of this.
And what about you?
I'm going to follow
those giant footprints.
I feel something terrible
is going to happen.
Where are we?
Almost at the northernmost land
known as the Field of Death.
Things are smooth, Captain.
What was that?!
That was close.
It's huge! It's enormous!
A giant made of rocks!
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Kindness is the magic of kind people
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Even if the place I call home may change
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
anata wa nannte iukana
I wonder what you'd say
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
Seeking new weapons, Dai and his friends
head to Bengana Kingdom.
Their first time in a department store,
Dai and Popp are excited
by all the unfamiliar foods and items.
Little do they know
that a new threat approaches.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Off to The Department Store"
The adventure continues!