Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
MASTER OF DARKNESS AGAINST HIS PUPIL
You are all worthless.
You are vermin to Dark King Ban.
Surrender will not be allowed.
Die.
Begone from this world,
along with this entire country!
Make sure your final screams are loud
enough that King Ban can hear them!
The Shadow Legion!
Here they come!
Vermin?! Surrender won't be allowed?!
He thinks humans are
this world's garbage?!
Who does he think he is?! That does it!
Wait! I'm coming, too!
Leona, run when you have the chance!
Be careful out there, you two!
Huh?! Uh, what about me?!
I understand.
Huh?
I will look after those two.
Uh...
Thank you.
Popp, calm down!
You won't beat him by losing your head!
I know! But he just makes me so mad!
Dammit! I'll show him that humans
aren't as weak as he thinks!
Popp...
Curse them!
Just sit back!
But you were wounded rescuing me!
What was that?
Are you immortal?!
Big Guy's surrounded!
I'll go help them!
Huh? I thought your Refractor Fist
only works on living creatures.
Will it work on those things?
For enemies like that...
you use brute force!
Wow. I won't be teasing her any time soon!
Hold on! You're up against me,
you colossus!
I'll blow your head off!
IORA!
There! That should open a hole in you!
It did, but not by much!
And now a fly.
Miasmas, take him down.
These guys cast magic impair spells!
Mahoton!
Are you kidding me?!
Hurry.
Hurry and finish!
Dai.
Relax yourself.
Your agitation will affect the sword.
Don't worry.
Once this is complete, you will be able
to fight any enemy on equal ground.
Trust me. Trust this sword.
And trust Jank's son and the others.
Yes, sir!
I'm counting on you, Popp, Maam,
and everyone in Papunica!
I'll be there soon!
Begirama!
You won't beat us so easily!
Hang in there, Miss Maam!
I'm on my way to gallantly help you!
Hold on!
I, Baduck, Papunica's greatest
Inventor Swordsman, am coming to help!
Who in the world is this?
There's too many.
I'll have to take them all out with...
Popp, I heard you used Five Finger Flares.
Yeah, uh, kind of.
Never use it again.
Huh? Why?
That spell is practically Forbidden Magic.
Only a creature with no regard
for its own life can use it.
It'll shorten a normal human's lifespan.
I know it's for your friends,
but if you keep that sort of thing up...
Mentor! Are you...
Mentor, you didn't...
It won't be long now.
Shortened as it is,
a hundred years is still too long.
Considering how short Aban and Roka got.
Listen, Popp. You're still young.
Don't worry.
In time, you'll learn powerful spells.
Do you understand?
What an army!
Don't stop!
Show an opening and they'll take it!
Help is here!
Look out!
Huh?!
Hmm. That one has spirit.
Everyone...!
Don't worry.
In time, you'll learn powerful spells.
In time...
In time is too late!
I need it now, Mentor!
Finger Flares Bomb!
Holy cow! When did he learn that?!
Popp...!
We need to keep up! Here we go!
Right!
Roar, Vortex Axe!
Everybody! Scatter!
IORA!
H-How's that?! I got them all!
Popp, are you okay?!
Yeah I'm fine. I'm just a little tired.
All that's left is the colossus.
What?!
Did you think it was over, you fools?
My Shadow Legion is an immortal force.
So long as they have Dark Aura,
they will continue to resurrect!
In Sovereign Rock Castle's right chest,
the Lung Chamber,
new Armoured Warriors
are constantly imbued with Dark Aura.
The Lung Chamber?!
That's right. Sovereign Rock Castle
had such a forbidden chamber.
Then their army...
...is infinite?!
W-What do we do?!
D-Dammit!
We... We might be done for!
This is...?!
You disappoint me, Popp!
If you're really a Disciple of Aban,
don't whine over enemies like this!
Just defeat them all! No matter
how many times they're resurrected!
Hyunckel!
You came!
It was getting too noisy
to focus on training.
I came to silence them.
Hmph! What a show-off!
Showing up at the perfect moment as usual!
Another strange guy.
Maybe Miss Maam is
more popular than I imagined.
Hyunckel!
You seem well, Maam.
But we can reminisce
after we defeat that behemoth.
I see your overconfidence
hasn't changed, Hyunckel.
Come out of there, Mystban!
You're going to be defeated by me anyways!
Why don't you save me the trouble?!
You don't know...
the power of my Shadow Legion,
and the terror of
Dark King Ban's Sovereign Rock Castle.
That's the ultimate armour
of the Shadow Legion that Flazzard used!
Go forth, Dead Armours.
Three of them...
Stand back.
Huh?! By yourself?!
I thought you'd only begun training!
The essence of the Aban Style
isn't about the weapon.
The basics of Earth, Sea, and Air,
once mastered are easily applied.
Babysit Popp for me.
What was that?!
Are you picking a fight?!
Look out! They're coming!
Earth Strike!
Look out!
He's fast!
That first attack was Earth Strike,
a powerful attack like Earth Slash.
And this was Aban Style Spear Technique's
fastest attack, Wave Strike.
It hardly bears mentioning,
but my strongest attack,
remains just as powerful,
even with a different weapon!
That stance!
Bloody Sukuraido!
Amazing, Hyunckel!
He easily wiped out enemies
we previously struggled against!
Dammit. I hate to admit it,
but he really is powerful.
He's a genius.
That's Grand Cross!
Enough with the games.
Come out or I blow away the castle's head
with you in it, Mystban!
It stopped!
There you are, Mystban!
All of you back off.
Don't be stupid!
I'm not letting you show off any more!
I said back off!
Hmph! What's his problem?
Forgive him.
Mystban taught Hyunckel
the Dark Technique
back when he was in the Dark Army.
What?!
If Aban is his Master of Light,
Mystban is his Master of Darkness.
This is a battle between
the Master of Darkness and his pupil.
For Hyunckel,
it's settling his own dark past.
Looks like you're finally ready
to fight me, Mystban.
BLOODY SUKURAIDO!
TOMAKUGUTSOSHO
Let me make one thing clear.
Your pitiful attack
wouldn't scratch Sovereign Rock Castle.
But I have chosen to reveal myself.
You betrayed the Dark Army,
and embarrassed me in front of King Ban.
I intend to kill you by my own hands.
You've become quite the chatterbox.
Even when you trained me,
you barely said anything.
Don't worry about it.
I'll make you like you used to be.
Once I kill you, you'll be quiet forever!
Not possible. Not with your strength.
Are you running?!
Check out that flurry of attacks!
Do it!
What was that?! What did he do?!
Such hastily learned spear skills
can't match my killing blow.
See if they're hastily learned
for yourself!
Aban Stye Spear Technique, Wave Strike!
Byut Deathstringer!
His finger!
Rapidly stretching steel claws!
But I can see it!
Fool. This attack can be done
with any finger.
Th-This is...!
That skill!
Tomakugutsosho!
As a skill of darkness,
I never intended to use it again.
But it'll make a fitting end for you!
Die by the skill you taught me!
Now pierce yourself with your own hand!
Do it!
What...?!
I-Impossible!
Hyunckel!
This can't be!
My... My Dark Puppetry Aura Hand
is perfect!
You've said yourself
that it surpassed yours!
I thought so.
You're weaker than when you were
the Undead Legion Commander.
What?!
Having sided with justice,
your Dark Aura is not what it was!
What are you...?!
Did your father never give you a toy?
What?!
That's what happens to broken toys.
Hyunckel!
M-Maam?!
Maam!
You idiot! That was too reckless!
Indeed.
H-How did he...?!
I suppose it was more
pointless than reckless.
To sustain wounds
for one as useless as him.
Don't be stupid! An adept warrior
like Hyunckel isn't useless!
He was only adept when he was
a Dark Swordsman in the Dark Army.
Now he's just a mongrel
with some skills in Light and Darkness.
How dare you!
I've never neglected my training!
I learned the Aban Style Spear Technique!
I may have gotten stronger,
but I wouldn't have become weaker!
The reason is simple.
Your Dark Aura has diminished in power.
It once overflowed with hate for Aban.
Hate which I taught you to control.
But the great King Ban saw through you.
He saw the deeply buried feelings
you had for Aban.
Deep down, you admired and
were grateful for Aban's kindness.
Your single-minded obsession with revenge
made you bury such feelings.
As a result, you possessed
polar opposite energies.
Your body contained both
the Aura of Justice and the Dark Aura.
It made you the ultimate warrior.
A body wielding
the powers of both good and evil.
That was the secret
to your undying strength.
Having awakened to justice and using
Aura of Light attacks like Grand Cross,
your power is only half what it was.
You cannot defeat my true Dark Power.
You lie! I won't believe it!
Hyunckel...!
Die, Hyunckel.
I shall dispose of my mistake myself.
You won't harm Hyunckel! I'll fight you!
Maam!
And it's not just Maam!
Don't forget we're here, too!
That's right!
Even you can't fight all of us at once!
Foolish insects. You can't even see
you're already caught in my web.
What?!
What is this spider web-like thing?!
Dark Puppetry Aura Decimation Field!
This is Tomakugutsosho!
He's caught everyone here at once?!
Unbelievable! Is this the depths
of Mystban's Dark Aura?!
He's unbeatable!
I'll have to resist him with my own
Dark Power to fight!
I'm the only one who can move
within the Decimation Field.
What will you do, Hyunckel?
If you don't believe me,
try to stop this flow of Aura
with your own Dark Power.
Curse you...
Curse you...!
Mystban!
Don't, Hyunckel!
Let my wrath burn!
Let my hate and malice towards him boil!
You can't!
The power... The Dark Power!
You won't move a finger
with darkness like that.
Hate... Hate him!
Just as I once hated Aban!
Don't do it!
Maam?!
We might all die
if you don't regain your power of evil.
But I can't bear to see
those ruthless eyes again!
If you're going to fight,
fight with only the power of good.
I know you can win!
Maam...
I see you've stopped resisting. So be it.
You can die together!
Byut Deathstringer!
W-What?! My Decimation Field?!
I almost made
the same foolish mistake again!
I...
I choose... the Light of Justice!
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Sovereign Rock Castle
advances toward the summit members.
Popp and the others remain held in
the Dark Puppetry Aura Decimation Field.
Mystban's Dark Aura
overwhelms even Hyunckel's Aura of Light.
All seems lost for Papunica, but Dai
finally arrives with a new sword in hand.
Will he be able to overcome this peril?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Strongest Sword"
The adventure continues!