Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE TEAM BATTLE BEGINS
Nova!
I guess it was a good lesson.
Here's a lesson to take with you.
In this world,
there's always someone stronger.
Well... goodbye!
Nova!
At least die gloriously, you loser!
No!
You talk too much.
But you were right about one thing.
There's always someone stronger!
Hyunckel!
Maam! Big Guy!
Rushing while carrying three was rough.
You can rest for a while.
-Crocodine!
-Right!
Yow, ow, ow!
Be a little more gentle, Big Guy.
Thank you! But be careful!
They're really strong!
So all the Disciples of Aban are here.
I suppose we can't back down anymore.
Look Dai.
I impaled his head and he still lives.
They really are just like Flazzard.
They're metallic lifeforms
made by Forbidden Magic.
If we find their cores and use
our Air technique, they can be defeated.
That's right. We just need
to find their cores!
Don't bother searching!
Our cores are right here!
The same as you humans.
Is he an idiot?!
He just revealed their weakness!
Knowing that won't help you beat us.
Just like you humans,
it's meaningless if you can't hit it!
This makes it five against five.
We're evenly matched.
As a reward for impaling me,
let us show you...
the true power of the Hadorra Royal Guard!
Their confidence is almost terrifying.
So what?!
After all we've been through,
our teamwork won't lose to those puppets!
Maam, try to take care of that horse-head.
Without his spell reflector,
I can blow them all away
with my Extreme Spell!
Got it!
I'll take the big one.
Dai, which one is their leader?
Hadorra isn't here, so that queen
should be their leader.
Got it.
I'll be taking the armoured one, Albinass.
You will not, Hym.
You must take the Hero, Dai.
What? You're telling me
to just ignore what he did to me?
I won't be happy
until I impale his head, too!
We are all pieces for Lord Hadorra.
We live and die all for Lord Hadorra.
Don't forget that.
I guess I can't argue with that.
If you're going to fight, revealing their
strengths will better serve Lord Hadorra.
Whoa!
Very well, then!
You've got to know when to switch gears!
I'm taking the Hero!
Mera!
That's it, Hym. Keep it up.
Are you my opponent?
How confident. You could have
pierced my core from behind.
Are you a woman?
No need for concern.
I am merely a piece
bearing the role of queen.
A piece has no gender.
No need to hold back.
You're pretty brave.
But I think you underestimate us.
That one must be a pawn.
Did you think pitting the weakest piece
against Dai would actually stop him?
You're the one underestimating us.
Excuse me, but I believe you're unfamiliar
with the game of chess.
In chess, there are no stronger
or weaker pieces.
There is only a difference in abilities.
A pawn is not necessarily
weaker than a queen.
It's all in how you use it.
Recognize your opponent's abilities
and deploy your pieces accordingly.
It's the basic strategy in chess
to stop your enemy.
Right there!
If I can hit the heart with Air Slash...!
Now!
Aban Style Sword Technique! Air Slash!
If you're using this knife against me,
you still don't understand my power.
Or is that thing on your back
just a decoration?
Well?!
Dai!
Hym is unmatched
in close-quarters combat.
Without your Hero, it seems
you're the ones at a disadvantage.
I can't shatter that shield.
I need to stop his movements!
For a human to attain such speed
is quite a feat.
The speed...!
However...
no one can eclipse my agility and speed!
I appears that our piece placement
was better than yours.
Then I merely need to take out
the queen who commands them!
What?!
It hardly bears mentioning,
but I, too, am very strong.
This is bad!
They're controlling the battle!
I need them grouped together,
otherwise I can't cast my spell.
What can we do?!
And where did that pointy guy
who was chasing me go?
Right here!
You're wide open!
You bastard!
My brand-new staff!
Over 80% of my body is blades.
I wouldn't suggest touching me.
Get back! Don't touch me!
Popp!
Come on! You don't have time
to be worried about others!
Darn it!
It won't come out!
What a disappointment!
Don't carry around a weapon
that you can't even use!
It appears that he hasn't yet
mastered that sword.
It seems that we need not bother
summoning Lord Hadorra.
Don't be so sure about that!
Impossible! He actually hit me?!
Unfortunately, we humans aren't pieces.
Don't think you can
approach this like a game.
Gira!
Futile, futile!
Everyone!
Draw it. This is your last chance.
At this rate, everyone is going to die!
If I could draw my sword,
I could defeat them easily!
Darn it! Why won't it come out?!
What a joke. You really can't draw it.
You're not worth Lord Hadorra's time.
My Heat Knuckle can easily shatter
someone like you.
Time to finish things.
Don't worry. I'll take your head
before you feel any pain.
Nova?!
Curse you, you feeble weakling!
Quick! Give me your staff!
It's over!
Nova!
Thank you for saving me, Nova!
Don't bother thanking me.
It's a Hero's duty to protect the weak.
Don't worry. He's just unconscious.
He exhausted himself
by using up the last of his Aura.
He fought to the very limit.
He's tougher than I thought.
To the very limit!
REFRACTOR FIST
TOMAKUGUTSOSHO
It's no good!
All this training and I couldn't
draw my sword once!
Hyunckel's already mastered
the Dark Armour Spear...
But I...
I...
Don't you get it, Dai?
It's only natural.
Of course you can't draw it.
The Sword of Dai can't be unsheathed
to face a retired warrior like me.
If there's a reason that
you can't draw your sword...
it's in your inability
to properly read your opponent.
The issue is in you!
It's... in me?
That's it!
Ever since I sliced that giant
Sovereign Rock Castle,
I've been unconsciously
relying on the sword's power!
I mistook the power I wielded
with the sword as my own!
But...
my sword has its own soul.
It can read my enemies
far better than I can.
I'd forgotten that!
Only when I've fought to the limit
with my own strength,
will my sword lend its power to me!
Nova, seeing you fight so desperately
has made me understand
what Ron Berku tried to teach me.
I guess we both have
a lot to learn as Heroes.
There's still a way!
What's wrong, Dai?
If I still can't draw my sword,
it means there's still a way
to defeat them without it!
Dammit!
You and your meddling!
You'll pay for that!
Full power Dragonic Aura!
Dai, knock Hym this way!
That's right! I'm not the only one
who can use Air attacks!
Aban Style Spear Technique!
Air Strike!
Hym!
Hyunckel!
Great! That's one down!
No.
You still haven't mastered Air Strike?!
It's true that it's not an easy skill.
But the queen spit this out,
shifting my aim from Hym's core.
Without this, I could have ended it.
It's instantly fatal
depending on where you're hit.
I'd suggest healing it quickly.
Maam!
Maam, we need you!
Why you...!
Everyone gather for a moment!
Understood.
Kiari!
Damn. I can't lift my arm.
-Fenbren.
-Sure.
That makes things easier.
To be honest, I misjudged them.
Sorry, Albinass.
I did, too.
The Disciples of Aban have grown far more
powerful than what Lord Hadorra described.
Our abilities surpass theirs.
But their experience
makes them relentless.
They can't be underestimated.
You should be okay, Hyunckel.
Thanks.
Hym is going to fight without an arm...
Where do they get that tenacity?!
Popp has a point.
Their solidarity and sense of purpose
are terrifyingly strong.
But Dai, while I missed,
you were on the right track.
You still have your friends.
Don't try to do everything yourself.
I made my own discovery.
Crocodine!
Individually, their abilities
are far beyond our own.
We can't win fighting power
with power or speed with speed.
We should fight their strengths
with different strengths.
I get it.
Matching their strengths is no good.
Okay! Let's switch things up!
Maam, confuse the big one with your speed.
And Big Guy, use your strength
to overpower the knight.
Dai and Hyunckel, I need you to take
the other three at once.
Keep together as a team!
I'm going to prepare my Medoroa!
Once the knight's mirror is disabled,
try to gather them together!
I'll be firing a huge spell,
so get some distance!
Got it?!
Right!
Here we go then!
Beast King Redemption Blast!
Okay!
Pathetic!
You can't beat me
with an Aura Flow this weak!
Then how about the other whirlpool?!
What?!
I risked my life
in the Baruji Whirlpool for this!
My new attack will tear you apart!
A second twister with a reverse spin?!
Beast King Indomitable Blast!
Sigma!
Now! Everybody scatter!
A spell won't work!
No!
Medoroa!
W-What power!
That's worth bragging about.
Well done learning such a spell.
That's amazing, Popp!
Popp!
That was amazing!
So that's what all that training was for!
I did it!
I definitely hit them this time.
One good hit with that...
and we win!
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
The fierce team battle was ended
by Popp's new spell, Medoroa.
Meanwhile, Chiu infiltrates
the Field of Death with his companions.
They get closer to the secret
of the Dark Army's stronghold.
But the hand of the Dark Army
reaches towards them.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"We're the Beast King Commandos"
The adventure continues!