With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE HOPE IN THE FLAMES
Dai...
Looks like we're screwed now.
Darn it!
It's no good.
Even if I keep holding the flames off,
my stamina won't last!
That said, my hands are full as it is!
I guess this is it...
Popp!
Sorry.
I went and jumped in here...
but I couldn't do anything.
It looks like... this is... the end.
Popp.
I'm sorry!
Dammit!
You fools!
Hadorra?!
You two...
You call yourselves Disciples of Aban?!
For you two to die in a place like this
and still call yourselves that...
You would disappoint Aban
in the afterlife!
What?!
Look at me!
The Disciples of Aban
that I gave my life to trying to defeat...
had the most dauntless of souls!
They were warriors of hope!
A will of iron that
never gives up until the very end!
Isn't that...
Isn't that supposed to be the greatest
weapon of a Disciple of Aban?!
Hadorra...
The bastard!
He's the one who killed Master Aban!
And yet...
he said exactly what Master would say!
Now do something about it!
I thought I fought the Disciples of Aban!
Don't make me a clown
who lost to a bunch of posers!
Our enemy is lecturing us.
Having fought us, Hadorra understands
what it means to be Disciples of Aban...
more than we do ourselves!
In that case,
who cares if we can't do anything!
We'll resist until the very, very end!
Popp!
Okay. Now what?
It doesn't change the fact
that we're out of options!
Wait... There one last way out!
A way out?!
Dai, you can still cast spells, right?
Yeah, I can.
But I don't know about my aim.
Plus, my Magic Power isn't...
You don't need to aim at anything!
Huh?
You just need to cast one spell.
Rura!
Cast Rura right there, and fly out above!
If I do that,
I'll hit that wall of flames!
The sky will be visible when you do!
Thanks to my Medoroa!
That's it!
Yeah! Medoroa!
It can blow everything away!
This trap works by focusing
eight flames in one point!
That means, if I cast Medoroa above
where the flames have gathered...
it should disperse them,
leaving the sky visible for an instant!
Let's bet on that instant!
Okay!
Listen! Use Rura to fly up
when you see the sky!
I'll grab onto you immediately!
Casting Medoroa is probably going to
drain me of all my Magic Power.
So that's our best option.
Got it.
What are you waiting for?!
If there's a way, try it before you die!
Forget about me.
I'm doomed to be a corpse soon anyway.
Make sure you two make it out!
Right!
Everyone!
Popp?!
We're going to make our last attempt!
Pray for us!
Popp!
Here goes!
Popp?!
Crap! If I weaken my Ice-type magic
even a little, I'll be overpowered!
Dammit!
It's no good!
I can't cast Medoroa like this!
Dammit!
Hadorra...?!
With his Magic Power...?!
What the hell are you doing?!
Ignore me! I'm doing what I want!
This is your chance! Cast your spell!
Hadorra?!
I gave my life for this fight!
I won't let Kilban's trap spoil it!
If my fight, if the fight
of my companions...
end without any victors,
there'll be no one
to tell the world about them!
Hurry, Popp!
This corpse has risen!
Consider it a stroke of luck!
Dai! Here we go!
Right!
Do it!
Medoroa!
The sky!
It opened!
Now!
Hurry and...
Rura!
Dai...
Where's Popp?
Huh? Wait...
What happened?!
Where's Popp?!
Popp!
Maam?
I messed up.
I never thought it would end like this.
Sorry.
I can't... see the future... with you.
Popp!
It's complete.
The Nine of Diamonds
is in its final stage.
It's time to say goodbye,
little Mage.
Help... Somebody...
Somebody do something!
I love this final moment.
Everything focuses at the center diamond
and vanishes to the Underworld.
Not even ash is left behind.
Like fireworks,
I love how sentimental it ends.
You're in a good mood...
considering one of them escaped.
I have more Kill Traps.
I have as many traps as cards
scattered all over Ban Palace.
In fact, we're lucky we got that brat now.
You hold him in high regard for a human.
You mustn't underestimate humans.
In terms of growth potential,
Popp's is greater than Dai's.
None of them will ever reach this place.
I'll take care of them all.
One by one, little by little. Right?
To the end of Popp. Cheers!
Cheers!
Hadorra?!
It looks like you enjoy
futile resistance as well.
Don't be stupid!
Don't give up! Stand up and try again!
I'm out of Magic Power and stamina.
But I managed to save Dai.
I think that's enough.
You little fool!
If you hadn't hesitated...
you would have made it out as well!
Why did you?!
Sorry. I froze when I saw you.
What?
In that moment, seeing you
desperately try to help us survive...
You didn't feel like a stranger anymore.
I knew you wouldn't make it either way.
But I just couldn't... leave you behind.
I mean, just look at you!
You fought for your honor.
You worked with your companions.
You worked hard.
To fight us fair and square,
you desperately...
you desperately did all you could!
How are you any different from us?
We're the same!
Popp...
you...
Seeing you crumble in that instant...
I couldn't bring myself to look away.
I reached out to you.
That's why... I couldn't grab Dai.
I'm such a klutz.
To end up dying
trying to save my mortal enemy.
Master Aban's might scold me
in the afterlife.
Nah. He wouldn't scold me.
He'd understand how I feel.
Popp!
Hadorra?
Are you... crying?
Popp... I can't believe it.
To give your life...
for someone like me!
Forgive me!
What are you talking about?
If you hadn't been here,
I couldn't have cast Medoroa.
Thank you, Hadorra.
Your tears are evaporating instantly.
It's a pretty shabby place to die.
But let's go together!
Master Aban's waiting in the afterlife!
God!
God of humans!
As a Darkling, this is my first prayer!
If indeed you truly have the power
to preside over the lives of humans...
save him!
Save this magnificent man!
Please don't let him die
for a monster like me!
God!
And now, the grand finale!
Burn away, you filth!
Darn it!
No!
Popp!
Popp?
What is this?
Now, now, Popp.
We can't have you going to the afterlife.
Even if you had,
I wouldn't have been waiting there.
No way...
Is this a dream?
No...
I thought...
Impossible!
How?
How?!
M-Master?!
It can't be!
I must be dreaming!
Or...
is this really the afterlife?!
You'll have to wait a moment
to be healed, Popp.
It seems that I owe you
a word of gratitude...
Hadorra.
You... Are you really Aban?
I'm surprised. I never thought
you of all people would save my student.
The Hadorra I knew would
never have done such a thing.
It appears that you are
no longer the same man
that I once knew you to be,
Dark Lord Hadorra.
You...
I know it's strange saying this
to someone I've fought again and again...
but truly...
Do you intend to say, "thank you"?!
You're soft! You're as soft as ever!
You make me sick!
You won't be meddling again this time...
damn Reaper!
That damn Kilban...
Hadorra?!
I guess it looks like
that truly was the last of my strength.
Hadorra... you...
Hear me, Aban.
Dark King Ban is a dangerous man.
Forget any mercy. Be cold as ice.
It's your power...
that your students will need
for the battle ahead.
They were glorious.
Those students of yours.
So much so... they even...
changed who I was.
With your power...
lead them... to victory.
Hadorra!
That's...
how you can...
show your gratitude to me.
Hadorra...
Popp.
It seems the god of you humans...
has a sense of poetic irony.
Huh?
In return for my life...
your god brought back
the treasure I once stole...
and returned it to you.
Not only that...
your god let me die...
right here...
in the arms... of this man.
Hadorra.
In your last moments, you were one of us.
You were...
our friend.
Hadorra...
It was Aban who saved Popp and Hadorra.
He was believed to have died
protecting Dai and Popp
from Dark Commander Hadorra,
but with his return,
the Disciples of Aban
are both bewildered and overjoyed.
Together with the greatest possible ally,
the party heads to Ban's palace.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Return of the Great Hero"
The adventure continues!