Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Standing firm became strength
naa mitsukaranai?
Have you found it yet?
jishin janaku jibun jishin
Not confidence, your true self
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
I smolder because I've actually burned
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
tada me wo mihiraite
I'll just open my eyes
yume wo miru
And dream my dream
yume wo shiru
And know my dream
ONTO PAPNICA KINGDOM
All of you fought well.
Especially Dai.
This victory was thanks to you!
You truly have grown into one
worthy of the title "Hero."
From this day on,
you may call yourself, "Dai, the Hero."
Congratulations, Dai.
Your dream came true.
Your Majesty, it's too soon for me.
Huh?!
What are you talking about?!
I couldn't have won alone.
Popp, Maam, Gomechan, and everyone in the
castle worked together for this victory.
If I'm a Hero, then everyone is a Hero.
Dai...
So, until I get a little stronger
and can fight without burdening anyone,
please don't call me a Hero.
It's a little embarrassing.
Very well.
I look forward to your further growth.
Sir Brass, you truly have raised
a good boy.
Y-Yes. He's... He's my pride and joy.
Knock it off, Grampa.
That's called over-doting.
You imbecile! Nobody asked you!
These gifts are the least I can do.
Wear them and go show the people.
Everyone wants to see
the heroes who saved this country.
I hear he's still a small boy!
I'd love to catch a glimpse
of the mighty Hero!
Those youths are the ones who saved us!
Our heroes! Hurrah!
Man, real Heroes look so cool.
If you fought now, you probably won't win.
Sh-Shut up!
It seems you're the real deal after all.
Good luck to you, boy.
It feels pretty good to work hard
and have people thank you.
Popp, you're actually a little cool today.
Yay! Thank you for your cheers!
Dai, listen to them cheer for you.
While you may not wish it yet,
I'm sure the people will speak of you...
as "Dai, the Tiny Hero."
W-What's that?!
It came from the Heart Chamber!
The Heart Chamber?
That's where Magic Rituals are held.
This is Begirama,
the most powerful Heat-type spell.
Along with that new body of yours,
accept it as your reward for slaying Avan.
Magnificent.
Now I have mastered both
Heat and Explosion-type spells.
Lord Hadlar...
Zaboera.
Use your Heyedras
and send an order to all our forces.
Yes, Lord!
Summon the remaining Legion Commanders
here at Sovereign Rock Castle!
Dai, until the day the Dark King
is defeated and peace is restored,
we shall live quietly
here on Dermline Island.
So, Dai, don't worry about us.
Fight on with all your might.
Woo-hoo! This is exhilarating!
I can't believe King Romos just casually
lent us a ship. He's so magnanimous!
And man, is this ship fast!
Right, Dai?
He didn't say goodbye to Brass.
It was too hard for him.
I see.
Well, I guess I'll just have to
cheer him up!
What's with the long face?!
I know you care about your old man,
but you don't need to worry!
Are you sure?
All we got to do is wipe out
the Dark King and your problem's solved!
Popp...
You're right. We just have to do our best!
Sure. It'll be fine.
You've got strong allies at your back!
With me here, you've got nothing to fear!
With that last battle,
I feel my caliber as a man,
or as a Mage,
really leveled up like crazy--
W-W-What's that?!
"Leveled up like crazy," huh?
Sorry if you were startled.
This ship continuously pours out
Holy Water as it sails.
Your average monster can't even get close.
Huh. That sounds lavish.
Nothing like the tub we sailed over in.
Indeed. You could never make it
to the Continent of Holkia with that.
The Continent of Holkia?
Let me show you on a map!
We're heading east, past Dermline Island,
to the Continent of Holkia.
Papnica is right here.
Huh. Dermline Island is so small.
But why head to Papnica?
There are other large countries.
Well, it's to see
his beloved princess, of course.
Right, Dai?
Th-That's not the only reason!
"Beloved princess"?
He's friends with the princess of Papnica.
That's why he wants to rescue her
from the Dark Army.
Huh. I didn't know.
You're quite the ladies' man.
I said that's not it!
Oh. Look at him blush.
I see. But the princess of Papnica, huh...
Huh?
Is there a problem?
The Dark Army has sent legions
to each continent for an invasion,
but I hear the battle in Papnica
has been the most intense.
From what I've heard, 15 years ago, Holkia
was the Dark Lord Hadlar's main base.
Hadlar's?!
Apparently, that's why the most
terrifying Legion of the Dark Army
has been sent to take
the Continent of Holkia.
They say, its a legion of immortals
called "the Undead."
A legion of immortals...
Leona...
I'll be there soon! Just hold on!
NORTHERN COUNTRY OF ORZAM
BLIZZBLAZE LEGION LEGION COMMANDER
BLIZZBLAZE GENERAL FLAZZARD
Frail! They're all so frail!
Why do humans have such fragile bodies?
If these are their best warriors,
then this country is all but mine!
Master Flazzard!
What?!
We've just received a message
from a Heyedra!
All Legion Commanders are to gather
at Sovereign Rock Castle!
All of us?! What's going on?!
It seems a new young Hero
has risen and defeated Crocodine!
Crocodine?!
I see. So it's an emergency.
Fine. I'm going to Sovereign Rock Castle.
You finish off this country!
Yes sir!
Burn the villages
and put the surviving humans in ice!
Leave no trace of the humans,
be it house, field or even livestock!
Got it?!
Y-Yes sir!
Avan Strash!
HELL'S CLAW
Blizzblaze General Flazzard has arrived!
Flazzard!
Hm? Oh, Zaboera, the geezer.
As fast as ever, I see.
You live up to your name of
"Blitz Captain of the Dark Army."
I heard Crocodine was defeated.
How pathetic. To lose to a kid.
No, that boy, Dai,
is not to be underestimated.
Oh?
I offered a sure-fire scheme
and he still lost.
He's placed in Resurrection Fluid,
but his chances are 50% at best.
If whoever caused this wound really is
just a kid, then he's a damn monster.
No one, no matter how strong, can damage
Crocodine's steel body this much.
He must possess more than
just physical power.
Not bad, Blizzblaze General Flazzard.
Not just some hot-blooded brawler, huh?
Having both flaming brutality
and ice-cold cunningness...
I concur.
Baran!
This new Hero possesses great potential.
DRAGON LEGION LEGION COMMANDER
DRAGON MASTER GENERAL BARAN
You made it.
My sympathies, pal.
Heading off to take Ringaia and then
being summoned right back.
Your sympathies are unnecessary.
I've already crushed Ringaia Kingdom.
-What?!
-Really?!
Lord Hadlar awaits
in the Left Shoulder Chamber. Come.
He wiped out the Fortress Kingdom
of Ringaia in such a short time?!
He's as powerful
as a wrathful god just as always.
Thank you all for coming so far.
Hmm. I see Master Hadlar
has gained more power again.
It's as though power oozes from him.
It appears his seat as Dark Commander
remains secure for now.
That leaves Mystvearn and Hyunckel.
Who the hell is late
for an emergency summons?
Flazzard, didn't you notice
Mystvearn is already seated?
SHADOW LEGION LEGION COMMANDER
MYSTVEARN, THE SHADOW VIZIER
You?! When the hell...?!
Always the unsociable one, I see.
That leaves Hyunckel.
Unfortunately, it appears
I must apologize to all of you.
I intended to gather our forces
and crush the new Hero, Dai.
But Dark King Vearn
has made a direct order.
He gave the task
of slaying Dai to Hyunckel.
What?!
Is this really the famous
scenic port city of Papnica?!
Captain, this place is dangerous!
Once we're off the ship,
get away from here!
Are you sure?
If he does that, our ride back...
This isn't the time
to be worried about that!
Hey, wait up, Dai!
Please be okay, Leona!
Leona!
Dai...
This is terrible. I doubt any survivors...
S-S-S-Skeletons!
This must be the immortal legion!
They invaded this country!
Calm down, Dai! We're clearly outnumbered!
Oh, fine then.
It looks like we have to fight!
Who is that?!
That was Avan Style
Sword Technique Earth Slash!
Then he's a Disciple of Avan, too?!
I didn't know there were other users of
the Avan Style Sword Technique.
If he's a Disciple of Avan,
I'm sure he'll join us!
Are you sure?
He's got the face of a villain.
Thank you for saving us!
Are you a student of Avan, too?!
Who are you?
It's true that
I learned to fight from Avan.
If I'm to be called a student of Avan,
then I would be the first.
Huh?! You're his first student?!
Oh wow!
What a freaky sword.
I've never seen a sword
so ominous and eerie.
He's got a strange, malicious feel to him.
Is he really on our side?
Tell us what happened to this country.
It fell to the Undead Legion
of the Dark Army two days ago.
The Undead Legion?!
You mean those skeletons?
What about Leona?!
Do you know what happened
to the princess of this country?
No idea. I was wondering that myself.
It's an outrage! Hyunckel?!
That little pipsqueak!
I never liked the fact that
even though he's just a human,
he was accepted as a Legion Commander!
Calm down, Flazzard.
You're heating the place up.
How am I supposed to calm down?!
I understand your rage.
But this was
our Dark King Vearn's decision.
I'm sure the whole thing
was Hyunckel's idea!
Just because the Dark King took a liking
to him, he gets all uppity! That brat...
Mystvearn...
The shadow being who can remain silent
for decades at a time...
He's laughing!
The Dark King's words
take precedence above all.
Exactly.
We have no choice but to obey.
Besides, Hyunckel
is the perfect choice for killing Dai.
Dai cannot defeat Hyunckel.
After all...
We were lucky to meet you here.
Join us and fight with us.
Hold it!
Something's off here!
What are you talking about, Popp?
Yeah. Only a student of Master Avan
could use Earth Slash, right?
If you're really a student of Avan,
then you should have
an Insignia of Avan like us.
An Insignia of Avan...
He really has one!
See?
We need all the help we can get!
Please, fight with us!
What's so funny?
I was just laughing
at what fools you all are.
What?!
What's the meaning of this?!
I told you! He's a villain after all!
But his Insignia of Avan...
It's probably a fake!
It's not fake.
Not all students of Avan
respect their teacher and love justice.
Some of them love violence
and have embraced the darkness.
After seeing just how weak...
justice really is!
But...!
I am Hyunckel!
One of the Six Legion Commanders
of the Dark Army!
UNDEAD LEGION LEGION COMMANDER
HYUNCKEL, THE DARK SWORDSMAN
Hyunckel, the Undead Legion Commander!
But... How could a student of Master Avan
be a Legion Commander of the Dark Army?!
Dammit!
Mera!
These are resurrected corpse warriors
who have surpassed death!
They will not stop their advance
unless pulverized!
Wait Hyunckel! Haven't you heard?!
Master Avan...
Master Avan was killed! By the Dark Army!
Yes. I heard about it.
I heard Hadlar killed him.
And yet you still fight
for the Dark Army?!
It was quite a shock.
He was killed by an enemy
he once defeated!
That's what he gets for taking on students
while neglecting his own training.
I was hoping to kill him myself.
Such a shame.
I asked Vearn, the Dark King,
to let me wipe out his students,
but to run into weaklings like you
is such a disappointment.
Earth Slash...
Don't disrespect Master Avan any more!
I won't forgive anyone
who talks like that! Take it back!
Oh? Interesting.
And what if I say I won't?
I'll do this!
He blocked Earth Slash!
Reexamine your skills
before your run your mouth, boy!
Darn it!
How about this?!
Avan Style Sword Technique Wave Slash!
Oh no! Hyunckel's sword beats Dai's
in both strength and skill!
I know all about
the Avan Style Sword Technique.
Dodging someone of your skill is easy.
It's not over!
That stance...!
Avan Strash!
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Kindness is the magic of kind people
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
doudarou
I'm not sure
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Even if the place I call home may change
naa kaasan boku wa
Listen to me, Mother
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I will never change those I protect
anata wa nannte iukana
I wonder what you'd say
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
At times I can be cowardly and small
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
Unlike the today that I sought
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
Dai's Avan Strash had no effect.
Hyunckel dons the ultimate armour
and fights with his Dark Sword.
His heart overflows with intense hatred.
Eventually, Avan and Hyunckel's past
is revealed.
Can Dai defeat Hyunckel?
Next time on
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Hyunckel, the Dark Swordsman"
The adventure continues!