Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
A SINGLE SHARD OF COURAGE
Beast King Anguish Blast!
Victory is mine!
What's that?
Could it be Dai and Maam...
No. It's not my concern!
It's not my business anymore
whether they live or die!
You're still here?
Oh, you're the Mage
from the fake Hero's party.
The name's Masopho.
You're nothing but a looter!
Would you like to join us?
You seem to have a lot of potential.
Don't be stupid!
I'm a student of Aban, the Hero!
I'm not a small-time crook like you guys!
Oh really?
So does the famous Aban
make students of people
who abandon their companions?
Here. Let me show you.
Dai?! Old man Burasu?!
Why?!
So you survived.
Dai...
I'll heal you.
Maam!
It looks like they're in trouble.
Somebody should help them.
But, even if I go,
what can I do against Crocodine?
Dammit!
"A Hero is one with courage!
And true courage is not planned!
True courage does not depend
on the strength of one's foes!"
Like that?
They're not my words.
They were my master's.
Your master?
When I was young, I trained to be
a Mage to fight for justice.
But I couldn't hack it.
I would often abandon my companions
and run away from danger.
And just look at me now.
Old man...
Now, hurry on!
While there's still a single shard
of courage left within you.
You disgust me!
I am disgusting!
All I do is think of myself and run away!
While Master Aban and Dai
always risked their lives to fight!
Well, that kid's dead.
Poor thing.
Oh, he'll be fine.
That boy is a student of Aban.
Aban?! You mean the real Hero?!
He's made of different stuff than us.
A Heyedra.
Zaboera!
She won't get in your way now.
Go ahead and finish Dai.
Somebody...
save Dai...!
Now, it will finally end...
with this blow!
Dai!
Farewell!
Stop!
Popp?!
Ah, the Mage from before.
What can someone like you
possibly do by showing up now?
Begone!
Master Aban, one fifth,
no, one tenth of what you had is enough.
Lend me your courage!
How dare you!
What?!
You hurt my friends! How dare you?!
Boy, do you know what you're saying?
S-Sure!
I'm saying I'm going to beat you!
You dumb lizard!
Popp! Don't attack that Lump Shaman!
He's...
I know! I recognize him!
You kidnapped him from the island
and turned him into your servant!
You dirty fiends!
Get Crocodine's Magic Cylinder...!
Maam!
Go on and run away.
Compared to Dai,
you're nothing but a gutless worm!
Leave now and I'll spare you.
Screw that!
I'm never abandoning my friends!
Aban didn't train any cowards!
Popp!
Crocodine! Fight me one on one!
A puny ant like you...
Or are you going to use a hostage
against a gutless worm like me?!
What?!
I guess you're a worm, too!
You dumb lizard!
Very well! If it's death you seek, you can
go with your friends to the afterlife!
Burasu! Stay out of this!
Good. Now I can fight
without worrying about him.
Let's see if my best spell will work.
Here I come!
You distanced yourself.
Unlike Heroes and Warriors, Mages like you
are physically no different
from normal humans.
One blow from me will kill you.
Now it depends on whether the spell
you want to cast will work!
See for yourself
whether it'll work or not!
Merazoma!
Did it work?!
Even if you are a worm,
you're Aban's student.
I didn't expect
you to be able to cast Merazoma!
Unfortunately...
I created a shield of wind
with my Vortex Axe,
and avoided a direct hit!
I hope you're ready, boy!
And that's that.
It hurts! It hurts so bad!
I'm... done for!
P-Popp...
Run... Popp...
Dai?!
Don't worry, Dai.
I'm not running anymore!
You kept fighting
after taking tons of blows like this!
I can't be lying down
after just one or two!
You can stand?!
I'll just have to sacrifice myself
and do what I can!
Maybe I can't bring it
to a stalemate like Master Aban, but...
Wait... Like Master Aban?
I've never done it before,
but I'll have to try!
Have you lost your mind?
What are you doing?
Why do you endure?!
What can you do with your rod shattered
and your Magic Power spent?!
What's so funny?!
It's all planned out.
Shattering my rod
and saving my Magic Power...
What?!
Watch the legendary spell
my master, Aban, excelled at!
A magic circle?!
Dark influence, begone!
Mahokator!
Aban Strash!
Beast King Anguish Blast!
Huh? What?
I did... it!
What?!
Impossible!
Where am I?
What happened to me?
Old man...
Popp?!
You were under the Dark Army's control.
It was a dirty plot
to use you against Dai.
Listen, you can't leave that magic circle!
Use me against Dai?!
Did I...?!
Curse you!
What is this?!
You, boy!
What have you done?!
Mahokator.
It's a spell that creates
a magic circle that repels evil.
I can't cover an entire island
like Master Aban, though.
Fool! What point is there
in saving Burasu now?
Look. You used a major spell
beyond your abilities and you're spent.
It doesn't matter.
Dai's still... Dai's still here.
Dai?!
If old man Burasu is okay,
then Dai can fight freely.
He'll take care of you easily.
He's really strong.
You were willing
to sacrifice yourself for Dai?!
It's nothing noble like that.
It's not like I want to die.
But...
I've still got my pride.
To live on after having
abandoned my friends...
I just thought that would be
more pathetic than dying!
Master Aban...
Besides, Popp,
I believe the power we gain through
training should be used to help others.
Master...
I think I get it now.
I'm sorry it took so long.
This fledgling of a boy
is risking his life to fight.
And yet, look at me.
I abandoned my pride out of fear
and resorted to dirty schemes.
Is this truly the right way?
What is victory worth
if it's at the cost of my pride?
Dammit, Crocodine!
What are you doing?!
Kill the boy already!
Victory is at hand!
Do you want to lose your seat as
Legion Commander over feelings of mercy?!
Popp, run! Get out of here!
I can't even stand up.
Don't! Stay inside the magic circle!
If you step out of there,
all my hard work will be for nothing.
It's a tiny magic circle,
but it contains all of my Magic Power.
Popp...
Don't! Don't do it!
Forgive me, boy.
Popp!
What?!
He stands?! But Dai was all but finished!
And what is this light?!
What?!
It's a miracle!
Crocodine, you'll pay for that.
You used my Grampa for evil
and hurt my friends.
You'll pay for that!
What is this light?!
Maam!
What's that mark?! And this light?!
Come on!
Enough of this!
Take this!
Impossible!
Maam! Hang in there!
Popp...
What is that power?
I don't know.
It must be some hidden power of his.
I think that strange mark
responds to Dai's anger.
And right now, Dai is truly angry.
His anger is exploding
at the Dark Army's dirty schemes!
Is this Dai's true power that
forced Lord Hadorra to retreat?
I can't lose here!
If I lose, what did I
throw my pride away for?
I must win even if it kills me!
Beast King Anguish Blast!
Oh no! Dai's unarmed!
Here's a Hoimi. You should be able to run.
Help Dai!
Right!
Your body may be like steel,
but at close range, this will end you!
With my greatest, most powerful attack,
I send you to the afterlife!
Dai!
Use this!
Do it, Dai! The attack of our master!
Beast King Anguish Blast!
Aban Strash!
Aban Strash, is it?
An impressive attack.
You... win!
Yes!
If losing was my fate,
I wish I'd fought you fair and square.
Crocodine?
You, boy!
You taught me a lesson...
on how valuable pride really is.
If my defeat is by ones
such as you, I have no regrets.
In fact, I'm proud.
I was obsessed with victory.
I was a fool!
Farewell, Dai.
Don't ever lose.
A Hero must always be strong!
That idiot Crocodine. He lost.
But what was that astonishing power?
And that mark?
I must inform Lord Hadorra
of the situation.
Crocodine...
Dai.
You won!
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
Having defeated the Beast King Crocodine,
Dai and friends head to Papnica Kingdom.
There, they learn a terrible truth.
On their way to Leona, the party
is surrounded by undead monsters.
Just then, a mysterious man
carrying an ominous sword appears.
Next time on
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Onto Papnica Kingdom"
The adventure continues!