With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE SACRED INHERITANCE
Head back to the stairs!
Is everyone okay?!
Yes.
I'm okay.
But...
This is a problem.
We're at ten hours.
Sadly, we have to head back.
Queen Flora, let's keep going.
What?
Leona?!
There's no guarantee
we'll find a way back in ten hours.
Let's take our chances
on finding Minakator.
But then it'll take more time
getting back!
We only have two pieces of Kiseiseki,
but if we use Minakator,
it should repel the Malice of this cave.
That should allow
Queen Flora's Reremito to get us out.
But it would take nothing
short of a miracle to succeed.
We're hoping to achieve
the great miracle of defeating Ban.
How can we hope to do that if we can't
pull off a small miracle first?
There's no time to fight them!
Let's go everyone!
-Right!
-Yes!
I was right in choosing you Leona.
Your words have a power
that gives people strength.
Ten hours left.
I know we can obtain Minakator!
Aban Strash!
Good!
You've learned to
rapid-fire the Arrow Type!
But I don't think this is enough
to counter Ban's Kaiser Phoenix.
When I pierced his spell before,
I used the Break Type.
Now that I don't have my sword and
I can't use attacks with my Dragonic Aura,
I need an attack as fast as the Arrow Type
and as powerful as the Break Type.
What is it?
Nova, could you ready yourself?
Huh?
I just thought up a new attack!
A new attack?
Have you discovered
a third type of Aban Strash?
It's nothing that impressive.
Have your Aura Blade at full strength.
Got it.
Come on!
It looks like the same stance.
Wait...
Here goes!
Are you serious...?
If my weapon wasn't an Aura Blade
that would've taken my head off!
Sorry about that.
But it works!
It's just a small part of our arsenal,
but we've got a new power!
"A small part"?
To me, it looks like you've created
a terrifying new attack.
You think so?
You never cease to amaze.
I can't believe I tried to rival you.
It's not much.
And my timing is still off.
Yeah. Let's keep training!
Then let's go!
This is the 25th level.
The level where Minakator can be found.
I sense a strange power
from the center area.
That must be the ritual altar.
Hmm.
So I pray here?
It looks like it.
Wear your Insignia.
Okay.
Here goes!
It's finally time.
Yes.
I sense monsters!
Well, that makes sense.
Leona.
Leave the monsters to us.
Focus on the ritual.
Okay!
Here they come!
Damn it...!
There's more!
What a welcoming party.
Why do so many monsters inhabit
a cave made by the God of Humans?
According to ancient texts of a Sage,
the lowest level of the Cave of Trials
connects to the Underworld.
You won't get any closer!
Princess Leona...
The Ritual of Inheritance is beginning!
God of Humans,
grant me this legendary spell.
The word of strength
imbued with holy power...
Minakator!
Leona!
Princess Leona!
That's not real fire!
It's spiritual energy.
A flame of the soul!
So it's an illusion?!
No. This must be a test
left by the God of Humans.
If Leona is unworthy of using Minakator...
I believe this flame will incinerate her.
No!
Leona!
Leona, be strong! Maintain a strong will!
BEHOMA
HEAL-TYPE SPELL
REFRACTOR FIST
You who seek Minakator, present your soul.
My... soul?!
Reveal the root of your soul
which seeks the power of purification.
Have you a purpose
worthy of this great power or not?
I can't answer
such a difficult question so suddenly!
I only have one reason
for seeking the power of purification!
Because I believe!
In the world I was born and raised in!
In all its countries!
And in all the people who live there!
It's not to defeat evil!
It's to prove that the things
we've inherited weren't in the wrong!
For that, I need power! That's all!
The flames!
What is that white light?!
That's the will to see the truth
and pursue what is right!
That is Leona's power.
The light of the soul of justice!
Everyone! Come to me!
Minakator!
A pillar of light?!
That must be Leona!
Let's get back!
Betan!
It's no good!
No matter how much
I expend my Magic Power...
No matter how much I punish myself...
It doesn't...
glow at all!
You know, even though
his was provisional, too...
Dai's father was a Dragon Knight.
Leona's the Princess of Papunica.
Maam's parents were the Warrior
and Cleric from Master Aban's party.
Hyunckel's a combat pro who's been trained
by both good and evil since he was a kid.
I'm the only one!
I'm the only one who's different!
I'm not like them!
What is it, Popp? Say something.
You came here looking for advice, right?
What is it?
Well...
I can't tell you.
You may be my mentor, but this is...
Well, this is pointless.
How can I give advice
when you won't say anything?
I'm not a Seer, you know.
I know that.
I know that asking for advice from you
won't solve what's troubling me.
This is my own problem.
Though...
I doubt it's something
I can do anything about.
I'm just the normal son of
a weapons merchant.
In the end, I've finally hit
a wall I can't overcome.
I suppose that's all it is.
But... even so!
I don't want to be
a burden on everyone else!
I don't know what I should do anymore!
So I ended up here.
Sorry. I'm actually kind of flattered.
Flattered?
I have no idea what you're going through.
But seeing the green little brat
I trained finally reach this level
makes me both happy and sad.
I feel all tingly inside.
I never had a wife or a kid,
but I guess this is what
being a parent would feel like.
Mentor...
Now that I've taught you Medoroa,
when it comes to combat,
you've probably surpassed me.
If I had an Insignia of Matorif,
I'd have given it to you a long time ago!
Popp?
Sorry, Mentor, for whining like that.
I'll... I'll figure it out for myself.
Hold on.
Listen up. This is
the last piece of advice I have for you.
"The last"?
Believe in yourself.
Believe in myself?
If you were just a spoiled brat,
you never would have come this far.
Because you were a weak son of
a weapons merchant, you looked up to Aban,
and struggled harder than anyone
to make it this far.
Have some confidence.
You're strong.
I'm proud to call you my student.
Popp, I'm pretty sure I know
what you're going through.
This will probably be
the biggest hurdle of your life.
But...
if you can overcome it...
you'll make it to a place
that I never could.
We have attained
the Great Purification Spell, Minakator!
We shall succeed in our plan
to rescue Hyunckel and Crocodine...
and then send the Hero's party
into Ban Palace!
The Princess made it back safely.
You did it, Leona!
Yeah! It was pretty easy, right everyone?
That Kiseiseki should glow for you
as an Insignia of Aban now.
Thank you!
It was unbelievable!
That's right. Leona's a royal princess
and even she's trying hard.
I need to try at least ten times harder!
How about you? Did your training go well?
Go well? He easily invented a new attack!
Wow! That's amazing!
Now I just need a sword
that can endure my Dragonic Aura...
If only we had your Sword of Dai.
Queen Flora! Emergency!
A Darkling is approaching the Fort!
What?!
Wait! He's not an enemy!
What a hostile welcome.
Indeed! You're insulting your savior here!
Ron Berku!
Go on! Out of the way!
Oh! Princess!
It's good to see you're well!
The Dark King used the staff, didn't he?
Yeah. The Kōmanotue.
Did you really make it, Ron Berku?
I did. With that in hand,
Ban is truly unbeatable.
Face to face, you don't
stand a chance against him.
That's why I came all this way.
How did you even find us?
I asked this.
Wait! Is that...?!
That's right.
This came to me along with
Hyunckel's Dark Armour Spear.
These weapons came to me seeking
greater power for the battle ahead.
So I accepted their plea.
This is the newly reborn Sword of Dai.
May I draw it?
Ask it yourself.
The feel of it in my hand...
I've missed this.
Show yourself to me, my sword!
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
I finally realized it
imasara kizuitanosa
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
Must be the reason I was born
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
I shake off the clinging night
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
As Dai invents a new attack,
Ron Berku arrives, bringing the restored
Sword of Dai and other new weapons.
Morale is high, but Maam and Amy
are not their usual selves.
And Popp still struggles
to make his Insignia of Aban glow.
As the battle approaches,
things grow strained.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Night Before the Battle"
The adventure continues!