With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
motto Make you strong
You're The Bravest
Make you more strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
motto Make you strong
You're The Bravest
Make you more strong
MYST AND KILL
It's over.
Do what you want with us!
You won't resist?
Now that Popp is dead,
we have no way of defeating you.
We have no hope.
I can see just how central
that boy was to your group.
Come to think of it,
Kill respected him, too.
He said such people can become
the heart and soul of their team,
so they should be gotten rid of first.
His valiant efforts
are deserving of respect.
He even forced me to use the Phoenix Wing.
Phoenix Wing?
It's a high-speed palm strike
that reflects any spell.
Not even Medoroa is an exception to this.
I couldn't have survived that attack
without using this forbidden skill.
The Phoenix... The immortal bird...
That means...
Kaiser Phoenix.
I see! Then Mystban is Ban's...
I've got it!
I know Mystban's true identity!
And if I'm right, it makes sense
that he's this powerful!
Mercy is an insult. Kill me quickly.
But remember this,
Master Dai will kill you!
That's right.
The all-important Dai still remains.
I'll make it quick for you.
You can await Dai in the afterlife.
What?!
No matter how many times
Dai grows in power,
he can never kill Dark King Ban.
Of course he can't.
Hm?
How could he?
Dai can't kill Ban.
After all, the real Ban...
is here!
Right before our very eyes!
Huh?
That's right, Mystban!
You're the real Dark King Ban!
D-Don't be stupid!
You've all seen him together with
the Dark King numerous times yourself!
I knew it would be you, Hyunckel,
to be the first to realize the truth.
Ever since Mystban revealed his face,
I sensed a familiar presence.
It was none other than
Dark King Ban's presence.
While his voice may be youthful,
his mannerisms and fighting style
all line up with Ban's.
I suspect the reason Mystban
was forced to keep silent for years,
was because if someone
familiar with Ban heard his voice,
they might realize the similarities
between the two.
If the Dark King can't be silent,
then the shadow must.
But that shadow was really...
Don't bother with the rest.
Let me just say that
you're mostly correct.
You can figure out the rest
after you're dead.
Oh come on. He's said that much.
Why not tell us the rest?
Oh!
You...
I'd like to hear more about who you are.
Kill.
Where's Aban?
He's dead.
No!
You can find his hand over that way.
It can't be! Please! No more, please!
Miss Maam!
Tragedy upon tragedy.
But more importantly, Kill,
what did you mean by that?
Mean by what?
To say something as absurd as
wanting to know who I am.
Over these centuries,
you've seen me fight
revealed like this a few times.
And I said to you then...
"Don't bother asking."
"Not even you will be spared if
you knew the true meaning of this face."
I am no exception to that.
That's why, when I tried
to reveal this face before,
you threatened to kill me, didn't you?
So why?
Don't you go forgetting either.
I may be obligated to help the Dark King,
but I'm not duty-bound to.
That's right.
Of all the Dark Army,
only you are different.
You are nearly equal
to Dark King Ban himself.
I still remember
the day you first appeared before us.
So which... is King Ban?
I am.
And who are you?
Kilban... is what you can call me.
Kilban?
Then you are of his...?
Indeed.
I am a messenger from one you know well.
My specialty is assassinations.
I have dressed this way
specifically for you.
As a gesture of friendship from him,
I have been sent as an aide
to help you in your plans.
Hm.
As an aide...
What a joke.
And if my plans should happen to fail,
you will immediately attempt
to assassinate me, will you not?
A watchdog over my plan
to destroy the Surface World.
Kill...ban.
In other word, a coded name
meaning "Eliminate Ban."
Interesting.
You are truly the god of the Underworld.
You are very gracious.
This one, like yourself,
is a powerful being of the Underworld.
He is my right-hand man.
I was immediately impressed by you.
To appear before the Dark King
yet remain so calm.
Your brazen attitude was quite impressive.
Over the next few centuries,
while our personalities were opposite,
we got along well.
But it turns out
I'd been lied to this whole time.
I understand what you mean.
You were never truly
a servant of Dark King Ban.
Right.
You merely worked with him
under orders from your master.
If I'm the real Ban,
it would mean you've been
helping someone completely different.
And it would mean
our strange friendship was also false.
Am I wrong?
Yes. You're wrong.
There is no mistake in your aid to him,
and neither is there to our friendship.
Then why don't you just reveal
your secret to us here, Mystban?
What was that for?!
You are not the Reaper!
The official name of Mystban
was given to me after Kill arrived.
He doesn't call me Mystban!
He calls me by my old name of Myst!
Reveal yourself, faker!
Whoops. That was a mistake.
I overlooked a rudimentary thing
like what you call each other.
You!
Aban!
A Morph spell!
Huh?!
Using the Transformation Spell Morph,
he was pretending to be Kilban!
That's right.
I came to join you, but Hyunckel was
in the middle of solving the mystery.
So I thought I'd take Kilban's form
and have the secret revealed.
After all, he said it himself...
he may be obligated to help the Dark King,
but he isn't duty-bound to.
Where's Kill? What happened to him?
Seeing as I'm here, there only one answer.
The Reaper... was the one who died.
MEDOROA
REAPER FLUTE
The Reaper... was the one who died.
If Dai defeats him then that's that.
I may be obligated to help him,
but I'm not duty-bound to.
I'm not like Myst.
I'd like to hear
just how you're not like him.
Just his glove?! And it's full of sand?!
Aban!
It seems that this surprised even you.
This is magic sand that I concocted.
I uses Lunar Rurabloom
making it a marker against enemies.
I can use the Lilirura spell to catch up
to where this is applied.
And it works even if
a dimension is closed off.
You'd realize if I threw it on you,
so I snuck some in my glove
and grabbed your leg.
You may have intended to slice my wrist,
but I retracted my hand in that instant,
and successfully got my glove
and the sand back to this dimension.
It was the last gamble I could make
when grabbed by the Judge.
It's not your cheap parlour tricks
that surprise me!
Why?! Why are you still alive?!
After the Judge's Megante!
I don't know.
I can only call it a rare miracle.
I may be the only human who's suffered
a Megante spell twice in their lifetime.
But since I've survived, all that remains
is to use what life I have against you!
Here goes, Kilban!
Wave Strike!
He's fast!
He should have sustained heavy damage!
And yet he remains so strong!
I've been called the Reaper,
but for the first time, I'm scared!
I've used all the traps I can against him,
so how is he still alive?!
Well?
You've used all your Phantom Razors,
and your Judge is gone.
I doubt you've prepared any other traps!
This time, it's really over!
Don't worry about me.
I can survive even with my limbs
or even my torso severed.
I'm neither mad nor suicidal,
so any concern is unnecessary!
What is that sphere?!
One arm should be enough
to finish you off.
I never like to harm myself, so to make me
use this is quite a feat, Aban, the Hero!
You're one of the few men
King Ban feared.
I offer a final attack worthy of you.
It's called...
Incinerating Inferno!
What an intense fireball!
My blood is the same composition
as Underworld magma!
Once lit, it becomes
a blaze of scorching heat!
That's his true ace in the hole!
I doubt it can be stopped or dodged.
In that case,
I'll use my greatest attack against it!
Aban Strash, is it?
Hardly a threat!
It can't compare with this attack!
Says the man fighting seriously
for the first time in his life!
I won't allow insult!
I control the life and death of all!
I am the god of death!
Fool!
Beautiful! I was right
to use this attack to finish you!
It can't be!
I guess you should
stick to doing things you're good at!
Farewell, Reaper!
Aban Strash!
This is impossible!
How could he survive
my Incinerating Inferno?
How?!
Hadorra?!
Back then...
Hadorra's ashes
from when he died in my arms...
Did they protect me from the Megante
and Incinerating Inferno?
Hadorra, did you protect me?
Hadorra saved me through such a miracle.
I guess he really did despise
what you did, Reaper.
How dare you!
How could something as nebulous
as a miracle defeat me?!
Hadorra's body was made of Superior Being
cells that could emit Dark Fire Energy.
They remained as ashes,
shielding you from heat!
That's it. That's the only explanation!
A miracle... A miracle could never...!
When I used Aban Strash,
the residual blaze around me
caught on to his body.
It ignited the magma blood
that flows in his veins.
This is bad! This is very bad!
Hyado! Hyadaruko! Hyadain!
It's no good! Not for me alone!
Please! I'm begging you! Help me!
Kilban's going to be reduced to ashes!
I'll tell him not to be bad anymore!
Please! I'm begging you!
Aban...
Are you okay?!
Y-Yes. I think I am, Piroro.
I guess I should thank Aban.
Yeah. Exactly!
No thank you.
Sorry, but I don't fully trust you.
I've never encountered an enemy
so cruel and lacking of merit.
That's cold.
I insist you accept these.
You seemed to enjoy my Phantom Razors!
Yes! Yes!
With Piroro, I can restock my blades.
And as you're aware,
only I know where these 13 blades are.
And now the tables have turned!
I told you.
I was 100% certain this would happen.
That's why I already laid a trap for you.
What?!
If you want to keep
the life that I spared...
then don't move.
He's lying! It has to be a bluff!
Indeed.
You? Laid a trap? For me?
Don't make me laugh!
A Phantom Razor?
Why is it here?
That was one from
the other dimension that was stuck in me.
It came back to this dimension with me.
It was the 14th invisible blade
to the 13 you released.
That's why you didn't know where it was.
You planted it when you saved me.
I got sloppy...
It's no good. He can't be healed.
Even immortal, no living creature
can survive without its head.
The loser loses their head.
It's cruel, but those were his rules.
Darn it! Darn it!
Then Kill...
was defeated?
That little familiar of his
can't do anything.
Kilban, the Reaper is dead.
And now, thanks to what you've said,
I know your real identity, Mystban.
As well as Ban,
the Dark King's greatest secret.
What is that?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
We act tough and follow our hearts
hajimeta monogatari
And we began this tale together
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
We've been seeking something certain
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
mata kono sekai de
Again in this world
Having won against Kilban, Aban sees
through the Dark King's greatest secret,
and begins revealing it to everyone.
Meanwhile, Dai blew Ban away
with his Doru Aura, but dark clouds gather.
The dots of Ban's mystery connect,
and rise as the greatest threat.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Ban's Truth"
The adventure continues!