With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
CHECKMATE
King... Gaze!
As I thought!
You're so weakened
that a single hit will kill you!
You've taken so much damage that
Heal Type spells are no longer effective.
Just a nudge from a pawn and it's over.
I should warn you that no bluff
will work against my brain and eyes.
This brain contains all the battle data
that the Heyedras
have gathered on you lot.
I suggest you stop resisting
and die with one shot!
I have a question.
Hm? What is it?
I won't accept any pleading for your life.
You called yourself "Ban Palace's
greatest and most powerful guardian."
So why aren't you guarding Ban?
A simple warrior like you
who only sees the battle in front of them
would never understand.
Allow me to educate you.
The word "defeat"
doesn't exist in my lexicon.
Weeding out the weak and wounded
to decrease an enemy's numbers
is a rule of combat.
To enter battle means
victory must be assured.
My army, once deployed,
has never failed to wipe out an enemy.
To fight means to win!
That is how my army works!
Mystban should be holding off
the Hero and his friends at the moment.
First, I'll dispose of you weaklings
then I wipe out the Hero and his friends
keeping Mystban busy.
If I do that, I'll get credit
for wiping out all the intruders.
What a lowlife!
Do you understand?
Now it's time for you to die.
Actually, perhaps I should let
Mystban struggle a little longer.
He always looks down on me
and calls me the "Cleaner."
He should learn to be grateful to have me.
Who's the Cleaner of Ban Palace?!
A metallic lifeform born
from an Orichalcum chess piece.
What?! The Hadorra Royal Guard?!
We've already defeated all of them!
There are more chess pieces
than the ones you've beaten.
Have you fought the king?
Huh? Isn't Hadorra the king?
Hadorra isn't a chess piece.
It makes sense that
the real king is still out there.
Besides, there are pieces come in pairs.
So there are other Orichalcum warriors
besides the Hadorra Royal Guard?!
Not ones with their own wills like them.
Only the king was born with its own will.
And it appears the king
has finally decided to make a move.
I understand.
Hm?
You're utter filth!
You're not worth leaving alive!
This is why I love
finishing off the dying.
I can end your lives with just a snap.
Go forth, my pieces!
Look at that! A bum rush
by my pawns and he's finished!
Return!
Huh?
What's wrong? I said to return!
W-What?!
He shattered Orichalcum with his fist?!
That bastard! He did it!
They're different.
Huh?!
I was right.
They're different from Hym!
What are you babbling about?!
Knight!
And you aren't Sigma!
What?!
In the Hadorra Royal Guard...
Hym and Sigma and Albinass...
They were all great warriors
with their own wills!
They were powerful and loyal
and willing to die for their master!
But your servants are simply pieces!
They're mindless puppets!
Hyunckel...
Y-You arrogant little...!
King Gaze!
S-See?! You're barely alive!
It'll only take a scratch
to take you down! You just got lucky!
But it's all over now!
Take him, Bishop! In one sure strike!
Yes! I did it!
Th-That's impossible!
The flame of my life may dwindle...
but it can't be extinguished
by mere puppets!
Dammit! Go forth, rook!
You too!
You're hollow!
P-Pawns!
All of you, take him!
It's not dropping!
That last single point of damage!
A-All it should take is
one scratch to deplete it!
Why?! Why doesn't he die
from all those attacks?!
A-According to my databank,
the Dark Swordsman Hyunckel's
immortality is nothing but a label!
He should be a mere human!
I-In that case...!
Super Gaze!
L-Look at that!
There's no way anyone can safely
shatter Orichalcum bare-handed!
He's... He's beyond all healing!
S-So how...
So how can he still move?!
Amazing! The power driving Hyunckel
is greater than life itself!
That's... That's Fortitude!
All I have are five pawns left.
There's no way they can't
cause a single point of damage...
but I have to admit that he possesses
some kind of supernatural power.
My next... My next order is...
All return! Return and guard me!
He's... He's gone?!
W-Where is he?!
Right here.
They're just puppets.
They won't help you
unless you order them to.
You really are like
the king on a chess board.
All you can do
is order other pieces around.
You use your troops to surround
and corner your enemies.
Your tactical mind
is your only real strength!
If you really had any power at all,
you wouldn't have summoned
your troops back to you!
Checkmate, Maximum.
He's won!
GRAND CROSS
AURA KNUCKLE
King Access!
I can control my pawns with just a finger,
but it's not enough to defeat him!
I need to find a definite weakness.
Oh?!
Got it!
Hyunckel, finish them off!
Hym!
Stop!
Hey! Let go!
You idiot! You should just
forget about me!
I can't do that!
Damaged as you are,
falling from here would kill you!
Exactly!
So, what now?!
You can't do anything!
That's enough! Just let go!
He can't.
His past data proves it.
No matter what happens,
this man can't sacrifice
his friends to save himself.
Even if it means death for you two,
he can't choose his own survival.
He's just that kind of fool.
What? He considers me a friend?!
However, that's a mortal weakness!
You used to be a heartless warrior,
but all that compassion and love
from your friends has made you soft!
It's the one weakness
of the immortal warrior!
Love?
The fact that I discovered that
proves how great my mind is!
It's super, super great!
I see. I...
I did what Maam did.
To think... I could do that...
Hyunckel?
I'm sorry.
I was hoping to at least save you,
but I wasn't strong enough.
But if I'm going to lose
for my compassion or love...
that's a loss I proudly accept.
You idiot!
I share that opinion.
He's indeed quite the idiot.
And now I shall take
that last point of yours.
My fist is far greater than any pawn!
Now splatter into pulp, you weakling!
"Thud?"
Wh-Who dares?!
Wh-Who would display such insolence?!
"Such insolence"?
It's what I always do...
to scum who fight dishonorably.
I make it a point to impale them
with my Dark Spear.
Y-You!
Identify yourself!
Land Rider...
Larhart has arrived!
L-Land Rider?!
Larhart!
What? Who is that?
It seems that miracles
come in twos and threes.
Huh?
Like Aban, another amazing individual
has returned from the afterlife.
My greatest rival,
and the friend whose will I carry...
Land Rider Larhart!
Access!
Larhart. Former Dragon Legion follower
and one of the Dragon Masters.
Master of the spear and original owner
of the Dark Armour Spear.
According to my records,
he died in the fight with the Heroes.
Did you lose your way,
you lost soul?!
But my magnificent brain
obviously contains data on you, too!
I've already accessed it!
I already know all of your attacks!
Oh? That's impressive.
What sort of data?
Supposedly you possess great speed...
Your greatest attack
is your Hakendisutoru.
But, empty-handed,
you have no choice but to evade me!
To counter that...
Huh?!
That movement...!
Take a good look, Hym.
You're pretty fast,
but there's always someone faster.
Well? Could you see it?
My supposed "great speed"?
If simply knowing I'm fast was
enough to win, things would be easy.
At this rate, your other data
is probably useless in actual battle.
Take him, my pawns!
I see. In that case...
let me show you for posterity's sake!
This is the real...
Here it comes!
...Hakendisutoru!
Very well! I'll let you
have the victory for today!
But my army cannot lose!
Next time I swear...
There is no next time.
If you take one step
from that position you will die.
What are you talking about?!
Your hollow threats don't scare me!
Wait, you didn't even notice?!
He already shredded your whole body
at an incredible speed!
What?!
That's impossible!
You're all trying
to trick me, aren't you?!
King Access!
I get it! This is a psychological trap!
You can't trick me
with such uncertain information!
And now, goodbye!
Until we meet again!
Huh?
You reap what you sow. A fitting end.
That king really was a true idiot.
Wait! I could have been
one of those pawns!
Thank goodness I was born
as Lord Hadorra's servant.
That's one in eight...
What is this Larhart guy?
What happened between him and Hyunckel?
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
The one who saved Hyunckel and Hym
was the Dragon Master, Land Rider Larhart,
who was thought to have died.
Larhart dons the Dark Armour Spear
and heads off to Dai and the others.
Meanwhile, in the White Garden,
the stage is set
for the battle against Mystban,
the greatest enemy in the Dark Army.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Battle in the White Garden"
The adventure continues!