Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE HERO LOST IN THE GLACIER
I...
will take care of him.
Let's finish him this time!
Oh, of course.
Hadorra already took care of the Hero.
He may be a downgrade, but I would lose
face if I didn't kill a Disciple of Aban.
Why you...!
Bring it on!
I'll fight to the end alone if I have to!
That's right.
You have to avenge Dai, don't you?
He died trying to rescue you after all.
That's right!
Dai was defeated because of me!
Because of my recklessness!
If I lose my head and get killed fighting,
who's going to rescue Dai?!
Remember...
a Mage must always be
the most level-headed in the party.
Mentor!
How do I use what little
Magic Power I have left?!
The one thing I can do
for Dai right now is...
Come on now, little Mage.
Hey!
All I can do is run as far as I can...
and let everyone know what happened!
A wise choice.
He kept his cool
even after I provoked him.
Dammit!
Got you!
Big Guy!
That's right. There was another
from the Hero's party who could fly.
The Beast King's here!
Are you my opponent now?
Beast King Redemption Blast!
You're kidding.
The brave Beast King Crocodine
just up and ran away.
I've never let a target
escape me twice before.
That boy is beginning to irritate me.
Big Guy...
Are you okay?
I...
I didn't want to abandon Dai and run.
But... there was nothing else I could do!
I didn't have a choice!
I know.
You'd never choose to turn tail
unless the situation was severe.
That's why I ran without hesitation.
I know the sort of man you are.
Let's go back to Papunica.
Is it done?
No. I doubt he's unharmed,
but my Ultra Combustion Slash
didn't find its mark.
In that instant, Dai focused
all his remaining power into an attack,
which defended himself
by countering my Combustion Slash.
What combat instincts!
What an unyielding will to fight!
That must be the millennia of battles
etched in the blood of the Dragon Knights.
And the attack he used
in that instant was...
Gigabrake!
The spell was Raiden
and its power was weak...
but that was definitely the attack of
his father, General Baran!
He may say he rejects his father,
but it appears that the shadow of Baran
is a great influence on Dai.
Like father like son.
Don't die yet, Dai!
Otherwise, I'd have to question
why I bothered becoming a monster!
You idiot! You stupid fool!
-Stop it, Chiu!
-Come here!
Come here, you idiot!
You know, I was actually beginning
to think you weren't that bad!
And then you went off
and put Dai in danger!
You call yourself a friend of the Hero?!
I-I'm sorry, Chiu.
Everyone...
There's no excusing what I did.
It's all my fault.
Apologizing won't fix anything!
-Chiu, was it?
-Huh?
Try to forgive him.
Hyunckel?
He's just a fledgling. It's not his fault.
He's got enough on his plate
saving his own hide.
Go get yourself patched up
and get some rest.
Hey! D-Don't say that!
I'd rather take a fist to the face
than sympathy from you!
Crocodine, you'll have to search for Dai.
Right. Got it.
Hey!
Dai probably fell in the ocean
in the far north, northwest of Orzam.
Please hurry.
Hey!
Dai's no normal human. I doubt he's dead.
Hey, rat.
I've got room for someone your size.
Care to come?
Of course!
How wise of you to bring me along!
W-Wait! Let me come with you!
This isn't for the wounded or children!
Hey!
Dammit!
You can't search if you can't fly.
I doubt you have
the Magic Power for that right now.
Are you kidding me?!
Dai's lost because of me!
I can't leave this to someone else!
P-Princess, please!
You've got to do something!
Have you got a spell or something
that can heal Magic Power?!
I've never heard of a spell like that.
Oh, but...
Didn't I give the Papunica Troika some
Magic Water that heals Magic Power?
Yes. I believe Marin has it.
That's it!
And now he's all fired up.
You talked to him like that
on purpose, didn't you?
I figured it'd be more effective
than yelling at him.
Healing from wounds
caused by Dark Aura takes time.
I can't have him being morose
while I'm stuck in bed.
I need him on his feet.
Hmm. Sometimes it's hard to tell
if you guys rely on Popp or not.
-Please!
-Stop!
-I'm begging you, Miss Marin!
-Fine! You can have some!
-I'm begging you!
-Okay, now let go!
-You've got to!
- I said yes, so let go!
Huh?!
Here he comes.
I bet he's worried
that I'm going to outshine him.
Hold on, Dai!
I promise I'm going to rescue you!
What did you just say, Hyunckel?!
I said once Dai's safety is confirmed,
we should invade the Dark Army stronghold.
But...
Sovereign Rock Castle, the enemy's
first line of defense has fallen.
The only remaining
pillars of the Dark Army
are Hadorra, Mystban, and Kilban.
Our fight with
Dark King Ban is drawing near.
BEAST KING REDEMPTION BLAST
ULTRA COMBUSTION SLASH
Right here.
We can assume that Dark King Ban
is in the Field of Death.
Everyone, what is our course of action?
I agree with the Disciples of Aban.
We should invade the Field of Death.
Can we defeat them in an invasion?
We doubt we can defeat them all.
But if we can take even one of them down,
it will bring us that much closer
to Dark King Ban.
Very well then.
Now it's time to unite all of the world!
Come on, my fellow world leaders!
Yes.
King Bengana, do you object?
No. I have no objections.
It's just, I believe
we'd need that boy for this.
You mean Dai?
That's right.
I've been focused on weapons and arms,
but when I saw him save us,
I was honestly in awe.
Heroes truly are powerful.
My heart was pounding the whole time.
You were worked up
like a child back there.
Princess Leona, if he is successfully
rescued, I promise to help however I can.
I know they'll find him.
Dai's friends are searching the icy seas
from the sky as we speak.
But, isn't that close
to the enemy stronghold?
If memory serves,
the Field of Death
is a place that even birds avoid.
Perhaps it's because of
the Dark King's power.
Please be okay, Dai!
Dai, I'm going to find you!
This might take a while.
So it's time to face King Ban.
Mystban, I never confirmed Dai's death.
In fact, I'm almost certain he's alive.
I haven't wiped out
the Hero and his friends as ordered.
I've failed my promise to King Ban.
It's possible
I'll be executed on the spot.
That's why I'll say it now.
I used to shun you
for your mysterious nature,
but now I'm grateful to you.
Of all the six Legion Commanders,
it's possible that
you were the most sincere with me.
Underneath that mask of silence you wear,
I can't help but sense a fiery soul.
Hadorra...
I can now face my end with my head high.
Thank you.
Oh, don't be such a worrywart.
You've powered up greatly,
just like King Ban expected.
It'll be anticlimactic,
but he'll commend you and that'll be it.
He'll commend us?
Well, this was all thanks
to my research after all.
Huh?! What about me?!
King Ban, I, Hadorra, have arrived.
-Oh!
-Can it be?!
At ease, you two.
My heart feels bright and clear.
Like the sun shining through
the clouds above.
My face has never been seen
by anyone but you two.
But, I believe revealing it to Hadorra
is the best way
to express my approval of him.
What's wrong?
Does this ancient,
haggard face surprise you?
Are you...?!
Indeed.
I am Ban.
Dark King... Ban.
BAN, THE DARK KING
Is this truly the King Ban
that I've feared for so long?!
I sense the pressure from him.
There's no mistaking that immense presence
I feel through that thin veil.
But he's so incredibly old!
Does he really possess the power
of a god of the Underworld?
That frail neck...
As a Superior Being,
I could snap it so easily!
Care to try, Hadorra?
My King, forgive me!
Fear not.
That's what I've always liked about you.
That boundless spirit,
and heart that believes only in power.
Your recent behavior
had been rather uncharacteristic of you.
Seeing that spirit rekindled within you
puts me at ease.
I can never beat him.
He is truly worlds beyond me.
As I had hoped,
you have broken through your shell.
Your power is now
almost in league with my own.
I hereby rescind my previous order.
I would like you to continue your duties
as Dark Commander by my side.
If I may speak, my Dark King.
It pains me to say this
after you have granted me such mercy...
but there is something I wish to do
before being reinstated as Dark Commander.
Is this about the Hero?
Yes.
By any means, I wish to defeat
Dai and the other Disciples of Aban!
That is my final desire!
I beg you grant me this!
There is no need for such formalities.
Dai, the Hero, and his allies
are the greatest threat to my army.
What objection
would I have to their defeat?
The Six Legions are in shambles.
It seems unnecessary
that you command them.
Mystban, you will take command.
Yes, sire.
Hadorra, you will protect
the Field of Death.
Surely you won't object to that?
If Dai survived,
then they will surely
come to attack this place.
To take my head.
Indeed. I shall obey, my King.
And what should I be doing?
You will maintain your current role.
Very good, sire.
I suppose I'll continue
my morbid work for now.
Why?!
Why haven't they mentioned me?!
My Mystic Legion and I
are still in fighting shape!
They're acting like
I don't even matter anymore!
What did I suck up to Hadorra and
the other Legion Commanders for?!
I have to distinguish myself
to make Dark King Ban acknowledge me!
And for that...
What... happened to me?
Where am I?
In the ice?
I can't move.
My wounds haven't healed.
How did I survive like this?
I see. You protected me.
It's warm.
You kept me from being frozen in ice.
A crack!
Did Hadorra's attack cause that?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
You sustained such damage for me.
And you've been protecting me
all this time.
I have to get out of here!
Tell me, would you like
some more servants?
Sire?
The game of chess is quite deep.
It's thought to be a game of humans,
but it was originally
invented by the gods.
The beauty of chess
is in using the five types of pieces with
different abilities to protect the king.
The pawn moves forward
to defeat its enemies.
The knight leaps eight ways,
striking from above.
The rook charges horizontally or
vertically to decimate foes.
The bishop glides diagonally
like a phantom.
And, possessing the abilities
of both rook and bishop,
the queen is the most powerful piece.
Th-That shine!
Are those pieces made of...
Orichalcum?!
Indeed.
Very observant of you.
You can have those five pieces.
I haven't had anyone to play with
in a long time anyways.
If you use the Forbidden Magic
you used to create Flazzard,
and make those pieces the ultimate force
that would serve with you as their king...
wouldn't that make things interesting?
It's around here! I'm sure of it!
Dai's somewhere around here!
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Popp's party wanders
the freezing ocean in search of Dai.
Zaboera appears, seeking
to Kill Dai to earn recognition.
The two sides eventually clash.
Desperate, Zaboera attacks
using a terrifying Super Spell.
As the battle in the glacier intensifies,
a mysterious shining warrior appears.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Orichalcum Warrior"
The adventure continues!