With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE STEADY ADVANCE OF JUSTICE
Dark portal closed since ancient times...
I command you to open!
A-Amazing!
Check that out!
The gate opened like it's welcoming us!
Come everyone. Let us go.
Okay!
What is it, Dai?
Master, thank you!
Right now... with all my heart...
I'm truly glad that you came to help us.
Me and my dad had to work together
to shatter a door like this.
I was just wracking my brain
thinking about how to shatter this door.
But you showed us that
there was another way to open it.
Dai...
I'm sure of it now.
Dark King Ban's way of
"might makes right" is wrong.
Thank to you, I can truly believe that.
That's right.
Being powerless can be a problem,
but power isn't everything.
Knowledge and strength of heart
are forms of power, too.
Come. The true battle lies ahead.
We should hurry.
Yes sir!
Oh! They all got inside!
Let's crush this bug
and follow them!
You can't.
Now that the real father figure is back,
I can stop playing the older brother.
Now, I can be a warrior again.
What are you babbling on about?!
Everybody charge!
Don't you get it?
It means I can cut loose
without worrying about the consequences.
Bring everything you've got!
Today I feel no fatigue!
Huh?! Again?!
His second time today?!
Grand Cross!
Impossible!
None shall pass!
Oh wow.
Indeed.
I expected the castle of
an evil Dark King to be more gloomy.
But this is like a high-class palace.
It's more luxurious than any castle.
But its path is too linear.
There are two reasons
to build a palace like this.
Firstly, it displays its beauty
in a set route.
Secondly, if anyone should ever invade,
it forms a single path
that can be ambushed from either side.
This place looks magnificent...
...but Master Aban is right.
It's a single path the whole way.
Hyunckel will cut off any pursuit.
Our issue is how to defeat
enemies in our way.
Hold on!
Time out!
What's wrong?
I can't keep up! I'm exhausted again!
I'm out of Magic Power
and running drains any stamina I regain!
Come to think of it,
Popp's been exhausted the whole time.
Aren't you exhausted, too?
Nah. Running just gave me more energy.
How does his body work?
Please gimme a healing spell!
Huh?
I'm dying here! Don't abandon me!
How about I end your suffering with this?
Hmm. I see.
It can't be helped.
That settles it!
Let's take a break over there.
Huh?!
In the enemy castle?!
Yes.
I see my services
may be required, King Ban.
Ah, it's you.
You cannot leave things
to Mystban and the others.
Perhaps it is time you called upon
Ban Palace's most powerful guardian.
Do as you please.
My King!
Ah thank goodness!
I figured that we would need
this picnic set I brought!
What sort of situation was he expecting?
Honestly, what is up with you?
Suddenly saying we should
take a break in the enemy castle.
Hyunckel's still out there
fighting alone you know.
I may be in bad shape,
but I'm not about to rest here!
Popp!
M-Master, what are you...?!
Huh?
My Magic Power's restored.
That's a different feather from before.
This is a Gold Feather for attack.
It uses the Shining Stone,
a simplified gem of Kiseiseki.
It's an item for amplifying
the impact of magic.
And what I just used on Popp was this,
a Silver Feather for healing.
The gem is made from Holy Stone,
and can store Magic Power.
The Magic Bullet Gun I gave Maam
uses the same gem.
Oh really!
Then a stone that possesses
both properties is...
Exactly. The Kiseiseki
in your Insignias of Aban.
But Kiseiseki takes time to mature
even after its completed.
I was only able to create these two types
of Feathers in the Cave of Trials.
Ow!
Oh?
Popp, it looks like your Magic Power
hasn't fully been restored yet.
Huh?
This Feather contains enough Magic Power
to fully restore up to three normal Mages,
but it's completely empty.
When did I get that strong?
It looks like you've grown
in power a great deal.
How about another jab for good measure?
Uh, no thank you!
But I insist!
Healing up and readying yourself
is an important duty.
It may hurt a little, but it must be done.
To refuse would be an insult
to those out there fighting.
All right, Master.
Here, Maam. Use these
to restore everyone's Magic Power.
And heal their stamina with Healing Magic.
Yes sir. But what about you?
I'll take the time to go ahead for a bit.
There should be
more powerful traps laid ahead.
I'll get rid of them while I can.
TRAP-SMASHER HAMMER
I'll also map out the castle's layout.
Isn't it dangerous alone?
Yes. Good point.
So, Princess Leona.
Y-Yes?
Would you be so kind as to assist me?
M-Me?!
Yes sir.
Maam, look after the others.
Leona...
Don't worry. We'll be back in no time.
Stay put even after you finish healing.
You can enjoy the meal that I prepared.
Shall we?
What now?
Let's heal up.
This must be the meal he meant.
Wow. He's still the same Master.
Yeah. It feels like
he'll take care of Ban himself.
Don't get complacent
just because Master Aban's here.
We should assume we'll be fighting
without him like before.
Oh come on.
For now, we should heal up
like he told us to.
So we'll be ready to fight.
That way, Master won't have to
risk his life for us again.
Let's get this over with then!
But can we avoid
the jabs to the head this time?
Let's stick to the arm, okay?
Like there's a difference?
ABAGAMU
MINAKATOR
Master Aban,
what exactly do you need me for?
Unfortunately, Minakator is
the only Purifying Spell I can cast.
I didn't have time
to attain any of the others.
It's alright, Princess.
I brought you along for one reason.
I want you to have these.
You've giving these to me?
But why?
Because I believe you can take my place.
Me?!
Lord Mystban!
It... It wasn't supposed to be like this!
Your Underworld monsters
weren't that tough!
We've beaten them!
Now you're all that's left!
You underestimated us.
In the end, your Underworld monsters
were just a pack of beasts.
They don't know how to coordinate
or work together.
It looks like the humans here
have a greater sense of purpose.
In... In that case, I'll have to have
Mystban fight the humans!
I can use that opportunity
to escape from here!
It's my only choice!
Lord Mystban!
Please! I beg of you!
Show your great power!
With our legion of monsters defeated,
your power is all we can count on!
I shall return to Ban Palace
and protect King Ban!
In the meantime,
you can crush these fools!
You're certainly clutching at straws,
aren't you, Zaboera?
If you can't defeat these fools, what
can you do against Dai in Ban Palace?
Well...
They're arguing?
When you reap what you sow
they say it always comes
when you are at your lowest.
You've come a long way
by using others for your benefit,
but at the very end,
you chose the wrong target.
I shall return to Ban Palace
and protect King Ban.
I am under no obligation
to offer my help to you.
Lord Mystban!
Try doing things yourself for once!
Oh Zaboera...
either way, if you return to Ban Palace
with no results, you will be executed.
At least try to deal with these humans and
their Magic Circle of Light by yourself.
But...
Perhaps such efforts from a worm like you
will change King Ban's mind.
Lord Mystban... no, Mystban!
How can you say that?!
We're both former Legion Commanders!
I thought we were comrades
who fought together!
How can... How can you
abandon me like that?!
"Comrades..."
So you're finally resorting to
the platitudes of the servants of justice.
But Zaboera...
if we're such close friends as you say...
then you should know all too well
what I would say in this situation.
"Th-The Dark King's words..."
Exactly, "...take precedence above all."
He's been abandoned!
Zaboera used countless warriors
to further his own ambitions.
Now, for the first time,
he himself has been cast aside.
I see you understand.
Wait, Mystban!
You and I aren't through yet.
Are you going to run like a coward?
You can believe that if it suits you.
There aren't many in this world
who can fight me on equal ground.
To be honest, I'm relieved.
You are an impressive one.
Maybe if you had fought at full strength,
our battle wouldn't have taken so long.
Of course, the same could be said for me.
Mystban...
Farewell, Ron Berku. And you humans
with your unexpected mettle.
I respect anyone with powerful bodies
and minds, be they ally or enemy.
I promise to remember
your achievements this day.
But there's one ally here
that he never respected.
Zaboera, you're all out of options.
Surrender!
If you return to Ban Palace
you'll be executed.
That said, you're not stupid enough
to think you can beat all of us.
Stupid?
Stupid, am I?
What a joke! What a sick joke!
To have the poster boy of stupidity
call me stupid!
What?!
You think you're so magnanimous!
It's true that I wasn't
able to use Mystban!
But unlike all of you, I always
prepare a backup plan when I enter battle!
I still have ways to fight
without soiling my own hands!
The hundreds of monsters here
will protect me!
Don't be stupid! Your damn monsters
are all half-dead!
What?! Half-dead?!
No, no. We can't have that.
A spell?! Watch out!
We can't have that.
We can't have that at all!
You bastard! How can you slaughter
your servants like that?!
You fools wouldn't understand.
I need them as corpses.
Need them... as corpses?
They're the parts to my final weapon.
Parts?!
Superior Being Synthesis!
I've long considered
what the ultimate power up could be!
Superior Beings are incredibly powerful,
but they deplete life energy too fast!
I'll convert others,
but I'd never become one myself!
My wish is to have the ability
to remain completely unharmed
while moving freely at will
and easily crushing my enemies!
Th-The mindset of a scoundrel!
This is the result!
Superior Being Number Two...
I suppose I should call it
a Superior Being Zombie!
A Superior Being Zombie?!
So I guess you're just trying
to use size as an advantage.
Don't think that sort of play will work!
Yes!
Thank you for that mighty blow, Ron Berku.
You've confirmed my hypothesis.
This is the ultimate Superior entity!
Ron Berku overwhelmed Mystban!
And yet his blade...
...doesn't work!
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Cornered, Zaboera turned into
a Superior Being Zombie.
With a body of concentrated monsters,
not even Ron Berku's blade can cut it.
Just as it seems that the tables
have turned in the battle of Loroi Valley,
Nova, against the protest of those
around him, faces off with Zaboera.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Other Hero"
The adventure continues!