Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
ALL IN AN INSTANT
A Superior Being is invincible!
Maam, hit him in the stomach!
That should force him to spit out Dai!
Oh no you don't!
That kick was a feint!
Warrior Master Style Refractor Fist!
Yes! She knocked Dai free!
Dai! Thank goodness he's alive!
It must be thanks to the new clothes.
Maam, it looks like Dai's okay!
Chiu, use one of your items to heal Dai!
Okay! Leave it to me!
Th-This is...!
My immortal body...!
How?! How?!
That girl's incredible.
Maam's unbelievably strong!
And that special attack is amazing!
Impressed?
That's the essence of Grand Master
Brokin's Warrior Master Style,
and Miss Maam's greatest attack,
the Refractor Fist!
That's right. The Refractor Fist!
Maam, your progress
has been beyond impressive.
You've mastered in days what would take
normal Martial Artists years to complete.
All that remains is to teach you my
Warrior Master Style's greatest skill.
But I am ill and feeble.
It pains me that I can't show you myself.
Am I a disappointment?
N-No, of course not.
Um, Grand Master? What is your illness?
Kiaributtitis.
Huh?!
Why does Kiari-butt-itis
make you cough?
But I know you can master it, Maam.
Don't worry.
What sort of skill is it, Grand Master?
It's a combination of a certain spell
with the Warrior Master Style.
But Grand Master...
I used to be a Warrior Priest.
I can't use attack spells.
Attack spells aren't the only way
to defeat an enemy.
Huh?
That spell is...
Hoimi.
Hoimi?!
Hup!
Hoimi is a spell that magically
boosts a body's biofunctions.
But, just as plants wither
when given too much nourishment,
excessive healing magic
can destroy a body's tissue.
Long ago, such excessive healing magic
was feared and known as "Mahoimi."
Mahoimi...
Only the most powerful Priests and Sages
could wield Mahoimi
as a trump card against monsters.
But, in time, users of the spell
all disappeared.
The amount of Magic Power Mahoimi uses
is magnitudes above a Behoimi spell.
However, by using healing spells
with the Warrior Master Style Fighting,
I developed the technique to generate
devastating force at the moment of impact.
When used, it creates
an overwhelming anti-creature effect
applying a fatal shock to an enemy's body.
Fatal to an enemy's body?!
A truly terrifying skill.
Yes. It's a terrifying skill.
Only those who can understand
just how terrifying it is can be taught.
I've been called a Grand Master
for decades now.
But you, Maam, are the first
I've ever thought worthy to teach.
Grand Master...
Just as your first Master, Aban, trusted
you and gave you the Magic Bullet Gun,
I, too, trust your kind and just heart.
That's why I will teach it to you, Maam.
Thank you, Grand Master!
Wow!
Aren't I cool?
Oh boy...
Oh wow.
That's Miss Maam for you!
Dai, you're awake!
Was I rescued?
Yeah! Thanks to Maam!
Be grateful!
It's amazing.
I didn't know you could fight like that.
Dai!
Hey! Aren't you supposed
to have some item?!
If so, hurry and heal Dai!
Oh, right!
I'll give you a medicinal herb,
so be grateful.
Here!
That's an antidotal herb.
That's a poison herb!
What the heck?! They're gone!
I always carry around
five medicinal herbs!
That's right!
I used them all when I was attacked by
Teeny Sangiuni in the mountains!
Who uses five whole medicinal herbs
against such squibs?!
It's over!
Oh no!
Good! It looks like
my brain's still sharp!
You have two types of attacks!
Attacks where your hands glow,
and where they don't!
In other words, that attack can't be used
with your whole body.
I deduced it can only be done with your
hands, and only at the moment of impact!
Give it up!
That's a special coating mucus!
It won't come off easily!
It's time to give up!
Oh no!
If she can't use her glowing fists...!
What can we do?!
Don't you have anything?!
For me or Dai!
Something to heal our stamina!
Oh! This is...
A Teardrop Acorn!
What's that?! Is it useful?!
As the name implies, it'll cure
a sparrow's teardrop worth of stamina!
That's useless!
No. It's enough! That's all I need!
Give it up!
Without that attack, you have nothing
that can hurt my immortal body!
Die, little girl!
Maam!
Please, Chiu, take me
and that acorn up there!
Hurry!
REFRACTOR FIST
DARK INCENSE
Die, little girl!
Maam!
Run! Get out of there, Maam!
Dai, if you're planning something, hurry!
You're a lot heavier than you look.
Sorry.
But I can't spare the stamina
to climb up there.
I need to release it
all at once at the very end!
Huh?
Watching Maam fight,
I realized just how wasteful I've been
while using the power of my crest.
I've been fighting
with my power at full throttle.
That's why I always use up
all my energy in no time.
Like Maam's glowing fists,
I should focus and release
all my energy at the moment of impact!
Even if it's just a little bit of power,
if I use it all at the last moment...
I can beat him!
You've caused me quite a bit of trouble.
I'm curious about
that strange attack you used,
but threats like you
should be eliminated on the spot!
Dai?!
He's going to the Sword of Champions!
I see! Dai's planning to do something!
I have to do everything I can
to distract this thing!
How typical of you guinea pigs.
You desperately resist,
even when you know you're going to die.
You're nothing more than trash!
No life is trash!
No matter what creature it is!
If you can't see that,
then you're the real trash!
Listen to me, Zamuza, you are a tool.
Not just you. Every creature
in this world is a tool for me.
Gain power and knowledge.
Use it for my benefit.
Father...
Otherwise, you're nothing but trash!
Isn't that right?
A useless tool
is nothing but trash, isn't it?
I'm...
I'm not trash!
My power and mind are the greatest!
I could be the Legion Commander of
the Mystic or Furfang Legion if I wanted!
How dare you mock me?!
Maam!
Miss Maam!
Chiu! Give me that acorn!
Right!
Did it work?
Yeah. It's only a little,
but I feel my strength returning!
Sword of Champions, lend me your power!
What?!
That brat! When did he reach the sword?!
A Mera spell!
Where did you come from?!
Just cast a Mera spell!
Sure I've got enough Magic Power
for a Mera spell,
but that won't help!
Fire it at Maam.
Huh?!
Hurry.
Okay!
Maam!
Mera!
Use it on the mucus!
No!
Refractor Fist!
Now!
All I have into this instant!
Aban...
Strash!
How's that?!
Did it work?!
We won!
What?!
Impossible!
I'm the ultimate Superior Being!
How can these pieces of trash...?!
Hooray!
They did it!
They defeated him!
How? How can this be?
Where did my calculations go wrong?
There was no way I could lose.
How?!
Who knows? Try asking the rat.
This cornered rat right here.
Huh?
The rat?
I see.
What led to my defeat
was assuming lower creatures were trash.
The error was in my own heart.
Well done, Dai!
That was an amazing Aban Strash!
Yeah. It's thanks to
the Sword of Champions...
Huh?! No! The Sword of Champions!
Not even the legendary sword
can endure Dai's Dragon power?!
No! That's impossible!
The Sword of Champions, much like
the Crown of Champions I gave you,
is made from
the legendary metal, Orichalcum!
Orichalcum is said to be everlasting!
Then why?!
Sorry to disappoint you.
That's an elaborate fake.
The real Sword of Champions
has already been offered to Lord Hadorra.
What?!
A-And...
if I can offer this,
my mission will be complete!
To my father!
What the hell did you do?!
I sent it to my father.
It contains the results of
my Superior Being research.
As well as all my knowledge.
With that, my father can continue
and complete the research.
You idiot! You father is Zaboera!
Do you think he'll be grateful
to you for that?!
I'm well aware of that.
My father sees everyone
other than himself as tools to be used.
I doubt he'll shed a tear even if I die.
But, despite what he is,
he is still my father.
Zamuza!
This is the fate of those
who become Superior Beings.
When defeated, not even a corpse remains.
They crumble as black ash.
Perhaps it's punishment
for toying with the life the gods gave.
Zamuza...
Save me your pity.
I'm quite satisfied how things turned out.
For just a fleeting moment,
I had the word's most powerful body.
And I got to fight with you.
But someday...
Someday a complete
Superior Being will come defeat you.
My... My fight was not in vain.
That right.
It could not have been... in vain.
You know, he probably just
wanted to be praised by his father.
No matter what he said, deep down,
he must have wanted his father's love.
I can understand.
I kind of understand how he felt.
Well done! Well done indeed, Zamuza!
Your life was but a brief 200 years,
but it was quite worthwhile!
Be proud in the afterlife!
Your research shall produce
the greatest, most powerful Overfiend
in the Dark Army!
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Dai, the Tiny Hero.
His adventure with his friends has been
filled with battles against powerful enemies.
Next time, a look back on
the trail of Dai's Adventure.
THE TRAIL OF ADVENTURE, THE PATH FORWARD
The adventure continues!