nakama tono kizuna wo
With your bonds with your friends
sono mune ni idaite
Embraced in your heart
hikari no you ni isshun ni
Like a flash
In an instant
subete wo kaketeku
You risk it all
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
tachimukatte ikunnda to
You will face it again
kakugo wo kimetanara
If that's what you choose
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even when hurt
Oh tsumazuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
susume kono tabi no hate
Continue on
To your journey's end
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Again and again
To the future you make
Oh Oh
tachiagareru
You're The Bravest
You can stand up
Oh Oh
tachiagareru
You're The Bravest
You can stand up
Fly up to the world
Never let go
Never let it go
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
Fly up to the world
Never let go
Never let it go
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
THE ABAN STYLE ULTIMATE TECHNIQUE
What's wrong, Lord Hadorra?!
My conversion to Superior Being
was a rapid one.
It put a strain on me.
Should I continue to fight,
I won't last long.
Is beating Dai and his friends worth it?
It is!
I'd gladly pay with my life!
I want to know!
I want to know how powerful I can be
if I cast everything aside for it!
Power is a hollow glory.
No matter how strong,
there's always someone stronger.
Dragon Knights, King Ban...
I have no idea just what level
I can achieve.
But I'd like to die as a more powerful
being than the Disciples of Aban.
I managed to kill Aban,
but his students kept appearing
and threatening me.
I merely killed Aban. I didn't defeat him.
I can't bear to die still losing to him.
Lord Hadorra...
Forgive me.
You were born from Forbidden Magic.
You can't live if I die.
It doesn't matter!
We are your pieces!
Use us to fulfill your ambitions!
If it means dying for you...
I would gladly be shattered to pieces!
Hym.. your eyes...
Why is water coming out of my eyes?
I'm not human!
Hym... weeps?!
Forgive me, Lord Hadorra.
Fenbren?!
No wonder this place is called
the Field of Death.
Let's hurry and find Chiu!
Chiu!
Are you okay?! You better be alive!
Chiu! Hang in there!
Oh. So you all saved me.
What are you talking about?
I found this for you. Be grateful.
Once I give everyone
the new intel I've discovered,
they will all be grateful to me.
Idiot! That's enough!
You idiot! Going to such lengths!
I'm going to totally chew you out
when we get home!
He thinks we drove off his assailant.
Yeah.
From his wounds,
it was the bishop that attacked him.
What's wrong?
Popp, take Chiu and the others and go!
Huh? What's the problem?
Even with these extra guys
I can still take everyone.
Forget about us.
Go back to base and see to their wounds.
Don't be stupid! You may be strong but...
Please! Popp!
Sure...
I don't know what it is, but be careful!
What was that about?
Come on out!
I know it's you hiding there!
It's been a while, you two.
Baran?!
I thought I completely hid my presence.
You've gotten better, Hyunckel.
You were wise to send that Mage home.
He lost his life once because of me.
If he saw me,
he might not be able to stand.
Have you come to settle things with Dai?!
Keep away from Dai!
The humans are about to gather
all of their forces
to attack Dark King Ban!
Dai needs to be at their head!
I'm of the same opinion, Baran!
That's why I chose to stay here!
I'll risk my life to prevent that fight
from ever happening again!
You can risk your lives,
but you cannot defeat me.
What?!
Settle down.
I don't care about any of you, even Dai.
My objective is the Dark King himself...
Ban alone!
Dark King Ban?!
You're here for his head?!
Why?!
I owe you no explanations.
He cannot be allowed to live. That's all.
Wait Baran!
Then our objectives are aligned!
Let us put the past behind us
and work together!
You rescued Chiu, didn't you?!
With you by our side,
our forces will be considerable!
Please!
For Dai!
Crocodine! Get away!
Over my dead body!
Crocodine!
I am Dragon Master General Baran!
Don't insult me!
The humans are also an enemy
that must be defeated!
I would rather die than help them!
I merely saved the little rat
because I stumbled on him while searching
for an entrance to Ban's stronghold.
It was just a whim.
I now know the entrance is underwater.
They claim not even a Dragon Knight
can penetrate it.
We'll just see about that.
Wait Baran!
Go alone and the enemy
will focus their attack on you!
And?
I'll face Ban's minions
no matter how many hundred he sends!
From here on is between
the true Dragon Knight and the Dark King.
A battle beyond
your imagination will unfold.
Go back if you want to live.
Back to Dai.
Those eyes...!
He's not the same Baran I once knew!
Could it be...?!
Our base of operations
has become a field hospital.
We can still regroup.
Chiu and the others are okay.
They've been healed and are all asleep.
Thank goodness!
Now if Hyunckel and Crocodine
can just come back safely...
Popp, how could you leave them behind?!
Well, it's just that
he got so serious all of sudden.
I couldn't say no.
Why would Hyunckel act like that?
What's wrong?
I'm not sure.
Wait!
I can't let you go any further!
That's enough.
I didn't come here to thrash you two.
I know... no, I finally realize
what you're really after!
You intend to throw away
your life for Dai!
Not even a Dragon Knight can emerge from
a fight with Dark King Ban unharmed.
You're not expecting to.
But I won't allow that!
I can't let you fight such a hopeless
battle, even if it's for Dai!
If it's for Dai, then wouldn't
letting me go be more beneficial?
Why stop me?
If you go alone, you'll die!
I can't allow that to happen!
No...
I leave Master Baran
and Master Dino in your hands.
This Dark Armour Spear I wield...
can't allow that to happen!
Larhart?
You would try to dissuade me?
Do you think I'll just listen
and obey you?
Never!
Sadly, my only choice is to defeat you
before Hadorra detects us.
What is that stance?
To cast aside his weapon
in the face of battle?
What is he up to?
His Aura... is gone!
BLOODY SUKURAIDO!
NEEDLE THOUSAND
Hyunckel's Aura has completely vanished!
He's like a still pond
without a single ripple.
You drop your weapon
while facing Baran?! Are you insane?!
Don't worry, Crocodine.
Besides, it looks like Baran realizes
just how dangerous this skill really is.
What?!
I can't sense any Aura from Hyunckel!
Baran's begun quelling his own Aura!
What's going on?!
Now my Aura is the strongest one here!
I see. This is a self-sacrificing move.
Self-sacrificing?!
Unleashing a powerful attack creates
an opening for anyone.
You intend to allow that attack,
thereby forcing that opening,
which you'll exploit with a counterattack.
When I read my master Aban's book, there
was one skill I thought impossible for me.
Fifteen years ago, when Aban fought
the Dark Lord Hadorra,
he attained this technique.
It's the Aban Style Ultimate Technique...
The Hollow Stance!
The Hollow Stance?
Against a powerful attack from an enemy,
in order to avoid a fatal blow,
one must completely erase their Aura,
and ride out the force of the attack.
But one cannot reach such a state
with a weapon and intent to kill.
So Aban chose to cast his sword aside.
Come on, Hadorra!
Fool! Have you given up?!
This is the end!
Aban...
Strash!
Aban used the Hollow Stance
and Aban Strash.
By combining the ultimate passive
and active techniques, he defeated Hadorra.
I, on the other hand,
always held my weapon for revenge.
To cast it aside and force myself
into such a hollow state...
always seemed like pure absurdity.
Even so, Baran, this is probably
the only skill that will have an effect.
Using the Hollow Stance, I'll create
an opening and use a counterattack.
I get it!
The stronger the attack, the greater
the opening the Hollow Stance creates!
For someone as overly powerful as Baran,
it's truly a terrifying skill!
That's why he tried
to suppress his own Aura to fight.
You've grown into
a terrifying foe, Hyunckel.
I tried to suppress my own Aura,
but I can't erase it like you.
That state cannot be reached
without the strongest of resolves.
Hyunckel? Who's he fighting?
That man...!
What?! Baran's begun increasing his Aura!
Correct. That's your only option.
You'll attack, but hold back.
Once you endure my counter,
you'll unleash your second attack.
That is, if you can endure my counter.
Baran means to put himself at risk too?!
Hyunckel, you've shown me your resolve.
As you wish, I shall face that skill.
Here goes, Hyunckel!
Larhart, not a day goes by
that I don't think about you.
This attack will be the best I can do.
Should I fail to stop Baran,
you can laugh at my foolishness
from the afterlife.
Dragon Master Baran?! That's him?!
Deserter of the Dark Army,
and Dai's father.
There's no telling when he'll turn
against Lord Hadorra.
This is perfect.
We can eliminate both of them here.
Don't do it, Albinass!
They may be our enemy,
but you can't interrupt a duel.
Who knows how angry Lord Hadorra will be?
I shall take full responsibility.
All is for the sake of Lord Hadorra.
All threats must be weeded out!
Here goes!
Albinass!
What happened?!
Did you get them?!
That wound...!
No wonder you like him.
Hyunckel...
What a terrifying warrior.
Albinass!
He's no longer a threat now.
That's the one silver lining.
So it was you, Baran...
who rescued me from that explosion.
Wait! Hyunckel!
Where's Hyunckel?!
Hyunckel!
It's too late.
He lives, but he'll never fight again.
How...
What in the world could do this to him?!
In that instant,
the Dark Army interrupted our fight...
and attacked.
I was so focused on attacking Hyunckel
that I couldn't do anything else.
Hyunckel and I would both have been
caught off guard and died.
That's when Hyunckel...
Needle Thousand!
Bloody Sukuraido!
Hyunckel used his Hollow Stance
on the Dark Army instead...
driving them off.
All while knowing
he'd take the full force of my attack.
His words weren't just dull platitudes.
He was willing to give his life
to save mine.
Hyunckel...
Crocodine, what must I do?
How can I ever repay this man?
Don't ask me!
It shames me Baran,
but deep down,
I wanted you to fight Ban!
I thought it would benefit the humans!
I figured it was futile
to try to stop you!
And yet...
And yet, Hyunckel still...
I don't deserve to say anything!
He can be cold,
but he's a man I'm proud to call a friend!
Just respect what he was trying to do!
I see.
The Great Citadel, Ban Palace.
The Dark Citadel Gate lies underwater.
Chiu did a good job in finding it.
I think I have to go there...
while everyone is fighting
the Hadorra Royal Guard on the surface.
Wait a minute, Dai!
Not even a Dragon Knight
can destroy the gate.
It's too dangerous to go alone.
You need someone to go with you.
I'll go. Leave it to me!
You're our key player
against the Royal Guard!
I'll go instead!
I shall go!
Baran?!
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
I finally realized it
imasara kizuitanosa
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
Must be the reason I was born
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
I shake off the clinging night
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
Baran's appearance
takes everyone by surprise.
While uncertain, Dai sets out
on a collaborative mission with Baran.
Dai and Baran split up with the others
to head for the Dark Citadel Gate.
What will they find waiting for them?
With much on their minds
they head to the Dark Army stronghold.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Father and Son Dragons Set Out"
The adventure continues!