With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE PERIL OF
THE GREAT PURIFICATION SPELL
G-Gods!
Popp?
What's wrong, Popp?!
I knew it...
I knew it wouldn't work!
I can't do it!
I sense a tremendous number of monsters!
Popp!
What's wrong, Popp?!
Popp, it's okay!
If you... If you just
relax and try again...
It won't work.
Huh?
It's no good, Princess.
My Insignia of Aban won't glow
no matter how much I try!
I've tried time and time again!
It's never glowed!
I already know.
About the Insignias
and the power of our souls.
You all did it just by thinking...
but I can't even get mine to flicker!
I trained desperately,
but nothing changed!
I took this last make-or-break shot...
but it still didn't work!
I'm sorry, guys.
It's all... It's all my fault!
But my strength
just isn't enough for this!
Popp...
Master...
Why'd you give this to...
someone as inept as me?!
It's no good!
At this rate, even if Leona casts
Minakator, it won't be strong enough!
Popp...
Those are...!
We're completely surrounded!
I've never seen these monsters.
How could I not sense all these monsters?!
Because they were in those Magic Capsules.
They set a trap for us.
Behold! The elite warriors
of the New Dark Army!
They're all monsters from the Underworld,
the home of us Darklings!
-What?!
-The Underworld?!
Monsters of the Underworld are far more
powerful than Surface World monsters!
You pieces of filth
don't stand a chance against them!
O-Oh yeah?!
They'll make quick work of you.
Kill them all!
Oh no! Even with Crocodine,
there's so many...!
We have to help!
Right!
Don't!
You must complete Minakator!
If you move from there, the power
of the four of you will vanish!
Leave the fighting to us!
You just need one more to complete it!
Wait, Queen Flora! I...!
Popp, Aban would never choose
the wrong person.
Don't worry. We'll handle the Dark Army!
There's no way you can handle them!
If we can't move, our forces...
Crocodine, how many can you handle?
They may be unknown, powerful monsters,
but I can take 40 or 50 of them!
Dai and the others
have to focus on Minakator!
We have to hold off the enemy ourselves!
Well said, Hero of the North!
As former head of the Furfang Legion
I should be able to handle about 100!
Let's finish this!
Attention!
All of you relax!
So what if they're from the Underworld?!
Show them the Beast King Commando spirit!
EVERYONE THINKS,
"CAPTAIN IS AMAZING!"
Ursula, Drohly, Nibbles,
hold off the enemy!
Terry, Drack-Drack, Rumbles,
attack from above!
Otoad, Spikey, Seari,
run around to cause confusion!
Gomechan, you're the messenger!
Tell Dai and the others to hurry!
Don't worry. Mr. Beast is right there!
Look at his bravery!
Everybody, follow Mr. Beast!
Whoa!
Listen! Don't try to win!
Be a wall!
All we have to do is hold them off
while the Princess completes her spell!
Let's go!
Stop!
Let me tell you the same thing
you once said to me, Ron Berku.
So long as the two of us are tied up here,
you have no hope of victory!
The tables have turned.
What the hell is taking so long?!
Yeah. We already know.
Popp, everyone is trying to hold
the monster army at bay!
Hurry! You have to try again! Popp!
Princess, let's make a tactical retreat!
It's no good.
No matter how long I try here,
I don't think it'll work.
We've rescued Hyunckel. If we retreat now
and try again when we're ready...
Popp, I told you.
There's no second chance.
Having come this far, our enemy will never
let us approach Ban Palace again.
This is our last chance to cast Minakator.
But I'm not...
Besides, if you run now,
your Insignia will never glow.
The soul's power makes Kiseiseki glow.
There's no difficult technique to it.
The problem is inside of you.
If you choose to run now,
your soul will have lost.
Your Insignia will never glow
no matter what.
Why?! Why can't Popp do it?!
He has such a kind and honorable soul!
Then...
Then just give this thing
to somebody else!
Popp?!
I'm not... I'm not like any of you!
I'm not royalty
or any kind of born warrior!
Popp?!
MEDOROA
DARK INCENSE
Courage, Fortitude, Justice, Love...!
What else is there?!
A power unique to my soul?
Do I really have that?!
If so, tell me what it is!
If there's some way to do this
I'll do whatever it takes!
If you guys have the answer then tell me!
Popp...
Please, Princess.
I can't bear to see anyone die for me!
We all will die anyways.
Along with all the people
of the Surface World.
Clear your mind, Popp.
I was once steeped in evil,
and yet my Insignia now glows.
You've pursued justice.
There's no way you'll fail.
Yeah! You gave me
the final bit of courage I needed, Popp!
Popp, I believe in you.
I know you can do it.
I know how strong your soul is.
No matter the odds, you've always stood
strong. I admire you more than anyone!
I...
I don't want admiration from you!
Go! Go!
Hm?
Those five...
They must be forming up for
some kind of spell of light.
One isn't glowing. It's that Mage brat!
That's it!
If I can put a stop to that spell
while crushing the remaining human forces,
it will be an even greater
contribution to King Ban!
If I do that, no matter how much
that Mystban despises me,
King Ban will accept me!
Let's finish him with this.
A life falls for my bright future!
Everyone, fight with
your hearts of justice!
Popp, cast aside your doubt!
You are a true Disciple of Aban!
Why...
Why do you always say such things?!
I was...
I was just expressing how I feel!
It's because he's in love with you, Maam.
And yet, to be told what you feel for him
is just admiration...
Is there... Is there anything I can do?!
Any little thing for Popp in his plight!
Is there any way I can be useful to Popp?
What is this evil power?!
Where?! Where is it?!
A horrid mass
of malice and Dark Power...!
This Venom Chain has been steeped
in my Dark Power,
making it a bullet to pierce my enemies.
Even just a scratch on the body
is enough for its deadly poison to kill.
It may not work on those four
bathed in holy light,
but it will be fatal to him!
Up there!
Come, Popp. This isn't the time to argue.
Try again.
That's right, Popp!
I don't believe that you can't do it!
Hurry!
Popp!
You think too much of me.
If I run now, you won't have
a reason to keep standing here, will you?
Popp!
I don't have it in me.
I just...
I just can't stand watching others
get hurt because of me!
If this makes you think
less of me, so be it!
Now!
Somebody, stop that projectile!
Stop it!
Yes!
M--
Meruru!
No!
Dammit! That little girl got in the way!
You bastard!
Somebody! A Hoimi spell!
She needs a Hoimi spell!
Anybody!
I'll do it!
Wait.
Meruru!
None of you must move.
Meruru...
I'm beyond help now.
Don't let your Circle of Magic
go to waste because of me.
I know Popp will be the fifth star.
Meruru, why?! Why did you...
Why did you do this?!
Because you were suffering.
I wanted to help.
This weapon was aimed at you.
I'm the only one who saw it.
But you didn't have to be a shield for me!
Not for someone worthless like me!
Why do you have to die for me?!
You idiot!
You're so thick!
Meruru believes in you more than anyone!
That's because she's in love with you!
How could you, Princess.
I wanted to tell him myself someday.
Meruru...
No... That's not true.
I doubt I'd ever be able to say it.
I don't have the courage.
Popp, I've always loved you.
From the first time we met.
You always act like a clown,
but you're so strong inside.
No matter your suffering,
your fear, or your sadness...
you always, always overcome it in the end.
For someone withdrawn like me,
you are my inspiration.
But I couldn't say it.
I followed you so I could be near you,
but I could never say how I felt.
I was so afraid that doing so
would ruin what relationship we had.
I always hated how weak I was.
But look at me now.
For the first time,
I've been useful to you.
Meruru!
Oh no! The wound's too deep
and she's been poisoned!
Even a Behoma spell couldn't...
Just cast Hoimi on her!
Popp...
Will you grant my last request?
I know the answer.
It's just a selfish request.
Tell me who it is
that you're in love with.
I already know who it is.
And that it's not me.
But I want to hear you say it.
That way I can give up.
That way, when I'm reborn again...
maybe I can be someone
with bravery like you.
I'm sorry, Meruru.
I...
I'm...
I'm in love with Maam!
My Insignia of Aban! It's glowing!
Why?! Why is my Insignia...?!
Is it...?!
I don't have the courage.
That's it. The power of my soul...
was Courage!
Then it wasn't Dai!
The one with the soul of Courage was Popp!
I was just like Meruru.
I was afraid of ruining things
with Maam and the others.
Meruru, look! My Insignia...
No! Meruru! Please! Open your eyes!
You can't die! You can't!
Please don't die for someone like me!
Popp's a Mage,
and yet he's using healing energy?!
Like...
Like a Sage!
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
I finally realized it
imasara kizuitanosa
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
Must be the reason I was born
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
I shake off the clinging night
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
Thanks to Meruru,
the power of Popp's soul awakens.
His Insignia of Aban glows with the color
of Courage, and the Pillar of Light rises.
The Disciples of Aban
restart the ritual to cast Minakator.
In Ban Palace, someone awaits them
that not even Dark King Ban expected.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Last Challenge"
The adventure continues!