Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE FINAL AVAN STYLE TECHNIQUE
Zaboera!
Wait a minute! I'm not...!
Take this!
I'm not him!
A Morph spell?!
It's too bad that
that wasn't the real me.
I'll eventually show you dimwits
that I'm on a different level up here.
Sneaky little imp.
Mystvearn's gone, too.
What did I...
Where's Hadlar?
I remember killing him...
Valge tower. We're finally here.
We have to hurry
or Leona won't make it! Let's charge in!
I knew you'd say that.
Let's go!
Halt!
The Blizzblaze Legion!
We won't let you get to Master Flazzard!
Get them!
Bagi!
Dai?!
We don't have time to hang around here!
-Popp!
-Right!
Merazoma!
The Frostburn!
Okay! Now for the Dancing Flames!
Maam!
Got it!
Here goes! Hyadaruko!
We did it!
Anything's possible
if we work together, huh?
Okay! Let's go!
Right!
Flazzard!
Sitting back and waiting
with the hostage just isn't my style.
Here you go!
That's one down!
That axe...!
Your savagery ends here!
Crocodine!
So you were helping them!
It wasn't just me.
Hyunckel!
See? I told you.
You can't kill a guy like him.
Wait. Does that mean he beat Hadlar?!
Bastard.
I remembered I owed you
much like I did Hadlar.
So I came back from the depths of hell.
There's no escape now.
What's wrong?! You giving up?!
I guess so.
Huh?!
My Blizzblaze Curse Field's gone.
And with two Legion Commanders
on your side, even I can't win.
I guess it's time to face the fact.
He's acting awfully well-behaved.
Flazzard's not one
to say something like that.
So you'll admit defeat and release
the Princess of Papnica?
Don't be stupid.
Even if I lose everything,
I'll never give up a chance at victory!
Then what was that about facing the fact?!
I meant the fact that
I won't get through this unscathed.
The final attack I'm about to use
hurts me real bad.
I'd prefer not to use it, but...
Dark King Vearn, grant me glory and victory.
What?!
You're throwing away your medal?!
What's so important about that?
The day Sovereign Rock Castle
was completed...
That's right.
It was the first time we
Six Legion Commanders had gathered.
Oh great Dark King Vearn,
the Six Legion Commanders to lead
the Dark Army are before you now.
This Sovereign Rock Castle shall be our
base as we plunge the world into darkness,
and offer it to you, King Vearn.
Well done, Hadlar. I am most pleased.
My king.
To celebrate the Six Legion Commanders,
I shall grant a gift.
A gift?
W-What the...?!
Huh?
What's that?
That is the Infernal Emblem. Consider it
the greatest symbol of loyalty to me.
Now, whoever believes
themself worthy may take it.
What intense flames!
But we must prove our loyalty
to King Vearn!
Well done, Flazzard.
That's when he gained the title
"Blitz Captain of the Dark Army."
That medal is a symbol of his glory.
To him, it's almost worth life itself.
And he threw it away?!
Who needs past glory?!
If it will let me claim new victory...
I'm willing...
Look out!
...to risk my life!
What?!
He self-destructed?!
Self-destructed? With this weak a blast?
Even in death he seeks glory. How pitiful.
Ow.
Ow!
Ow, ow, ow!
This is... a fragment of Flazzard's body!
What?!
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
Could it be...?!
Yeah! It really can be!
Each one of these rocks is me!
These are bullets of rock!
They're Rock Bullets!
Curse you!
Crocodine!
What do you think you're doing?!
It doesn't matter how strong you are!
The more you break,
the more of me there is!
This is my final attack method,
Rock Bullet Shrapnel Detonation!
Then I'll just freeze them all!
Hyadaruko!
Ow, ow, ow, ow!
Whoops. He has ice rocks.
Popp!
Don't, Dai!
Looks like you're up, big Hero!
Earth Slash!
Die!
Dai!
MAGIC BULLET GUN
FIVE FINGER FLARES
Dai!
Hyunckel!
Bastard!
Dai, aim for his core!
His core?
That's right. He said all of these rocks
are him, but that's not true.
He's an energy rock life-form created by
Hadlar using Forbidden Magic.
There should only be one core rock
that's the source of his life.
You have to find it and break it!
His core...
But how can I find a single rock
among all of these?
Unless you do, Flazzard can't be beaten!
What are you talking about?!
Nothing can defeat my ultimate attack!
Darn it!
It's not good! I can't find it!
No human can shatter my core hidden here!
I can't beat him!
How can I cut an enemy I can't see?!
Once you can cut the unseen,
your blade will become
three, or even five times more powerful.
An enemy I can't see!
That's why he had me train!
The air... in other words,
you slice the emptiness.
Dai...
A Hoimi! spell...
Looks like hiding behind Crocodine
spared you some damage.
Flazzard?!
His flames and cold are dwindling!
I look pathetic to you, don't I?
This final attack method
drains my life drastically.
Why do you risk death just to win?!
My being has no history.
It's been barely a year
since Master Hadlar created me.
That's why I want achievements!
Achievements no one can beat whether
they live to be a hundred or a thousand!
You're so pitiful.
Can't you prove yourself
through something other than fighting?
Who asked for your pity?!
The thrill of victory!
The jealous glares of my peers!
They are what fulfill me!
If you all would just die,
then everything will be perfect!
Wait!
Dai!
Don't you see that you can't win?
I'm going to use my final attack now.
It's the greatest technique of
my master, Avan.
I've never successfully done it before.
If I fail, you win.
But...
if I can do it... I win!
You're just bluffing!
Dai!
That attack...!
Here goes, kid!
Blizzblaze Shrapnel Detonation!
He didn't dodge?!
Avan Style Sword Technique...
Air Slash!
Did it work?!
If that pathetic attack is his greatest
technique, I guess Avan's not much, huh?
No... I failed.
Is it...
Is it really beyond me, Master?
What is it, Dai?
That last one, the Air Slash,
I don't get it.
Oh come on.
Master's explained it a ton of times.
Then did you understand it?
I'm a Mage, so I don't have to.
That sort of thinking is why
your progress is so slow.
What would you do
against an evil swordsman?
Then again, an evil swordsman
wouldn't use this skill.
Huh? Why not?
Air Slash requires an Aura of Justice.
An Aura of Justice?
There are monsters in this world
created by dark magic.
Air Slash is an attack
that vanquishes such evil beings.
To do it, first...
you charge your blade
with the Aura of Justice.
And then...
you have to release it towards
the enemy's true form.
The difficult part is determining
where the enemy's true form is.
Unlike the weak spots of normal monsters,
you can't see it with your eyes.
Did you get that?
Kind of?
Don't worry about it.
I'm sure you'll pick it up eventually.
How to see an unseen enemy.
It's no good, Master!
I can't... see it!
I'll burn you to a crisp!
Dai, run!
This is the end!
What the hell?!
His Air Slash wasn't a complete failure!
No way! You're telling me
that attack grazed my core?!
Okay! I'll do it until I succeed!
In that case, one more time!
Don't! If you use
that attack again, it'll kill you!
You'll all die first!
Besides, the risk of getting burned
is what makes gambling fun!
He's blinded by the glory of victory!
Here goes, Dai!
It's a showdown between our final attacks!
Rock Bullet Shrapnel Detonation!
Air Slash!
It's not working!
Looks like with this many targets,
there's no hope for any accidental hits!
Looks like I win this fight!
Dai!
Dammit!
Is it no good?!
Isn't there anything Dai can do?
There is!
Hyunckel!
Dai's forgetting that Air Slash
is an attack that slices the empty!
Unlike the earth and the sea, you can't
see the empty no matter how hard you try!
I'm going to...
remind him of that!
Dai! Over here!
Huh?!
W-What are you doing?!
Dai! Look with your inner eye!
My inner eye?!
As an attack, your Air Slash
is already complete!
But it's not yet a mastered technique!
Once you see your enemy
with your inner eye,
it will be a true technique!
It'll become a true Air Slash!
Find him with... my inner eye!
Air Slash strikes dark energy
with light energy to destroy evil!
That's why I could never master it!
Now is the time for you to inherit
the greatest Avan Style technique!
You morons!
As if such a fantasy attack
could defeat my ultimate attack!
Dai!
Look out! Run!
That's right.
I can't find it
because I keep looking for it.
Sense it!
The life energy of everyone here!
I feel a warm presence.
That must be Maam.
There's Hyunckel.
The big one is Crocodine.
There's Popp over there.
Something's coming!
A giant evil energy!
It's approaching me,
giving off malice everywhere!
I can see it!
This is...
his core!
Flazzard!
Air Slash!
Looks like another dud...
That's my... My core!
It's done.
I've hit...
my target!
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
Dai's Air Slash struck Flazzard.
Just when victory is at hand, Mystvearn,
the Shadow Vizier appears before Dai.
After turning into Dark Aura,
a spiteful Flazzard attacks Dai again.
Dai and Flazzard's final showdown begins.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Now I Slice Everything"
The adventure continues!