With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE SILVER-HAIRED HYM
What's wrong?!
You were so determined earlier,
but you're still losing!
Fight back a little!
Where's your Bloody Sukuraido!?!
Try that Air Strike attack of yours again!
It wouldn't work.
Hym, you aren't just a pawn anymore.
My Bloody Sukuraido! probably won't hit you.
And you can no longer
be killed by my Air Strike.
In other words, most of my attacks
won't have an effect on you now.
In the rules of chess, a pawn
that has gone deep into enemy territory
can gain the abilities of a queen
or other powerful pieces.
The ascension of a pawn... A promotion!
That silver hair could be
proof of your promotion.
Proof of your evolution
to a top-class warrior!
So what?
So if you can't win,
you'll just give up all fighting?!
No!
Those aren't the eyes
of someone who has given up!
He still has something up his sleeve!
I'm beginning to see
the weakness in Hym's movements!
Right after throwing
a destructive left punch,
Hym's entire body freezes
for just an instant!
I'll have to attack
with all my strength in that moment...
with my greatest, strongest attack!
He's coming!
Bring it on!
Your toys won't work anymore!
Die, Hyunckel!
This is...?!
My Grand Cross!
Normally, it can be dodged,
but if fired inward, there's no escape!
Hym, it's time to experience hell with me!
I see.
He placed all his bets
on that self-sacrificing attack.
It might have worked
if it actually hit me.
I beat you! I win, Hyunckel!
In my peak condition, I could have won.
But I've already used Grand Cross twice,
so focusing my Aura took too long.
Now I've used all my weapons
and all the energy I have.
I'm truly all out of options...
It's still kind of weird
having Popp heal me.
Yeah, I feel the same way.
I only just attained the spell.
But if you can cast heal-type spells,
you didn't need to have Maam heal you.
Shut up! I really was
out of Magic Power at the time!
You little...
Popp's so amazing.
It feels like
there's less and less need for me...
Okay! We're all fully healed up!
Come and get us, Dark Army!
It's kind of unsettling...
This silence.
Aren't Master and Leona coming back?
Yeah. It's been a while now.
When entering an enemy's fortress,
it's actually a bad sign
for enemies to suddenly not show up.
That usually means...
Exactly. As you know...
it means someone powerful enough
to be entrusted with its defense is there.
It means there's no need
for any weak guardians.
Mystban!
This is the White Garden.
Also known as the heart of Ban Palace,
which leads to the central tower,
the Tower of Supremacy.
Past that is King Ban's chamber.
It's the most beautiful place
in Ban Palace.
What is this, a sightseeing tour?!
I thought you'd like to know
the name of where you will die.
Bastard!
Not yet! I can't give up yet!
Princess Leona told me
that the power of my soul is Fortitude.
So long as there's even a shred
of fighting spirit left within me...
Lord Hadorra, are you watching?
I... I've finally beaten
a Disciple of Aban!
Is he immortal?!
So he wants to fight until he dies.
Very well!
Here!
I appreciate it, but I won't use my spear.
No. Not just my spear...
What?!
What are you doing?!
Aura against Aura!
Hym, I've cast away everything
in order to fight you on equal ground!
This fist will settle things!
Are you insane, Hyunckel?!
My body is made of Orichalcum!
A human like you can't shatter me
with your bare fists!
Whether I can or not, I have to try first.
This fist is the only weapon I have left.
I have no choice but to wager
everything on it!
If I lose, all that remains is death!
Did you discard your armour and spear...
I did it to force myself into a corner.
I knew it!
When I first awoke to the Aura of Light,
I tore steel apart with my hands!
The flame of my life may grow weak...
but if I turn all of it into Aura
and focus it into my fist,
it could be strong enough
to penetrate your body!
I'll focus the last of my power
into this fist!
Unbelievable.
This is more than
just a desperate measure!
But don't bother, Hyunckel.
Your obsession for fighting
is impressive...
but you're forgetting one thing.
GRAND CROSS
TOMAKUGUTSOSHO
Take a look at this.
My Heat Knuckle. No, it's a fist of Aura
so it's my Aura Knuckle.
This is no normal weapon.
It's Aura-infused Orichalcum,
so that's obvious.
It doesn't matter how much
you enhance your fist with Aura.
My Aura Knuckle
is even harder than Orichalcum.
Can you beat Dai or Lord Hadorra
empty-handed while they wield weapons?
Of course you can't.
If this hits, it'll obliterate
normal flesh beyond all recognition.
I don't want you to die
in such a pitiful way.
What?
Defeating you was the first
purpose in life I've ever had.
From the moment I saw you, I knew it.
You walk around like
you're the strongest there ever was.
Turning that cool expression
into one of fear was my one dream!
I believed that doing so
would serve Lord Hadorra.
But if you're going to die,
don't die in a pathetic way.
I want you to die as you lived.
With a cool look on your face.
Hym, when we first fought,
you said something similar.
That it's better to die beautifully
than to live in disgrace.
It's true I don't fear death.
There was a time when I preferred
a glorious death to a life of disgrace.
But not anymore!
My friends showed me the truth.
A true warrior cannot ever give up
until they fulfill their purpose.
Even if it means eating mud,
one must carry out their duty.
It doesn't matter how disgraceful
or pathetic it may seem!
If there's even a sliver of a chance,
I'm going to bet on that!
Now come on, Hym!
This fist carries all of my fortitude!
Can it beat your implacable fist?!
It's time to find out!
You really are an amazing man.
I finally realize what it is about you
that I wanted to defeat.
You're an amazing individual, too, Hym.
You're second person
to ever drive me this far.
Watch me, my friend!
This is my last great gambit!
Here goes!
Hym backed off.
Here comes Hym's greatest attack!
I'll blow everything away
with my burning fist!
Take this! Aura Knuckle!
I've won!
What?! Why am I...
It's too bad, Hym.
Your fist never touched me.
My desperate strike
hit you before you could!
It's my fist that won!
I won. It took everything I had
to pull it off.
Hym truly was a powerful foe.
Dammit. How could my Orichalcum body...?
It's because your attack
was just that powerful.
Mine?
My Aura and strength aren't enough
to shatter Orichalcum.
I realized I had to use the force
of your charge and counter it.
The Aban Style has a similar skill.
I just applied it to my fist.
The one you used when fighting Baran...
But the Hollow Stance requires emptying
oneself and taking an enemy blow.
If I had tried that here, even with my
Aura suppressed, one blow would kill me.
So I had no choice but to hit you
with my Aura-infused fist first.
The timing was truly
a life-or-death instant.
But I managed to pull it off.
It was because you accepted
a head-on challenge from me.
Normally, you could have used
your martial arts to whittle me down
and gained a sure victory.
I'd never do that.
Even knowing that would bring me victory,
I'd never do that. Ever.
Beating you like that would be pointless.
I'd give my life to win,
but I'd rather die than win like that.
Hym...
It hurts.
Getting wounded used to only
cause me a tiny bit of pain.
I guess this is the pain of living.
You've won.
Now finish me like a victor should!
Hurry up!
What are you doing?
You aren't someone who should die here.
If you reach my friends,
they can heal you with magic.
Get up and go to them!
Are you kidding me?!
I gave it my all and lost!
I have no regrets! I don't need your pity!
It's not pity.
This is an order.
An order?
If the victor has the right
to take the life of the defeated...
then I take your death, not your life!
You aren't evil anymore.
Your wish to defeat me was a pure one.
Then there's no need
to finish you off in battle.
But I...
More importantly,
your life is no longer just your own.
You carry the lives of Hadorra
and the Royal Guard.
I don't believe you gained a new life
just because of a promotion.
You have an obligation
to live on for your friends.
Isn't that right, Hym?
I'm not telling you to join us.
If I survive the upcoming battle,
then I'll gladly fight you again.
So live on, Hym. With us.
That didn't come out well.
When my friends said it to me,
it came out kinder.
Damn you and your arrogance!
If I could move,
I'd punch you in the face!
Do it after you survive.
What's this shaking?!
It looks like the Cleaner of Ban Palace
has finally lost patience.
The Cleaner?
Why are there seven pawns just like me?!
And there's Sigma and Block and Fenbren!
What are you talking about,
you useless piece of scrap?!
Have you forgotten?
Chess involves a king and a queen,
two bishops, two rooks, two knights,
and eight pawns, making 16 pieces.
King Ban only gave Hadorra five of those!
And of the 16 pieces,
only one has its own will!
That is me!
The one King Ban truly trusts!
Ban Palace's greatest
and most powerful guardian!
The king, Maximum!
It's no good! Hyunckel's in tatters
and I can't move!
We don't stand a chance
against that many Orichalcum warriors!
Run Hyunckel! Just leave me and go!
Hym, stay where you are.
Forgive me. I don't think
I can keep my promise.
But you still have to survive.
Got it? You have to get to my friends.
I'll take care of them.
Wait! You're not...!
I've fought.
I fought all this way.
I believed that only my pain
could make me forget my past.
That only the blood and sweat I spill
could wash away my sins.
But...
It all ends today!
There's no doubt.
This will be my last battle!
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Hyunckel proved victorious over Hym.
Just as a bond is formed between the two,
King Maximum appears
leading an Orichalcum Army.
The chess army and Maximum
attack the wounded Hyunckel mercilessly.
Can Hyunckel and Hym overcome
this perilous situation?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Checkmate"
The adventure continues!