With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE SECRET WAY OF PURIFICATION
You're weak.
Far too weak!
M-Master's too weak?
What do you mean?! All of a sudden...
Exactly what I said.
Aban is weak.
Even if he joins us for this final battle,
he'll only die in vain.
Don't say that, Hyunckel!
That's right! How can you say that
after Master came to save us!
Then answer this,
is Aban's power enough to fight Ban?
O-Of course it is!
This man lost to the old Hadorra once.
He wouldn't stand a chance
against Hadorra as a Superior Being.
Now that our fight has reached this level,
what use would someone that weak be?
We've all grown in strength
through battles with powerful enemies.
There's a wide gap between
our current combat power and Aban's.
Did Hadorra look like
someone you could beat?
The current Hero, Dai,
fought him alone and beat him.
How much stronger
do you think Dai is compared to you?
In terms of pure combat power...
I doubt that I'm even
half as strong as Dai.
Your analysis is accurate,
as expected of the former Hero.
Shut up!
Popp!
What are you being so stuck-up about?!
You wanted to cry to
Master Aban more than anyone!
Who cares about a power difference?!
Master came all this way to help us!
Isn't that show of kindness enough?!
Kindness doesn't win battles.
I merely stated the truth.
As it stands, Aban is weaker
than Dai or me or even you.
Why you...!
Stop it!
Maam... You...
Anyhow, I won't stand for
a man this weak to be our leader.
If you all want to follow Aban forward,
then I'm staying here.
Hyunckel, I know it's difficult for you
to open up to Master Aban...
but...
Forget him, Maam. Let him whine.
Who throws a tantrum at a time like this?
Hyunckel, everything
you have said is true. But I...
Hyunckel...
You...
Everyone, let us move on.
Huh?!
Huh? Uh... But Master...!
I would like to respect Hyunckel's wishes.
If this is what he wants,
there's nothing I can do.
Yeah. Don't worry.
Maam, I know Hyunckel will follow us.
Mystban.
King Ban!
What is taking so long?
Return to me at once.
Is there an issue, Sire?
An unexpected turn of events.
Aban has returned from the dead.
Aban? Aban, the Hero?
But I doubt he possesses
the strength to be any threat to you.
You fool!
The threat is not from his strength.
Dai is far stronger than he is.
But Aban possesses
something beyond mere strength.
That is why I originally ordered Hadorra
to slay him at once.
I sense a strength from him
different than the kind I believe in.
That is Aban.
Left alive, the Disciples of Aban
will grow in power at an alarming rate.
What of Kill? Where is Kilban?
Do not forget, Mystban.
While you both bear my name,
he is not like you.
His purpose is entirely different.
It is not his job to protect me.
He exists to kill. That is all.
Aban is quite smart,
but he made a mistake.
He merely wounded his enemy.
He was such a meanie!
That was our favorite mask, too!
Left to his own devices,
I'm sure Kilban will hunt down Aban.
You must stop Dai and the others,
who've gained momentum from Aban's return.
My King!
But...
You're still watching him?
Yes.
It's his own fault.
But I just can't believe Hyunckel
would selfishly say such things.
Exactly.
Huh?
What do you mean by that, Master?
Listen up, everyone.
Once we approach that entrance, Hyunckel
will be attacked by numerous enemies.
What are you talking about, Master?
You're so thick, Popp!
Don't you understand his intent?!
Huh?
It's exactly what you did once before...
in the battle with the Dragon Masters!
That's right. I wanted everyone
to be able to fight and not worry,
so I pretended to be selfish and ran off!
Did he...?!
Hyunckel!
That idiot!
Master!
Try to understand, Popp,
what he really feels.
Hyunckel was able to realize
what my real power is.
He knew that my power would be
essential in navigating Ban Palace.
So he took on
the role of holding off any pursuit.
But, if you all knew the truth,
you would never have let him remain alone.
Master, did you realize
Hyunckel's intent from the start?
Yes.
I knew it at a glance.
Hyunckel would always trouble me
by saying and doing things he didn't mean.
He would always have that look.
That sort of mix of
sadness and remorse in his eyes.
Come on! You won't take
one step beyond here!
That bastard! He always does this!
He treats us like children
and acts like he knows everything!
He goes and hogs all the glory!
Next time I see you, I'll kick your butt!
So you better not die, Hyunckel!
You better survive this!
There you are, monsters of the Underworld.
There's only one of you?!
What an idiot!
We're not your only problem!
No enemy can invade the palace!
In that case, we have nothing to fear.
What?!
Firstly, I'm going to take care of
all of you.
And secondly...
no obstacle can stop
the others who went ahead!
You little brat!
Tear him apart!
Charge!
Curse you!
Looks like they've started!
Will Hyunckel be okay?
He trained under me because he thought
I killed his father and wanted revenge.
But it looks like he actually
paid attention to his lessons.
Hyunckel is following the rules I laid out
for entering enemy territory.
When charging an enemy fortress,
what's most vital,
is not taking down enemies in the way,
but preventing being flanked.
When weakened, the most dangerous thing is
getting attacked from both sides.
That's why, when choosing a formation,
you need powerful members
in both the front and the rear.
I took that role earlier
and managed to hold off that reaper.
Huh?! You fought Kilban?!
He wasn't dead?!
But it seems that Hyunckel noticed.
That's why he took on that role himself.
Then, when you caught up...
Yes. I used a spell to do it...
a new spell I've attained called Lilirura.
Lilirura?
It's a type of Rura spell.
It's a spell to regroup with allies.
It's a mystic spell that's normally used
to regroup when lost in a labyrinth.
A labyrinth?
M-Master Aban, are you saying
you've been...
A gate. It's huge!
GRAND CROSS
BEGIRAMA
HEAT-TYPE SPELL
This looks like the Dark Citadel Gate
at the entrance of Ban Palace!
The one you worked
with your dad to destroy?
This could be even more powerful
than that one.
Are you kidding me?!
To come all this way only to be blocked?!
Everyone, stand back!
Huh?
Let me show you why
Hyunckel gave me the lead
while he stayed back to guard the rear.
The new power I've obtained
through my training up to this point!
Training?!
That's right. I've been training
this whole time...
in the legendary Carl Kingdom...
deep in the Cave of Trials.
What?!
Isn't the Cave of Trials...
...w-where Leona attained
her Minakator spell?!
I knew it!
Master Aban must have
gone beyond where we went,
down to far deeper levels
in the Cave of Trials!
To attain even more powerful
Purifying Spells!
Back then, on the day I lost to Hadorra...
while the Amulet of Carl
did save my life...
my body was badly damaged
by my Megante spell.
I was sent flying.
When I awoke, I was in the ocean
near Dermline Island.
That's when I realized I had been saved
by the Amulet of Carl.
Dai, Popp...
I was there
when you two began your journey.
I dragged my wounded body there.
It would have been easy to call out
and join you on your journey.
But I couldn't bring myself to.
I wanted to help you two
to continue to grow...
but I couldn't forgive my own weakness.
I knew that Dai's latent strength
already far exceeded my own.
That meant that even if I went with you,
I would only hinder your progress.
I had to train myself in body and soul
and gain new abilities of my own,
or I would not be worthy
to fight beside you.
That's why I decided to perfect
my purification magic
in the legendary Cave of Trials.
I knew that would be
the best possible way to train.
Even if I was lacking in strength, I knew
it would help against Dark King Ban.
I see. That explains it.
Master never really
abandoned us after all.
He's been desperately fighting on his own.
Over the next few months,
I continued down the Cave of Trials
for the ultimate Purifying Spellcraft.
After the 50th level,
there were no more spells,
and the labyrinth became more complex.
I was running low
on healing items and rations
and numerous terrifying traps awaited me.
But we can discuss my adventures
another time.
Basically, at the lower levels,
the cave tests the challenger's knowledge.
When Princess Leona used Minakator
on one of the upper levels,
I knew the final battle was approaching.
Thank you for that.
What level were you on then?
We were 25 floors underground.
Where were you at the time?
Hmm, I believe it was
somewhere around 150 levels down.
For a human, that must be a new record!
Well then...
Let's give it a shot!
So this is Master Aban's Purifying Magic.
I was right! Aban attained
the power of purification!
I can't imagine a more powerful
Purifying Spell than Minakator.
Yeah, but there must be one.
He went down 150 whole levels!
That's six times deeper than 25,
so it must be six times stronger!
You won't get the answer
from simple math, Popp.
Huh?!
We don't have a spell more powerful
than Minakator at the moment.
But we might find one deeper down.
At least I never found one where I went.
Th-Then what is that spell?
It's not a spell, it's...
the Secret Way of Haja.
Secret Way of Haja?
Take a good look.
It can prove quite useful.
It's like Minakator!
I see! So that's it!
The Secret Way of Haja!
Huh?
It's not a spell, but a secret way
to amplify a spell's purifying power!
Yes! That's correct!
Used with this Secret Way,
the evil-nullifying effects of various
spells can be amplified to their limits!
Earlier, when I rescued Popp, I used the
barrier-nullifying spell Baria,
and amplified it using
this Secret Way of Haja.
He did that with just
a Toramama spell?!
And obviously, the spell
I'm about to cast against this door...
It's the spell for opening doors...
Abagamu!
Dark portal closed since ancient times...
I command you to open!
It's the same as last time!
It's opening!
That's impossible!
The door to King Ban's palace!
It-It's opening!
Well done, my Master Aban.
As I told you before,
no one can stop their advance!
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Aban's Secret Way of Purification
opened the gate.
As Hyunckel holds off the horde of
monsters, the others enter the palace.
Eventually Aban makes a request to Leona.
Meanwhile, in Loroi Valley, Crocodine
and the others push Zaboera back.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Steady Advance of Justice"
The adventure continues!