Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE LANDING OF SOVEREIGN ROCK CASTLE
We've been waiting for you, King Romos.
This world summit
is a wonderful idea, Princess Leona.
That's...!
King Romos, he is...
He's a friend of Dai's now?
King Romos...
King Romos! This! The Crown of Champions!
Can we make this into a weapon?!
We're making an Orichalcum sword!
That is already yours.
Why would I oppose to remaking it
into a weapon for world peace?
Thank you, Your Majesty!
Bengana's ship is entering port!
That's huge!
Such a large ship...
Princess Leona, I've come
answering your summons.
King Bengana, we specifically
asked of you to be discreet.
Using such a warship is...
And what are those weapons?
They're tanks, King Romos.
The pride of my country,
the elite Tank Brigade.
Isn't that right, Akhim?
Sir! The Bengana Tank Brigade takes pride
in being the world's strongest army!
It's all about weapons now. Swords
and magic are nothing against a cannon.
This world summit is a war council on how
my army will attack the Dark Army, right?
So where's it being held?
Please follow me.
I guess not every king is very admirable.
Crocodine,
I know this is a bad time, but we...
Don't worry and go. Papunica still has me.
I guess it also has them, too.
Okay, Popp.
Hold it! Let me rest a little!
Wow! What do my eyes see,
but Papunica Kingdom!
If we're landing there,
I'd have preferred a more impressive boat.
I need to look the part of a Hero.
What are you saying?!
We decided to change our ways and
try to be a real Hero's party, didn't we?!
Sure.
Papunica's putting up a good fight with
the Dark Army, so it should work out.
We can defeat the Dark Army
and become real heroes!
If we stick with them and fight a bit,
we should get some money and experience.
Let's go to Papunica!
No objection!
Huh?
Huh?!
What's that?
L-Landing... cancelled!
No objection!
How goes the Hero's Sword?
Same as before.
He tossed the Crown in the furnace
and is still staring at Dai's hand.
It's already been half a day.
Who knows what he's doing?
Um, Ron Berku...
Long ago, people and weapons were one.
People strove to match up
to powerful weapons.
People were strong,
and so weapons evolved.
Now they're all worthless.
But you...
You will show me the most powerful being
paired with the most powerful weapon.
Thank you!
Jank, give me a hand.
This will be a big job.
At last!
He's started!
Dad?!
Ron's started forging the sword
like he's possessed.
I'll help him,
so don't break his concentration.
Apparently, this sword is a new life
being created specifically for Dai.
So it won't be like forging
an ordinary weapon.
I see. That's why he was studying
the hands that would wield it.
They say a true weapon
chooses its wielder.
Yes.
Okay, Dad. You've got this.
I don't need you to tell me that!
What's wrong, miss?
Meruru?!
I see it! I see it!
A giant shadow!
A terrifying... A terrifying power!
At this rate, Papunica will fall!
What?
Nothing.
King Bengana, as we've said,
we must gather the world's forces as one
to defeat the Dark Army.
That's why we've all gathered here.
And my army will lead.
I'm saying to relax and leave it to me.
King Bengana,
Ringaia was a powerful country
called the "Fortress Kingdom,"
yet we fell before the Dragon Legion
of the Dark Army in one week.
So I've heard.
Their power can only be understood
by those who fought them.
My apologies,
but your country still exists
only because the enemy has not yet
brought in their full force.
You insult me, General Bowson!
Do you not know the power of my army,
the world's greatest army?!
This is going nowhere. Even after
we finally managed to hold this summit...
Observe!
That cutting-edge, top-class warship!
That unstoppable Tank Brigade!
No matter what forces
the Dark Army may have, they can't...
What is that?!
That's...
impossible!
What is that thing?!
I don't know!
I don't know, but I do know this!
Papunica is finished!
That face! Sovereign Rock Castle?!
So Hyunckel's hypothesis was right!
Sovereign Rock Castle itself
is a walking fortress! A giant Overfiend!
That said...
I can't believe how big it is!
This is bad!
A giant! A giant is attacking!
Wait! How did something that big
get so close without you noticing?!
Well, there was a thick mist
over the ocean!
A mist?! Did you say a mist?!
Could it be...?!
Mystban!
Bengana's ship.
Just as Hadorra suspected.
The world leaders
are gathered here in Papunica.
Pathetic ants who defy King Ban.
I'll smoke them out and crush them.
BEHOMA
HEALING-TYPE SPELL
TOMAKUGUTSOSHO
What a creature!
Unbelievable!
It's beyond human comprehension!
It must be here to wipe us all out.
They knew about this meeting.
Akhim! Take command of the Tank Brigade!
Show them the true power
of the Bengana Army!
Sir! As you command!
Don't be so reckless, King Bengana!
It destroyed a warship with one attack!
My tanks! My tanks won't lose!
They'll blow that lump of rock to pieces!
Follow me!
Wait!
That's not just a giant made of rocks!
It's Sovereign Rock Castle!
The main fortress of the Dark Army!
To face it head-on
will only mean pointless death!
His Majesty has ordered me
to display Bengana Army's true power.
Win or lose, we must show our courage
to lead the rest of the world!
Out of the way!
He seemed unpleasant at first,
but he has his own loyalties.
I sense a warrior in him.
I can't let him die.
Crocodine!
Old man!
Sorry for the wait! It's finally complete!
Oh! That's my Vortex Axe!
The life of legendary weapons,
the Magic Jewel was undamaged.
So I rebuilt it using Papunican metals!
I call it Vortex Axe Returns Mark II!
Thanks! This'll give me
the strength of a hundred!
No, the strength of a thousand!
Thanks, old man!
We're counting on you!
I'll join you in a bit!
It's no good. I can't use
a crystal ball like Grandmother can.
That was enough.
All we needed was a glimpse.
Something big is here.
Let's go back to Papunica!
Stop!
Have you forgotten?!
This sword is being made for you!
It's being given life for you!
It's not a normal weapon! It has a soul!
A sword with a soul?
When it answers your soul
and accepts you as its wielder,
it will unleash
the world's greatest power!
That's why you must
bear witness to its birth!
We'll come back for it.
Can't you make it in the meantime?
A blade requires
the voice of its wielder's soul!
Without that voice, this will become
just another weapon!
Ron Berku is pouring his life into this.
It must take godly strength beyond our
understanding to create this sword.
He's using a material like Orichalcum.
It's not a normal forging.
But at this rate, Papunica...
Okay. Dai, you stay here
and complete your sword.
Meanwhile, we'll hold off the Dark Army!
We have to work together
to defeat an enemy of that size!
That's why you have to stay here, Dai.
They're trying to kill
all the world leaders at once.
We need your Hero's Sword now
more than ever!
Popp...
Or do you think we can't even
buy you some time?
After all we've been through,
you can't possibly think that.
Leave it to us.
Yes.
Everyone!
So that's the deal!
Leave things to us for now!
Prepare to fire!
Fools.
Fire!
Continue firing!
Amazing!
Weigh anchor and keep firing!
Yes, sir!
That was pretty cool what I said back there.
I can't back down now having said all that.
I really might get killed this time
fighting something that big.
Dammit!
What's with him?
He's freaking out, Miss Maam.
Are you sure about him?
Honestly.
He's fine.
Popp can seem unreliable at first,
but he always overcomes pain and fear.
That's how he's always been.
Yes.
Okay! No point in chickening out!
Take the bull by the horns!
Okay! Let's all go!
Right!
Dad, try to be useful to Ron Berku!
Shut up! And you better not
get in everybody's way!
Show 'em what you're made of!
Bye!
I'm off!
Rura!
Honey...
Stein...
Popp's gone away again, hasn't he?
Yeah.
But I've never seen Popp
with such a serious look in his eyes.
He's gone and grown up all of a sudden.
As a kid he used to always be
such a wimp and a quitter.
When he left home,
we were angry at Master Aban, but...
We should thank him...
for making our boy into a man.
See that?! See that?!
The force of the invincible Bengana Army!
We can win this, my friends!
Everyone! Get back!
What the...?!
Popp!
Princess, where's the giant?!
The bay! How did you know?!
Meruru showed us! So we hurried back!
Where's Dai?! I thought he was with you!
He's making the world's strongest sword!
It'll be ready soon!
So we came back first
to try to hold them off!
Forget your "world's strongest sword!"
Who'd need that?! Look!
My Bengana Tank Brigade
will soon blow that giant to pieces!
No. It's not working.
What?! Don't be ridiculous!
Can't you see it's breaking apart,
dropping pieces of rock everywhere?!
But in that smoke,
its energy hasn't waned at all.
In fact...
Cease fire!
Well?
There should be nothing left.
Look out!
Abandon ship!
You?!
A castle?!
You fools.
You've revealed it by yourselves.
Sovereign Rock Castle's true form.
Princess of Papunica, Leona...
and other world leaders.
I serve the great Dark King Ban.
I am Shadow Legion Commander Mystban.
Shadow Legion Commander Mystban...
So it really was him.
I bring you an order.
What's his deal?!
Is he going to threaten us,
saying come out or die?!
Die.
You are all worthless.
You are vermin to Dark King Ban.
Surrender will not be allowed.
Die.
Begone from this world,
along with this entire country!
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
The Shadow Legion appears
with Sovereign Rock Castle.
As Dai waits for his sword to finish,
Popp and the others fight without him.
But the enemy's forces are endless.
Mystban himself appears
and attacks using his Dark Aura.
The next showdown begins in Papunica.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Master of Darkness Against His Pupil"
The adventure continues!