With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE LAST CHALLENGE
No! Meruru! Please! Open your eyes!
You can't die! You can't!
Please don't die for someone like me!
Popp's a Mage,
and yet he's using healing energy?!
Like...
Like a Sage!
What?!
How can that brat have
that much Magic Power?!
What happened?!
You won't interfere any further!
She's alive! Her heart is beating!
The poison's gone! She just might live!
It's thanks to Popp's
immense healing energy.
It's stronger than my Zaoraru spell.
It could be Zaoriku-level.
Oh wow, Popp!
Miss Amy, don't let her die! Please!
Right!
Okay! Let's do this!
This is for Meruru! Come on everyone!
Yes! It worked!
A green light.
This light of Courage is Meruru's.
She was far braver than I ever was.
I'm not...
I'm not letting her down!
At last.
They did it! Five pillars of light!
Now it shall shine!
The ultimate Purification Spell!
Minakator!
What's this?
Popp, now!
Rura!
Yes!
Yes! They did it!
Those guys...
They've all gone to face the Dark King.
They finally did it.
Go, mighty Heroes! Defeat the Dark King!
Justice prevails!
Everyone, form up around
the Circle of Magic!
The enemy monsters will be weaker
around there!
We'll regroup and defend this position!
Yes!
It worked. Where are we?
This is where we once fought
and lost to Ban.
It's the tip of Ban Palace.
It was pretty torn up,
but it's been fixed.
Guys.
I'm not going to make any lame excuses!
I'll make up for
the trouble I caused by fighting!
Maam, try to understand.
Popp's been in love with you
since he met you.
He's worked really hard
to come all this way.
Part of that was probably for you.
Th-This is all too sudden
to take in right now!
I'm not ready!
Hey Leona, maybe we should all
stick close together.
It's the enemy stronghold so...
Dai! Why can't you put
that aside for now?!
It's just I can't handle
this sort of mood!
But we certainly don't have time to waste.
Let's hurry, Dai!
Come on! Which is it?!
Minakator...
An ancient gift from the God of Humans.
They managed to dig up
quite an interesting little trick.
King Ban, are you alright?
I feel a slight effect,
but it's not suppressing my Magic Power.
However, I can't move Ban Palace now.
And its field is gone.
The transfer of my Magic Power
into Ban Palace is likely being blocked.
There'll be more annoying guests now.
I suppose this calls for me.
Wait a minute. We have other guests.
Ah... This Aura. I remember this.
So that's your move...
Hadorra!
Hadorra! What did you do with them?!
Sorry, but they'll have to face
the Royal Guard.
What do you want?!
I have but one wish.
A one-on-one duel against you!
That's all I want!
A-A duel with me?!
MINAKATOR
ULTRA COMBUSTION SLASH
Dammit! What was that?!
Is this somewhere else in Ban Palace?!
Exactly.
This is the tail section of Ban Palace.
My Rura spell brought you here.
You're the knight, Sigma!
I'm honored you remember me.
We don't want any interference
while Lord Hadorra settles things with Dai.
I shall be dealing with you.
Then Maam and the others...
Like yourself,
they're somewhere in the citadel.
This is the rear right wing.
This is exciting, Hyunckel.
Hym...
We both managed to survive
and now we fight again.
Seeing your metal face
doesn't make me feel anything.
What a boring response.
I don't have time.
Just fight already!
Very well then!
Let me grant your wish!
The queen, Albinass...
The strongest of the Royal Guard!
How unfortunate for you.
To have to face me alone.
The plan just ended up this way.
Don't hold it against us.
So this is your plan to assure victory.
I saw Sigma take Popp
and Hym take Hyunckel.
With a mirror that can reflect spells,
Sigma took Popp.
And Hym has the most experience
fighting Hyunckel.
That leaves you against me.
Your analysis of our strategy is correct.
Although you made one slight error.
Aside from Dai, our only real threats
are Popp and Hyunckel.
My job is to take on everyone else.
I was supposed to kidnap
that other girl who was with you,
but that strange creature interfered.
Strange creature?
Listen, Dai!
Now we shall lay everything on the line
for a final man-to-man showdown!
Hold it!
Stop right there!
They missed one of them.
Leona...
Gomechan!
When the light hit us,
Gomechan popped out!
Gomechan protected me
from the enemy's spell.
It looks like the Rura spell
brought all of us here.
I see.
Anyhow, Dai, you can't accept
such a stupid duel!
Hadorra, that goes for you, too!
You turned against Ban, didn't you?!
Fighting Dai here will only serve Ban!
If you want to settle things,
then just wait for another time!
That's not possible!
I no longer... have any time left.
That's right.
Hadorra is...
It looks like he's not backing down.
Then I'll help!
Leona, get back!
W-What are you talking about, Dai?!
You don't have to go along with it!
Together we should...
Yow!
Dai...
I'm sorry.
But things are going to get hotter.
So I need you to back away.
Hadorra is already beyond saving.
Huh?!
Superior Beings have instant regeneration,
but he's still wounded.
Hadorra has little time left.
Yet he's choosing to risk what remains
of his life to fight for his honor.
And he's chosen me as his opponent.
I know we have to defeat Ban.
I'd rather not fight either.
But...
if I don't accept his challenge...
I feel like I won't be able to
call myself a man.
I'm sorry.
You can yell at me later.
Honestly...
how did he grow up this fast?
Hadorra, I'll take you on
with every ounce of my might!
Thank you.
Watch this, Dark King Ban!
This will be Hadorra's last battle!
But know that none shall be
allowed to interfere!
Doing so will cost you your life!
Very well, Hadorra.
Fight to your heart's content.
May you have no regrets.
Hadorra, aren't you being weakened?
You mean the Minakator spell?
I feel some effect,
but for someone as strong as me...
As you can see, I'm perfectly fine!
I see. I guess that means
Dark King Ban is as well.
The only thing being stalled
by the spell is Ban Palace.
Ban's Magic Power remains unaffected.
Too bad for you.
No, I'm actually relieved.
I'd hate for you to be handicapped
by the Minakator spell!
How very touching, you little brat.
Here goes!
Okay!
We should probably get farther away.
Let's go, Gomechan!
It has begun.
The duel between Lord Hadorra
and the Hero Dai.
A duel...
Lord Hadorra is beyond the help
of any healing spell.
His monster body will only decay.
To use the last of his life
in a fight against the Hero Dai,
a fair fight against his chosen rival,
is Lord Hadorra's wish.
Listen to me.
My body won't hold up any longer.
I have chosen the Hero
as my final opponent.
Lord Hadorra!
I have no desire
to fight for the Dark King.
But I cannot side with
Dai's party, either.
I'm the one who took
what was most precious from them.
That leaves me but one path left!
To fight the one
who drives me the most
and leave my final mark!
And that opponent is not the Dark King.
B-But...
What are you hesitating for Albinass?!
If we don't go through with this
we'll be nothing but losers, and
Block and Fenbren will have died in vain!
If we don't defeat our rivals and show
the honor of the Hadorra Royal Guard
how will we face them in the afterlife?!
Let's go out in a blaze of glory!
We'll defeat the Heroes
and then fight the Dark King.
We'll show all of them!
Hym...
I think you resemble me the most.
Th-Then you're sacrificing yourselves
in order to grant Hadorra his last wish?!
Hym and Sigma and you as well?!
Albinass, let's stop this.
We shouldn't be fighting.
Stop this?
That's right!
How you all feel for Hadorra...
that's no different from
how we feel about our friends!
We may be enemies, but I can't fight
someone who feels that way!
A fight between us is pointless!
Please, Albinass!
If you all truly care for one another,
then now is when we should stop fighting!
We'll help you as much as we can!
That's why...!
Maam, I'm so glad you feel that way.
Albinass...
I'm so glad you're the kind of
naive simpleton that I despise.
Now I can kill you without mercy!
Needle Thousand!
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
I finally realized it
imasara kizuitanosa
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
Must be the reason I was born
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
I shake off the clinging night
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
Maam couldn't reach Albinass,
who only acts with Hadorra in mind.
Having decided to sacrifice everything
for him, Albinass attacks unrelentingly.
Albinass's intense will
slowly backs Maam into a corner.
Can Maam get through to Albinass?
The warrior of Love will be tested!
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Clash of Love"
The adventure continues!