With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
ABAN, THE HERO
This is a story of Aban, the Hero...
from the days of his youth
as a member of the Order of Carl.
The time has come!
It is time to grasp the world
in my hands!
Go forth, my monsters!
Burn their towns! Wreck their countries!
Wipe out the pathetic humans!
Against the mighty Dark Lord Hadorra
and his monster legion...
the humans could do nothing
but tremble in fear.
But one kingdom stood resolute
in the face of the Dark Army's invasion.
Under their new lead knight, Roka...
the elite Order of Carl faced
the Dark Army as an unparalleled force.
Curse you, Carl Kingdom!
Oh!
It's Princess Flora!
Everyone, hear me!
No matter how much the Dark Army
tramples our world and burns our towns,
there is nothing to fear!
The Dark Lord is the one who fears!
For we humans have the power to unite!
That is why I will join in the fight!
Together with our proud Order of Carl!
The Princess is so brave!
We'll fight, too!
In place of its bedridden king,
Princess Flora led Carl Kingdom.
With her beauty and courage,
Flora was a goddess of hope
to the world.
Well spoken, Princess.
I'm merely doing my job.
It's you who should be praised.
Along with the Order.
Speaking of the Order,
I see he's missing again.
Aban!
I see Aban is his usual self.
I will go fetch him!
How dare he skip out on
the Princess's public appearance!
It's okay, Roka!
No it's not! I'll go discipline him!
I know exactly where he is!
Hmm. Something's missing.
This soup is no good.
Oh no! But I made it for you, Sir Aban!
The problem is in the flavoring.
If you grind a Feverfew stem
and mix it in, it should come together.
The Feverfew is good for illness
and injuries, plus it's quite nutritious.
For our secret flavor,
we add a pinch of Seeds of Agility.
You know so much, Sir Aban!
Could you taste my soup next time?
Aban!
Oh my, Roka. Can I help you?
Stop playing innocent!
You're just in time.
Some bread with this soup is...
Come on!
No! Sir Aban!
Honestly, what is with you?!
You skipped guard duty
for a cooking class?!
I apologize for that.
But as the strongest in the Order,
you're enough of a bodyguard.
Improving the food that everyone eats
is a much better way for me
to serve the country.
You're my friend, but I have no idea
why you were chosen for the Order of Carl.
Probably because I study.
The Zinuar family comes from
a long line of scholars.
Listen up! We're in the age of war now!
There's no telling when the Dark Lord
will target our country!
You're quite right.
There's no point in just studying
and being fawned over by girls!
You have to practice your sword skills!
Yes that's important, but surely
you intend to have a family someday.
You might have an adorable child
who takes after you.
If you don't at least know how to cook...
Hah! I'm devoting my life to the sword!
I don't need a family!
Are you sure about that?
You'll regret it.
If I ever get married,
I'll run across the entire country naked!
Listen, at least practice
so you can defend yourself!
Your stance may need work,
but you can at least practice swinging!
I understand, Roka.
As you said...
a war is coming.
What's wrong, Princess?!
What is this?!
Blood writing just appeared!
What language is this?!
It's the Darkling Language.
It's a communication spell
sent through mirrors.
The writing says this...
"Tonight, I shall come
to claim the Princess...
as a sacrifice to
the God of the Underworld.
The Dark Lord."
What?!
The Dark Lord wants the Princess?!
This is an emergency! Increase our security!
Aban...
Captain Roka, castle security
is on high alert!
Good!
Okay, Dark Lord! Come if you dare!
Roka, where is Aban?
Aban?
He said he had important business
and went off into the woods.
The woods?
There's nothing more important
than your safety!
I promise we'll protect you
even without that coward!
You have nothing to fear!
Damn you, stupid Aban!
You may not be strong,
but I never thought you'd run away!
As of today, you and I are through!
Look at that!
What is that light?!
It's the Dark Lord!
Everyone at the ready!
You filth.
I summon you, my monsters!
Derupa!
Thrash the humans!
Captain! Monsters are attacking!
What?! Where did they come from?!
Dammit!
Damn! He's so powerful!
Princess Flora.
I have come to claim you!
Behold! The Dark Lord himself!
Dark Lord, I know what you're up to!
A sacrifice to the God of the Underworld
is just a cover story!
Oh?
By stealing me away through any means...
you intend to demoralize my people
and hasten your domination of the world!
Very sharp!
You're young, but you're still a ruler.
This will save me a lot of trouble.
Now kneel before me!
I refuse!
If you'd like I can kill you right here!
Princess!
Will it be submission or death?
Which do you prefer?
Come! Make your choice!
That's no good.
Aban!
BEGIRAMA
HEAT-TYPE SPELL
IONAZUN
EXTREME-EXPLOSION SPELL
If you'd like I can kill you right here!
Princess!
Will it be submission or death?
Which do you prefer?
Come! Make your choice!
That's no good.
Aban!
Who are you?
Mister Dark Lord.
You need to be more gentle
when trying to seduce a lady.
Save me your nonsense!
Hmm. This Magic Bullet Gun
needs more work.
What wrong?!
What have you done?!
Oh, I just sprinkled it with
a little Coagulant.
Coagulant?
It's a little secret compound I cooked up.
Monsters sprinkled with it
lose their minds and attack each other.
The monsters outside
are fighting each other!
I sprinkled some on the ones outside, too.
And now your trusty monster legion
has been rendered useless.
I see! He went to the forest
to find Poison Moths!
Not bad, you trickster!
You worm! You dare humiliate me
with your conniving trickery?!
You'll pay for that!
I'll pay for that?
What?
I sense from this frail man... Aura?!
You're the one
who's going to pay, Dark Lord!
I've seen that before!
That expression on Aban's face!
It was three years ago.
In my youthful lust for adventure
I snuck out of the castle alone.
Aban was the one who rescued me when
I was attacked by a monster in the forest.
I told him who I was
and recommended him to the Order.
And yet, once he joined,
he began wearing those dud glasses...
and acted as though
he couldn't fight at all.
It was like he was suppressing
his immense power.
But I could tell.
He acted that way because
he didn't want to show off.
I'm sorry, Princess.
But I'm still a member of the Order.
Should the need arise, I shall use all my
power to protect you and Carl Kingdom.
But until that time comes...
I understand.
I will keep what I know
about you a secret.
You're saying the time has come, Aban?!
You fool! You're not
picking a fight with me, are you?
I don't want to fight.
However...
I can't sit by and watch someone
hurt others for their own ambitions.
Don't assume I'm that naive!
Enough from you!
Merami!
What?!
He can use spells?!
Begirama!
For a human,
he uses highly advanced magic!
Wow! I never knew Aban was that strong!
You can do it, Aban!
What?!
It's over! Merazoma!
Not a bad show.
But you're still just a human!
Compared to my magic,
yours is a trivial thing!
He can even use Ionazun?!
No! If I dodge, he'll hit the Princess!
Fool! You'd choose your own death?!
In that case... Die!
You filth!
Roka!
I got him good.
He can't cast that spell now, can he?
Very well! A Iora spell will suffice!
I'll reduce you all to ash!
You dare...
You dare hurt my friend!
You'll pay for that!
IORA!
What is this blinding light?!
He did it!
Aban defeated the Dark Lord!
Good going!
No. The Dark Lord still lives.
If he was really dead...
that arm would crumble to ash.
It's proof he's still alive.
Very observant!
I suppose I will retreat for now.
But you won't defeat me
with that paltry power! Ever!
He's right.
With my current power
I can't defeat the Dark Lord.
So you're leaving, Aban?
This is your symbol of peace.
Until the day you defeat the Dark Lord
and save the world...
I shall hold on to this.
I'll try to hurry back.
Take this as well.
It's the Amulet of Carl
which is passed down in the royal family.
I'm sure it will help you someday.
Well then.
Please accept this.
It's Kiseiseki that has been made
using a Zinuar family secret process.
I'm the only one left who can make these.
You'd give me something so valuable?
Are you sure?
Consider it a trade.
Roka!
I'm coming with you, Aban!
I need to pay the Dark Lord back
for what he did!
You can't! Without the captain of
its Order, who will protect Carl Kingdom?
It's fine! We can leave it to
the ones that I've trained.
Besides, we can't do much
just defending ourselves.
We need to go on the offensive!
The best defense is a good offense!
But there's no guarantee that we can win.
We're facing the Dark Lord.
I saw hope in
that blade of light of yours.
But that was by accident!
Coincidental or still incomplete,
it still drove the Dark Lord back!
I believe in that light!
After much intense training,
that blinding strike...
was completed to become the Aban Strash.
Aban...
Strash!
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
I finally realized it
imasara kizuitanosa
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
Must be the reason I was born
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
I shake off the clinging night
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
To bind with the legendary
Great Purification Spell, Minakator,
Leona and the others brave
the Cave of Trials where monsters roam.
Meanwhile, Dai enlists the aid of Nova
to train with his sword.
The remaining Popp learns of a mysterious
power hidden in the Insignias of Aban.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Cave of Trials"
The adventure continues!