Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
WE'RE THE BEAST KING COMMANDOS
Medoroa!
We win!
Wow! Very impressive, Popp!
You wiped out
those powerful enemies all at once!
Couldn't have done it
without your new attack, Big Guy.
It seems there was a spell
that not even Orichalcum can withstand.
What's wrong?!
What is it, Hyunckel?!
Keep your guard up!
Something's still there!
What?!
It can't be!
That's...
impossible!
They survived!
How?! Nothing could survive
a Medoroa spell unscathed!
That was close.
They've got a pretty nasty Mage with them.
Block! Are you okay?!
Back there...
if Block hadn't fallen on us
to push us into the ground...
all five of us would have died.
Thanks, Block.
You're a lot sharper than you look.
I-It's the optimal way to dodge.
And you wouldn't even think of it, unless
you were willing to sacrifice yourself!
Even I have to admit
that was pretty brave!
It looks like even
the evil can use teamwork.
The value of using individual strengths
to compensate for weaknesses...
is something we know all too well.
We already knew we'd be fighting
powerful enemies!
No matter who they are, all we can do
is fight on together, right?!
Everyone!
Exactly.
I guess so.
We're hardly nimble enough
to keep pace with our enemies.
Okay, let's pull ourselves together
and deal the finishing blow!
That won't happen.
Sigma?!
This Mirror of Shahal
will not break even if I die.
It's a legendary item Lord Hadorra
granted me, not a part of my body.
That was quite an impressive spell.
But now that we've seen it,
it won't work on the Royal Guard again.
Let's get on with round two!
Hym.
Block needs healing first.
And our mission is to...
Who cares?! I'm done with that, Albinass!
Nothing can stop me
once I'm this fired up!
I'll avenge Block, too, so don't worry!
That's enough, Hym.
Not that I dislike
that personality of yours...
but don't make things
difficult for Albinass.
It's you!
Lord Hadorra!
There he is!
Hadorra!
Dai.
Wait!
It's just an illusion!
An illusion?! Then he's not really here?!
That's correct.
This is just a magical projection.
The real me is in the Field of Death.
So you sit back and let your servants
do your dirty work?
I guess the rumors that you'd grown
as a warrior were just a lie, Hadorra!
I never intended to defeat you through
an ambush, nor did I believe I could.
We were content waiting for you
in the Field of Death.
But then the other humans
decided to meddle.
Huh?!
What are you talking about?!
I told you! The Royal Guard
protects the Field of Death!
We would accept
your challenge there fair and square!
But then we learned the other humans
intended to invade the Field of Death.
We came to weed out the unworthy.
Weed out?!
On Lord Hadorra's orders,
we came to test all of you!
Basically, anyone not standing now is
unworthy of entering the Field of Death!
Dai, you and your friends are all we want.
I won't have the Dark King's presence
soiled by the blood of the unworthy.
I'll be waiting!
Come to the Field of Death at once!
Wait!
And with that,
we shall take our leave.
Seeing your strengths
made our time well spent.
Come when you will. We shall welcome you.
Farewell.
I want the Hero, but I want you even more.
Hyunckel, was it?
I'll be paying you back for this.
But Lord Hadorra's orders must be obeyed!
I'll be praying that
he orders me to kill you.
Get back here!
Screw you and your weeding out!
Popp! Don't make the same mistake!
Huh?!
Oh, right.
We need to tend to everybody first!
We need more help!
Dai and Popp, get Leona and the others!
Got it!
We have done as you commanded.
Well done.
Lord Hadorra, Hym, Sigma, and Block
require regeneration.
Very well.
As do you.
It's just a scratch.
I see you took quite a beating.
What did you think of them?
I like them. They make worthy opponents.
Where is Fenbren?
A rat has entered the Field of Death.
It had to be dealt with.
You know your mission, Troop Number Three!
Okay!
I see a suspicious light!
What is this? It's just Popp's staff.
He must have lost it in the last fight.
I guess I'll take it to him.
Even he might feel some gratitude.
I see. So there's nothing
but bare mountains.
Yet when you fly over the mountains,
a mysterious force blocks you?
I guess recruiting Seari
was the right idea.
It's a Seaslime I recruited on the shore.
It's Troop Number Three.
Huh? Uh, sure! I-I won easily!
It's not very strong, but I figured
we could use it as a scout.
You know?!
It's searching the ocean floor
for an entrance.
If there isn't one above ground, then...
Very good instincts, little one.
You're the Dark Army!
One of the Orichalcum enemies!
Indeed. I am the bishop of
the Hadorra Royal Guard...
Fenbren.
BLOODY SUKURAIDO!
ULTRA COMBUSTION SLASH
Seari?!
What?! A giant gate under the ocean?!
I see! That entrance must lead
to the Dark King!
So it really was underwater!
Hey, Dark Army! The Beast King Commandos
have found the entrance to your base!
How do you like that?!
Oh my. So you've seen
the Dark Citadel Gate.
The Dark Citadel Gate?!
That's the giant underwater gate.
It's the only entrance to Ban Palace,
Dark King Ban's Great Dark Citadel.
The Great Dark Citadel, Ban Palace?!
You messed up! Thanks for the information!
Once we return to Dai
and tell him what we know,
they'll launch a full-scale attack
on Ban Palace!
Look forward to it!
Sadly, little one,
your little scheme has three flaws.
The first is assuming
that you can leave this island!
Wind...? A Bagi spell?
Indeed. I have mastered
all Vortex-type spells.
I can incapacitate anyone around me
and make quick work of them.
Dammit!
The second flaw is in entering
the Great Dark Citadel.
This is an impossibility for any and all.
The Dark Citadel Gate has been sealed by
the Dark King's Supercharged Dark Magic.
It's a legendary gate
that hasn't opened in centuries.
That makes no sense!
Then how do you get in and out of it?!
We are warriors of the Dark Army,
bestowed with a special enchantment.
It allows us to enter and exit
with Rura spells.
For an outsider
to pry open the gate and enter
would be impossible, no matter
what great power they wield.
You're saying no one can get to
the Dark King no matter how hard they try?
Not even a Dragon Knight could.
You lie! I don't believe that!
It doesn't really matter what you believe.
Your third and final flaw,
is assuming Dai will hear any of this.
Huh?
Because you are going to die here!
All Dai is going to see is your corpses!
Seari!
Worm!
Know your place!
Rattus Rocket Ram!
Fool. My body is almost entirely blades,
yet you flung yourself into me.
And you shredded yourself
just to save this little worm.
Sh-Shut up!
They may look like worms to you...
but they're the first followers
I've ever had!
They're all proud members of my troop!
I'm... their captain!
A captain protects his troops
with his life!
Well said. You're braver than any rat.
You make me want
to see you grovel for your life.
Huh? What?!
The other Royal Guard members
are all chivalrous warriors.
But not me.
I keep in line so as
not to disrupt the order, but...
I... am very cruel.
Hurry! Get him some help!
Th-This is...!
What a sad state of affairs!
Wait! Where's our army?!
What were our invincible
Bengana elite warriors doing?!
When the dock was attacked,
they were the first to go down.
They're probably still in...
What?!
Nova, are you okay?!
Dai...
Thank goodness! You need healing!
Forget it.
I can't... move a single muscle.
I'm just dead weight.
I can't bear to be seen like this.
Consider it a mercy, and just leave me.
W-What are you...?!
Ow, ow, ow, ow! What was that for?!
See? You can still stand.
It's your stupid pride that's
sapping your energy to stand up.
There are many wounded here who are
weaker than you yet fought harder!
If you can stand, then go back
to the base on your own two feet!
Or would you like me to carry you?
I'll carry the wounded.
Whoever marries Maam
is in for quite a handful.
That's the pot calling
the kettle black, Leona.
Hey!
It's no good. We can't find Chiu anywhere.
Gomechan's missing, too.
It looks like they really went ahead.
What?! So they went
to the Field of Death?!
Sorry. If I knew he'd do this, I wouldn't
have given him the Beast King Flute.
He probably recruited
a flying monster and flew there.
He probably intends to scout,
but the enemy's too dangerous.
I'll use a Rura spell and go get him.
Hyunckel and I will be backup.
Glad to have you.
I'll go, too.
Stay here, Dai.
It's temporary,
but we'll be splitting our forces.
You and Maam should
protect everybody here.
All right.
Popp.
Once you find Chiu, come straight back!
We've lost our ship, so we need
to regroup and form a new plan.
Fighting can come later.
Aye-aye. I'm well aware of that.
"Never make the same mistake twice"
is the Popp motto!
We'll be off. Look after things here.
Take care, you three.
You're quite resilient.
You're tougher than I thought.
A rat... shows its true strength...
when it's cornered!
And now it's over.
Don't... worry!
I-I promise...
I promise I'll get you all out of here!
This barely even tickles!
I doubt I'll ever meet anyone
this steadfast again!
Gomechan!
W-What was that blow?!
What?!
Impossible! This is impossible!
My body is made of Orichalcum!
That little Slime put a dent in me?!
Inconceivable! Impossible!
No matter how it happened,
I must end its life immediately.
Not only is this worm creepy,
but it goes and damages my face,
a crime worthy of death!
You won't touch Troop Number Two!
Move!
You troublesome rat.
You can both be impaled together!
Wh-Who's there?!
Who are you?!
What an ugly sight.
The strong bullying the weak...
I never realized how ugly it was
until I saw someone else do it.
What?!
Begone from here.
Otherwise you'll lose more than your eyes.
I don't know who you are,
but remember this!
I promise you'll pay for this!
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Popp, Hyunckel, and Crocodine enter
the Field of Death searching for Chiu.
There they find Dai's father,
Dragon Master General Baran.
Upon learning of Baran's new goal,
Hyunckel and Crocodine try to stop him.
That's when they realize
there's something different about him.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Aban Style Ultimate Technique"
The adventure continues!