With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE FIVE COLORS OF LIGHT
Charge!
Ron Berku, what are you doing here?
Mystban, I see you have a mouth.
Why bother clamming up now?
Is there a reason
I shouldn't hear your voice?
Dai and Hyunckel are allowed to hear it,
but I'm not.
It appears your silence is not
of your own choice.
And here we are again.
Just like back then.
I forget how many decades ago it was.
Nearly a century ago...
in Dark King Ban's
Seventh Palace in the Underworld...
What's wrong, Ron Berku?
I'm leaving.
I should never have come here.
Wait a moment.
Ron Berku.
I hold you in very high regard.
I would prefer if you would
serve me forever.
The Kōmanotsue you made
is truly my greatest weapon.
Your other weapons are
also magnificent.
True masterpieces from
the Craftsman of the Underworld.
It's the Kōmanotsue
that let me down.
If that thing is considered
my greatest masterpiece,
then it will quell my drive to create
the ultimate weapon.
I don't want to lose my touch.
Come now. Will you reconsider?
I refuse.
You may be Dark King Ban,
the most powerful being in the Underworld,
but you can't bind my freedom.
Understandable.
You are worthy of saying such a thing.
You are strong enough to do so.
I already know.
I know you're one of the greatest
swordsmen in the Underworld.
And I know why you hide it
and work as a weaponsmith.
To be blunt,
now that I possess the Kōmanotsue,
all that I want is
your strength as a swordsman.
Look at the dark,
murky sky of our Underworld.
The battle to bring
true light to it is coming.
And for that, I want
as many powerful servants as possible.
I offer you the position
of commanding such a mighty army.
How about it?
My job is done. Farewell, Dark King.
Calm down. He will fight if pushed.
Even knowing he cannot
beat me in combat, he still defies me.
We'd only kill him.
That would be a waste.
But Darklings live a long time.
Perhaps he'll change his mind.
I can see you're out for blood.
Is that Ban's will?
Or...
W-Why won't he dodge?!
I've insulted Ban's generosity.
That's why I allowed that first strike.
This wound is my penance.
But if you intend to continue,
I won't hold back!
This man defied King Ban
for his own freedom.
So why does he side with
Dai and the humans?
I don't need any more
wounds from you, Mystban!
H-He's fast!
I see. An ultimate Purification Spell
using five Disciples.
Where are you going?
To take down Mystban.
He's not going to just
let you cast Minakator.
But we...
If I can at least hold him off
and buy you some time...
That's Mystban...
and Ron Berku!
He came, too?!
He's evenly matched with Mystban?!
He did singlehandedly
trounce us after all!
Hey! This is our chance!
Let's get this over with!
Right!
While the others are buying us time!
Let's begin.
Ow, ow, ow! Why you!
Take that, and that!
Mr. Crocodine!
Ah! Crocodine!
Princess Leona filled me in!
I'll help clear out the riffraff
so we can cast Minakator!
Listen up!
This is the former Beast King,
Mr. Crocodine! Everybody salute!
Good grief. I'm already "the former"?
Mr. Crocodine, we have
a new axe Ron Berku made for you!
Oh?
Crocodine, swing that axe and cry out...
"Howl, Inferno!"
Howl, Inferno!
Whoa, this is...
That's Ron Berku's special Great Axe!
Wow!
"Inferno" casts Mera-type spells
and "Detonation" casts IO-type ones!
It's exceptional!
Howl, Detonation!
Yes!
Great Axe, huh?
It's like using my own Aban Strash!
Oh! Garuda!
Old man, you can take it easy now!
Oh really?
I guess I'll take you up on that.
As if! I can't lay down for this!
Merami!
They're preparing for Minakator!
Miss Amy?
This execution stage is
right under Ban Palace.
It's perfect for the Circle of Magic.
Okay. Everyone stand on the circle
and form a pentagon.
Amy...
This is your Dark Armour Spear.
Ron Berku repaired it.
It looks the same, but its attack
and defense have been greatly enhanced.
You're giving me the weapon
you once took from me?
It's better than you dying.
You'd fight without it, after all.
So fight...
and live!
Amudo!
GRAND CROSS
MEDOROA
I remembered your words
while I was imprisoned.
Huh?
You glared at me and told me
to stop walking gladly into death's arms.
Your words made me want to keep going.
To grasp at the chance to keep living.
You have my thanks.
So I was actually able to help you.
But the fight's barely started.
You can thank me after we survive.
Amy, are you finished?
I'd like to explain the spell.
Right! I'm very sorry!
Miss Amy...
Put on your Insignias.
Minakator is a powerful
Purification Spell on its own.
But with Kiseiseki...
With a pentagon of five Insignias of Aban
making a Magic Circle,
the purification power is amplified.
If it works, it should stop Ban Palace,
and nullify the magic field around it.
It should allow us to invade Ban Palace.
So what do we do?
Do we just stand here?
I'll be the one casting the spell.
All you need to do is increase
the power of your souls one by one.
Once we do that,
the light of our Kiseiseki should unite,
creating a pillar of light
that will reach Ban Palace.
A pillar of light...
We'll join hands going clockwise.
When you turn comes, focus your thoughts
and pass them on to the next person.
I'm the last.
W-...
What if...
And I'm just asking...
If we can't gather the five lights...
what happens then?
Popp...
Don't say stuff like that!
Without the five lights...
Minakator will use only my Magic Power.
It probably won't work on Ban Palace.
I see.
We're all nervous, too.
We've never done this before.
Don't bother worrying... empty your mind.
I know that!
Okay! Let's do this then!
Northern Grand Blade!
You can't move when you're in pieces.
Howl, Inferno!
Crocodine!
Ah, Nova!
So you've cut most of them down!
Yes. There's only a few left.
Now! Everyone attack!
What happened to Mystban, their boss?
He's up there,
flashing every now and then.
That's a whole other level of battle!
Indeed. Ron's quite impressive.
Oh holy light,
with thy blessed power...
drive away the evil power of darkness.
Th-This is the pillar of light?
Your turn, Dai.
Uh... Er...
Amplify my thoughts...
and focus my mind...
Dai.
You should try emptying your mind.
It'll be easier that way.
It worked!
There it is! This blue light is
the light of my soul, right?!
That's right.
Okay. Next is Hyunckel.
We're evenly matched.
Neither of us can win like this.
What are those pillars of light?!
They reach Ban Palace!
Could it be...?!
You're going nowhere, Mystban!
It's... my turn.
So long as I'm here,
you're stuck sparring with me.
You won't interfere with them!
How very foolish, Ron Berku.
Did you think holding me at bay
would give these humans a chance?
What's wrong?
You're suddenly very chatty.
I thought you didn't want
me to hear your voice.
You may have knowledge of the Underworld,
but hearing my voice won't matter
to one who will soon be dead.
You're all going to die here.
What is that?!
This disgusting laugh...
So it's you, the Mystic Bishop Zaboera!
Dark Army Second-in-Command
is my title now.
Laboring for years can
sometimes yield such payoffs.
Save your prattle!
You can't turn the tide of battle now!
This time I'll give you
what you deserve at last!
Zaboera, this is your chance.
Do as planned and wipe out the humans.
Leave it to me, Commander Mystban.
IO!
What is he up to?!
What are those?!
These are Magic Capsules,
the latest model of my Magic Cylinder!
Each can be loaded
with dozens of monsters!
What?!
And inside these ones
are powerful monsters that
none of you have ever encountered before!
What?!
You're all finished now!
Oh no!
Hurry, Popp!
Right!
G-Gods!
Come forth, monsters of the Underworld!
Derupa!
Popp?
What's wrong, Popp?!
I knew it...
I knew it wouldn't work!
I can't do it!
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
I finally realized it
imasara kizuitanosa
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
Must be the reason I was born
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
I shake off the clinging night
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
Popp's Insignia of Aban won't glow.
Under Mystban's order, Zaboera unleashes
a horde of Underworld monsters
and the Battle of
Loroi Valley intensifies.
With Minakator incomplete, nerves fray
and Zaboera's hand closes in.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Peril of
the Great Purification Spell"
The adventure continues!