With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
You're The Bravest
THE INHERITED HEART
This...
This is Ban Palace?!
Was this thing buried under
the Field of Death?!
Guys!
Ow!
Well?!
It's a giant floating palace...
or more like a gigantic bird!
We're sitting on the edge of
an unbelievably gigantic bird!
No way...
This couldn't have been done by a human!
Something this big is in the air?
Such is the depth
of Dark King Ban's Magic Power.
It's made of some material
between rock and metal.
It must be floating due to some reaction
with the Dark King's Magic Power.
All of Ban Palace is made of this.
What now?
Should we escape with a Rura spell?
Come on! We can't run
and leave Dai and his father behind!
You're right!
That explosion must have happened
during their fight against Hadorra.
Nothing else would explain
that destructive power.
I doubt Ban would intentionally
unveil Ban Palace so soon.
Let's find Dai and Baran!
If this is Ban Palace, it must have
an entrance from which they entered!
But with it being this big...
we probably shouldn't just wander around.
Popp, you saw this whole place
from above, right?!
Was there anything like that?!
No...
I don't think...
I saw anything...
Everyone!
There.
The explosion happened there.
That's the head of the bird.
There's a staircase.
That must be the entrance to
Ban Palace, the Dark Citadel Gate.
Popp, can you take us all there?
Sure! You bet!
A Rura spell will still work
if I can see the target.
Everybody, come closer.
Here we go!
The Dark Citadel Gate!
Yeah. You can see
where Dai and Baran shattered it.
Let's go!
The survivors have moved to
the entrance of Ban Palace.
They've gone to rescue Dai.
What shall we do, King Ban?
A simple welcome
would hardly be sufficient.
They're honored guests to my Ban Palace.
Gomechan?
Don't move, Dai.
You wound is pretty deep.
Hyunckel... You're all okay.
Good.
He must have managed
to contain the blast, Baran...
What's wrong?
Did something happen to...
How...
How did that happen to him?!
Dai, take a good look around you.
I'm not sure exactly what happened.
But I'm certain of one thing.
Baran shielded you from
that massive explosion,
using all of his Dragonic Aura.
And...
Hold on!
Hang in there!
Maam, cast Behoimi on him!
Maam!
I can't, Dai.
Hoimi-type spells only work on
creatures with life energy left in them.
Your father, he...
What are you talking about?!
That... That's not possible!
Just cast Behoimi on him!
Stop it, Dai.
Is that you... Dai?
I can't... see anymore.
It's me!
I'm... I'm right here!
Your friends.
Are they all... safe?
Yeah! They're all alive!
They're all okay!
I see.
That's good.
But Dai...
you mustn't badger them.
I am... beyond help.
At the moment of detonation...
I used Doru Aura and unleashed
all of my Dragonic Aura...
to suppress the scale of
the Black Core's blast.
My body doesn't have
a shred of life energy left within.
No healing can save me now.
No!
A real Dragon Knight... the true
Dragon Knight is unstoppable, right?!
No matter what, you won't die!
You can't die!
Don't weep, Dai.
I'm not the true Dragon Knight.
I had the power and the magic...
but I lacked the heart.
You have that which I lacked.
The monster that raised you...
had a far purer heart than I ever did.
You don't need to weep over my death.
For you... he is your true father.
You're wrong.
Grampa is Grampa.
He's not...
my real father.
What?
I can barely hear anything anymore.
Dai.
This is your last chance.
Call out to your father
with all of your strength.
Don't weep...
Dai.
Be strong...
and live.
D...
Dad!
GIGABRAKE
ABAN STRASH
Don't weep, Dai.
Though my body may perish,
my soul lives on.
I will be with you in the battle ahead.
Dad...
We shall always be together,
never to part again.
Fight on, my son.
And defeat Dark King Ban.
Now stand!
Stand up, Dai!
Dad!
What's wrong, Dai? What just happened?
Dad...
Dad's heart entered mine.
I finally know...
all the things he never said...
everything he felt...
I heard it all.
Dai, let's go back to the surface.
Dai, I know nothing we can say
will ease your loss.
But we're in enemy territory.
You know as much as we do
that we can't stop here.
Whoa, what are you saying?!
You don't mean we should go charging
after the Dark King right now?!
Are you serious?!
Don't you have a shred of humanity?!
He just lost his father in front of him!
What can he do in this state?!
Our only option is a temporary retreat!
Say something, will you?!
Popp.
The pain of losing a parent
is like a physical wound.
That much I know for myself.
But consider why Baran died,
not just the fact that he did.
Baran died to open the way for Dai and us.
Now that Hadorra
and his Royal Guard are gone...
getting to the Dark King's palace
should be easy.
But, given time,
they'll regroup their forces.
This is the very chance
that Baran gave us, Popp!
Yeah, but...
If we retreat now,
his death will have been in vain!
We're fighting for everyone in the world.
I know Dai's father would...
Maybe so, but...
Popp.
Don't worry about me.
I'm fine.
Let's go!
Are you... Are you really sure?!
That means leaving your father here!
It doesn't.
Dad is... right here.
Dai...
And he told me...
"Stop crying and fight!"
So we have to move forward.
Otherwise, he'll yell at me again.
All right! All right, Dai!
If you say so, I'll follow you to
the very, very end!
So let's finish this and go home!
Let's go kick that Dark King's butt!
Yeah!
That's a rather bold statement,
young Mage.
Kilban!
Mystban!
Why don't you try repeating that...
in front of him?
What?!
All hail!
Ban, the Dark King
shall grant an audience!
You...
You're...
Indeed. I am Dark King Ban.
What the hell?!
A decrepit old geezer just showed up!
He may be easier to beat than we thought!
Maybe we can go home early!
What a letdown, right guys?
Oh come on! Somebody say something!
Now things are even more
uncomfortable than before!
It looks like everyone
already realizes, Popp,
that King Ban is
far more than meets the eye!
It looks like it's quite a shock to
the former members of the Dark Army.
You only interacted with him indirectly,
but the overwhelming pressure you felt
is still coming from the venerable
gentleman you see before you.
His calm demeanor is
all the more terrifying!
And what makes you say that,
you third-rate Reaper?!
It's obvious!
They have the same expression
Hadorra did when he first met King Ban.
Kilban.
Stop trying to scare them.
Why do you think I went to
the trouble of coming here?
Sorry, sir.
Whoops. You made him mad.
Congratulations on coming this far.
I'm impressed.
I was certain you would be defeated.
With Hadorra and his Royal Guard,
our victory seemed certain.
There was also the Black Core
I implanted in Hadorra.
Ban Palace was supposed to
take to the skies
only when all enemies had been eliminated.
It's a miracle.
Even with Baran helping you,
the fact that you all stand here
is nothing short of a miracle.
So what if it is?!
I thought I'd give you a reward.
To commend your miraculous efforts.
A reward?
I thought it over.
What is it you want most?
It would have to be
nothing other than my life itself.
However, Mystban and Kilban
are as strong as Hadorra...
if not even stronger.
Against the three of us,
you would have no chance of killing me.
So I shall give you a chance.
These two will not intervene.
I shall fight you alone.
That is your reward.
Wonderful, isn't it?
To act without these two
is something that
I haven't done in centuries.
Dammit! He's playing with us!
He truly believes that
we have no chance of beating him!
Damn him!
So?
Surely you won't refuse.
Of course not!
We would have fought even if you had
Mystban and the Reaper!
That's why we've all come this far!
Very well then.
Let us begin.
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
I finally realized it
imasara kizuitanosa
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
Must be the reason I was born
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
I shake off the clinging night
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
At last, Dark King Ban
appears before Dai and his friends.
Even alone, Ban fights
with a smile on his face.
His confidence comes from his overwhelming
Dark Aura and Magic Power.
As the party is driven back,
Ban unleashes his powerful magic.
What will happen to Dai and his friends?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The God of The Underworld"
The adventure continues!