Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE TERRIFYING DRACONIC AURA
When this Dragon Crest shines,
my body is enveloped in a current of
life energy called a Draconic Aura.
It's a Defense Shroud that hardens my body
like steel and repels all spells.
I see. That explains it.
When that crest shined, Dai's body
became unbelievably hard.
And when I fully deploy this Draconic Aura
and fight using its power...
no creature in the world can face me!
Dammit!
Big Guy!
And now, you can no longer fight.
Princess.
Take care of Dai!
Got it!
What a wound.
So this is what Gigabreak does.
Dai, hang in there!
You're a Hero, aren't you?!
Surrender.
Hold it!
Popp!
What are you doing?
Magic doesn't work,
so I'll hit you with this!
Don't be stupid, boy!
I'm like a frog being glared at
by a snake! I feel paralyzed!
The reason I thoroughly crushed Crocodine
is because his type is the most dangerous.
The Draconic Aura repels all spells,
but a greater force or Aura can pierce it,
and damage my body.
A-Are you sure you want
to give away your weakness like that?
Young fool.
Crocodine is mighty. A strike from
a weak Mage like you will hardly tickle.
In fact, your arm would likely break.
I'll still have to try!
This is crazy, Popp!
Wait a minute!
But Popp is...
Popp is going to get killed!
Meruru... you...
Here goes!
Crocodine!
I said leave this to me.
But you can't win in that condition!
I still have my left arm.
There's still hope.
But...
Even if I lose both my eyes,
I'll still have my inner eye.
The inner eye you helped clear.
Me?
That's right.
In that fight in Romos...
you risked your life to face me,
someone you couldn't hope to beat.
You showed me the greatness
of humans, trusting and fighting together.
The one who cleared
the filth staining my heart, Popp,
was you.
Big Guy...
That's why I risk my life, too!
Baran may be unbeatable, but I can't
call myself your friend if I do nothing!
Thanks, Big Guy.
But you don't have to die alone!
We die together!
Here goes, Baran!
This will be my final attack!
Fool. Dodging an attack
from you now would be child's play.
But I doubt you could dodge this.
Gigabreak?!
I held back earlier against Dino,
but not this time.
Former colleague or not, I won't let you
call humans great and live!
W-What an aura of wrath!
That was him holding back?!
I'll reduce both of you to ash!
It... It can't be!
Dai's back in action!
What?!
I cast Behoma! He's at full stamina!
And what difference will it make?!
I'll just blow you all away!
Gigaden!
What?! Impossible!
Crocodine, look where I aim
and use that attack!
Got it!
Aban Strash!
Right there!
Beast King Redemption Blast!
You did it!
Crocodine!
You're all right, Dai.
Your eye. Did he get your eye?
This is nothing.
Leona! We need you
to look at Crocodine's eye!
Got it!
Meruru!
It's all right. Just his eyelid was cut.
What are you two still doing here?!
I wanted us to run.
But this one insisted on helping you.
I can do basic heal spells, too.
You shouldn't!
Leave the healing to Leona and run!
But...
Dai's right, young lady.
Huh?
Maybe if it were someone else, but
we're fighting to world's strongest man.
Still, after being hit
by an attack like that...
I knew it!
He fully deployed his Draconic Aura
to protect his whole body!
We're doomed!
He's unhurt after taking both Aban Strash
and Beast King Redemption Blast...
What are we supposed to do?!
No, it worked!
Blood?!
It's blood!
The same red blood that we have.
What?!
Impossible.
They pierced my Draconic Aura
and damaged my body!
Even with help from his friends,
for such a small child...
But it wasn't just his power.
The power of his friends
had a large influence.
Dai's friends risked their lives
and did everything they could.
In turn, Dai's compassion for his friends,
made his heart multiply his power.
Unless that bond is broken,
Dai's power will continue to grow.
He may even be a threat to me eventually.
He's coming!
Crocodine, it looks like
our attacks had an effect!
In that case...
Indeed. Either he falls or we do.
We just fight on until we're spent!
Unfortunately, the same trick
won't work twice.
You won't avoid my Gigabreak
with such tricks again.
But you never know.
The boy holds terrifying potential.
That is why I shall use all my focus
to take the source of Dai's power!
His Aura is gone?!
What is he up to?!
What the...?!
My crest is acting on its own!
What the hell is that noise?!
Their Dragon Crests are resonating!
BEAST KING REDEMPTION BLAST
GIGABREAK
M-My head... My head is splitting!
Grampa Burasu?!
What are you doing here?!
Gomechan... and everybody from the island?
Why is this all flashing in my mind?!
Dai!
Baran, what have you done?!
I've taken what my son no longer needs.
What?!
But I've used too much of my strength.
I must retreat for now.
I shall return to reclaim Dino.
Huh? Are we safe?
Dai!
Are you okay?
Man, what a relief!
What's wrong? You look dazed.
Who... are you?
What am I doing here?
Why did Baran just leave?
He can't have given up.
I see.
I got food, medicinal herbs,
and other things we might need.
Thanks. It's a real help.
But wasn't it hard
with the country in chaos?
It wasn't. It was the opposite.
Huh?
Everyone was shut inside
or praying to the heavens.
It was like the country was dead.
Seriously? After what just happened?
That's the sort of place Teran is.
It's all people who know nothing
but to worship and pray to the gods.
Who can blame them?
We'd like to do a little praying
of our own right now.
How's it look, Princess?
Crocodine's eye should heal.
But...
You're cute. What's your name?
Come here. Be my friend.
What's wrong? Why are you crying?
It's total amnesia.
No...
Baran said he took what Dai doesn't need.
He meant Dai's memories as a human.
Then that was some spell
that takes memories away?
No it wasn't.
It was probably an attack
using the resonance of Dragon Crests.
He focused all of his energy
and funneled it all into Dai's brain.
Dai was too young to handle
Baran's massive energy and was blown away.
As a result, Dai's memory was erased
leaving his mind a blank slate.
Can he be cured?
I don't know.
But right now, Dai is like an infant.
If Baran attacks us now...
Forget that!
What's more important is that
the memories of us in Dai's head is gone!
Tell me, Dai.
Do you really not remember anything?
Have you forgotten my face?
You all keep calling me "Dai."
Is that my name?
That's right! You're Dai!
You lived on Dermline Island with monsters
and you dreamed of being a future Hero!
And there... And there...
you met me!
Dermline Island... Hero...
My head... hurts!
Here. Put this on.
Thank you, mister.
Why you...! Have you even
forgotten my name, too?!
Even Master Aban who died to save us?!
Well?!
It hurts! You're hurting me!
Popp, stop it!
That's enough, Popp!
Come on!
Here! Take this sword! And remember!
Remember your greatest attack!
No. I can't do that!
The hell you can't!
You mastered Aban Strash! Something even
a genius like Hyunckel couldn't do!
Your brain may not remember,
but your body has to!
No! Swords scare me!
Do it! Do it now!
Be it Earth Slash or Wave Slash...
Just do it!
That man scares me! He's bullying me!
It's hopeless.
With Dai like this...
when Baran attacks again...
we'll be powerless!
Popp...
Let's go, Dai.
Huh?
Where the hell is Baran?!
Not only did he fail to capture Dai,
he hasn't reported back!
I knew we couldn't leave this to him!
No, that was a brilliant move.
To cut the bond between Dai
and his friends and render him useless.
And now it's...
checkmate.
The next battle will be one to see.
I'm sure Baran will gather
all the forces he can.
You mean...
Alert! Alert!
Baran has been located!
Where?!
The southern tip of Bengana Kingdom.
He's been recuperating at Argo Point.
What is he doing now?
Showing now.
What are those three colored bonfires?
He's summoning the Dragon Masters.
What are they?
Baran is unmatched even when using
Dragons alone, so it's not widely known,
but he has three powerful servants
called the Dragon Masters.
I summon you, masters of the Three Fields.
It is time for the Dragon Legion
to go to battle!
The Dragon Masters are
powerful Dragon Riders
who control Dragons of land, sea, and sky.
When they gather under Baran, their
destructive power defies imagination.
He controls such servants?
He's pulling out all the stops.
So much for your chances, Hadorra.
There you are, Dragon Masters.
Member of the Dragon Masters,
Sky Rider Galdandy is here!
King of the Sea,
Sea Rider Borahorn has arrived!
Land Rider Larhart at your service.
We await your command.
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
The three Dragon Masters
gather under Baran.
Together with Baran, they head
to Teran Kingdom to reclaim Dai.
Meanwhile, Dai remains without his memory.
The panic and uncertainty
creates cracks among his friends.
Baran and the Dragon Masters
advance without mercy.
But one man makes his way toward them.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Dragon Masters Approach!"
The adventure continues!