With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE CLASH OF LOVE
Needle Thousand!
I have no intention of sacrificing myself!
I intend to save Lord Hadorra instead!
Save?
At this rate, Lord Hadorra will die.
No one can stop that.
But King Ban's Supercharged Dark Magic
may be able to save Lord Hadorra.
I am going to defeat all of you myself
and then go to King Ban to beg a favor.
So that he will save Lord Hadorra!
Is that something you...
Yes, this is of my own volition.
I'm sure Lord Hadorra will be angry.
But Lord Hadorra's survival
is my greatest wish!
Albinass...
If you feel sympathy,
then stop resisting and die quickly...
oh, kind little Maam.
Needle Thousand!
You're like a rat.
But I can't waste any more time
on the likes of you!
The queen is a piece that rarely moves.
But I'll show you the form I take
when I fight at full strength!
Hands?!
So that's your true form?!
The queen is the most powerful
piece in chess.
In order to hold back that power
I normally disable my hands and feet.
Now that I've taken this form,
you have no chance of winning!
So fast!
My best spell is Begiragon.
Needle Thousand works by fragmenting
this spell and emitting it from my body.
But when I use my hands,
I can focus the energy in one spot.
I call it Thousand Ball!
Behoimi will hardly delay the inevitable.
It's strong! Too strong!
With that much power, Albinass
might really defeat all of us alone.
But...
Please, Albinass...
What is it?
I don't want to fight you!
Please reconsider!
If you're going to beg for your life,
at least admit it.
The emotion that drives you
to such a decision...
It can't just be loyalty, can it?!
What you...
What you feel for Hadorra is...
Are you going to say that I love him?
Spare me your nonsense.
I am neither male nor female.
I am the queen! A mere chess piece!
A piece is a tool of war!
It does not deserve to love anyone!
Albinass!
Silence! Stop trying to buy time
to heal yourself!
That's good. Stand still, just like that.
It's no good!
No amount of convincing will work!
They're lost in their own emotions
and beyond reason!
What can I... What can I do?
Good girl, Maam. Now go to the afterlife.
Thousand Ball!
Maam...
But Maam...
there are times when love and kindness
aren't enough to protect people.
Just as strength without justice
is powerless,
so too is justice without strength.
That's right!
I can't let myself be defeated here!
That's right. I also...
I also have...!
Amudo!
Albinass, I will defeat you!
I also have people precious to me
that I have to protect.
Just like you do!
That's Ron Berku's...
That's right! Like Hyunckel's weapon,
this Dark Armour Fist turns into armour!
And it makes me
completely immune to magic!
Until now, I couldn't
bring myself to use it...
because it's far too powerful!
But I can't allow you to defeat me here!
I'll fight to the fullest, too...
Albinass!
REFRACTOR FIST
NEEDLE THOUSAND
Ridiculous! Take this!
This is why Ron Berku told me
to wear it on my non-dominant hand!
It especially enhances
the defense of the side it's on!
And with this Metal Fist...!
It works!
Even against Orichalcum, I can shatter it
if I have this much speed and hardness!
What?!
Got you!
Did you think you could win
just by wielding that?
Why can't I...?!
So fast... At this rate, I'll lose!
But Albinass is made of Orichalcum.
My Refractor Fist won't work!
I'll use the other skill
Grand Master taught me!
The Warrior Master Style
Tiger Shatter Fist!
This attack is the most physically
destructive attack I know.
You focus all your Aura into one point
and unleash it at a high velocity.
But you mustn't use it
unless absolutely necessary.
The massive force it causes
can reflect back on you.
With my Dark Armour Fist protecting me,
I should be able to use it!
Oh? So you intend to stop flailing around
and want to use a single killing strike?
It will not change a thing.
I still intend to try!
Even a brute
who downs a bear in one strike
can die to a swarm of bees.
Do you understand?
Th-This is...!
S-So strong!
This is your answer, Maam!
I'll keep hitting you
while moving at a high speed!
That's all I need to do
to slowly eat away at your life!
This fight is already over!
I see you've run out of strength.
You've proven quite troublesome.
I'll praise you for that.
The queen truly is strong!
But why?
With this sort of power,
why didn't Albinass use it before?
This battle could have
been won much sooner...
So why?
The queen is a piece that rarely moves.
The queen is indeed the strongest piece.
But its extreme mobility
can be its downfall.
That's it! That's my only option!
You've accepted your fate!
Then, as you wish,
I shall pierce your chest!
Goodbye, Maam!
I'll quickly send your friends after you!
H-How...?!
You're fast, but even you
can't dodge that many projectiles.
And due to your extreme speed,
the collision caused overwhelming damage!
That's the queen's weakness!
On my back,
you could only attack from the front.
You charged straight into
the fragments I shattered!
You've lost, Albinass!
N-Not yet!
It's not over yet!
Forgive me, Albinass!
This is my final attack!
Warrior Master Style Secret Attack...
Tiger Shatter Fist!
I've won!
Come no closer.
I have lost.
It seems that
underestimating you cost me my life.
Albinass.
With my core penetrated,
my body will soon explode.
Forgive me, Albinass.
I didn't have a choice.
You need not feel sorry.
If you hadn't won,
I would have killed you.
You were just stronger.
Not just in power,
but in your drive to help others.
That's all it is.
It's a shame. It's regrettable.
It seems, in being
a piece that was created,
my will could never be
as strong as a human's.
Lord Hadorra...
I wanted him to live.
For even a moment, even a second longer.
Even if it cost me the life he gave me.
Now go from here.
And witness in my place...
Lord Hadorra's final glory.
Albinass, you were more
than just a chess piece.
What you felt for Hadorra...
I'm sure it was...
what humans call "love."
Bloody Sukuraido!
D-Dammit!
I-I won't lose! I still haven't lost!
Hym, you weren't weak.
You were just unlucky.
You faced me right after
I awakened to a new power.
Hyunckel!
You defeated Albinass?
Thanks to Ron Berku's Dark Armour Fist.
I just defeated Hym.
It looks like they're trying to buy time
for Hadorra to fight Dai.
Yes.
Let's hurry back!
What's that?!
It's Popp.
He's fighting...
The knight, Sigma!
Sigma has the Mirror of Shahal
that can reflect any spell!
If Popp uses Medoroa...
Are you worried about Popp?
Yes.
Don't be. Even I couldn't
easily defeat Popp now.
Even at a disadvantage, not even
a Royal Guard-level enemy could beat him.
You're right.
We should trust Popp's abilities.
Maam, why are you so concerned for Popp?
If it were me or Dai,
you wouldn't feel this conflicted.
But you and Dai are really strong!
You always pull through on your own!
But Popp...
Popp's strong, but...
he's always so careless without help.
It's hard to watch at times.
That's it!
That's how I've always looked at Popp!
That's why Popp
tried so hard to get stronger!
It was because of me!
Maam.
Hyunckel.
Remember what Popp said?
Your power is love.
Your love saved me, too.
I'm truly grateful.
But there are two kinds of love.
Loving someone to help them
and loving someone for yourself.
Loving someone for yourself?
You always love others
out of a desire to help them.
You have the spirit of Love.
But after this battle is over,
you'll eventually come to
love someone for yourself.
Like how Miss Amy loves you?
Though I can never reciprocate her love,
I can somewhat understand how she feels.
Love is an emotion beyond control.
It can at times lead people astray.
Like how Baran and I fell to evil.
Like how Meruru and Albinass
were willing to sacrifice themselves.
Maam.
If you feel any emotion for Popp
that you can't describe,
then go find out for yourself.
Leave Dai to me.
Hyunckel...
Popp is still waiting for an answer.
Thank you, Hyunckel!
Maam... The angel of Love
who gave me light.
Go on and find love for yourself.
Not just for everyone else.
And find happiness.
I can never bring you happiness.
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
I finally realized it
imasara kizuitanosa
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
Must be the reason I was born
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
I shake off the clinging night
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
The battle between
Maam and Albinass ended tragically,
but Maam's strong will led her to victory.
Meanwhile, Popp fights
an evenly matched battle with Sigma,
but he has no counter against Sigma's
Mirror of Shahal which reflects magic.
As the two continue to face off,
both sides attempt a gambit.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Victory or Annihilation"
The adventure continues!