Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
I smolder because I've actually burned
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
tada me wo mihiraite
I'll just open my eyes
yume wo miru
And dream my dream
yume wo shiru
And know my dream
THE SUPERIOR BEING VERSUS CHIU
Now it's your turn to see!
With the strengths of over
a hundred monsters combined...
the power of the ultimate Superior Being!
This is a Superior Being?!
Come on, Dai!
I've chosen you
to have the honor of being
the Superior Being Zamuza's first opponent!
You should be grateful!
No way!
He's fast!
How is something that big so fast?!
Oh? Impressive.
Not bad at all.
He's way stronger than before!
At this rate...
Oh no!
This is bad! Dai pushed himself too much
and exceeded his time limit!
What do you mean?!
The power of his crest
doesn't last that long!
What?!
I'm going to eat you whole!
A mouth on his stomach?!
He really is a monster!
Dai!
Now you will nourish me, Dragon Knight!
It's no good. My strength...
Dai!
Such foolish resistance!
But it looks like you're finally spent.
Gira!
To repeatedly cast
such concentrated Gira spells...
Now!
Merazoma!
Now! Get Dai...
Who can blame him? Zamuza's made from
the strongest parts of many monsters.
He instinctively knows
he doesn't stand a chance!
You guys, look after the king!
Right!
Why won't my tail stop shaking?!
Hang in there, Dai!
You're a stronger Mage than you look!
Not many can cast
Gira or Merazoma at this level!
You'll make a good guinea pig!
How?! I thought Dai destroyed that claw!
The wounds from my spells
are already healing!
I told you!
A Superior Being is the ultimate beast!
It possesses a body that can heal
any wound during battle!
This body is already 90% complete!
All that remains is the issue that
I can't cast spells after transforming.
But I can complete my research
after I defeat the Hero's party!
Stop!
He fired a focused blast of Aura!
It's like Crocodine's
Beast King Redemption Blast!
You'd do well to remember.
Interrupting a wild beast's meal
incurs its wrath!
Stop!
Dai?!
He got Dai?!
Then you should hurry.
A good meal.
This can't be! It's a nightmare!
The Hero was swallowed whole!
Dai!
That demon! I've had enough!
I'll defeat it!
I swallowed him alive,
but the powerful digestive fluids
in my body should quickly dissolve him.
Dammit!
Don't bother resisting!
Wouldn't you rather live a little longer
as a guinea pig than die here?
Don't be stupid!
I won't accept either!
Oh?
If memory serves...
the Mage, Fobster, is in there.
So be it.
I have enough guinea pigs.
You can sacrifice your life like Dai did!
Hold it!
Monster of the Dark Army!
Huh?!
Your evil ends here!
The rat. You're still here?
Listen! I'll give you
one chance to apologize!
If you don't want me to hurt you,
you'll surrender and free everybody!
That idiot! He can't
seriously think that's realistic!
Have you lost your mind, insect?!
Didn't you just see me defeat Dai?!
Settle down, tail!
Otherwise, I'll bite you off!
I'll rescue Dai, the Hero!
Here goes!
You idiot! Don't!
What did I tell you?!
Even a normal human doesn't
have the reach to hit him!
You can't fight something that big!
Ow, ow, ow.
Dammit!
Again!
Run! Get out of here, Chiu!
Chiu!
Popp?! And Chiu, too?!
It's no use. Give it up.
Even my might couldn't do anything.
What can your frail arms do?
But...
It's not just with strength.
Even my sword was useless.
My whip didn't work either.
Spells are useless.
It appears that it absorbs all attacks.
So we can't escape?
There's nothing we can do.
What's with you?!
All you big men
and you're already giving up?!
I'm not giving up!
My friends...!
I can't just do nothing
while my friends are being hurt!
That won't work.
You're the only one
who can escape this peril.
If you utilize the power you've gained
through your training, you can break free.
You...
Are you...?!
What's this?!
My body feels numb!
Curse you! You annoying gnat!
Again!
Could I do that?
Could the old me?
Could I face an enemy
I couldn't beat as a fledgling?
I couldn't. There's no way I could!
You've earned some of my respect, Ratty.
He's breathing?
That's it! He must also breathe
through the mouth on his stomach!
In that case...!
Dammit! You're the last person I wanted
to see me like this!
Oh really? It's impressive enough
that you stood up to him without running.
Hmph! How rude!
Only the worst kind of trash
would abandon their friends!
Don't remind me.
Hey, Ratty.
I've got a plan to rescue Dai.
Wanna help me out?
Can you really do that?!
Yeah!
Listen. The mouth on his stomach
is going to open.
When it does, use your strength
to hit him in the stomach!
The shock should push Dai out!
The mouth is going to open? How?!
I don't have time to keep playing!
I'll crush you in one blow!
He'll just heal from any ordinary spell.
It looks bad using an enemy's attack,
but it's my only option!
Finger Flares Bomb!
HYADARUKO
ICE-TYPE SPELL
DARK INCENSE
Finger Flares Bomb!
What?!
I did it!
It worked!
Blizzblaze General Flazzard's attack!
I figured, at my level,
I might be able to pull it off!
Oh wow!
You fired three Merazoma spells at once!
It's supposed to be five.
With all my Magic Power,
it looks like that's my limit.
But it should be enough!
Those flames won't go out easily.
Even if his hide can withstand it,
the air around his face should burn!
It should suffocate him!
The pain! I can't breathe!
If he can't breathe,
he'll have to open
his other mouth for air!
In other words,
the mouth that Dai is trapped in!
This isn't good! I can't take it!
Now, Chiu! Get him right in the stomach!
Right! I've got this!
Or so I say, but what should I do?
You can always fight
with headbutts and ramming attacks.
That's it!
Who cares if it looks cool or not!
Here goes!
There! It's Dai!
He's still alive!
That attack was actually pretty cool!
A name! A killer attack requires a name!
I know! Rattus Rocket Ram!
You idiot! Pay more attention!
You could've saved Dai with one more hit!
I've had it with you!
You'll pay for that, you pieces of trash!
I'll slaughter you!
It didn't work!
It's no good! I can't move!
So it ends here!
What?!
Impossible!
How is she fine in this paralysis gas?!
Why is she the only one?!
It's her Magic Power.
See that white light
surrounding her?
That's faint healing Magic Power
that she's spread all over her body.
Is that even possible?!
This prison is immune to all attacks.
But it's still a living creature!
Grand Master. I shall now use
the Warrior Master Style Secret Attack!
What?! What is she going to do?!
She's going to punch it?!
It's useless! It can't work!
After all we did, nothing worked!
What can a little girl do?
Die like the trash you are!
Crushed like filth!
Don't!
Miss Maam!
What's that?!
Impossible! My Bioprison!
I'm going to free everyone!
Maam!
Miss Maam!
You're going to free everyone?
Don't make me laugh!
Miss Maam...
Behoimi.
Wow! Not bad for a former Warrior Priest!
Chiu, go help Popp!
What? Him of all people?
While I'm fighting this guy.
Hurry!
Right!
This small wound...
I can heal a wound like this in no time!
We must rescue them!
Don't worry about me!
Go help those people!
Hurry!
Yes, Majesty!
You little brat! You'll pay for that!
Forget being a guinea pig!
I'll dispose of you here!
I'm going to tear you to shreds!
Into shreds!
Of all the enemies I've ever fought,
you're the worst one.
To take human lives
granted by the gods...
The lives of monsters...
And to toy with them!
That is unforgivable!
Silence! This is a glorious experiment!
A triumphant step
for Darklings in reaching godhood!
I don't care if humans
or monsters live or die!
Then it's time you learned...
the pain of life!
Don't make me laugh!
What can a puny creature like you do?!
I, Zamuza, stand at the apex
of all creatures!
I have an immortal body!
What?!
Impossible! I'm not regenerating!
How?!
There it is! Miss Maam's ultimate attack!
Her ultimate attack?
The greatest Warrior Master Style Secret
Attack she learned from our Grand Master!
The Refractor Fist!
The Refractor Fist?!
Is this the power you used
to breach my Bioprison?!
This is impossible! I am a Superior Being!
A Superior Being is invincible!
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
It may just be a rationalization
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
Even now, even now I waver
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
How far will we go?
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
Exposed to love and sorrow
hokori mamire michi no tochu
On the path strewn with pride
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
Fleeting moments of cowardice
nomikonda SOS
The SOS I held back
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
I clenched my trembling fist
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
That single little promise
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
Those trivial little memories
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
They're still in my heart
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
As embers that keep me burning
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
A single transparent beam of light
me no mae wo terashite yuku
Lights the way before me
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
There is little that I can do
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
With Maam's Refractor Fist, Zamuza,
the Superior Being can be damaged at last.
But it's not enough.
The exhausted Dai notices a difference
in how he and Maam fight.
Will the remaining power
of his crest be enough to defeat Zamuza?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"All in an Instant"
The adventure continues!