With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Never let go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Never let go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
You're The Bravest
HADORRA'S CHALLENGE
Got you!
Baran... falls!
What was that?!
An Aban Strash?!
Was that... the Hero brat?
H-How can there be this many
people out there stronger than me?!
Damn... it all!
I've never drawn my sword
without thinking before.
I felt my sword's will
and my own will as one!
I completely forgot about the seal!
All I could think about was saving...
So that's your sword.
Impressive.
With our blades, not even
the Dark Citadel Gate will hold.
Let's go, Dai!
Focus all of your strength into this blow!
Okay!
We did it!
This rumbling...!
They breached it.
That gate that was sealed
by the Dark King's power.
Send for another.
Yes, my king.
How very impressive.
We did it! The entrance
to Ban Palace is open!
We were bound to succeed.
The combined might of two Dragon Knights
is a force that normally should not exist.
Shattering the gate is not our goal.
Keep your guard up.
Come! Our target is Dark King Ban!
This shaking can only mean...
Dai and Baran have breached
the Dark Citadel Gate!
Fenbren is dead!
Damn it!
Wait! Where are you going, Hym?!
To avenge Fenbren!
You will not!
But...!
Have you forgotten, Hym,
your vow to Lord Hadorra?
With Fenbren's insubordination,
how can we abandon our position now?!
You're right.
Our purpose here is to allow Lord Hadorra
to fight Dai and Baran whole-heartedly!
What?!
That means...!
We'll take care of you here!
Hadorra intends to fight Dai and Baran,
two Dragon Knights, at once?!
Hadorra?!
He's alone?!
Impossible! How is he here?!
Perfect. I wouldn't have it
any other way!
Hyunckel!
Pick yourselves up. We need to
take them out and follow Dai and Baran!
All that damage and he still shows up
on the battlefield?
Is he really human?
He must be immortal. Just like us.
This is crazy, Hyunckel.
You can barely even stand!
That magnificent, reckless fool!
Hey, big brute!
I've had just about enough of you!
Hyunckel, are you sure about this?!
Coming here couldn't have been easy!
Don't worry about me.
That's right!
All he can do is stand around anyways!
Don't bother worrying!
Popp!
Just stand right there.
Having you stand behind us is enough.
You're still our senior Disciple of Aban.
Popp...
Even if you can't do anything...
just by showing up,
you've given us plenty of courage.
We won't lose.
Just relax and stand there.
I appreciate it, but standing still
is actually more exhausting.
I'll take my chances.
Hmph! Learn to take a compliment!
The bishop's missing.
Is it dead?
Probably. Dai and Baran must have won.
Dai and Baran?
It looks like they had
already figured out our plan.
Hadorra is waiting for Dai and Baran.
He plans to fight two Dragon Knights?
Is he sure of his victory?
Or does he intend to die?
Or...
could it be both?
We have to hurry!
Focus on taking them out!
That's our line!
You aren't the only ones
who can't afford to lose here!
We'd like to wipe you all out right now!
So, let's see who gets
to go to their leader!
So, who will go first?
I don't have much time.
Is this some sort of game, Hadorra?
Do you really think us so weak
that you could easily win?
Of course not.
Dragon Knights are the ultimate creatures
created by the gods.
Knowing one served under me, Baran,
made me live in fear.
I was petrified that you'd come
for my throne.
Then when I learned Dai was
a Dragon Knight, I was terrified.
I imagined the two of you working together
to come and defeat me.
And now that fear has become a reality.
And yet, I find myself looking forward
to this fight. Life can be strange.
He intended to fight both of us
from the start.
Fenbren's insubordination was unexpected.
It seems that inside me,
there was still some lingering
narcissism and desire for glory.
These were manifested in Fenbren's
personality through the Forbidden Magic.
Children tend to grow up
to be their parents.
Now I shall defeat Dai, the Hero!
And Baran, if you intend to defend Dai...
I will take both of you out!
Fool!
Save your overconfidence!
It seems you've grown in power somewhat.
But don't assume you can take on
two Dragon Knights at once!
I shall slay you here myself!
TWIN SWORD PINNING
ABAN STRASH
Wait! Hadorra isn't being overconfident!
He's become a Superior Being!
A Superior Being?
He really is strong enough
to fight both of us!
We have to fight together!
It's the sure way to defeat him!
Ridiculous.
After what he said,
you'd choose to fight him together?!
Have you no pride as a Dragon Knight?!
If I could win with just pride, I would.
You already said our target
is Dark King Ban!
So it begins. The climax of this battle.
Which has the upper hand?
Hadorra may have become quite powerful,
but against Dai and Baran
at their full power, he cannot win.
Separating from his Royal Guard
was pure suicide.
Suicide, you say?
It seems to me,
he intends to draw out his own power
to its limit through desperation.
A clever ploy by Hadorra.
But, should Hadorra be defeated,
the two Dragons will gain entrance
into the citadel.
That won't happen.
Sire?
That is an impossibility, Mystban.
Those two will never see my face.
I misjudged you, Dai.
I thought you had grown as a warrior...
but you're still far from ever being
a true Dragon Knight!
If worrying about pride
keeps me from doing what has to be done,
then I don't want to be
a true Dragon Knight.
Besides, I'm part human.
I have the blood of my mother.
I've always fought for those around me,
doing the best that I could.
For me, making sure we defeat Hadorra
and Ban is more important than my pride!
Dai...
Hurry up. Who will fight?
Or will you both fight me?
I'll fight you, Hadorra!
You won't listen to reason,
so I don't have a choice.
You'll see in just a few seconds.
So Dai comes first.
Here goes!
Hadorra has a sword?!
Good, Dai! You've improved
since our last fight!
Dai isn't weak!
The power of the attacks
he unleashes rivals that of my own!
How very generous.
To fight in place of your father
who has no experience fighting me.
However, Dai...
it's not as though you know
the extent of my powers either!
A weapon in his left hand?!
Hell's Chain!
IORA!
Aban Strash!
Ionazun!
Dai!
Are you alright?!
What did I tell you?
I see now.
Hadorra has become a formidable enemy.
Well done, Dai.
You never cease to surprise me.
I could say the same.
He completely nullified my Strash
with his Ionazun spell.
A wound like that
will regenerate in no time.
That... It can't be!
I'm sure of it!
The Coal of Hell! A Black Core!
What's wrong?!
How could Dark King Ban
do something so barbaric?!
To implant such a thing
in his own servant!
A Black Core?!
You had such a thing
hidden in Hadorra's body?!
Now do you see?
I said those two will never see my face.
Even if Hadorra falls,
if the Black Core
in his body is detonated,
at the very least,
we can bring it to a draw.
A draw? It will blow away
the whole Field of Death.
Perhaps, but it won't mean anything
to Ban Palace.
They're fighting
in the exterior perimeter after all.
That thing's... a bomb?!
That's right.
An Underworld super-powerful bomb
called a Black Core.
No, it's a nightmare weapon
beyond the definition of a bomb.
How do you know that?
I once saw one in the Underworld.
Black Cores are made
from a stone called Black Crystal.
It's found deep in the Underworld,
and absorbs power endlessly.
They're weaponized using Old Magic.
But, due to their
extreme destructive power,
even evil creatures that casually use
Forbidden Magic fear using Black Cores.
Thirteen years ago, when Hadorra rampaged
the surface world as Dark Lord,
I fought Veruza, King of the Abyss
in the Underworld.
Veruza used a Black Core while battling
on a certain Underworld Continent.
What happened?
The entire continent was vaporized.
In his attempt to kill me,
he destroyed his own territory.
Even Veruza refused to use
a Black Core after that.
It makes sense, considering his ambitions
to rule the Underworld and surface world.
What's the point
if there's nothing left to rule?
But for Ban to use a Black Core...
It seems his plan
is not to rule the surface world
but to annihilate it.
I never intended for Hadorra
to be a sacrificial pawn.
But when I saved him
from the brink of death,
I implanted it in him as insurance.
But then he went and
turned himself into a Superior Being.
This was something even I did not expect.
The power increase beyond his limits
had an adverse effect on the Black Core.
That bomb could be set off at any moment.
This must be manifested in Hadorra
as bouts of extreme pain.
Of course, he assumes it's merely
due to his conversion to a Superior Being.
Knowing the outcome to a battle...
is a boring thing indeed.
But we must see it through.
For my dear right-hand man,
it could be his final grand performance.
Hadorra...
Awakening as a true warrior
ultimately shortened your life.
How ironic.
I would prefer that you win and survive...
but should you fall,
at least go out in a blaze of glory.
Be honored to know that your death
shall be for the great King Ban.
If it explodes, we'll be in trouble.
What do we do?
I don't know.
What?!
But we can't use spells or Magic Swords.
Fight only using blunt force.
That's impossible! We can't win like that!
Just listen to me!
That Black Core has been imbued
with great Magic Power.
It must have absorbed Hadorra's
increased Magic Power to its limit.
Simply hitting it with a powerful spell
might set it off.
Are you done planning?
I'll take you both on! Here I come!
That's...!
Oh no! He's coming!
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
I finally realized it
imasara kizuitanosa
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
Must be the reason I was born
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
I shake off the clinging night
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
To avoid setting off the Black Core
and alerting Hadorra of its presence,
Dai and Baran must
hold back their attacks.
Meanwhile, Hadorra hounds
Dai and Baran relentlessly.
Hadorra gets in position
for his Ultra Combustion Slash.
Against the overwhelming odds,
Baran makes a deadly gambit.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Hadorra Versus Baran"
The adventure continues!