With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
BAN'S TRUTH
His corpse?
No. He's still alive.
Huh?!
But he can't fight anymore.
He's barely alive.
I couldn't withstand it.
Not even with my Kōmanotsue.
Actually, it appears this spear
is all that stood between me and death.
How impressive.
Truly.
I almost died trying to test you.
I thought I had a firm grasp
of your abilities.
But you went above and beyond
my expectations.
I can't have you kill me like this.
After all, this body is the base of me.
The base... of you?
That's right.
To be concise,
the man before us
both is and is not Dark King Ban.
After all, the Secret Spell of Frozen Time
isn't a spell you can cast on yourself.
And it can't be successfully cast
without the highest levels of Magic Power.
In my case, because I wasn't
strong enough,
not only was I was caught in the spell,
but Hadorra was freed in about a year.
And so my friends and I gathered again,
and I completed the Aban Style
Sword Technique and defeated Hadorra.
But that's beside the point.
Basically, the only one who could properly
cast the Secret Spell of Frozen Time
is none other than
Dark King Ban himself.
And Mystban never really existed
in the first place.
That's obvious from what he just told us.
Myst is a powerful monster
of the Underworld.
Entrusted with his master Ban's body,
or a copy of it,
he fused with it to create Mystban.
Any creature under the Secret Spell of
Frozen time becomes an immovable statue.
But if there were a monster that could
merge with that body and control it,
it would create a super warrior
with an immortal body.
The monster with that power is Myst.
That's you.
His voice changed!
So this is the real Myst's voice?
You're correct, Aban.
This body is King Ban's.
King Ban's original body.
King Ban entrusted me with it,
and ordered me to hide its identity.
At the same time, he allowed me
to use its power to fight when necessary.
Obviously, I require
King Ban's permission to do so.
I am the black Myst
that covers King Ban's true face.
I am Mystban!
Mystban.
Ban?!
Oh! King Ban!
Forgive me, King Ban.
Kill was defeated and I revealed your...
It matters not.
Let us admit what happened.
Their power was greater
than we anticipated.
I was almost killed by Dai.
It seems the time has come where I must
take back what I have placed in your care.
My king. I shall return it.
The true body of Dark King Ban
that is unrivaled in the Trio of Worlds.
He's gone!
In order to live a life
as close to eternal as possible,
I divided my body into two.
This base body retains
my wisdom and Magic Power.
And my youth and strength
went into this other body.
With every full solar eclipse,
I recast the Secret Spell of Frozen Time,
and keep my body sealed at its peak.
And now, the bodies become one again.
How many millennia has it been?
I forgot long ago.
THE ADVENT OF BAN,
THE TRUE DARK KING
This...
will no longer be needed.
Ron Berku's Kōmanotsue
has served its purpose well.
I had him make it for my protection.
For when I took on a weaker, elderly form.
But now that this body is whole,
I have all that I need.
Hmm.
I got my complete power back so quickly.
Things may take some getting used to.
I may go a bit overboard.
It looks like my hypothesis was correct.
Ban has now regained his original body.
No wonder we lost.
We were fighting against someone
who you could consider to be
Dark King Ban himself.
Hah! What a joke!
Showing off when
it's not really your own power.
It was just a parasite
who couldn't do anything on its own.
I won't forgive insult.
Just its voice?
No. It's here!
I can't stand insults of that nature.
That's... That's your...?!
That's right.
This is my true form.
A gaseous life form?
No. It's better to think of it
as a mass of Dark Aura.
It was possessing Ban's body
with that gaseous body.
Normally, it was covering his body,
but when fighting, it broke that seal
and entered the body.
What this ghost thing did
to Popp and Grand Master...
Maam!
Miss Maam!
I have no physical form,
so I am immune to all physical attacks.
Lunge at me carelessly and look!
This is what happens to you.
I am a mass of Dark Aura.
I'm something between a ghost
and a gaseous life form.
I was born from the dark thoughts
of thousands of years
of battle in the Underworld.
With my instinct to fight on
even without a body,
eventually I was able to
control other living creatures.
Just like this.
Once I capture a creature, its soul
is erased and then it becomes mine.
In the Underworld I moved from one strong
creature to the next, growing in power.
That was all I could do.
So that's it.
The reason you never lost respect
for strong men like Hadorra and Baran,
was because you had no body of your own.
That's right.
While I can become strong
simply by stealing the body of others,
I cannot grow strong
through my own efforts.
Anyone who could do that, I respected.
I envied them.
Don't look at me
with such pity, Crocodine.
Thanks to this accursed body,
I was able to meet King Ban.
And King Ban told me,
"It was your destiny from birth
to serve me."
King Ban needed my abilities.
I needed a great master like King Ban.
I must continue to work for King Ban!
Stop!
You can have my body!
Get out of Miss Maam!
-Move.
-Huh?
TIGER SHATTER FIST
INCINERATING INFERNO
Hmm. Not a bad body.
This is better than I thought.
Maam's body has been taken over!
I'd suggest not holding back.
That is, if you are prepared
to attack one of your own.
Don't underestimate me!
One cannot fight if afraid of losses!
You can't be as strong as
when you used Ban's body.
It doesn't matter what happens to her
if we can eliminate Master Dai's enemy.
Wait! You might hurt Maam!
Myst! The same goes for you!
Taking a hostage like that
isn't something befitting of you, is it?
A hostage?
Please don't underestimate me.
If you think I'm using this girl
as a shield, then you're gravely mistaken.
This little girl's body, in my hands...
can do this.
Oh no!
Is this really Maam?
She's strong! Too strong!
See what I said?
I was warning you
when I told you not to hold back.
This girl normally suppresses her power
out of concern for her opponents.
So when I use her power to the fullest
without hesitation...
this is the result.
At this rate Maam will...
How dare you! I'll kill you!
It's a shame for her...
but with my Aura Knuckle,
I can blow Myst away with her!
So you're finally serious.
Don't, Hym!
Your punch will pulverize Maam, too!
Of course it will! That's how it works!
Sorry, but understand that
it's necessary for victory.
There's no attack that can
conveniently defeat Myst alone.
No, there is!
That's it! Air attacks!
But even with an Air attack,
to leave Maam unharmed
and only defeat Myst is a difficult feat.
I would do it.
If I could move normally,
I'd do it myself.
Maam is a Disciple of Aban.
She believes in the power of light
and the legendary skills
of the Hero more than anyone.
I would put my faith in the light!
This is what it means
to learn from one's own student.
Let me use that.
The Aban Style Spear Technique,
Air Strike!
Will that work?
I don't know. I don't know, but...
We're counting on you, Sir Aban!
She ran!
Air Strike!
Did it work?!
She's back to normal!
Then it worked?!
Right before I hit, it left Maam's body!
It should still be nearby!
Dammit! Where the hell did it go?!
Its next target...
...is none other than...
you, Hyunckel!
I was after you from the start!
Hyunckel!
It went after the wounded
and immobile Hyunckel!
But why?!
We have to save Hyunckel!
One more time!
Air Strike!
My Air Strike was reflected?!
Hyunckel's body has begun emitting
incredibly powerful Dark Aura!
What?!
So that's what reflected
that light attack!
That's right, my friends!
This is why I chose Hyunckel!
I never cared about
that little girl's body!
Now that I've reached this point
it doesn't matter
if even his entire body is damaged.
I don't feel any pain, after all.
First it was Maam, now you plan
to use Hyunckel's body until it's ruined!
You fiend!
No. This body is the last!
I've prepared it specifically
for when I return King Ban's body.
I came to the decision to make
this body my own over a decade ago!
This Aura! It rivals the Aura it exuded
when it fused with Ban's body!
Witness the birth of the new Dark Warrior!
Hyunckel!
Someone help the others!
Right!
Myst...
Hyunckel! Right now I'm moving
through your consciousness.
I can hear your inner voice well.
But that will be over soon.
Your soul will vanish
and this body will be mine.
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Myst was after Hyunckel.
Inside Hyunckel's mind,
the two clash many times.
Meanwhile, Ban, the True Dark King
finally reveals his true form.
Dai casts aside his doubts
and faces him with his strongest attack.
Can Dai land the first blow against Ban?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Demonic Guard of Heaven and Earth"
The adventure continues!