boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
are itsukarada?
Since when was it?
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Being honest became whining
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Standing firm became strength
naa mitsukaranai?
Have you found it yet?
jishin janaku jibun jishin
Not confidence, your true self
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
I smolder because I've actually burned
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
tada me wo mihiraite
I'll just open my eyes
yume wo miru
And dream my dream
yume wo shiru
And know my dream
MAAM'S TURMOIL
Dai! Run!
He's paralyzed!
Stop!
Dai!
Why did you shoot Dai?!
Calm down! Look!
I can move!
I can move my body!
Damn you!
How can you move?!
What did you do?!
That was Kiari.
A spell that cures paralysis and numbness.
I shot him with Kiariku to help him.
We were interrupted...
but you merely
extended your life a few moments!
Dai!
Dammit, what is that weapon?!
I know! Can you cast Hyado?!
Sure! My Ice-type spells
are unparalleled...
Forget the bragging!
Load it into this bullet!
Huh? How?!
Press the stone at the top
and cast the spell!
Hurry!
All right...!
Hyadaruko!
Die!
Now!
The sun?!
How's that?!
You dare scar my face...
No, my pride!
Remember this, Dai!
I swear I'll kill you! I swear it!
Dai! Are you okay?!
Popp...
Popp, how could you ditch me?
Um, that was...
So you really did abandon him!
This is my Magic Bullet Gun.
It was a gift from Master Avan.
You load spells
into the Magic Bullets and fire them.
Huh. So it's shoots
attack and heal spells.
Oh, so you're
a student of Master Avan, too.
That explains your strength.
How do you feel?
Much better.
Your Midheal is better than Grampa's.
Hey, could I get a heal spell, too?
Here! Medicinal herbs!
What the hell!
What's this difference in treatment?!
The difference between
a Hero and a coward!
W-What?!
These clouds bode ill tidings.
I hope nothing's happened to Dai.
What is this terrible presence?!
You must be Brass, the Lump Shaman.
The Dark Army?! Impossible!
This island is protected
by Sir Avan's Magic Circle!
Even when Hadlar breached it,
there was a huge tremor!
How could anyone come in so easily?!
With my Mystic Magic Power
it's mere child's play.
Who are you?!
I am the Mystic Bishop Zaboera.
Legion Commander of the Mystic Legion,
LEGION COMMANDER OF THE MYSTIC LEGION
MYSTIC BISHOP ZABOERA
one of the Six Legions of the Dark Lord.
Gomechan!
Maam! Are you okay?!
Of course she is!
Maam's tough like a monster!
A monster?
I-I mean, she's like a saint!
Very good.
Maam, who are they?
They're nobody suspicious, Elder.
They're Heroes fighting the Dark Army.
They are?
Come to think of it, Gomechan was
the only one who never went crazy.
So your name's Gomechan!
I'm glad you were reunited!
Maybe Gomechan has some power
that blocks the Dark Lord's influence.
I'm just glad we're reunited.
Thank you, Maam.
You're welcome.
Maam.
Oh, Mom!
Huh?
Allow me to introduce my mother, Leira.
H-Hello.
Mom, these two are
Master Avan's students, too.
Oh, Sir Avan's?
You know Master Avan?
Of course she does.
Mom and my late father
fought the Dark Lord with Master Avan.
What?!
It was a long time ago.
My husband was a Warrior
and I was a Priest.
Together, we aided Sir Avan.
After the Dark Lord was vanquished
and peace was restored,
Sir Avan visited this village once.
That's when he tutored Maam.
That was four or five years ago.
Wow, it's already been that long.
So, is Sir Avan well?
Huh?! Uh, er...
He's fine!
He's as lively as ever!
Dai...
I see. That's good to hear.
You should stay here a while after all.
I'd love to hear about Master Avan.
Uh, we wouldn't want to intrude.
Good idea. Please, stay a while.
We really shouldn't.
Stay! Stay! That way
I get to play with Gomechan again!
I wanna play, too!
Me too!
The whole village welcomes
any student of Sir Avan.
Most of the men
have gone to protect Romos Castle.
So the rest of us
protect the village together.
With you in the lead.
My father was a Warrior and my mother
a Priest, so I guess I'm a Warrior Priest.
Master Avan taught me Healing and
Support-type spells and some martial arts.
But I can't use attack spells...
So he gave you the Magic Bullet Gun.
Yes. At my graduation.
I'll never forget that day.
What's this?
Your certificate of graduation.
An Insignia of Avan.
With this, anywhere you go,
you're officially a protector of justice.
And this is a present from me.
A present?
Master, what is this?!
A Magic Bullet Gun. A great weapon
that lets you charge and fire magic.
I made it based on research documents...
Master!
Huh?
I don't want this scary item!
I just want to be like Mom and Dad.
I just want to protect
everyone in the village!
That's all.
Maam, you truly are a gentle soul.
But Maam...
there are times when love and kindness
aren't enough to protect people.
Just as strength without justice
is powerless,
so too is justice without strength.
Besides, not only will this weapon
boost your attack,
but it can save people
with Healing and Support-type spells.
It's all in how you use it.
Don't worry.
In your hands, this will never
become power without justice.
I guarantee it.
Master Avan...
He was a little silly,
but strong and kind.
He truly was a wonderful teacher.
Oh man. I suddenly miss him.
At first I thought she seemed boorish.
Now that I look at her, Maam's actually...
MAGIC BULLET GUN
IO
EXPLOSION-TYPE SPELL
Pathetic! Disciple of Avan or not,
I let that child best me!
Dammit!
I see you're in a bad mood, Crocodine.
Who dares?!
Not that I blame you.
Not after some mere children
scarred you so.
Zaboera!
Good to see you, Beast King.
How did you know of my wound?!
The Heyedra, watchers of the battlefield,
belong to my Mystic Legion.
There is nothing I do not know.
And? Have you come to laugh at me?
Learning of your plight,
I've come to offer my aid.
You?! Offer to aid me?!
As a fellow Legion Commander.
I should go see the village elder.
What's wrong?
I need to ask him to load
these bullets with attack spells.
The elder is
the best spell caster in the village.
Huh.
In that case, I'll do it for you.
Really? Thank you!
Sure. Leave it to me.
Congratulations, Maam.
Popp hardly ever does anything for anyone.
Back me up a little, you moron!
Take care of that then.
I'll go prepare dinner.
We can't tell her that Master Avan died.
Yeah.
But Master Avan really is amazing.
So many people admire him.
Yeah.
I should fill these up.
Popp.
I gotta go!
Huh? Where?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, Dai!
What's his problem?
What?! You'd have me use
such a dirty tactic?!
There's no dirty or clean
in defeating an enemy.
Shut up!
I don't need your dirty help!
I'll fight him fair and square and win!
Are you sure?
That boy, Dai, cannot be underestimated.
Apparently he cut off Lord Hadlar's hands.
Besides, if you should happen to fail
you won't have a seat left
in the Dark Army, Crocodine.
Lord Hadlar may be aware of Dai's power,
but what will the other four
Legion Commanders say?
"So Crocodine, the Beast King,
was a fool who
couldn't even kill a child."
H-How dare you!
It's for your own good. Use this.
You wouldn't want to lose
your current position, would you?
It's to defeat Dai.
Take it.
I have a favor to ask!
Dai?
Please train me in magic!
I can't be saying I'm no good at spells
when fighting the Dark Army!
It's true that I am
the best Mage in the village,
but I'm not good enough
to teach a student of Sir Avan.
Magic training?
I was only trained by Master Avan
for three days.
What do you mean?
Elder, you can't let Maam
or her mother know.
Master is...
Master Avan...
died.
What?!
He was protecting us from the Dark Army.
I have to get stronger!
To avenge Master Avan!
I'm a disciple of Avan!
You can use this room.
-Okay.
-Thank you.
Maam's shut herself in her room.
I wonder what's wrong.
Master...
Master Avan...
Oh! Looking good this time!
Now cast it forth!
Mera!
Another failure!
Not yet!
What?!
I did it!
He threw the fireball!
Well done, young Dai!
I did it!
I finally managed to do a spell on my own!
What does he mean?
Well, sometimes this mark lights up
on his forehead.
When it does, he gets real strong
and casts amazing spells,
but normally, he can't.
Hyado!
He's pretty weird, huh?
A mark on their forehead... A crest?
The ones who can use
any fighting skill or spell.
I've heard of such a race
of ultimate knights, but...
He couldn't be.
Mera!
Okay!
Talk about a forced spell.
You can't call that a success.
Now, now. It just needs to hit his target.
He uses ingenuity to overcome weakness.
He's a clever lad.
Okay. I can't get complacent!
Here goes, Dai!
Huh? You're leaving tomorrow?
Yeah.
You said you were going to
Romos Castle. What for?
To help the king.
We heard he's being
threatened by monsters.
I see.
Maam seems kind of down.
Listen, Dai,
why don't we tell Maam the truth?
Huh? We can't!
But she might decide to join us.
But Maam has her duty
to protect this village.
Even so...
I see.
What?
Popp, you like Maam, don't you?
W-W-What are you talking about?!
W-Why should I like her?!
Liar. You're always staring at her!
I am not! Forget it!
Get to sleep! Goodnight!
Bye-bye, Gomechan!
Good luck out there.
Yeah.
Bye Maam. Thanks for everything.
I'm sorry. I really wanted
to go with you, but...
That's okay. The elder gave us
a map of the forest.
I see.
Goodbye! I promise to come back!
And I'll come, too!
They're good boys.
So young, yet they're
standing up to the Dark Army.
What's wrong, Maam?
They're both risking their lives
to avenge Master Avan, and yet...
I...
Maam, go on after them.
Mom?!
You want to help them, don't you?
Don't worry about us. Go on.
But...
I once left this village, too.
After I saw Sir Avan and your father
fighting even when they were wounded.
That's right.
You're my daughter. It's in your blood.
Mom...
Maam, don't worry about the village.
I still have strength in me yet.
That's right! Go on!
We'll protect the village!
Go help Gomechan!
Everyone...
Thank you!
Is it this way?
Or this way?
You're like this even with a map?!
Dai! Popp!
Maam?!
Why?
Dai! Popp! I'm coming with you!
Hooray!
Good for you, Popp.
W-What are you talking about?!
I just figured she'd be useful in a fight!
Dai, Popp...
if you're both disciples of Avan,
then I'm your senior.
So I'm going to carry on
Master Avan's will and fight, too.
Maam?
Did you...?
You can tell me on the way.
It's this way!
Come on! Hurry!
I think she's going to be
bossing us around.
That means she's reliable.
Let's just go!
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
With their new companion, Maam,
Dai and Popp reach Romos Kingdom.
Meanwhile, seeking revenge on Dai,
Beast King Crocodine attacks with an army.
Fighting his pride as a warrior,
Crocodine appears before Dai
like a furious titan.
Next time on
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Furfang Full Assault"
The adventure continues!