With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE DEMONIC GUARD OF HEAVEN AND EARTH
So you became my teacher of darkness
to raise me to be your perfect body!
Hah! You're too late in realizing that!
When I found you
after you had left Aban, I had an idea.
No matter how strong it is,
this body is still King Ban's.
It's not mine.
Even if I find a replacement, it might
not be compatible with my dark power.
But if I were to raise one from scratch
and train it to use the greatest
dark power, it would be the perfect spare.
Should the time come
to return King Ban's body,
it would be the perfect weapon for me.
A weapon?
All I was to you was a weapon.
That's right. You're my weapon. My tool.
There were times when I considered killing
you, but I'm glad I kept you alive.
In the end, you served me well!
Hyunckel!
I've found it! Your soul!
Hyunckel, now you will die.
Unlike that girl, the erasure of your soul
won't be temporary.
This soul will be disintegrated
and you will become a living puppet!
Then, at last, we will become one!
My spirit and your body will create
a warrior that will rival Mystban!
Consider it an honor! You get to be
a successor to King Ban!
This is...
Aura of Light?!
Hyunckel, you focused Aura of Light
into your own soul?!
I couldn't move well anyways,
so this was all I could do.
But you couldn't have gathered
this much power in an instant!
Not unless you knew I would possess you!
How did you know?!
I just had a feeling.
You were certain to choose me.
Hyunckel!
-Hyunckel!
-Are you okay?!
Where's Myst?!
He died...
inside of me.
So the never-ending struggle between
master and student of darkness has ended.
He should be happy.
He got to die in the perfect body
that he raised over the years.
Master.
What am I... to you?
Isn't it obvious?
You're my pride.
Why?! Why won't you attack?!
Isn't that supposed to be
the ultimate body?!
Just wait.
Master.
You're awake, Maam.
Where's Myst?!
Don't worry. It's gone from this world.
You banished it, didn't you, Master?
-By driving it from my body.
-Huh?
Uh, ahem, something like that.
Of course, I couldn't have done it
without everyone's help.
You'd rather not let her know
about your dark connection with Myst.
Hyunckel...
I can tell just how important
Maam is to you.
I'm well aware.
But...
But Popp...
Popp and Grand Master were killed by Myst.
Uh...
Ah, you're awake, Maam.
Oh!
Hm?
What the hell are you doing here?
Can't you tell? We're healing.
It's healing time.
Before I disguised myself as Kilban,
I rescued them from the Medoroa spell.
I left their unconscious bodies behind
and put on my disguise,
but with all the excitement,
I never got a chance to explain.
It looks like they just woke up, too.
It's not like they meant to worry you...
Uh, Maam, you're not listening.
Maam? Maam?
What are you being all prickly for?
Wait. Are you thinking,
"I should be the one to heal Popp!"
Is that it?
You idiot!
Maam, calm down!
We understand, but...!
Oh dear. And after I healed him, too.
Are you sure she still doesn't have
some residual evil in her?
Nah. Those two are always like that.
But it's always Popp's fault.
-Be that as it may, Captain...
-Hm?
It looks like Medicinal Herbs
don't work on me.
Can't you cast any Heal-type magic?
Ahem! I cannot!
Okay! Let's go help Master Dai!
Are you ready?!
Excuse me...
I'm not ready.
Good grief.
Hey Maam.
I mean... I was so worried.
He's always so thick.
That was a little violent
for trying to hide your relief.
Come on! Get up already!
A Hoimi spell!
Cast it yourself!
Not only him, but anyone with major damage
should either stay here or head back.
No. After all this, there's no going back.
Not to steal Hyunckel's line,
but I want to see this battle through.
Even if it costs you your life?
To be honest, I'm scared to go on.
Even as Mystban's body,
Ban's power was near perfect.
Up there, he now has the elder body's
Magic Power and intellect as well.
I know how terrifying
the bodies were apart,
so I'd honestly rather not
face them together.
Then why go?
I could ask you the same, Larhart.
You couldn't do a thing against Mystban.
Knowing there's someone even stronger,
why do you still go?
A foolish question.
Even if I can't do anything, it doesn't
matter so long as Master Dai wins.
To die for that cause is my duty
as leader of the Dragon Masters.
If I am but a shield for Master Dai,
then so be it.
That alone makes going worth it.
Well there you go.
Then you're the same as us.
No one here believes that
they can actually face the Dark King.
But we've made up our minds.
Win or lose, we're still going.
Because... Dai's up there!
The more shields there are, the better.
Good point.
Let's go.
To Dai!
GRAND CROSS
GIGA STRASH
It should take about five seconds.
Huh?
Five... four... three...
two... one... zero.
What is it, Dai?!
I'm... I'm healing! My body's healing!
What?!
You should be fully healed now.
Was that Leona's Behoma spell?!
That's right.
The Behoma spell cast on you while
you were unaffected by Hoimi-type magic...
it has finally taken effect.
I thought you would revert soon,
and I was right.
When fighting beyond your limits
with Aura similar to Dark Aura,
sometimes such backlashes
to the body can occur.
Weak beings can even die from it.
It can vary,
but you can estimate when someone will
be restored from their eyes and skin tone.
Why did you wait for that to happen?!
It's obvious.
So he could fight with me at full power!
What?!
You're quite perceptive, Dai.
It's been a while
since I've used this body.
Crushing an enemy not at their best
would be utterly boring.
If we're going to fight, I'd prefer it be
after you were fully healed.
Don't insult us!
Are you trying to show off?!
Such threats won't work on us!
What's wrong with me? I can't speak.
All he did was glare at me
and it's like my body's frozen!
I'm not trying to threaten
or show off, Princess.
I genuinely look forward to fighting Dai.
The Secret Spell of Frozen Time is broken.
Until the next full solar eclipse
in a few centuries,
I'm stuck in this form.
You've taken a few centuries
of my immortal time.
If you don't pay the price,
then I'll have been robbed.
You are obligated to amuse me
as best as you can.
He's pure evil!
I kind of understand what he means.
Dai, don't be stupid! Don't listen to him!
Now that you're in that form,
you're stronger than before, right?
Of course.
Much, much more so.
Being that strong in this world
is just boring.
It's not that I enjoy fighting,
but I kind of understand how that feels.
Dai...
You're like me, Dai.
Don't pretend otherwise.
Descended from warriors,
you have the blood of battle.
You can try to hide it,
but your true nature reveals itself.
Child of a Dragon who was foolishly
drawn to humans...
I shall tear off that mask you hide behind
and make you experience hell!
Leona, get away!
It's okay.
No matter what, I'm still me.
I'm everyone's Dai.
As I've already said, I haven't fought
in this body in thousands of years.
I can't hold back,
so it might be over rather quickly.
I hope you'll forgive me if it is.
Grandiose talk before a battle
isn't my style!
Raiden!
Oh?
That's Giga Strash!
This is the most powerful attack I can do!
Correct!
I do enjoy that about you.
You're bold and rational.
While you can appear reckless,
you use the most logical attacks.
To see how strong he is...
To know our difference in strength,
using my strongest attack is the best way.
And this attack takes time to prepare,
so it's difficult to use in a close match.
This is a head-on approach!
Then I should show you
a skill worthy of your attack.
Impressive that you instantly understood
the danger of this stance.
It's called the Demonic Guard
of Heaven and Earth - Tenchimato.
Tenchimato?
To my eyes it just looks like
he's taken a simple stance.
But there's no way it can be that simple.
Just look at how Dai is sweating!
And now let our greatest skills clash.
Which of us will fall?
What's wrong, Dai?
Will you back down now?
I should tell you that
your judgement is correct.
Your Giga Strash is indeed
the best attack to use...
win or lose.
That's right!
Giga Strash is the strongest attack
that I have!
This is...
my only...
option!
He's not dodging!
Is he going to try to take it?!
Giga Strash!
Phoenix Wing!
Calamity End!
Kaiser Phoenix!
Allow me to explain while my hand heals.
Why did Dai fall in an instant?
That's the secret to
Tenchimato
"Ten" is the attack.
"Chi" is defense.
And "Mato" is reminiscent of
the use of magic.
I see you understand.
I can attack, defend, and use magic
in a single instant.
This impenetrable stance is
the Tenchimato.
As an old man, two of the three
is all I can do.
But this young body allows me
to fight in such a way.
With this ultimate skill,
no matter how lethal an attack one uses,
it becomes useless.
Of course he couldn't win.
Giga Strash is a mix of magic
and attack that uses the Magic Sword.
But his opponent can add defense to that.
Anyone who charges into that stance
will have their attack nullified,
and be simultaneously torn apart
by his attack and magic.
I see even the strong-willed princess
is at a loss for words.
What a nice face.
Stop!
Hm?
Get away... from Leona!
You may be shielded by your Dragonic Aura,
but there's nothing
Calamity End can't cut.
No blade in the world can match
a strike from the side of my palm.
I wonder if you've realized.
That wound is in the exact same place
that you cut me before.
Now you shall slowly feel my wrath.
I think I've come up
with an entertaining idea.
Princess Leona.
You must serve beside me.
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Even Dai's Giga Strash didn't work against
the Demonic Guard of Heaven and Earth.
Ban tries to make Leona his own
to make Dai feel despair.
Meeting fierce resistance, he shows signs
of quiet anger for the first time.
As Dai falls into peril again,
Popp and the others arrive.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Eye Jewel"
The adventure continues!