Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE COLLABORATIVE RAIDEN
I...
W-What is this?!
L-Let go!
Now, now, little girl.
I wouldn't struggle if I were you.
Huh?!
This is the Underground Palace
of the Undead Legion.
We're heading for the entrance
down an extinct volcano.
One wrong move and down you go
into the abyss.
We've imprisoned the girl in a cell.
Good work.
And a message just arrived from a Heyedra.
Hadorra, the Dark Commander,
will be here shortly.
Hadorra?
My name is Baduck.
I'm a swordsman for Princess Leona.
For Leona?!
Well, I'm just
a wandering soldier for now.
Is Princess Leona safe?!
Of course!
The Princess always said,
"We can win once Dai comes.
Everyone hold out until then!"
Huh?
So where's the Princess now?
I was separated from everybody when
the Undead Legion destroyed the temple.
I see.
But, the three most powerful Sages
in Papunica are always with her.
I'm sure they're alive
out there somewhere.
We got split up with Gomechan,
so I guess it's just us now.
That old man's going to be disappointed
when he hears Hyunckel kicked our butts.
Why didn't you use
the power of your mark back there?
Listening to Hyunckel,
I understood how he felt.
You understood?
I was raised by monsters, too.
If somebody ever killed Grampa Burasu,
I'd probably hate them.
I couldn't get mad
when I thought about that.
You moron! If we don't beat him,
we can't save Maam or the Princess!
We fight! Once more, together!
The Underground Palace.
It's been 15 years.
So this place used to be your home castle?
Yes.
Well, well, Sir Dark Commander.
I see you're doing quite well.
To what do I owe this visit?
Call it a battlefield inspection.
I know the Dark King ordered you
to kill Dai, but I had my concerns.
Your concerns are unnecessary.
I've already fought him. He was nothing.
Next time, I'll kill him for sure.
Strength-wise, an obvious result.
However, you're a human,
and a former student of Aban.
Flazzard voiced his doubts
that you might somehow fail.
Just let the stupid general whine.
How dare you!
Listen! My orders come directly
from Ban, the Dark King, himself!
No one, no matter who, may question them!
Very well.
Just one more thing.
Has Crocodine shown up recently?
He left his tank of Resurrection Fluid
before he was fully healed.
I thought he might have gone after Dai.
I haven't seen him.
I see. Very well.
Why don't you stay a while
and look around?
Revel in the memories
of the rise and fall of an empire.
"Dark Commander." Hah!
If you'd been strong enough,
my father wouldn't have died.
Just wait and I'll show you
just how weak you really are.
That insolent brat!
What does Dark King Ban even see in him?
Perhaps he picked him on whim.
Or perhaps...
It was back when Dark King Ban
chose the Six Legion Commanders.
My Dark King, I cannot agree
with making Hyunckel a Legion Commander!
He is a human! And a student of Aban!
Hyunckel learned from Aban
in order to kill him.
Quite audacious, wouldn't you say?
Furthermore, should something happen to
my power, the Undead Legion will suffer.
A living human is the best candidate
to comfortably control the Legion.
Why do you favor him so much?
It's his eyes.
His eyes?
Those eyes are magnificent.
Eyes that curse all around them
and burn with aggravated rage.
They are what I seek.
Truly the eyes of an Underworld warrior.
Dark King Ban is great,
but his motives can be unfathomable.
Regardless, if Dai is killed, so be it.
If Hyunckel fails,
it gives us reason to punish him.
Ah, good morning, Dai!
Oh. Good morning.
This is my old Chain Mail,
but it's still usable.
Thank you.
Say, have you seen Popp anywhere?
Hm? I saw him in the forest earlier.
That's strange.
He never wakes up before me.
Popp!
What's going on?
What does it look like?
I just bound with a new spell.
A new spell?
We can't beat him by sword.
So we'll have to beat him by magic!
Did you forget? His armour repels magic.
Dai, you know the Weather-type spell,
Rana, right?
Uh, wait, what is it?
I just bound with the spell that
summons lightning clouds, Ranarion.
It's the most basic
of the spells that control weather.
I've been thinking all night
for a spell that might work on Hyunckel.
And I found one! An attack spell
that's guaranteed to hurt him!
Raiden!
Raiden?
Right!
His armour repels all spells,
but it still has to be made of metal.
That means, the shock
from a Electric-type spell
should penetrate his armour
and damage him directly!
But Raiden is a spell only a Hero can use.
You can't use it, and I...
That's why we do it together!
Huh?!
Raiden summons lightning clouds
and strikes enemies with lightning.
So if I summon the clouds with my spell,
even your Magic Power should be enough
to drop a lightning bolt!
Oh!
I see!
We combine our spells,
defeat him, and save Maam!
Got it! Let's try it out!
Spirits scattered in the heavens,
hear my voice!
Ranarion!
Maybe this spell
was a little too advanced for me.
D-Do it, Dai!
Raiden!
It worked! I did it!
Y-You dummy! Look closer!
Huh?
You've already got the clouds,
so of course it worked!
What's the point if you miss?!
Do it again!
Open it.
Don't worry.
You're just bait to lure in Dai.
Once I'm finished, you can go.
Huh? You won't kill me?
I won't kill a girl.
Even if she's an enemy.
It's the basic code of a warrior
my father taught me.
My father was the model warrior.
I still believe that.
You respected your father.
Of course.
That's why you hate Master Aban
for taking his life.
That's right!
How could I forgive Aban for killing him
for that justice and peace nonsense?!
Hyunckel, you poor soul.
Your pain of losing your father
was so great, you had to blame someone.
But that doesn't mean
you should hate justice!
That wouldn't make your father happy!
He was in the Dark Army, but your father
was a good, honorable man, wasn't he?
Quiet!
Open your eyes, Hyunckel!
You're a better man than that!
You're not a weakling who would vent
his anger on others out of sorrow!
Shut up!
Hyunckel...
Raiden!
Those kids have been going at it
for half a day. Just how tough are they?
Dai, a little more!
Raiden!
Good! You're starting to hit it!
I struck a defenseless girl.
But, when I look into her eyes,
I find I can't rebut her.
You're still here?!
You seem quite taken by that girl.
With one spell,
I could make her fall in love with you.
You may be strong,
but you lack experience in...
What are you doing?!
You parasite!
You shame of the Six Legion Commanders!
Begone from here!
You'll regret that!
Crocodine lost because
he didn't listen to me!
Wrong.
I bet he lost because
you put stupid ideas in his head!
Y-You'll pay for that!
I no longer have ears for anyone.
I will fight as I see fit!
Raiden!
Good! One more!
Okay, this is good!
Now we can go save Maam!
Yeah!
Hey! Come on, you two!
BAGIKUROSAI
VORTEX-TYPE SPELL
BLOODY SUKURAIDO!
That's the base of the Undead Legion.
So Maam's down there?
Looks like it.
The temple was empty,
so they probably took her down there.
Then Crocodine...
He probably died.
It looked like his wounds
from fighting you hadn't fully healed.
That's strange.
The usual guards aren't there.
Then that's perfect.
Okay.
Let's go!
Right!
-Okay!
-Huh?!
With my mighty sword...
Wait, you don't have to, old timer!
They called me
the greatest swordsman in Papunica!
We need you here
to keep watch just in case!
In that case, I suppose...
We're off then.
Take care!
It's better this way.
No offense to him, but that old man
can't do anything against Hyunckel.
Yeah.
Same with us.
We can't use Raiden underground.
Once we find Maam, we run. Got it?
Hyunckel will be tough to beat.
Dai, I've been thinking.
Hyunckel is in the wrong here.
I get he has his motives...
but that doesn't excuse
destroying Papunica Kingdom!
Popp...
Listen...
when I fought him, I was terrified.
I thought of running away like that one time.
But thinking about justice,
and Maam, and you made me feel
that I had to try no matter what.
When that happened,
I felt a little less scared.
Oh, so I come after Maam?
C-Come on! I'm being serious here!
If Hyunckel chases us outside,
that's when we'll fight!
What's going on?!
The brats have entered the palace!
Lead them to where
Master Hyunckel commanded!
Got it!
Oh no!
I've got to get out of here!
G-Gomechan?!
When did you get in there?!
Oh, you were worried about me
and snuck in.
Thank you.
Gomechan, can you get those?
This place is huge.
We can't find the prison at all.
This used to be Hadorra's Dark Palace.
Merami!
The hostage has escaped!
Run!
There they are!
Popp, this way!
It's narrow, but hang in there.
It's an air duct,
so there has to be an exit.
There! An exit!
What is this place?!
This is the Colosseum
of the Underground Palace.
Oh crap! It's a trap!
The Dark Lord Hadorra used to have
prisoners fight monsters,
and he enjoyed watching
the death in this bloody place.
I chose it as the perfect place for you!
He's already fully armoured!
We can see the sky here!
Your time to end has come!
Where's Maam?!
Don't worry. Once you're dead,
I'll have no use for her.
She'll be safely released.
In fact, you can leave as well, Mage.
Th-Thanks but no thanks!
Popp, we'll have to fight here!
Okay! Let's target him
when he raises his sword!
I don't need my sword!
I'll crush you right now!
He's toying with us!
He won't use his sword!
I'll draw his attention!
You summon the clouds!
Are you sure?!
I'll give it a shot!
Have you given up?
Fool! Haven't you realized
you're outmatched?!
He's anticipating my movements?!
Good going, Dai!
Just hold on a little longer!
Spirits scattered in the heavens,
hear my voice!
Is this a hidden room?!
Oh! A treasure chest!
Sh-Should I open it?
Maybe it's a Cannibox.
But it could contain some useful,
powerful legendary weapon.
Th-This is...?!
Just one fight and he's already
keeping up with me?!
Curse you!
What?! Chain Mail?!
Ow, ow, ow, ow!
Very well.
If it's a gruesome death you seek,
I'll end you with my blade of hell!
Here it is!
Time to die!
Popp, now!
Ranarion!
What?!
Take this!
Raiden!
It worked!
We did it! Hooray! Hooray!
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
With his anger towards justice,
Hyunckel's power is overwhelming
in both sword and magic.
Helpless, Dai falls prey
to his Bloody Sukuraido!.
All appears to be over, but Hyunckel
is shocked by a truth that Maam reveals.
Just then, Dai rises again!
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Deciding Moment"
The adventure continues!