boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE ROMOS MARTIAL ARTS TOURNAMENT
It's the balloon!
The balloon has returned!
We're back!
Princess!
Where has she been this whole time?
And she's brought more members.
Princess Leona, as the princess
of a country, you must behave--
Gather the key figures
of our country at once.
Huh?! Uh...
Time is of the essence. Hurry!
Princess!
Huh? What's going on?
Leona!
What about us?
You'll have to wait for now.
You should rest or train.
Just prepare for battle.
Prepare?
Would somebody
just tell me what happened?!
Take us to Romos.
My Lady!
It looks like Princess Leona
is leading the country to take action.
What should we do?
I don't know.
You all haven't fully healed yet.
Rest comes first.
But...
Shut up and obey! I'm off to bed, too.
Ah, that's enough.
Grand Master!
It's time for you to leave the mountain.
Test the results of your training here.
ROMOS KINGDOM
GRAND MARTIAL ARTS TOURNAMENT
This is...!
I'm not myself without this after all.
Your clothes look clean, too.
Meruru fixed them for me back in Teran.
She was so demure when we left.
She took really good care of us.
I wonder if she has a thing for me?
As if!
He's so dense when it comes to
girls he's not interested in.
What a waste.
Okay, Mentor! Let's start my training!
With my powered-up spells,
I'll blow away...
So he finally managed to do it.
Huh?
We'll train later.
Go check it out.
Dai!
You actually learned to cast
Raiden by yourself?!
Yeah! I can do it any time
without the power of my crest!
Check it out!
Raiden!
Whoa! Awesome!
Indeed. You've grown strong, Dai!
That's nothing compared
to his real power, old man.
Dai! Now try using
the power of your crest!
Oh! The power of the Dragon Knight?!
Wait right there!
What's this?
A gift from the princess.
No weapon or armour can endure
the full power of a Dragon Knight,
but these clothes have been made with
special Papunican cloth and technique.
They should be fine!
Huh?
The Knife of Papunica!
I thought it burned up!
There are three Knives of Papunica.
The one the princess had
and gave to you was the Sun Knife.
The one right here is the Wind Knife.
Yeah, the other one had a red gem.
This one's is green.
The Sea Knife has been lost,
so take care of this one!
You can't use it when you're using
the power of your crest!
Got it!
Good. Now try them on!
Ooh!
Huh.
Oh! A perfect fit! You look good in them!
Dai, the princess is currently
working on something big.
Since she can't help in person,
she felt that giving you this equipment
was the least she could do.
Leona, thank you!
Okay! Then let's begin!
Crocodine!
Right!
Wow! The power of the crest
even lets him cast Toberura!
That's fast!
This is great! It feels so light!
Then what about this?
Beast King Redemption Blast!
Dragonic Aura!
He withstood it?!
Well done. Even my most powerful attack...
Huh?!
Dai!
That scared me.
He suddenly fell out of the sky.
We thought Dai's power of the crest
was invincible, but it has a weakness.
With all of his Aura focused in his fist,
his energy gets drained rapidly.
If you can't control your energy use,
you won't be able to fight long battles.
That's not its only weakness.
Huh?
You can't use weapons.
Your fists will be enough
for a normal enemy,
but not against a powerful one like Baran.
Dammit!
Maybe if you had a sword
like Baran's Demon Dragon Blade.
Is the Demon Dragon Blade really
the only weapon a Dragon Knight can use?
I'm sure that's not true.
The world's a big place.
I'm sure there are other
amazing weapons out there.
For example,
the famous Sword of Champions.
The Sword of Champions?
That's just a legend.
No, it's not!
At the Martial Arts Tournament in Romos...
Martial Arts Tournament?
...the prize for the winner
is the Sword of Champions!
What?!
-Is that true?! Is it?! Is it?!
-Really?! Is it?!
It's true! Amy told me
when she came back from Romos!
That's it!
The Sword of Champions?
It's the prize for the tournament, right?
Oh, that.
I met King Romos
on orders from the princess.
ROMOS KINGDOM
GRAND MARTIAL ARTS TOURNAMENT
He wants to gather
strong warriors to fight the Dark Army,
so he's holding a Martial Arts Tournament.
Ooh!
Any fighting style is allowed
as well as weapons.
The winner will receive the legendary
Sword of Champions.
It's true!
When's the tournament?!
Today.
Today?!
The preliminary fights begin at noon.
Noon?! There's still time!
Where is it?!
At a Colosseum built
a short distance from Romos Castle.
We can reach the castle with Rura!
We should hurry!
Rura!
Wait!
Mister!
You!
The Hero!
Where's the Martial Arts Tournament?!
S-Straight down that road!
Down the path to the right!
-Thank you!
-Thanks!
We just might make it!
Let's win this thing
and get the Sword of Champions!
Yeah!
MAGIC BULLET GUN
HYADARUKO
ICE-TYPE SPELL
Oh my. I thought they ran off in a hurry.
So they already went to Romos.
It's probably better than
waiting around here.
Lady Amy, what big thing
is Princess Leona planning?
I'm not at liberty
to discuss that right now.
But not only have
the Papunica Troika been deployed,
but the princess herself is traveling
the world in preparation.
I see.
Crocodine, what are your plans?
For now, I'm hoping Baduck
can repair my weapon.
Then I apologize for this, but...
I'm leaving to train.
To train?
The battle with Baran taught me something.
When powerful individuals
fight each other at full strength,
the battle becomes truly horrific.
As a Dragonoid,
Baran couldn't control his power.
It turned him into a monster
capable of killing his own son, Dai.
I used to believe all I had to do
was defeat my enemy, but I was wrong.
The power to fight and win isn't enough.
Now that I've been given this Dark Armour
Spear, I must live up to Larhart's will.
To do that, I must gain the power
to stop even one like Baran.
But how will you train?
I don't have that much experience
with a spear.
But the Book of Aban contains the secrets
of the Aban Style Spear Technique.
So Aban was a master of the spear as well?
He said he was a master
of all fighting styles.
I must master
the Aban Style Spear Technique
and learn to use this Dark Armour Spear.
Wait! Shouldn't you
take the Book of Aban?!
There's no need.
I've read enough to memorize it.
Besides, it's a little too precious
for me to take.
Dai and Popp should have it.
Hyunckel...
Take care of things for me.
Got it. Leave Dai and Papunica to me.
He's always so hard on himself.
He's begun to realize his responsibility
as the eldest Disciple of Aban.
Do you think Dai will be able to win
the Sword of Champions?
Oh? This says...
We're too late?!
The preliminary fights begin at noon,
but registration ends an hour before.
Can't you do something?!
We came all the way from Papunica!
I know it's a request from the Hero...
And I'd like to do something...
But rules are rules.
Oh, come on!
The preliminary fights are starting.
It's about to start!
I wonder who'll be fighting.
Man, what a crock.
What did we waste all that effort for?
Dammit.
How about we challenge the winner
and beat them?
-Is that what Heroes do?
-What do you think?! Well?!
Man, let's go home.
Forget the Sword of Champions.
Why don't we check out the tournament?
We might learn something.
No thanks.
It's a domestic tournament in Romos.
No one interesting will be in it.
Hey! Hurry up!
There's a cute girl fighting!
But we might just learn something.
Wow! Amazing!
Amazing!
Let's see how cute she is.
Why you...!
Oh, wow!
Actually, let's go.
I'd rather not get to know
any girl this freakishly strong.
I heard that, Popp!
Huh?!
Three minutes, 15 seconds!
The Martial Artist Maam wins by knockout!
Oh, wow! That girl really is tough!
The next fight will begin in ten minutes!
Maam!
Dai! Gomechan!
So you entered this Martial Arts
Tournament as a Martial Artist!
That's right! What a surprise!
I didn't expect to run into you here!
Popp?
What's wrong, Popp?
Is it really Maam?
I can't be sure. It could be a fake again.
Okay!
What?
Huh?
The real Maam's eyes should have
a different look from Zaboera's...
What are you doing?!
That slap's the real deal...
Who the hell are you?!
A Fat Rat!
What's it doing here?!
You got a problem?!
The rules don't say a monster can't enter!
A talking Fat Rat!
What the hell are you?!
Ow, ow, ow! What are you doing?!
That's my line! You dare disrespect
Miss Maam, you random pervert!
Wait! I'm not...!
That's enough, Chiu!
Yes, Miss!
I told you about them.
This is Dai, Popp, and Gomechan.
Huh? This is the Hero's party?
No way!
Yes way!
That hurt, you little rat!
I'm gonna roast you on a spit!
Wait, Popp.
He's my senior pupil. Please forgive him.
Senior pupil?! Ratty?!
That's right.
I was trained by Grand Master
Brokin the Holy Fist.
This is the Karate Rat Chiu
who studied together with me.
Hah!
A Karate Rat?!
Huh.
I see. So you're the Hero Dai
I've heard so much about.
You're smaller than I thought.
Uh, you think so?
The next fight is between the
Wrestler Gomes and the Karate Rat Chiu!
Both fighters enter the ring!
Just sit back and see my strength!
Miss Maam, I'll make quick work of him!
Hey you, pervert Mage!
Let's talk later! Don't go anywhere!
That little...!
Sorry. He's not a bad guy at heart.
What's he like?
He used to be an evil monster
who ravaged a local village.
Grand Master Brokin captured him
and put him to training.
He gained a strong heart immune
to the Dark Lord's evil will,
and studied to learn to talk.
Brokin sounds impressive...
So what are you two doing here?
Well, we fought the Dragon Legion.
What?!
Uh oh! We have to explain what happened
gently, or the shock might be a bit much.
It was such an ordeal.
Hey! Dai!
Popp even died once!
Care to explain?
Well... Uh...
Huh? What the hell?
A monster wearing fighting gear?
You don't even know
my real strength, you fool!
What did you say?!
If I can defeat this thug
and show off how cool I am,
Miss Maam's heart will be mine!
So that's why you need
the Sword of Champions.
Yeah. If you win this...
Even if I win, I won't accept
the Sword of Champions.
Huh?!
I can't help you kill your own father!
Maam...
But...
Hmm. This appears to be
quite a success, Mister Zamuza.
Yes. And it's all thanks to you,
Your Majesty.
No, no. Gathering strong fighters
to increase our country's strength
was your idea. I merely agreed to it.
Let us hope we gather many of them.
Of course, Your Majesty.
That is our goal after all.
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Dai and Popp rejoice at their reunion
with the Martial Artist, Maam.
Leaving the tournament and
the Sword of Champions to Maam,
they watch over the battle
in anticipation.
The tournament moves on to the finals,
but behind the scenes,
an unknown plot begins to take motion.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Incident at the Finals"
The adventure continues!