Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE INCIDENT AT THE FINALS
Who the heck is that?
Get him!
So that's why you need
the Sword of Champions.
Yeah. If you win this...
Even if I win, I won't accept
the Sword of Champions.
Huh?!
I can't help you kill your own father!
Maam...
But...
And now, Gomez versus Chiu...
Let the fight begin!
Baran may be the enemy,
but he's your long-lost father.
If it's for defeating him, I don't want
you to have the Sword of Champions.
Maam, the power of a Dragon Knight...
It's a terrifying power
that could destroy the world.
Baran's using that power
to wipe out humans.
But Dai's been using that power for good.
That's why I want Dai to have
a weapon that will let him face Baran!
Maam, I don't want to defeat Baran.
I want to show him.
Unlike his ideal Dragon Knight,
being raised by Grampa,
learning from Master Aban, and fighting
with everyone has made me far better.
Dai...
To do that, I need the Sword of Champions
to match his Demon Dragon Blade.
If it ever looks like I'll use it for
the wrong reasons, you can punch me.
All right, Dai.
Hearing all this startled me, but
I promise I'll win the Sword of Champions!
Maam!
Hup!
Right!
Thanks!
Okay! Let's go cheer on Chiu!
Huh?
Not bad there, lad.
Grand Master and Maam are the only ones
I've ever struggled this much against!
But Grand Master and I are
the only ones you've ever sparred with.
Stop acting tough, you puny rat!
Hah! Laugh while you still can!
You'll regret it
once you see my killer attack!
Oh! Here it comes!
Chiu's boulder-busting killer attack!
His killer attack?!
Here goes!
Rattus Fastus Fist!
Whoa!
Two minutes five seconds!
The Wrestler Gomez wins by knockout!
Good going!
Amazing!
A boulder doesn't hit back after all.
He's not very strong.
He tries his best though.
Oh. I get it now.
Why was my killer move defeated?!
Chiu, this is hard to say,
but I found out your weakness.
Huh?! I don't have any weaknesses!
Power, speed, technique... In all areas...
You're a Fat Rat, so your limbs are short.
Your limbs are short...
Short..
You're a Fat Rat...
Your limbs are short...
He lacks reach. That's a critical
weakness for a Martial Artist.
His attacks can't reach his enemy.
No!
What's with him?
The victor is Baloria!
Listen, try to cheer up.
Be quiet.
I've just been given
a Martial Artist's death sentence.
Don't try to cheer me up.
Don't worry about it.
You can always fight
with headbutts and ramming attacks.
You've got the power.
Do you think a hero who fights with
headbutts and ramming attacks is cool?
Not really.
H-Hey.
I have to be cool!
The only reason I entered this tournament
was to show how cool I am to Miss Maam!
What?!
You're awfully audacious for a monster!
Hah! Love has no boundaries!
Get real!
You're a noisy one!
I didn't like you the moment I saw you!
What?!
Ah-ha. I get it. You're Miss Maam's ex.
Wha...?!
I don't care about a woman's past.
I don't know what happened
between you two, but...
Here's two gold coins.
So forget about her, alright?
Who taught you this stuff, you stupid rat!
Why you...! You dare raise a hand
against a Martial Artist?!
You'll regret that!
Hmph! I'll let you off the hook
with that for today.
Oh boy...
We've made a weird friend today.
It's Miss Maam's turn!
Miss Maam! Do your best for me!
Let the fight begin!
-Good going, Maam!
-Miss Maam!
Wow.
The Romos Martial Arts Tournament
has found its best eight fighters!
Let us introduce the eight fighters
who are the pride of this country!
First is the top contender to win!
The Warrior of unmatched strength, Larba!
-Larba!
-Win!
Next is the Omni-whip master, Stangul!
Sir Stangul!
The mighty spell-wielding Mage, Fobster!
Amazing!
The hunter who never misses, Hilto!
They're all equally matched
mighty warriors!
Next, with both power
and wrestling technique,
it's Wrestler Gomez!
Right!
The Knight with
the gale wind sword, Valoria!
Is he strong or is he weak?!
The mysterious figure, Mr. Ghost!
And the only female contestant,
the Martial Artist Maam!
So cute!
Good luck!
She's pretty popular.
These eight will compete in the finals!
Just who will win?!
Just who will claim
the Sword of Champions?!
So that's the Sword of Champions!
That one?!
Wow. I'll be winning that.
You can't even use it. I'll be winning it.
Don't bet on it. I can just sell it.
It'll be worth an unbelievable amount.
I won't let anyone have it!
That sword is for Dai!
It's going to be used for good!
So Maam entered the tournament.
This will be interesting.
Hm?
Where's Mister Zamuza?
Right there!
And now, the host
of this tournament, Mister Zamuza,
will explain the rules of the finals!
Huh. So this Martial Arts Tournament
wasn't the king's idea.
I wonder who he is.
All of you have fought well.
With such members,
I am immensely satisfied.
It was worth suggesting this tournament
to the king and hosting it.
Such a wonderful gathering
of promising samples!
You eight shall be the base
for the future Dark Army!
What kind of joke is this?!
Playtime is over!
W-What?!
Mister Zamuza,
what is the meaning of this?!
Thank you for your help, King Romos.
This will help our Dark Army greatly.
Who are you?!
The Dark Army's Mystic Legion Commander
Zaboera's son...
the Mystic Scholar Zamuza!
ABAN STRASH
DARK INCENSE
The Dark Army's Mystic Legion Commander
Zaboera's son...
the Mystic Scholar Zamuza!
A-A Darkling?!
The Mystic Scholar Zamuza?!
Zaboera's son?!
We've been captured by the Dark Army?!
What?!
For our Mystic Legion's
Superior Being Studies experiments,
we require humans with strong bodies.
So I used you to hold
this Martial Arts Tournament!
Plus, I can remove humans who can
resist the Dark Army from Romos!
Truly killing two birds with one stone!
Curse you! How dare you deceive me?!
It's too late! These eight are mine!
And if I can take your life, King Romos,
then that's even better!
Die!
Huh?!
Dai! Popp!
We won't let the Dark Army
get away with this!
Did he say "Dai"?!
Popp, protect His Majesty!
Right! I got this!
I'm your opponent!
Dai, the Hero...
It could be that my two birds
have become three.
It's the Dark Army! Everybody run!
Dammit! Are you kidding me?!
I'm not letting the Dark Army capture me!
It won't cut?!
Magic doesn't work either!
This isn't a normal cage!
This cage is alive.
What?! It's a creature?!
Miss Maam!
Dammit! Come on!
What are you doing?!
Get your filthy hands off my Bioprison!
You gutter rat!
I'm not a gutter rat! I'm a Karate...!
You won't even make
a good guinea pig! Begone!
Stop!
You little whelp!
So this...
So this is the power of a Dragon Knight?!
Chiu, Gomechan, go to Popp!
What?! Why do I have to...?!
Ow, ow, ow! I get it! I get it!
Let Maam and the others go!
If you don't, you'll regret it!
Amazing! Magnificent!
So this is the power of a real...
A real Dragon Knight!
What's so funny?!
It's not funny, it's joyous!
Your appearance surprised me at first,
but to see a real Dragon Knight is the
most blessed surprise I could hope for!
The purpose of our research is to reach
a Dragon Knight's power after all!
A Dragon Knight's...?!
The Mystic Legion leads
other Legions in Magic Power,
but we lack strength and vitality!
So I've been researching in secret on my
father Zaboera's idea to make up for that!
That's the Superior Being Studies!
Superior Being Studies?!
A Superior Being, in other words,
one that transcends Darklings!
By surgically transplanting
the strengths of various monsters,
we've come up with the idea
to artificially create Superior Beings!
And when your father Baran took
his Dragonoid form, we were convinced!
This is it! This is the goal of
our Superior Being Studies!
A being that could only be called
the ultimate bioweapon made by the gods!
A weapon?!
For that, we require test subjects.
That what they are.
We can't sacrifice our Darkling servants
for every experiment.
Strong humans make the perfect
disposable guinea pigs!
I won't let you do that!
Then you'll have to get angry and fight!
I want to see it!
The full power that you possess!
You can't resist a fight. You're like
a moth to a flame! The perfect sample!
A sample for making
a monster like your father!
Sh-Shut up!
Wow! No wonder he's called the Hero!
What power! Dai has grown so strong!
He's truly a Hero! His victory is assured!
Don't lose your head
and waste all your energy, Dai!
He's hiding something!
I can win! If this is his best,
my Superior Being...
Mighty Hero, now's your chance!
Finish him off!
Something's wrong!
At full strength,
Dai's Dragon power can shatter mountains.
It's destructive enough
to split the earth!
Sure, Darklings
are more powerful than humans,
but there's no way they can take that!
And yet, while he's getting wounded,
he doesn't seem close to falling!
I think Dai's noticed that, too!
What's wrong? Is seeing
your first real fight freaking you out?
Don't be stupid! I'm not freaking out!
I don't know why, but seeing that guy
makes my tail tremble for some reason!
You must be wondering why you can't
shatter the body of a mere Darkling!
Care to guess why?
I'll finish him in one shot...
with that attack!
Crest Beam!
Nice! That's a Dragon Knight's
killer move!
It appears with a Superior Being's powers,
a Dragon Knight can be defeated!
Are you saying he's already...?!
Correct! Superior Beings
are already 90% complete!
Since I used my own body as the base!
You've shown me
the power of a Dragon Knight!
Now it's your turn to see!
With the strengths of over
a hundred monsters combined...
the power of the ultimate Superior Being!
This is a Superior Being?!
Something strange is going on outside.
Dai!
No wonder Chiu's instinctively terrified.
That thing really is
the sum of all monsters!
Come on, Dai!
I've chosen you
to have the honor of being
the Superior Being Zamuza's first opponent!
You should be grateful!
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
Exposed to love and sorrow
hokori mamire michi no tochu
On the path strewn with pride
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
Fleeting moments of cowardice
nomikonda SOS
The SOS I held back
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
I clenched my trembling fist
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
That single little promise
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
Those trivial little memories
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
They're still in my heart
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
As embers that keep me burning
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
A single transparent beam of light
me no mae wo terashite yuku
Lights the way before me
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
There is little that I can do
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
As Zamuza becomes a Superior Being, Dai
fights with the full power of his crest.
But his stamina depletes too quickly.
Popp fights as well, but against a being
that surpasses even a Dragon Knight,
there's nothing he can do.
With Dai and friends in peril,
Maam's senior pupil, Chiu, stands up.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Superior Being Versus Chiu"
The adventure continues!