boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
are itsukarada?
Since when was it?
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Being honest became whining
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Standing firm became strength
naa mitsukaranai?
Have you found it yet?
jishin janaku jibun jishin
Not confidence, your true self
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
I smolder because I've actually burned
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
tada me wo mihiraite
I'll just open my eyes
yume wo miru
And dream my dream
yume wo shiru
And know my dream
LAND RIDER LARHART
Dino...
Does it hurt?! I bet it does!
You're braver than I thought.
That pisses me off!
I've got to fight back! While I still have
stamina and Magic Power!
I have to do something!
Oh! I like that face right there!
I know. I'll do what you did to Ruud!
I'll blow your head off like him!
That's it! That's the look!
Just keep that face!
Who's there?!
Great. I'm saved by
the last guy I want saving me.
Sorry to disappoint.
I guess I should thank you, Hyunckel.
I see.
So that man is the Hyunckel
Master Baran spoke of.
Popp, it looks like you've been
overextending yourself.
You tried to stop your enemies alone?
I didn't have a choice in the matter.
Dai's memories have been erased...
by his father, Baran!
So Dai and Baran
are related by blood after all.
But what's this
about his memories being erased?
So, where's Baran?
He went ahead to get Dai!
I see.
Then we don't have time to waste
on these scrubs.
What?!
That cocky bastard!
Former Undead Legion Commander
of the Dark Army or not,
he's just a human!
I'll slice you up just like that kid!
Popp...
You can have that one.
Pay him back for what he did to you.
Are you sure?
I'll be taking your spotlight.
What the hell?! Are you serious?!
That battered little kid can't fight me!
You fight me!
There's no way you can beat Popp.
If by chance you should...
then I'll fight you.
This guy is a complete moron!
You're letting the guy you saved die!
Fine then.
This time I'll finish the job!
And then I'll be coming for you!
All I need are two more spells!
I hope my Magic Power holds out!
Die!
Toberura!
What a joke!
You want to fight me in the air?!
What?!
I told you, you can't beat him.
I hit you with my Bloody Sukuraido!.
It leaves a mark.
You can have the rest of my Magic Power!
IO!
Galdandy!
I did it.
But my Magic Power's all empty.
You did well.
Don't worry. Get some rest.
I'm not worried.
Your attitude sucks,
but I know how strong you are.
I think I'll be taking you up
on getting some rest now.
You truly did a good job, Popp.
Curse you! How dare you
do that to Galdandy!
You'll pay for that!
I'll pay for that?
That's right!
This time, I, Borahorn shall...
Borahorn!
You're the ones who'll pay.
I don't know who you are...
What an imposing Aura!
...but after what you did
to my junior disciple,
don't expect to walk away from this!
You bastard! You broke my precious fangs!
I'll pulverize you!
Just fight already.
I'm in a hurry.
You brat! You think you're so strong?!
The strength of Sea Rider Borahorn
is unrivaled in the world!
Taste it for yourself!
Impossible! Where does such a frail body
hide such strength?!
You really think that this is
"unrivaled in the world"?
My friend has
twice the strength in his arms.
Why you...!
Well? Weren't you going to pulverize me?
I was just about to!
Glacial Breath!
That should finish it.
Borahorn's Glacial Breath
is as strong as a Mahiado spell.
If I strike someone when they're
frozen solid by my Glacial Breath...
they shatter like glass!
This is how I've always won!
As promised, I'll pulverize you!
What's that? What is he doing?
No, he can't do anything! How could he?!
Now shatter!
What?!
That's...!
My Glacial Breath didn't work?!
Play time is over!
Bloody Sukuraido!
Something's strange.
It seems the enemy
has decreased in number.
Are you next?
Not bad for a human.
But don't assume I'm like the other two.
Stop trying to bluff.
As you can see, my armour
repels attack spells and breath.
I know.
That was made by Ron Berku,
the greatest craftsman in the Underworld.
It's the Dark Armour Blade.
This was a gift. I don't know who made it.
I see.
But I wasn't bluffing just now.
I'm not very good at spells.
More importantly, my weapon rivals yours!
Wait, is that...?!
Take a good look
at Ron Berku's other masterpiece!
The Dark Armour Spear!
Amudo!
BLOODY SUKURAIDO
BEHOMA
HEAL-TYPE SPELL
Amudo!
The same armour as me?!
And now we're equal.
No. I'm a better warrior,
so I guess I have the advantage?
Save your lies!
You've shown me your best attack.
I should repay in kind.
Now see my best attack!
I'd say that was a decent dodge,
but that was merely a greeting.
Take a look at your helm.
Well?
You claimed to be the greatest swordsman,
but can you do that with a sword?
He's right. Without terrifying speed,
and needle-point accuracy,
such a feat is impossible.
And he did it without even
scratching my forehead!
Looks like you understand.
Indeed, you're a powerful swordsman.
But your blade is all muscle.
You're no match for me.
If I wanted to, I could easily
pierce your heart
before you finished blinking.
Rubbish! If you really can do that...
then let's see you try!
Dammit!
Wave Slash!
Even Wave Slash, the fastest Avan Style
attack can't even scratch him!
That appears to be your limit.
I see. You have power in your attacks.
But even with that power,
unless you can hit me,
it's meaningless!
It's the same as before!
I can't see his strikes at all!
It's just a flash of light!
Dammit! I have to do something
about his attacks!
Give it up!
You'll never see my attacks!
And now, as promised...
I shall pierce your heart!
He's strong!
He's on a completely different level
than the other two!
Trying to see
those speed attacks... is impossible!
Oh? You still haven't given up?
It's a gamble,
but I'll have to let him hit me...
and strike back while he's not moving!
If I can withstand his attack
and pull him in,
then I just unleash
my Bloody Sukuraido! straight ahead!
My attacks are more devastating than his!
Very well.
Then I shall end it with this.
Die!
Now!
Bloody Sukuraido!
No!
He merely threw his gauntlet at me!
I thought you would do that!
But I'm not foolish enough
to fall for that!
Take this!
The Land Rider's most powerful strike!
Hakendisutoru!
Unbelievable!
Nothing I could do worked on him!
Dai...
You are only human after all.
Something strange with the enemy?
What do you mean?
I'm not sure.
Here. Let me try my crystal ball again.
What's that noise?
Dai!
Someone's coming.
I can tell. I know him!
Dino, no matter where they hide you...
I can detect where you are.
For we are connected
by our bond of blood.
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Baran slowly makes his way to Dai.
Meanwhile, Popp and Hyunckel fall before
the Dragon Masters trying to protect Dai.
Eventually Larhart begins to tell
the story of Baran's astonishing past.
Why was Dai separated from his parents?
And what was the sad fate
of Dai's mother, Soala?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Dai's Secret"
The adventure continues!