boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
are itsukarada?
Since when was it?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE CLASH OF POWERFUL SWORDS
My sword realizes it!
Hey! Don't use your crest at full power!
You need to conserve your energy!
No! He's not the Hadorra we knew!
I have to fight
with my full strength or we'll die!
An astute observation!
You truly are my rival!
I expect nothing less
from a Disciple of Aban!
Oh?
H-Hadorra's completely changed!
He's a complete monster now!
I've seen those features somewhere...
C-Could he be a Superior Being?!
W-What?!
He was converted
using the data Zamuza sent!
Isn't that right, Hadorra?!
You'll see when you fight me.
You can experience it yourself.
This power I obtained
by sacrificing everything!
And realize...
compared to all the powerful enemies
that you've fought...
just how powerful I am!
D-Dai!
Th-That's impossible!
I blocked him with
the crest power focused in my right hand!
It's numb!
I can't draw my sword like this!
IORA!
A-A spell?! How?!
I thought Superior Beings
couldn't cast spells!
Stop, Hadorra!
No, you stop.
Hold it. We're at a ceasefire for now.
Out of respect for Commander Hadorra.
After all, this is a one-on-one duel
between him and Dai.
Get real! We never agreed
to any one-on-one business!
I believe you have an obligation
to see this duel through.
Hadorra can no longer become a Darkling.
He gave up everything for this battle.
Gave up?!
I know!
In order to be able to cast spells,
he gave up the ability to turn from
a Superior Being back to a Darkling!
So Hadorra is stuck
in that monster form forever!
That's right.
I hate to admit it, but as a result
he has gotten just a little stronger.
Yup, yup!
"Just a little"?! Are you kidding me?!
A Superior Being that can cast spells?!
That's a formula for true flawlessness!
I no longer care for my Darkling body!
In fact, by giving it up,
I was able to discard my foolish pride as
the Dark Lord who dominated the world!
True victory can never be attained
by one obsessed with reputation!
This is a lesson
your master Aban taught me!
He's strong!
Not only that,
he's more resolute than ever before!
I can't beat him without my sword!
I need to draw it
with my left hand somehow!
IORA!
Wave Slash!
Ah...
So that's your new sword.
Very well.
We shall see with your next strike,
whether the power within my right arm
is stronger than the power of your sword!
The power within his right arm?
Does he have a power
greater than those claws?!
N-No way!
I've seen the awesome destructive power
of the Sword of Dai!
No matter what sort of
killer attack he has,
it can't be stronger than that!
Dai, hurry up and finish it!
Don't forget that Superior Beings
regenerate while fighting!
I know that, Popp.
I intend to finish it!
Good. The feeling's returned!
Hm?
Dragonic Aura!
That's...
Is that...?
Aban Strash.
The attack that cleaved Sovereign
Rock Castle was probably Earth Slash.
And he just used Wave Slash.
This will be the first Aban Strash
the Sword of Dai unleashes.
No matter what
amazing power you have hidden,
it can't beat this strike
I've filled with all my power!
Then try it.
If you're right, I'll be cleaved in two.
But I will be testing myself, too!
The ultimate being
said to be of divine creation...
A strike from such a Dragon Knight...
will reveal just how complete a weapon
I, Hadorra the Superior Being, have become!
He seems pretty confident.
I wonder what power he's gained.
I won't lose!
Not while I have the Sword of Dai!
No matter who I face!
I won't lose!
Here goes, Hadorra!
Come on!
Aban...
Strash!
Did it work?!
That's impossible!
A direct hit from the Sword of Dai,
and his arm isn't even cut!
Is his... Is Hadorra's body
harder than Orichalcum?!
Th-That's not it!
I felt the impact of something metallic!
That's right, Dai. I have one, too.
A legendary weapon equal to your own.
The Sword of Champions.
The Sword of Champions?
That's right! Zamuza gave it to Hadorra!
Indeed. The real Sword of Champions...
is right here.
In my right arm!
ABAN STRASH
REAPER FLUTE
Yow!
Could this Dark Aura be...?
Dark Fire Energy.
What?!
Dark Fire Energy! Dark! Fire! Energy!
A Dark Aura that burns life energy
beyond its limits!
Remember that!
I can tell from that strike!
My power is on par with
that of a Dragon Knight!
And with an equal weapon,
my fighting power is greater!
Dai!
But I won't hold back!
To not fight with my fullest abilities
would be disrespectful!
Take this, Dai!
A strike I unleash
using the Sword of Champions!
Ultra Combustion Slash!
Ultra Combustion Slash?!
Not a bad idea.
By using Dark Fire Energy
along his sword,
the power of his attack is magnified.
Oh wow!
Dai! Run!
Don't get hit!
I-I can't! It's too late!
I have to defend with my Dragonic Aura!
My Aura's weak!
Die!
Oh my. Did he finish him?
Oh! Look there!
A Rura spell.
Popp jumped in and rescued Dai.
It's supposed to be one-on-one!
You cheater!
Hey! They're running! Get back here!
They won't get away!
Oh wow! He's super fast!
Let's follow them.
I never thought
I'd be called a cheater by them!
P-Popp... Why...?
Dai, I'll be honest with you.
You can't beat Hadorra alone!
Until now, he always tended
to give in to his emotions.
That's why even I was able
to match him somehow.
But Hadorra's changed!
He isn't just stronger
from becoming a Superior Being!
It's like his mind has been cleared!
Guys like that
who don't waver are dangerous.
I'd know. I've been there.
B-But...!
Enough! We're going back to Papunica!
We're already exhausted
from fighting Sovereign Rock Castle!
Here we go!
Rura!
Oh crap! I've used too much Magic Power!
What's wrong, Popp?
Don't worry! Let's just run
as far as possible with Toberura!
Where are you going, Popp?
You're headed East.
That's not the way back.
How do you like
my flawless Superior Being?!
If he defeats Dai, it will mean
he's surpassed a Dragon Knight!
He will be greater than
the god-created Dragon Knight!
Meaning I've surpassed the gods!
Surely it's safe to say now
that I am a god!
He can already use Toberura
without the use of his crest.
I can't take my eyes off him for a second.
Dai! Don't!
Don't do it!
Popp, run! While I'm keeping him busy!
The power of your crest has faded.
That means your Dragonic Aura is gone.
It looks like I win!
I have to attack!
Defending with what Dragonic Aura or
Magic Power I have left won't be enough!
It's over! Take this!
Anything! Some sort of attack that uses
all my Aura and Magic Power at once!
Ultra Combustion Slash!
L-Look!
Dai!
N-No!
He got Dai?!
Dai!
Th-This can't be happening!
The Sword of Dai
was supposed to be unrivaled!
Come out, Dai!
Get back here and fight back!
H-He defeated the Hero!
A clash between Orichalcum weapons
means conditions are matched.
In terms of physical strength,
a Superior Being is more powerful.
This is probably Hadorra's victory.
It's no fair. He's hogging all the glory.
Hadorra!
See? Hadorra wins.
A true Hero.
I'd be disappointed otherwise.
H-Hadorra, too?!
I-It was a draw?!
Myst, go see to Hadorra, will you?
I...
will take care of him.
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
It may just be a rationalization
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
Even now, even now I waver
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
How far will we go?
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
Exposed to love and sorrow
hokori mamire michi no tochu
On the path strewn with pride
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
Fleeting moments of cowardice
nomikonda SOS
The SOS I held back
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
I clenched my trembling fist
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
That single little promise
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
Those trivial little memories
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
They're still in my heart
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
As embers that keep me burning
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
A single transparent beam of light
me no mae wo terashite yuku
Lights the way before me
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
There is little that I can do
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
Dai and Hadorra's fierce battle
has ended in a draw.
Wounded, Hadorra leaves the battlefield.
Meanwhile, Dai remains missing
after falling into the ocean.
Left alone, Popp is hounded by Kilban.
Can Popp manage to survive?
And what happened to Dai?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Hero Lost in the Glacier"
The adventure continues!