boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
are itsukarada?
Since when was it?
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Being honest became whining
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Standing firm became strength
naa mitsukaranai?
Have you found it yet?
jishin janaku jibun jishin
Not confidence, your true self
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
I smolder because I've actually burned
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
tada me wo mihiraite
I'll just open my eyes
yume wo miru
And dream my dream
yume wo shiru
And know my dream
THE STRONGEST SWORD
I choose... the Light of Justice!
What was that strike?
He broke
the Dark Puppetry Aura Decimation Field?!
That attack was like Dai's Air Slash!
What?!
That attack I just used
in my desperation...
That was the Aban Style
Spear Technique, Air Strike!
The Air technique that only a true
warrior of justice can use...
I was finally able to use it!
You did it, Hyunckel!
The greatest of the Aban Style Techniques,
the Air technique!
It's thanks to you, Maam.
Your voice called me back from
the allure of the great power of darkness.
Hyunckel...
I swear this to you now.
Even should I die, I shall follow
the will of justice to my last breath!
Hey! His Aura Storm
hasn't completely stopped yet!
Curse you, Hyunckel!
A man's face?!
Mystban!
You saw it!
Ow! Ow!
His power is even greater than before!
You filth!
You dare... You dare reveal my face!
The face I must never reveal to anyone!
O-Oh come on! I didn't see anything!
Silence!
Ow!
He's enraged?! The cool and collected
Mystban of all people?!
How vital of a secret
could that face hold?!
Dammit! If I can use Air Strike again...!
Why can't I use the Aura of Justice?!
Your abilities are underdeveloped!
What could you possibly do to stop me?!
The least I can do for King Ban is
to unleash suffering worse than hell
on the people of this country
before their death!
Cry! Scream! And be torn apart!
The giant castle isn't moving!
They must be keeping it busy!
Princess!
Help the leaders escape
before the enemy finds us!
Yes, Princess!
What?!
Why won't you use
all your country's might to face them?!
You would run?!
You would abandon your own country?!
A country is nothing without its people.
Our survival is our top priority!
I won't run! I'll fight until the end!
Take a look around you!
Your vessel and troops
were decimated by that giant!
Over there!
A monster?!
So there you are.
Mera!
Gira!
A Mahoton spell!
They've found us!
So this is...?!
Yes. It's complete.
This is the world's strongest sword.
What will you call it?
This sword was forged for Dai.
There is no other like it.
Therefore, its name...
can be none other than the Sword of Dai!
The Sword of Dai.
The sword that was forged just for me!
It's like it's drawn to my hand!
With this...!
What's wrong?
Huh?!
What's with this sword?!
It's locked and I can't draw it!
I told you.
That sword has a soul.
It chooses when and where it fights.
What? That sounds kind of finicky.
You'll see why soon enough.
But if I can't draw it...
When you require true power in battle,
the Sword of Dai will respond
to your spirit and break its own seal.
I understand.
Master Mystban.
Shadow, have you found them?
Yes master. The leaders of the world
are in the Grand Chapel.
They found them!
Good. Take Sovereign Rock Castle
and slaughter the leaders.
As you command.
Oh no!
It's moving!
It's headed this way!
Everybody, get inside!
Okay!
Be sure to tell me
how it performs when you can.
Sure! Thank you so much, Ron Berku!
You two as well!
Dai... Our son...
Do look after Popp for us.
If he ever gets in the way,
feel free to toss him aside, Dai.
Don't worry about him.
Popp is a lot stronger
than you give him credit for!
Well, I'm off.
Rura!
Dammit! I have to do something!
He's using an extra Aura Hand
on Hyunckel?!
As for you, I shall tear you apart
by my own hand!
Why do you obsess over just me?!
Is it because I'm awakening to
the Aban Style Air technique
that can vanquish the Dark Aura?
Or is it because...
I'm the only one who might
uncover the secret to your face?!
Hyunckel!
Die! You shall not speak another word!
Who dares?!
Who do you think it is?!
If anyone besides Hyunckel
can break the Aura Hand...
It's gotta be him!
Dai!
ABAN STRASH
TOMAKUGUTSOSHO
So it's you, Dai.
Indeed, your mastery of Air Slash
makes you the only one
who can completely cleave my Dark Aura.
That's true. But...
why with the Knife of Papunica?!
So you were seeking a new sword.
Very well.
Can that sword endure
the power of a Dragon Knight?
Come and show me!
Well? Show me!
No thanks!
What?!
My sword says
that you're not worth showing!
Little brat. You and your arrogance!
You can be swallowed and die
in my Decimation Field, too!
Aban Style Sword Technique...
Air Slash!
I can move!
Is everybody all right?!
If he were to use this power
with his new sword...
What's wrong with your new sword?!
Is it incomplete?!
That's not it. This sword...
Look out!
Hyunckel!
His shield is a boomerang?!
Just how many weapons have you got?!
Dai, leave him to me!
But you're wounded!
Look!
It's headed for the Grand Chapel!
No ordinary power will work
against Sovereign Rock Castle.
But with your power...
Your actions are futile!
He really is beginning to learn
the Air technique!
Go Dai!
That's right, Dai!
We can still fight here!
Protect Leona and the others!
Got it!
Watch this, everybody!
This is the power of the sword
that Ron Berku forged!
Shadow, hurry and crush the Grand Chapel!
Yes master!
There's nowhere left to run.
Was everyone... Were they all defeated?
Forgive me, fellow leaders.
Had I known they were this powerful,
I would have focused on evacuating
instead of facing them.
It's one thing to die for my own rashness,
but to drag you all into this with me...
It's shameful.
King Bengana, it's too early to give up.
That's right! Giving up before any of us
would be true shame!
You're right.
Dai!
Okay, my sword!
Now's the time to lend me your power!
What?!
He's facing that giant with a sword?!
There it is!
That's Dai's most powerful sword!
Fool! A sword can't cut a castle!
Insolent brat!
I'll crush you along with the others!
It's opening!
W-What happened?!
What?!
Impossible! You cut through
the Dark Army's Sovereign Rock Castle?!
How did he do that?!
So that's the most powerful sword!
Wow! With just a normal attack
it was like slicing open the sky!
What would happen
if I were to use all of my power?!
Curse you!
Open all cannon bays!
Reduce him to dust
with the might of Sovereign Rock Castle!
I don't think so!
Dragonic Aura!
Dai's Dragonic Aura is going up his sword!
Fire!
Where?! Where did he go?!
The central chamber?!
Right under this throne?!
Take this!
Master Mystban!
He cut the giant castle in half!
Holy cow!
Hooray! Take that!
Amazing!
Dai?! Where's Dai?!
There!
A true Hero!
He did it!
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
The Sword of Dai showed its true power
and cut Sovereign Rock Castle in half.
Enraged, Mystban attacks the party
with his fathomless power.
Kilban suddenly appears,
but disappears again after taunting Popp.
In his anger,
Popp pursues Kilban only to find...
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Field of Death"
The adventure continues!