boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
are itsukarada?
Since when was it?
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Being honest became whining
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Standing firm became strength
naa mitsukaranai?
Have you found it yet?
jishin janaku jibun jishin
Not confidence, your true self
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
I smolder because I've actually burned
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
tada me wo mihiraite
I'll just open my eyes
yume wo miru
And dream my dream
yume wo shiru
And know my dream
THE INSIGNIA OF AVAN
Begirama!
Sir Avan!
Is everyone alright?
Thank goodness.
Talk about very nice timing.
Master!
I didn't think he had the strength.
Master, are you okay?
I'm in a lot of pain.
But I don't have time for that now.
He's more powerful than
when he was the Dark Lord.
Not only that, he has
the Dark King backing him.
Our enemy is far beyond my expectations.
With our current strength...
we can't win.
But...!
That's why he...
Hadlar, the Dark Commander...
must be brought down here.
And Dai, Popp...
I ask that someday you two
defeat Vearn, the Dark King!
I underestimated you.
Well done, Avan, the Hero.
Wait...
Master, do you intend to die?!
Master, I'll fight with you!
Asutoron!
W-What's this?!
It's Asutoron!
Asutoron?!
It's a high-level defensive spell
that turns the body to steel
and repels any magical attack!
But if we're like this...
We can't move!
You should all be safe now.
You may watch my final battle from there.
By "final," you mean...!
Don't do this! I'll fight!
Together with you!
How foolish, Avan. To spend your remaining
Magic Power on your students.
Oh! Those are...!
Insignias of Avan!
Certificates of graduation!
Graduation?!
I give these to students
I believe are fully trained.
Dai, you possess outstanding potential.
I regret our training was cut short
at three days.
If we continued for the remaining four...
I'm certain you could have become a Hero.
Master Avan!
That is why I give this to you.
Continue with your training
and become a true Hero.
Master, I...!
Popp.
Don't!
Don't do it, Master! I don't want that!
Stop being so morbid!
Our training isn't over yet!
Popp...
I don't care if you were the Hero once!
Why are you doing all this?!
You said yourself you can't beat him!
It's because I can't beat him
that I must risk my life.
Besides, Popp,
I believe the power we gain through
training should be used to help others.
Perhaps my power was granted to me
by the gods to protect you on this day.
Don't do this, Master!
Someday I know you will understand.
So, hold onto this
for when that day comes.
Master!
Oh my. You haven't officially graduated
and you're already so emotional.
You'll need to work much, much harder
to become Heroes worthy of those.
Mr. Brass and Gomechan,
thank you for everything.
Sir Avan, don't do anything rash!
Don't worry. I will not lose.
Done saying goodbye to your students?
Let us fight, Hadlar!
Very well.
But having used your last Magic Power
to cast Asutoron has sealed your fate.
You've spent most of
your Magic Power, too!
Here goes!
Fool!
As we stand...
even with just combat skills...
I have more than enough...
power to...
tear you...
apart!
Master!
Move! Move!
Die, Avan!
You...!
A spell?! Impossible!
You should be out of Magic Power!
This spell requires
very little Magic Power.
Instead, it turns life energy
into explosive power to defeat enemies!
Wait! This spell is...!
Stop! Don't do it!
You'll die! It'll kill you too, Avan!
Do you want that?!
Popp, Dai! I leave the rest to you!
Stop!
Megante!
Master!
Sir Avan used the spell Megante.
Megante?
He used the final destructive spell
that uses his own life to save his allies.
Sir Avan, you truly are...
Master used his own life to protect us.
Master...
BEGIRAMA
HEAT-TYPE SPELL
IONAZUN
EXPLOSION-TYPE SPELL
Is that Master?!
Hadlar?!
No! Where's Master?!
You truly have grown weak, Avan!
You used your own life to cast Megante,
and you still couldn't defeat me!
Now there is nothing left to fear!
The Dark Army is unopposed!
He truly is a monster!
No way...
Curse you, Avan.
I need to wipe out your students
here and now.
Don't worry! The effects of
Sir Avan's Asutoron still remain!
It will repel any attack!
Don't be so sure.
Having you immobile is perfect.
Huh?!
He can use Mera, too?!
My Mera is pure hellfire.
It will burn until my target is destroyed.
I simply cast it, and the moment your
Asutoron wears off, you'll turn to ashes!
Don't! Please don't!
You should be happy.
When you die, you can go to the afterlife.
Your precious master is there,
waiting for you.
That's right! Master did it for us!
He gave his life so we could survive!
If we die here,
then what did he sacrifice himself for?!
I have my life
because Master gave it to me!
What?! Is he going to
break the Asutoron on his own?!
What is he?!
He broke the Asutoron!
You brat! Burn to death!
Merazoma!
Hyadain!
Dai used magic?!
And it's stronger than mine!
My flames...
Then I'll just pummel you to death!
Die!
What is this power?!
Impossible! Th-That crest...!
A Dragon?!
What is that light?!
I remember!
Dai used powerful magic in battle before!
That mark appeared on his forehead then!
A Dragon Crest?!
Is this boy a Dragon Knight?!
Impossible!
How dare you...
How dare you kill Master!
You'll pay for that!
Don't get cocky, boy!
Yes!
This is impossible! I may have
sustained damage from Megante...
And he may be a student of Avan...
But how could I be overpowered
by a mere child?!
Die!
Die! Die!
Eat this!
IORA!
Dai!
How's that? I used
the last of my Magic Power on that spell.
Surely he's dead now.
Dai! Don't tell me he killed you, too!
That's right! There's no way I can lose!
Impossible!
I won't lose! Not to you!
Die!
Dai! Above you!
Feel how powerful Master's attack is...
for yourself!
What?!
Avan...
Strash!
Curse you, boy! I'll remember
this humiliation and your name!
I swear I will kill you! Dai!
Dai, are you okay?!
Grampa, Gomechan.
Where's Hadlar?!
Unfortunately, it seems he escaped.
I saw him use a Chimaera Wing.
Oh...
Master...
Master!
The magic circle of light remains
even after Sir Avan has gone.
He still protects us even now.
I told you Master is amazing.
Popp...
Dai, what will you do now?
Huh?
Will you continue
your magic training under me?
Or...
I...
Master gave me a mission.
To one day defeat Vearn, the Dark King.
That's why... I...
SOVEREIGN ROCK CASTLE
I see you took quite the beating, Hadlar.
Forgive me, my Dark King,
for making you see me in this condition.
It matters not.
You have buried Avan, the Hero.
Consider them wounds of honor.
My Lord.
I have placed all of my trust in you.
With your rival Avan dead,
no one can stop my Dark Army.
Go forth and fulfill your dream
of overthrowing the world.
Yes, Sire!
It's true that Avan is dead.
But that boy Dai is a far greater threat.
Wounded as I was, to overpower me,
Hadlar, the Dark Commander...
And that mark on his forehead.
The Dragon Crest.
If he really is a Dragon Knight...
And, with Avan's training,
if he manages to reach power of a Hero...
he will become
far more powerful than Avan!
The wounds I received from him
are proof of that.
The wound from Dai heals slower
than the wound from Avan.
In that instant,
Dai's blade surpassed that of his master!
If I let him live, he is sure to grow into
a terrifying enemy.
I must crush him!
While he still remains a fledgling!
With my grand Dark Army!
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
With new determination in their hearts,
Dai and Popp leave Dermline Island.
Their first stop
is the Dark Forest of Romos Kingdom.
Dai and Popp meet the girl Maam.
The terrifying footsteps
of monsters approach.
Can Dai and his friends
safely make it through the forest?
Next time on
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Crocodine, the Beast King"
The adventure continues!