Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
FURFANG FULL ASSAULT
Dai! Popp! I'm coming with you!
If you're both disciples of Avan,
then I'm your senior.
So I'm going to carry on
Master Avan's will and fight, too.
Maam?
Did you...?
You can tell me on the way.
I think she's going to be
bossing us around.
That means she's reliable.
Let's just go!
There it is! Romos Castle!
Okay! Romos Castle here we come!
Go home! The king is already asleep!
Come back tomorrow!
Oh come on! We've come all this way!
Don't be like that!
Sorry, but security at the castle
has been increased due to monster attacks.
We cannot just allow anyone
in the castle at night.
Listen, we happen
to know the king personally.
You might get chewed out later.
Keep up with the lies
and I'll have you thrown in prison!
Get lost!
Dammit! I was sure we'd finally get
some hospitality at the castle tonight.
Oh well. Let's spend tonight in an inn.
Oh. There.
Welcome. It's quite late
to be out, isn't it?
Um, the three of us
would like to spend the night.
Huh? Just you three?
Aren't there any adults?
Mister, we may not look it,
but we're fighting the Dark Army.
You could say we're a Hero's party.
That's a coincidence.
It just so happens there's another
Hero's party staying here.
Huh? A Hero?! Really?
There. They're staying in that room.
Don't, Dai! Save it for tomorrow!
Oh come on! I just want to say hello!
Sir Hero! Sir Hero!
What? It's late.
I wanted to meet you!
Go home!
We're exhausted from
battling monsters all day!
Can't I talk to you a little bit?!
No! I'll sign an autograph tomorrow!
What's going on? Who is that?
Some annoying brat.
I've heard that voice before.
Hey, Sir Hero! Sir Hero!
Enough! Buzz off!
The fake Hero!
Th-Th-The monster boy!
Huh? What?
What are you doing in Romos?!
What's going on, Dai?!
These guys are villains
pretending to be Heroes!
They kidnapped Gomechan
and did all sorts of bad stuff!
Hold on! We've washed
our hands of that stuff!
That's right! We paid for our sins
and are working to be true Heroes!
Working by doing what?
Well, we defeat weaker monsters
and get rewards.
And open leftover treasure chests
at the castles the Dark Army cleared.
Coaching soldiers in fighting and magic
pays pretty well, too!
That's right!
Seriously?
That's basically what you used to do.
Honestly, how can anyone who only fights
weaker monsters call themselves a Hero?
You're one to talk.
Why don't we let bygones be bygones?
From here on, I must be ruthless.
The pride and honor of a warrior
are meaningless without victory.
I will use whatever method I can...
and kill him!
Come out Dai!
Otherwise, Romos Kingdom falls today!
That voice...
A massive army of monsters?!
It must be Crocodine's Furfang Legion!
They're launching an all-out attack.
Hey! What is all that?!
It's the Dark Army's Furfang Legion!
The Furfang Legion?!
An army of monsters this size
has never appeared before!
It's Crocodine!
Go forth! Wipe out Romos Castle!
Crocodine...
What is that thing?!
He's headed for the castle!
Dai, wait! Dai!
Your Majesty!
What is it?!
It's no good! The enemy army
is overwhelming! We can't hold them!
Our only option is
to help you escape, Your Majesty!
I cannot abandon my people and flee!
A king's desertion is the same as defeat!
I may be old and weak,
but I will not turn tail and run!
We must fight!
We must hold out hope until the end!
The gods offer no miracles
to those who retreat!
Who goes there?!
I am Legion Commander of
the Furfang Legion of the Dark Army...
Crocodine!
Curse you!
King Romos, I have no interest
in your pathetic life.
But I need you as bait
to lure out my target!
We have to go after Dai!
Huh?! Why?!
Didn't you see Crocodine's eye?!
He intends to kill Dai for revenge!
We have to help!
Count us out.
Indeed.
What's the point in fighting someone
you know you can't beat?
There's no greater treasure
than one's own life after all!
I can agree to that.
Stop goofing around! Hurry!
But Crocodine's really strong.
It'll be like just going to die.
That's why we have to help!
Dai might get killed!
We all have to work together!
Don't worry about it.
Dai's super strong in a pinch.
He won't die.
Popp?
What's with you, Popp?!
Aren't you Dai's friend?! His companion?!
Don't you care about him?!
Lay off me! I never wanted
to fight the Dark Army in the first place!
I never wanted to fight!
I mean, I know I trained together
with Dai and all.
But he's the reason they keep coming.
I don't want to end up
dying because of him.
Ow...
Why you...!
Popp...
Didn't...
Didn't you learn anything
from Master Avan?!
I thought you and Dai
were fighting to avenge him!
That's why I followed you two.
That's why I joined you two!
Maam...
You disgust me!
MAGIC BULLET GUN
IONAZUN
EXPLOSION-TYPE SPELL
Move!
Stop!
I'm the one you want!
It can't be... That boy...
There you are, Dai. I've been waiting.
Is it really Dai? He's grown up so much!
The gods have given me a miracle
in the nick of time!
Fight to your heart's content, Crocodine!
So long as you have that ace
up your sleeve, Dai can never win!
What's wrong?! Fight me!
Otherwise...!
Okay...
Mera!
A spell?!
In our last battle,
Dai could only use a sword.
Did he master Mera in only a few days?!
They say it only takes three days
for someone to change,
and he really did!
If he continues to grow, he'll become
the greatest threat to the Dark Army!
-Dai!
-Your Majesty!
Maam, cast Behoimi on the king!
Got it!
That's it, Crocodine.
Throw away your pitiful pride and use it!
Master Zaboera, what sort
of secret weapon is in that box?
It contains that boy's greatest weakness.
I didn't want to use this,
but you leave me no choice.
That's a Magic Cylinder!
A Magic Cylinder?
It can contain living creatures!
You can bring them in or out with a spell!
So it's like the Magic Bullets
that Master Avan made?!
Yeah! It must contain some sort of backup!
Come forth! Derupa!
Huh?! Grampa?!
Brass is Dai's adoptive parent.
He's a Lump Shaman.
If he leaves his island and falls under
the Dark King's Magic Power,
he instantly becomes
a vanguard for the Dark Army.
Now go, Lump Shaman Brass!
But...!
That monster!
Wait!
That's my Grampa!
What do you mean?!
He raised me after I washed up
on his island! He's not a bad monster!
Please wait!
He cannot harm his adoptive parent!
There's no one better to use against Dai!
Medapani!
Hey! Are you okay?!
What's wrong?!
He had Medapani cast on him
so he's confused!
Hold him!
Yes, Sire!
Let me go! Let me go!
Grampa, stop it!
Why are you doing this?!
Grampa, wake up!
Don't you recognize me?!
Darn it!
Grampa...
D-Dai...
Grampa!
Merami!
Lord Hadlar.
What is it?
I have word from my master,
Mystic Bishop Zaboera.
He is working with Commander Crocodine
of the Furfang Legion to fight Dai.
He says victory is at hand.
Understood. Leave me.
Yes, Lord.
Zaboera working together with Crocodine?
Curse that Dai.
Already he's grown strong enough
that Crocodine can't handle him alone.
But I suppose there's no worry.
Not if Zaboera is lending his wisdom.
In the Dark Army,
he has the most cunning and cruel mind.
He cannot be underestimated.
G-Grampa...
I'm fine, young lady!
Go help Dai!
This is the end!
Dai!
You again?!
I've got a Merami of my own for you!
Don't!
Dai?!
Maam, you'll hit Grampa!
But he'll kill you!
Please... He's the only family I've got!
He's...
my Grampa!
Brass, finish...
Crocodine!
How can you call yourself a warrior?!
After all that talk of pride, I thought
you'd be more honorable than that!
You call yourself the Beast King?!
Don't make me laugh!
That's right!
Using a hostage against a little boy?!
You're a disgrace of a warrior!
You should be ashamed!
That's right!
Shame on you!
You're no warrior!
Enough!
A warrior without an achievement
is merely a beast with no teeth!
Your words mean nothing!
I've already abandoned my pride!
He said it!
Well said, Crocodine.
With that attitude,
your victory is assured!
Impressive, Master Zaboera.
To turn a Legion Commander into a pawn.
Now if Crocodine wins,
your standing is sure to rise.
After I set all this up,
even a muscle-brained buffoon
like Crocodine can't lose.
What can we do?
The Magic Cylinder.
Huh?
If we can get that,
we can seal Grampa away again.
You keep Grampa busy.
I'll go for the Cylinder.
Got it.
Merami!
Too bad.
It was a good plan, but your speed
was halved with the damage from Merale.
D-Darn it!
It's over, Dai!
Dai!
You won't suffer long. I'll end it now...
with this, the Beast King Crocodine's
most powerful attack!
He's gathering all of his energy...
all of his aura into his right arm!
W-What is that?
Beast King Anguish Blast!
W-What's that?!
Victory is mine!
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
Dai is overwhelmed by
Crocodine's incredible power.
Maam is immobilized
by the Mystic Bishop Zaboera.
The final blow bears down upon them.
Meanwhile, Popp is far
from the battlefield.
What does Popp feel
about his friends' peril?
Next time on
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"A Single Shard of Courage"
The adventure continues!