With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE DECIDING ATTACK
If I fought Hym, even I might lose.
Stop being modest, Larhart.
In a one-to-one, you would probably win.
But in battle, there's compatibility
and strengths and weaknesses.
Larhart.
You use your super speed and skills
to defeat enemies with blasts and shocks.
You don't fight with Aura skills.
I see.
Hym is still inexperienced in skill,
but has that overwhelming Aura.
And it's Aura of Light, something
that hurts Mystban the most.
Basically, a natural enemy.
Hey Mystban...
I feel a little bad
beating you up like this.
The Dark Army was full of
annoying characters.
But you were the only one
who seemed to respect Lord Hadorra.
Hadorra?
That's impossible!
Are you telling my, your Aura and life
are a dying gift from him?!
That's the case!
Not that I've got
a more logical explanation.
I just want it to be so.
You're saying Hadorra's will gave Hym life?
How is that...
I think so, too, Little Hym!
Miracles aren't for the evil!
You're the 12th member
of the righteous Beast King Commandos!
That's all there is!
Thanks a lot, Captain.
Don't make me laugh!
A mere puppet pretending to be
the rebirth of Hadorra?!
You forget your place, you worm!
I, Mystban, shall use all of my power
to shatter you to pieces!
Sorry, but that's not possible!
To shatter my Orichalcum body
is something...
only one person in the world can do!
Huh? Me?
Ouch!
Whoa!
Good going, Little Hym!
No! At this rate...!
This pawn is stronger than I thought!
Sadly, I have no choice!
I have to use that power!
King Ban!
King Ban! Can you not hear me?!
No!
He may be fighting Dai,
but I can't believe King Ban would be
so focused as to not hear my voice.
Wait! Is it possible that Dai
is pressing King Ban that much?!
What's wrong, Dai?
Why are you hesitating?
Is he... Is Ban, the Dark King
really this weak?
Or is the Minakator spell affecting him?
No. It barely had any affect on Hadorra.
It can't be affecting Ban this much.
Then... I've gotten that much stronger?
How does it feel?
To overwhelm an enemy
who once defeated you.
I'm asking how it feels.
You question whether it's really me,
and can't get a grasp on your own growth.
But very soon...
very soon you'll feel euphoric.
Feel... euphoric?
To drown in your own power.
It's a feeling better than
drinking any exquisite wine.
Not that a child would understand
the joys of wine.
Mystban is moving to the offensive!
Without permission to use that power
I must fight with what strength I have!
I will pour all my Dark Aura
into this hand!
Here I go!
Dark Aura Ultimate Hand!
Oh no! It's his last ace in the hole
focusing all his Dark Aura into his hand!
Hym, don't let that touch you!
You have to dodge it!
You can't dodge this!
I'll pulverize you!
That idiot! He's not dodging!
That's crazy, Little Hym!
Wait!
That stance!
See?!
Not even Orichalcum can withstand
the force of my palm!
Oh no!
Now shatter into pieces!
No thanks!
I told you only one person
can shatter this body!
The best you can do
is shatter one arm!
Which lets me get close to you!
My ace in the hole is my left strike!
Aura Knuckle!
I-Impossible!
A mere pawn would defeat me?!
This is impossible!
-Yes!
-Good going, Little Hym!
It's taking damage
to inflict greater damage.
Besides, my arm can be healed
with a Hoimi-type spell.
Now to finish him.
That's not necessary.
He's already unable to fight.
More importantly, get his mask off.
His mask?
K-King Ban...
Oh no. Dai is losing the initiative.
It's Ban's strange confidence.
I'm sure that he's really fighting
at full strength.
He can't be holding back at all.
So why is he so confident?!
Dai! Be strong!
It's possible to win
simply through inertia! Stay aggressive!
Leona, don't show yourself!
Huh?!
Now I shall uncloak it!
The mystic veil that hides your power...
while I still can!
That flaming bird!
Kaiser Phoenix!
I've seen it before!
I can banish it with an Aban Strash!
A simultaneous attack!
Wh-What happened?
It looked like they collided at once.
Where's Dai?!
Dai...
The mighty Dragon Knight.
Even with my greatest attack,
I couldn't defeat him.
Dai!
GIGA STRASH
KAISER PHOENIX
King Ban...
You're saying to pull his mask off?
Mystban...
His identity has long been
shrouded in mystery.
I believe that his identity
is directly linked
to Dark King Ban's secret.
The Dark King's secret?
He used to never speak at all.
In other words, the face he hides,
or his voice, depending on who hears it,
is a great secret that Ban
doesn't want revealed to anyone.
Are you serious?
When I was in the Dark Army,
Ban to a favoring to me.
Among the Six Legion Commanders,
I probably interacted with Ban the most.
And Mystban was my teacher of Dark Aura.
If I can see his real face,
I might be able to get a glimpse of the
secret Mystban's been hiding for ages.
If we can relay that to Dai
as he's fighting Ban...
I get it! It could give him an advantage
in their final battle!
I'm fine with that.
Either way, this guy won't
put up a fight..
We can finish him whenever we want.
Pulling off this raiment is no big deal.
"Raiment"...
Here goes.
W-Wait!
Wait a minute!
What's wrong, Big Guy?
Why are you yelling?
I think that unveiling Mystban's mask
could be very dangerous!
Dangerous? What do you mean?
"Don't remove Mystban's Shadow Raiment."
Right before we came here
from the surface,
Ron Berku gave me this message for you.
Shadow Raiment?
That's right.
What is that?
You mean the clothes that Mystban wears?
I'm not too sure about it myself.
I can only express it in vague terms...
but there's no doubt that something
is suppressing his power.
There's only one reason that he and I
fought evenly matched for that long.
Just as I was, he, too,
wasn't at full strength.
It was a fight between
two people holding back.
Even in that ferocious battle?
During our fight I realized
even if he wanted to fight
at full strength, he can't.
Probably for a different reason than me.
What he said when he left was proof.
"Maybe if you had fought at full strength
our battle wouldn't have taken so long."
"Of course, the same could be said of me."
Then, Ron Berku, you're saying
Mystban is still hiding his true power?
Yes. Something's there.
Don't do anything that would force him
to fight a full strength.
Don't remove his Shadow Raiment.
In other word, Ron Berku described
whatever it is that holds
Mystban's unfathomable power back
as his "Shadow Raiment."
And that's his mask?
I'm not sure.
But Hym's use of the word raiment
made me remember.
Then Ron Berku meant
if there's a chance to defeat him,
do it before he reveals his true power.
Yes.
They make a good point, Hyunckel.
Mystban definitely is unfathomable.
And Ron Berku is the Legendary Craftsman
of the Underworld.
Couldn't he be far closer to the secret
of the Dark King and Mystban than you?
That's possible.
We can't ignore a warning from Ron Berku.
Hey! So what do I do?!
I don't mind either finishing him
or revealing his face!
Hyunckel.
That must be Dai!
The final battle with Ban
has already started!
Hym, it's better that
we finish him off here!
What about his true identity?
We should listen to any warning
from Ron Berku.
Plus we need to hurry ahead.
For now, we should get rid of
any Dark Army forces that we can.
Sure thing.
Yes. That's the right choice.
Even if this next blow obliterates
Mystban along with his secret.
The desire to know it may stem from
my personal feelings
because he was my teacher,
despite it being for evil.
Right now, victory comes first.
Bye Mystban!
Hope you rest in peace!
King Ban! King Ban!
Forgive me!
That was definitely
Ban's deciding attack!
And Dai managed to survive it!
But how?!
All I could see was
up to the instant they clashed.
Unbelievable.
To dive into my Kaiser Phoenix.
What?!
In that instant you...
Kaiser Phoenix!
Block my Kaiser Phoenix
and my Kōmanotsue hits.
Block my staff and the flames consume you.
Knowing that either way results in damage,
you chose to dive into the flames.
A seemingly reckless move.
But inside the Phoenix is the only place
from where one can successfully hit me.
I knew I'd be hurt either way,
so I chose the way where I could hit back.
Dai are you okay?!
Of course he isn't.
The Dark King's strongest spell hit him.
A natural result.
You may have managed to strike me,
but my Kaiser Phoenix hit you directly.
If you were unhurt
it would scar my dignity.
Now for another attack!
You won't get the chance!
Now it's my turn!
Before that wound
to your shoulder regenerates...
I'll use my deciding attack!
This time, Ban, it's your turn
to defend yourself!
And if I've thought this out right,
I know I can defeat you with this!
Interesting!
Then let's see this attack of yours!
Huh?!
Doru Aura?!
Fool. Have you forgotten that
Doru Aura has no effect on me?
No! Doru Aura will work!
I've fought Dad once, so I know it well!
Doru Aura is a spell no defense can stop!
Once cast, there's only
two ways to survive it!
Withstand it or dodge it!
But when you first appeared,
not even your clothes were damaged.
Dark King or not, if you withstood it,
you wouldn't be completely unscathed.
But if you dodged it with a Rura spell,
you wouldn't appear from under the rubble!
The secret to how you
survived my Doru Aura spell must be...
in the Kōmanotsue!
Not a bad hypothesis.
But what if you're wrong?
Doru Aura is a spell that drains
massive amounts of Magic Power.
I doubt you can use it more than twice.
You used it once, so what if I counter
after you've spent all your Magic Power?
I already know that.
Once I use this,
my Magic Power will be all spent.
But I know you won't counter!
Take this! Doru Aura!
He stopped the Doru Aura with his staff!
I knew it!
The blade of my Kōmanotsue,
can be burst forth as an energy wall
that can block any spell.
Just as you hypothesized,
I survived your Doru Aura by using
my Kōmanotsue to block it!
If I can withstand this, I win!
Got you!
Leona!
What?!
Silver Feather!
Curse you!
And another!
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Dark King Ban vanishes in the light
of Dai's second Doru Aura.
The shock reaches the White Garden where
the others hope to regroup with Dai.
But, though Mystban fell before them,
he rises once again
and reaches for the raiment
that covers him.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Shadow Raiment"
The adventure continues!