Come on, Hadorra!
This is the end!
The Hero defeated the Dark Lord.
There's no telling
what humans are capable of.
Just who do you think you are?!
Begone! Begone, humans!
DAI, THE TINY HERO
Dai, the Hero is here!
Yippee! Go, go!
Defend the island's peace!
You imbecile!
Ouch.
What was that for, Grampa Burasu?
If you have time to play Hero,
then do your magic training!
Aww...
How many years has it been
since I found you?
What kind of Hero
can't even learn a single spell?!
It's so annoying, Gomechan.
Grampa Burasu is the one
who told me about the Hero.
There once was a swordman of justice,
called the Hero,
who fought the Dark Lord,
a tormentor of people.
The Hero, together with his companions,
defeated the Dark Lord at last!
But...
We monsters, who were
under the thrall of the Dark Lord,
were freed from his evil will
and came to live here on Dermline Island.
It's all thanks to the Hero.
The Hero sounds amazing!
Dai, you're to become a brilliant Mage,
so that you can help the Hero someday!
Grampa just says that
because he's a Mage...
but I wanna be a Hero.
It sounds the coolest.
You agree don't you, Gomechan?
I knew you'd get me, Gomechan!
Huh?
It's a ship.
Whoa!
It's a Hero!
Why's a Hero coming to this island?!
I can't just sit here!
Wait here, Gomechan!
Hup!
Merman, take me to that boat!
I might just meet a real Hero!
For an island supposedly
infested by monsters, it seems peaceful.
Ever since the Dark Lord died,
they've all gone docile.
All we do is knock them around
and people worship us as Heroes.
Talk about an easy business.
Indeed. I can't wait to cut loose again.
Don't just slaughter them. It's not
an extermination mission this time.
The one-of-a-kind mythical creature,
the Golden Metal Slime.
Does it really exist?
What's that?!
A Merman!
There's a child riding it!
Wow! It's really you!
You're a Hero, aren't you?
That's right.
The Hero and his noble companions.
Oh wow!
Little boy, who are you?
I'm Dai!
You're from that island?
Yep!
But isn't that island full of monsters?
It's fine. They're all my friends!
Oh really?
They're your friends?
You want me to call everyone?
That's right.
We go around protecting innocent monsters
so they aren't bullied by humans.
So we want to know
the monsters' situation on this island.
Do it for us, Dai.
Got it!
The assembly whistle? What's going on?
Little boy, is this all of them?
Yep. Almost.
Look, isn't there one like this,
but more pretty?
Hmm...
Oh! You mean Gomechan!
Gomechan?
It's a nickname! The entire name is
Golden whatchamacallit,
but that's too difficult.
That's it!
Huh?
We'd really love to meet Gomechan!
He's a little shy, so I'll go get him!
What's wrong, everyone? What is it?
Oh, there's a surviving Lump Shaman.
Who are you?!
Deroline the Hero and his companions.
A Hero?!
No, I sense something malicious about you.
Why did you come here?!
What an obnoxious geezer.
Why are you struggling?! It's a Hero!
What's that?!
Hyado!
S...
Stop it!
Dai, run!
Grampa!
Thank you, little boy.
Here's a reward for you.
Bagi!
Dai!
Let's clean up and get out of here!
Everyone get down!
IO!
Those scoundrels!
That went well.
We'll have whatever we want now.
I can't stop laughing!
Why would a Hero do this?!
Why would a Hero kidnap Gomechan?!
That Hero was a fake!
No Hero would do something like that!
Grampa!
I'm going to go save Gomechan!
If you want to fight them, use these.
What are these?
Magic Cylinders.
But I can't use magic.
Don't worry. Each Cylinder
can trap one living creature within.
Just say "Derupa," and they'll suck in
whoever you point a Cylinder at.
Say "Iruru" to release the contents.
Hmm.
Come up with a plan
and attack with your friends. Also...
these Gold Cylinders were given to me
by the Dark Lord long ago.
I was too scared
to find out what they contain.
-Derupa?
-Just in case...
Iruru!
-Imbecile! Why...
-Derupa!
Iruru!
-...are you...
-Derupa!
Oh wow!
Okay! That's Grampa for starters!
And now...
Everyone who can still fight, come on!
Okay!
IRURU/DERUPA
MERA
FIRE-TYPE SPELL
Deroline, the Hero. Raise your head.
Your Majesty.
So, how was Dermline Island?
Was it a dark hive of monsters
as rumors say?
Yes. Evil remnant monsters assaulted us
in an endless stream,
but, together with my companions,
we vanquished them.
-Wow!
-Amazing!
A true Hero!
During this, we captured a rare monster
of which only one exists.
We offer it to you, King Romos.
A monster for me?
Th-This is...!
Called the mythical creature,
it is the Golden Metal Slime.
Truly a living jewel.
How magnificent!
Well done, Deroline!
You may have the reward you requested!
The Romos family symbol of a Hero,
the Crown of Champions!
You are truly a Hero worthy of this!
-What's that?
-It can't be!
Give back Gomechan!
Gomechan?
That Golden whatchamacallit!
Get back, King Romos.
He may look innocent,
but he's with those vicious monsters.
My friends aren't vicious!
But they can be against people like you!
Let's do this, everyone!
Iruru!
...sucking me in?!
You don't take a hint! You'll regret this!
Everyone, hang on!
How do you like that?!
Attacks from air, land, and sea!
We'll get you!
Mera!
Stay away!
Masopho, let's put them on ice.
-Bagi!
-Hyado!
Now! Let's get those monsters!
Right!
Mera!
Hyado!
IO!
Stupid monsters!
Why you...!
Don't underestimate a Hero!
You're no Hero!
You're a crook who kidnapped my friend!
Hmm?
Shut up!
Dai!
I'm your opponent here.
I'll silence you for good!
The Golden Cylinders!
Use the Golden Cylinders, Dai!
Okay!
Iruru!
Not one, but several?
You startled me! They're just Slimes!
Iruru!
A d-d-d-...
A Dragon?!
Bagi!
Good going, Dragon! Get that fake Hero!
That's enough!
All right, little boy.
Get that Dragon to back off.
Gomechan!
Otherwise...
Don't!
Derupa!
Nice going, Zulbon!
Darn it!
It looks like we win.
These were all...
A King Slime?!
Zulbon!
So a King Slime came out in pieces!
Stay away!
Now!
Derupa!
You did it, Dai!
Gomechan!
Damn monsters!
How dare you!
Stop!
They said they
were a Hero and his companions,
but no Hero would try to kill a child
or take hostages!
The King of Romos?
Get back!
Enough. Let us hear out this monster.
Well...
It seems as though my eyes were clouded.
How could I let them go to Dermline Island
without realizing they were fakes?
Dai's acts of violence were out of
his wish to save his friend. Have mercy.
Sir Burasu, it is I who should
beg for forgiveness.
Bring it forward.
Perhaps this brave child is the one truly
worthy of wearing this Crown of Champions.
I bestow this to the future Hero.
The future Hero...
Now, let us continue on our way
to the Papnica Kingdom.
Please! Don't leave us!
Wait!
Where's my Crown of Champions?!
Hmm? Don't ask me.
That's my treasure!
Where did you hide it?!
I don't know!
Besides, you have no use for
something for a Hero!
I'm the future Hero!
Your future is as a Mage!
And nothing else!
Oh come on, Grampa!
THREE MONTHS LATER
Mera!
Pathetic!
Ow!
Grampa, I wanna do Hero training!
You don't need such training!
Let's continue!
Aww...
Huh? It's a ship.
Hm?
Oh! It's a battleship!
A battleship is invading!
What?!
Isn't that a battleship?
That's the Sacred Ship. A special ship
that only a Sage is allowed to use.
Huh.
Is that a Sage?
Get your head down!
Ow!
You are Dai, the Future Hero
and Burasu, the Venerable?
The Future Hero?!
B-Burasu, the Venerable?
I am Bishop Temjin of Papnica Kingdom,
and this is Varon, the Sage.
We have come to this island with
Princess Leona of Papnica on a mission.
The Princess?!
Oh!
Are you Dai, the Hero?
Yep!
Oh wow, you're so tiny!
Talk about undependable!
Princess Leona of Papnica Kingdom
arrives at Dermline Island.
Dai guides her across the island,
but mysterious monsters attack.
Dai and Leona fall into peril.
Just then,
Dai is enveloped in a mysterious light!
Next time on
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Dai and Princess Leona"
The adventure continues!