With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
BATTLE OF TRUE DRAGONS
What's going on?! What are they doing?!
What does it look like?
They're fighting a ferocious battle.
Then Dai and Hadorra's clashes
are causing this gust of heat?
It's not just a gust.
It's highly concentrated energy.
They're completely in their own world.
We escaped here before we got burned.
What's going on?
How does this sort of thing even happen?
A Battle of True Dragons.
-Oh?
-What's that?
You don't know?
This is truly the Underworld's infamous
Battle of True Dragons recreated.
That sounds quite interesting.
In the distant past...
the two most powerful
Dragons in the Underworld...
finally decided to determine
who was stronger.
Veruza, the Abyss Dragon...
and Vorikus, the Lightning Dragon.
Evenly matched, the clash
between the two was truly savage.
Their Auras and flame breath
and Magic Power collided,
and the super-heated ground
was laid waste.
Their battle created
a field so tempestuous
it drained the life
of any who stood in it.
Those who approached were incinerated.
In the end, this ultimate duel
of pure power
was won by Veruza.
And he became the Abyss Dragon King.
Since then, this battle is called
the Battle of True Dragons,
and is revered as
the most intense duel in history.
Pay close attention, Kilban.
This isn't something one sees every day.
Only when both sides
are extremely powerful and evenly matched
does such a thing ever happen.
To think that those two
would show me such a battle.
They're both fighting
with all their might.
That energy must be spilling over,
creating that field around them.
How can you be so calm?!
Dai's like that and you're not helping?!
As you can see,
no one can approach those two.
It's almost as though their will
is keeping everyone at bay.
At least I think so.
Then why isn't Dai using his sword?!
Hadorra isn't either.
Ever since that heat field appeared,
they've been fighting hand-to-hand.
I think they both know
that drawing their weapons...
will signify the end of their duel.
Dai!
I'm not waiting!
My Medoroa can blow away any heat!
I'll hit Hadorra with this!
What are you doing?!
Don't, Popp. This is their duel.
This isn't the time for platitudes! Look!
Just standing there
is draining their stamina!
Dai may be a Dragon Knight, but between
little Dai and that huge Hadorra,
it's obvious who has more!
I don't care if anyone says it's unfair!
I'm helping Dai!
Wait, Popp!
Not you too, Princess!
Dai wants this duel.
That why we shouldn't interfere.
He's just naive.
He should just ignore Hadorra's condition!
Isn't his inability to
what makes Dai our Dai?
Our Dai?
I've been thinking about it.
About the power of Dai's soul.
I thought it was Courage,
but Courage is the power of your soul.
Yeah... Right.
In that case, what's his power?
Perhaps Dai's power
is that naivety you mentioned.
Huh? How is that...?
His kindness and innocence...
That clarity of heart...
Yes. His pure heart.
Dai was raised on Dermline Island,
an island of monsters.
So he doesn't discriminate
or hold any preconceptions of anyone.
It allows him to treat everyone
equally and naturally.
Isn't that his greatest trait?
It's what allowed us
to all become friends.
It allowed Hyunckel and Crocodine
to become our allies.
The reason we're all here now
is thanks to the power of Dai's soul.
So if Dai sensed anything within Hadorra
that made him accept this duel,
then it's our duty to respect that.
At least that's what I think.
What's wrong?!
I can't beat him like this!
I... I have to use
my strongest attack against him!
His sword!
That's the face.
Whenever you're about to do something
unbelievable, you make that face.
It's become my favorite face of yours.
It's beginning. The final clash.
The next attack will decide this battle.
Don't make outlandish predictions!
How can you tell that?!
Because I think that field...
The energy of that battlefield
sides with the victor.
Oh?
That super-heated field
that surrounds them
is maintained because
their energy is balanced.
That keeps it at bay and makes it grow.
Therefore, when that balance is tipped...
all of that energy flows
to the weaker side.
The weaker side...
In other words, the loser.
That's the most dangerous part
of the Battle of True Dragons.
When the deciding blow is struck,
all that accumulated energy
flows to the side that is struck.
The loser faces certain death.
How scary.
I'd never have a duel like that.
Scary, scary!
But, in this case,
Dai's disadvantage grows.
Hadorra's finishing attack
will be his Ultra Combustion Slash.
But as for Dai...
his greatest attack is his Aban Strash
used with his Dragonic Aura or a spell.
If Raiden is his strongest spell,
then his Magic Sword is nothing to fear.
Between Aban Strash and Ultra
Combustion Slash, the outcome is obvious.
That's not something he'd overlook.
So what will he do?
Aban Strash...
TIGER SHATTER FIST
ABAN STRASH
Aban Strash... So that's your choice.
The attack took my life once,
and even after Aban's death,
it was passed on to his successors.
Indeed, it's the perfect attack
to end this battle.
But you can't win with an Aban Strash!
Once you lose, this battlefield...
I know! All of this heat will flow
to whoever loses this clash!
So you already realized.
But I, no, Aban Strash won't lose!
Because I developed this
to fight Dark King Ban!
This is a new Aban Strash!
What?!
A new Strash?!
It must be the new attack
Dai developed in his training!
I really wanted to save this
until the fight with Ban.
But that'll be meaningless if I lose here!
So I'm going to use it now!
You're not one to try to
bluff your way through a situation.
Interesting! Then show me
this new Aban Strash of yours!
If it's just some silly attack
then my mighty strike will shatter it!
Oh no! Get farther away!
Don't be ridiculous!
We can't leave at a time like this!
Then at least get down!
Here goes, Hadorra!
His stance is the same.
It's slightly deeper than usual.
Aban Strash Arrow!
That's his new Strash?!
It's a normal Strash!
What is this?! What makes this an arrow?!
It's merely a breeze compared to
my Ultra Combustion Slash!
I'll blow it away!
Now!
Aban Strash Break!
What?!
He's catching up...
...with the first Strash!
Aban Strash...
Cross!
That's Dai!
Dai used his new super attack!
The Battle of True Dragons
has been decided.
He won! Dai won!
Did you see that?!
That unbelievably powerful new Strash!
So that's the new super attack
that Dai created.
Aban Strash... Cross.
I see. Aban Strash has the Arrow Type
where you launch Aura,
and the Break Type where you
charge the target.
But to combine the two...
Combine the two?
What do you mean, Hyunckel?
I mean he catches up to his Arrow Type
with his Break Type,
and detonates both Strashes simultaneously
at the moment of impact.
The upward impact of the Arrow Type
and the downward impact of the Break Type
cross at the enemy's chest.
The overlapping force is probably
over five times that of a normal Strash.
Over five times?!
But to time the impact
of the two attacks perfectly
requires unbelievable instincts.
To predict an enemy's movements
and time two attacks is beyond even me.
It's a super attack only Dai can pull off!
A super attack!
But it looks like
Dai has spent all his Aura.
Hadorra's finished, isn't he?
Yeah. It seems so.
That tremendous energy
that surrounded them...
the fact that it's gone means
it hit him with that Strash Cross.
Dai! Well done!
Dai! He's still...!
It's his will!
Dai!
Unbelievable! Hadorra shouldn't have
a shred of Aura left!
All of their Aura
were blown away in that clash!
Where does he get that strength?!
A Life Blade?!
What?!
Hadorra is converting his own life
and making it his sword!
Even though he knows what it'll cost him!
Dai!
They were all defeated... My Royal Guard.
Hym... Albinass... Sigma...
You've all done well.
I will join you all soon.
In retrospect, the Six Legion Commanders
of the Dark Army were all mighty.
But they couldn't defeat
Dai and his friends.
It's because, as their commander, I had
nothing but greed and self-preservation.
The fact that you all came together
and risked your lives for me
feels like the greatest proof
that I was able to reach great heights.
In the very end, I was blessed
by my servants.
Now it's time!
I shall answer your loyalty
with this strike!
Oh no! It feels like Hadorra's will
is totally overpowering Dai's!
Getting hit by that super attack
wasn't enough to defeat him!
I can tell that this strike contains
the will of the Royal Guard, too!
If we get hit, it'll all be over!
Dai, I'll...
Don't, Popp!
I won't forgive anyone
who helps me here! Not even you!
This battle...
For just this battle...
I need you to let me fight alone!
D-Don't be stupid!
You don't have that sort of strength left!
That last attack used up all of your Aura!
But look!
Hadorra is using the remaining
bit of his life for one final attack!
It contains his will and
the unfulfilled wishes of the Royal Guard!
You can't win with any normal attack!
And with all of your Aura spent,
you can't use Strash Cross either!
That's enough!
Just leave the rest to us, Dai!
I still have...
one attack I want to try.
Besides, Hadorra's not the only one...
carrying the wishes
of his friends as he fights!
Everyone's always with me!
Master and Grampa and Dad, too!
I won't lose!
I'm going to prove their belief in me!
That's why...
I can't lose to Hadorra here!
I really am just a coward.
Why couldn't I believe
in someone this strong?!
You've spoken well!
But what can you do?!
You barely have any Aura left!
I can do this!
Raiden!
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
I finally realized it
imasara kizuitanosa
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
Must be the reason I was born
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
I shake off the clinging night
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
Dai won the Battle of True Dragons.
But Hadorra rose again
through sheer force of will.
With the wishes of the fallen Royal Guard
Hadorra readies a mighty attack.
Against him, Dai readies his Magic Sword.
With his Aura spent,
can Dai defeat Hadorra?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Last Attack"
The adventure continues!