Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
ZABOERA'S SCHEME
Zaboera!
My Lord?
Summon your Mystic Legion at once!
What?!
I'll summon my elite guards as well!
We'll gather our remaining forces
and launch a mass offensive against Dai!
Wait a minute, Lord Hadorra!
That plan already failed once!
Dai's party cannot be defeated
with any regular tactics!
Assassination through careful planning
would be better.
Leave it to me.
A victor is not one who is strong.
A victor is one who survives
to the end by any means.
Let her sleep.
She's been using Behoma nonstop
to tend to our wounds.
It was a difficult fight.
We're lucky we all survived.
What's wrong?
The fight isn't over yet.
Baran may be gone,
but the other Legion Commanders remain.
We won't stand a chance
if we're attacked now. I'll stand guard.
You can't in that condition!
That's right.
The half-dead should take it easy.
Popp.
Leave guard duty to me.
What are you talking about?
If we're half-dead, you really were dead!
You need rest the most!
Actually, I'm not sure why,
but I actually feel better than
before I died.
Save your bravado.
See for yourself if it's bravado.
Was that a Gira spell?
That's impossible unless
you really focus your Magic Power.
See? For some reason
I'm in tip-top shape today.
Fine. It looks like
you're in the best shape among us.
Don't worry about it.
If things get ugly, I'll give a shout.
It's been said that drinking the legendary
Dragon's blood grants immortality.
Perhaps Baran's blood has made
Popp's body stronger than before.
Oh wow.
Then if you drink my blood
will you all get stronger?
Baran said
your blood is closer to a human's.
Aww. I thought if I had that power,
I could keep anyone from dying.
Don't worry, Dai. We won't die so easily.
And that includes Popp.
Don't worry.
This is the least I can do to be useful.
My suicide attack fails,
and I end up saved by my target.
Talk about embarrassing.
Next time, I won't miss!
I'm not going to cast Megante again.
I just meant I won't mess up.
I knew Popp was forcing himself.
I'll survive until the end.
I promised on the other side, didn't I?
You don't remember?
You really are a mystery.
Are you our guardian or something?
Please don't push yourself any further.
Who's there?! Show yourself!
Things sound rough. Need a hand?
Th-That voice!
Maam!
I-Is it... Is it really you?!
Have you forgotten
your friend's face already?
Of course I haven't!
So that's Maam,
one of the Disciples of Aban.
Popp looks so happy to see her.
But...
What about your martial arts training?
Huh?
You're all trained up now?
Oh, that.
I packed it in before I finished.
I got worried about you guys.
Huh?
Maam quit something before completing it?
I don't know why, but I don't like her.
There's something sinister about her.
Goodness! I must be just jealous of her!
What's wrong?
N-Nothing! Forget it!
Let's go see Dai and Leona and the others!
They're in for a surprise!
Huh?
It's okay, Popp. They're exhausted
from fighting and asleep, right?
Let's not wake them.
Besides, I'd like to stay here
a little longer.
Huh?
S-Something smells sweet.
I feel woozy.
Popp...
I-I can't believe it.
Maam would never do this.
Popp...
Maam...
Goodnight!
What are you doing, Maam?!
I've brought a friend with me.
What?!
I'll introduce you.
H-Hadorra?!
Then you're...!
I've heard of you!
I'm Mystic Bishop Zaboera.
You were on guard, so I borrowed
Maam's likeness with a Morph spell.
I was told you're quite fond of the girl.
Y-You dirty...
So it worked.
Yes.
I can't move!
What did you do to me?!
My body contains hundreds of poisons.
I injected the most potent
neurotoxin through my claws.
Everybody...!
Give it up! You can't even scream now!
Besides...
thanks to the Dark Incense
I've been diffusing,
everybody's in a slumber
deeper than the ocean!
You can assassinate
all of them now, Lord Hadorra.
Good.
I didn't expect this one
to resist the Dark Incense, though.
Perhaps he's gained some special power.
That's the Disciples of Aban for you.
They gain power when you're not watching
and bare their fangs.
I should kill him here.
I'm disappointed, Hadorra.
What?!
You were always cruel,
but you never played dirty!
We've fought before, but you always had
the dignity of the Dark Lord!
And now you're resorting
to the dirty tricks of this old gremlin!
Oh how the mighty have fallen!
Shut up!
I cannot fail again! I don't have
the luxury of choosing my methods!
You know,
Crocodine once said the same thing.
But in the end, he realized the truth!
There are more important things
than winning or losing!
You think you can lecture Lord Hadorra?!
I'll finish you myself!
A few more pricks and I'm sure you'll die!
Time to die!
What?!
Get your grubby little paws off of him!
Wh-Who are you?!
Mentor... Matorif!
BEGIRAMA
HEAT-TYPE SPELL
DARK INCENSE
Wh-Who are you?!
Mentor... Matorif!
Moron, you let them trick you.
You need to work on your perception.
Sorry, Mentor.
Remember, a Mage must always be
the most level-headed in the party.
Even when everybody's worked up,
you need to stay cool as ice
and understand the situation.
At least that was what I did
when working with Aban.
Now I remember!
You sided with Aban and resisted me!
You called yourself
the most powerful human Grand Sorcerer!
Yo, you seem well,
you third-rate Dark Lord.
What did you call me?!
You wouldn't just die
so now I have to play clean-up.
Plus you killed one of my only friends.
He was a good guy. He really was.
And he wasn't even a third of my age.
Roka... Aban... All the good ones die.
And crooks like you and me
end up surviving.
What an ugly world.
I'll make you a deal. I'll send you
to the afterlife, so go apologize to Aban!
Shut up, you old fossil!
I'll reduce all of you to ash!
Begirama.
What?!
Kiari.
Two spells at once?!
He's not healing right away.
They got him with a powerful poison.
Don't get cocky!
How about this?!
Begiragon!
I-Impossible! There's no way!
H-How can a mere human use Begiragon?!
Did you think you had a patent?!
Get over yourself!
I'm losing!
Is his Magic Power greater than mine?!
Zaboera!
Hurry up and help me!
This is for my arm!
Begirama!
I wish I was younger!
My body can't keep up with the spell!
N-No! My mentor is in danger!
At this rate everyone in the shack
will die, too!
No! Everyone, wake up! Please wake up!
Big guy! Hyunckel! Princess! Dai!
Dai!
Seems you've reached your limit.
In the end, you're the one
who'll be seeing Aban!
We did it!
Dai?!
Dai!
You're supposed to be asleep!
I heard Popp calling me!
That's impossible!
Begone, Hadorra!
I'll never let another friend die!
Curse you!
Not one more friend!
Begirama!
He focused all his power into his fist,
and reflected their Begirama spells
with his own Begirama spell.
Even I can't do that.
Are you okay?!
Y-Yeah.
You did it!
You hit them with all that Heat Energy.
Hadorra must be done for sure.
I don't know.
He's pretty tenacious.
Sorry. You had to save me again.
But... But you know,
I appreciate what you said.
"I'll never let another friend die."
You softies.
What happened?
Th-This is...!
Did we sleep through
an explosion of this size?!
Zaboera and Hadorra showed up.
W-What?!
I managed to get away with a Rura spell.
Those filthy little brats!
I doubt Hadorra survived that.
After all the help I gave him,
he's useless!
I'll have to ingratiate myself
with Mystban...
Lord Hadorra?!
Zaboera, I won't let you betray me!
You and I are in the same boat now!
If you try latching on
to someone else, I'll kill you!
I know about your secret research
about Superior Beings!
-What?!
-It's time to use that research for me!
Why?!
The Disciples of Aban
are growing fast! Too fast!
This body King Ban gave me
isn't enough to keep up!
I need greater power!
Power like that Dragonoid Baran!
I need the greatest power in the world
beyond anyone else!
I see. That explains
the Crest on your hand.
It's impressive power.
I'm alive thanks to you.
We're sorry. We fell into a trap
by Zaboera of all people.
Don't beat yourself up over it.
Somebody even had their feelings
manipulated and got all spoony.
I can't believe Hadorra
actually participated in Zaboera's scheme.
He was always one
who preferred brute force.
He probably realized
brute force wouldn't work.
Since it turns out the Hero is the son of
the legendary Dragon Knight.
He must have been pretty desperate.
I think something big is going on
within the Dark Army.
Hey, Mentor, you knew
Dai is a Dragon Knight, didn't you?
Yeah.
You should have told us sooner!
Plus you could've shown up sooner,
couldn't you?!
I knew learning the fate of the
Dragon Knight would hurt you mentally.
There's nothing I can do
to help with that.
I figured only one person could help,
so I dug this up.
What's this dirty book... Huh?!
This mark... Is it...?!
Master Aban's!
That's right.
This is the famous Book of Aban.
The Book of Aban?!
Aban, the Hero who saved the world,
wrote of his skills, spells, and thoughts
for future generations.
It's the only hand-written book of his.
I never knew there was such a book.
It was stored in the Library of Carl,
his home country.
I figured you'd need it more.
Check the Book of Air, page 192.
The Book of Earth is about combat skills.
Sea covers Aura skills and spells.
And the Book of Air is of the soul.
Uh...
"To the... and..."
Leona, can you read it?
I can't read a lot of the words.
"To the wounded and lost.
Defeat is not to fall from your wounds.
It is when you lose yourself
after falling.
Be strong of heart.
Calmly consider your goals
and your abilities.
We are all limited in what we can do.
When each of us does the best we can do,
even when on the edge of despair,
the path to victory shall shine through."
It's almost like Master is here
reassuring us.
Those were just the words
we needed to hear.
Aban...
It's just the item
for green little fledglings like you.
Take good care of it.
Thank you, Matorif.
"Your goals and abilities..."
Let's return to Papunica.
I want to do the best that I can do.
Something more for the world
than just fighting with you.
Something only I can do!
Dai! We're going!
Okay!
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
After returning to Papunica, Dai and
his friends prepare for their next battle.
They learn of
a martial arts tournament in Romos,
Hearing the victor can win a legendary
item, Dai and Popp head to Romos.
As a contestant stands
in the Colosseum, being cheered on,
Dai and Popp stare in astonishment.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Romos Martial Arts Tournament"
The adventure continues!