boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
are itsukarada?
Since when was it?
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Being honest became whining
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Standing firm became strength
naa mitsukaranai?
Have you found it yet?
jishin janaku jibun jishin
Not confidence, your true self
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
I smolder because I've actually burned
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
tada me wo mihiraite
I'll just open my eyes
yume wo miru
And dream my dream
yume wo shiru
And know my dream
CROCODINE, THE BEAST KING
So you're leaving, Dai?
Yeah.
I'm sorry. I'd like to join you,
but if I take a step off this island,
I'll be under the Dark Load's thrall.
It's fine, Grampa.
Just wait here with everyone.
I promise I'll defeat the Dark King.
Dai...
Where's Gomechan?
I wonder...
Maybe hiding somewhere
because saying goodbye is so hard.
I see.
How about Popp?
He's still asleep after crying all night.
It must have been quite a shock.
Grampa, take care of Popp, too.
Master! Don't go!
Don't leave me, Master!
Popp, use what you've learned
to help others.
Master! Don't!
Master Aban!
Master...
Romos Kingdom is the closest.
Head north and go straight.
Okay. I'll see King Romos first.
Then I'll head to Papunica.
Watch yourself out there, Dai.
Bye everyone! Take care!
Dai!
How dare you!
Trying to leave me here!
Popp!
Popp...
D-Don't get the wrong idea!
I'm not going to fight the Dark Army!
I just don't want to spend my days
on that island!
Just so we're clear. Got it?
Really?
Okay! We're off!
We'll be praying for both of you.
Help!
I was so scared!
Are you okay?
Thank you.
You're alone?
I got lost in the woods.
Huh? You're lost?
Please, could you take me to my village?
Um, well, about that...
Please!
We're actually lost, too.
Huh?
This is pathetic! I followed you
because you said you got this!
This place is a lot bigger
than Dermline Island.
What are we supposed to do?! We've been
lost for three days since we got here!
What is that?! That weapon's amazing!
Learn to see things through, little Mage.
What the hell?! You got a problem
with my magic?! Well?!
"Squish"?
What was that for?!
You pervert!
A girl?!
Maam!
Mina!
Bad girl. I've told you
never to go into the forest alone!
Mommy was bitten by a Poison Slime.
I came looking for an Antidotal Herb.
You should have come to me.
But I'm glad you're all right.
Yeah. They saved me.
Thank you very much. I'm Maam.
I live in Nayle Village,
east of this forest.
I'm Dai, this is Popp. We're traveling.
You're really strong!
You need this sort of equipment
to live near the Dark Forest.
The Dark Forest?
Ever since the Dark Lord returned,
tons of monsters started living here.
It's always been like a maze in here,
so the people of this country
began calling it the Dark Forest.
I see.
Where are you two headed?
They said they're lost.
To Romos Palace.
The palace is straight through the forest.
But the sun's setting. Why don't you
stay the night in our village?
I'd like to thank you for saving Mina.
Really?! That's...
What, Popp?
Forget that girl. Let's just go.
Huh?! But they'll let us stay.
You dummy!
The hospitality of a palace or
a scrawny village? It's not even a debate.
Hey, she might hear.
She can hear.
As you've guessed, my village is scrawny.
Why don't you hurry and go get
your dinner at the palace?
Um, he didn't...
After dark, ferocious monsters
start prowling this area.
So you better
get through the forest quick.
With your skills,
you'd probably get eaten.
In that case...
Sure! We can get through this brush
without your stupid advice!
Um...
Let's go already, Dai!
Before some scary monsters show up!
Are you sure, Maam?
Forget about them.
Oh?
Did they forget this?
A Slime?
Ooh! So pretty!
Don't touch it!
Don't be mean to it.
I wasn't...
Come here.
It's so cute!
Those guys...
What are we supposed to do with this?!
Should we go after them?
After we get you home.
Dammit! That stuck-up...!
I swear I'll get through this forest!
Oh man. We should have taken up her offer.
Shut up!
Hurry up!
My servant has located Dai.
In the Dark Forest.
I see. They're headed for Romos Castle.
The land of Romos
is Furfang Legion territory.
Get me the Legion Commander,
Beast King Crocodine.
Crocodine.
Who's there? What is it?
It is I, Hadorra.
Ah, Sir Dark Commander!
Forgive my rudeness!
What are you doing? I believe
I ordered you to take Romos Kingdom.
That kingdom is worthless. Nothing but
cowards and not a single worthy warrior.
My Furfang Legion monsters
can take it without my help.
Just give them a few more days.
You haven't changed.
But that's not why I contacted you.
Someone who would oppose our Dark Army
is lost in the Dark Forest.
What?! Are they strong?!
This is him. His name is Dai.
I want you to kill him yourself.
What's so funny?!
Surely you jest.
I hold the title of Beast King.
You would have me fight a child?
Don't underestimate him because he's
a child! He possesses unbelievable power.
He even wounded me!
What?!
He must be killed before he grows stronger
or he is sure to become a threat!
Interesting!
I'd love to fight a boy
who managed to wound even you!
I'm counting on you.
Make sure he dies.
ABAN STRASH
HELL'S CLAW
H-Huh?
A dead end?
We should've asked that girl to guide us.
I can't stand stuck-up girls like that!
Then what kind of girls do you like?
Well, obviously someone
beautiful, sexy, and rich,
who'll do whatever I say.
Popp, you really are selfish.
What's that voice?!
I sense incredible pressure!
That voice...!
It's coming!
There you are, boy!
A Croc Man?!
I am Beast King Crocodine!
FURFANG LEGION, LEGION COMMANDER
BEAST KING CROCODINE
Legion Commander of one of the
six legions under Dark Commander Hadorra,
the Furfang Legion!
Six legions?!
That's right.
The Dark Army is divided into six legions
based on the characteristics of monsters.
The Undead Legion!
A legion of warriors
who have overcome even death itself!
The Blizzblaze Legion!
Destroyers who incinerate all
and freeze even the soul!
The Mystic Legion!
A legion of Mages
who control unparalleled magic!
The Shadow Legion!
Dark hunters who kill from the shadows,
unseen and unknown!
The Dragon Legion!
A legion of Dragons,
the most powerful of monsters!
And my own Furfang Legion!
A pack of fearless beasts!
Dai, by Hadorra's command,
I'm here to kill you!
If you wish to live,
show your true strength.
The strength that let you wound
even the Dark Commander himself.
Stuff it, you stupid crocodile!
From what you say, you're nothing more
than Hadorra's underling!
Even Hadorra turned tail and ran from us!
We'll hardly break a sweat with you!
Right, Dai?
Huh?
But you didn't do anything.
What's so funny?! I could
easily wipe you out with my spells!
I don't know who you are,
but go ahead and try.
What was that, you bastard?!
Mera!
With just his breath?!
You couldn't kill a Slime with this spell.
Now it's my turn!
Wow! In terms of raw power,
he's stronger than Hadorra!
Don't underestimate us Legion Commanders.
In terms of our specialties,
we all surpass Hadorra.
That is why we were chosen
as Legion Commanders.
Popp, we can't beat him head-on.
I'll hit him when he's distracted,
so give me some cover with spells.
Popp?
Huh?!
Popp, no way...
A wise choice! The weakling can run!
My orders are to kill only you, Dai!
Here goes!
Sorry Dai!
Try to find a way to get out of there!
Ow, ow... What the...?
A-An Infanticore?
He's a lot faster than I thought!
What's wrong?
Stop running and fight me!
All right! Here goes, Crocodine!
What's that stance?
Aban Style Sword Technique!
Aban? The legendary Hero
who defeated Hadorra.
Aban was my master!
I see.
You carry on the will of Aban.
So you're a Disciple of Aban!
A Disciple of Aban?
That's right!
Earth Slash!
It didn't work?!
I couldn't even scratch him
with Earth Slash!
His hide is like steel!
Not bad. But it'll take
more than a knife to hurt me.
Now see the might
of a true warrior's weapon!
This is Bagi?!
That's right! I myself can't use magic,
but my Vortex Axe
is imbued with Vortex-type magic!
That's right. Master mentioned it.
Legendary weapons that can exhibit
spell effects when used as items!
Howl! Vortex Axe!
Got you!
It's no good!
I can't beat him with strength!
Speed! I'll dodge with speed
and hit him with Wave Slash!
Die!
What?!
C-Curse you!
That's...!
You!
Jump to the side!
Jump!
Right!
Wow! She's even stronger than me!
Are you okay?!
Uh, s-sure.
What happened?
Well, you see,
we were attacked by the Dark Army.
I managed to get away.
Where's your friend?
Well, um, you see...
Wait, you're not telling me
you abandoned him?!
No, no, no!
Then explain yourself!
Uh...
Huh?
It's like a Mera spell!
With a weapon like this,
she's no ordinary girl!
Huh?
This is a graduation certificate!
An Insignia of Aban!
Then you're also...
Uh, er, listen, this is...
Bothersome gnat!
Vortex Axe!
Now!
Aban Style Sword Technique!
Wave Slash!
It burns!
Heat Breath. My secret attack.
I'm impressed that
you managed to wound me.
Why can't I move?
That's enough. You fought well.
You were far stronger than
any of the veteran warriors I've defeated.
It's a shame, but I'll end your suffering.
Dai!
Dammit!
You won't stop me!
Dai! Run!
Why won't he run?!
He's paralyzed!
That's it! Use that weapon and...
Wait! Our enemy is Crocodine!
Where are you aiming?!
Stop!
Dai!
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
Dai and Crocodine's battle continues
in the Dark Forest.
Watching them fight, Maam remembers
what Aban told her when she was young.
As Dai and Popp head out again to fight,
Maam makes a decision.
Next time on
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Maam's Turmoil"
The adventure continues!