With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE LAST ATTACK
Raiden!
Hmm? Seems pointless.
Making up for lost Aura with magic.
Unfortunately, your Raiden Strash...
is far weaker than
that new attack of yours!
Why sheath your sword?!
That's it! He has that new scabbard!
This scabbard is a new weapon
made by Ron Berku!
My sword can't get any stronger.
But with this scabbard, I can increase
the power of my Magic Sword!
What?
If I sheath my Magic Sword like this...
the Magic Power is amplified inside!
When I draw it again, the spell will have
become its strongest iteration!
So his Raiden will become a Gigaden spell?!
A Rura spell?
Why did he move over there?
The Magic Power amplification takes time.
He did that to buy time.
That's not all.
Dai is confident that his next attack
is going to be insanely strong.
He distanced himself so that
we wouldn't get hurt by it!
Dai, I won't try to stop you anymore!
I believe in that power of yours
that's made miracle after miracle happen!
Give him everything you've got!
Ten...
Nine...
If he can use Gigaden,
there's only one attack he'll use.
The last gift from
his dead father, Gigabrake!
I could stop him right now, but...
Why bother?!
Using this attack will kill me anyway!
Then I shall use these few seconds
to increase my power!
Five...
Four...
Three...
Two...
One...
Zero!
GIGABRAKE
I knew it! Then I shall match it
with my greatest, final attack!
Using all of my life...
Ultra Combustion Slash!
ULTRA COMBUSTION SLASH
Come on!
Now witness this!
Shatter before this single strike
that contains my life!
You won't shatter this!
This is what every battle has led to!
This is the greatest attack I can do!
It can't be!
GIGA STRASH
Giga Strash!
Giga Strash...
Well done!
Everything that I have...
is defeated!
He won!
He really won! Dai did it!
That's it for Hadorra.
As a Superior Being,
now that Hadorra has been defeated...
he's going crumble to black ash.
Albinass... I understand now...
why you were willing to
give your life to prevent this.
Hadorra...
Don't say anything, Dai.
I've lost.
I've lost again.
I've always lost to Aban and his students.
But I'm still satisfied.
Aban's attack with Baran's power.
I could never beat that.
Was that another attack
you created in your training?
No.
I came up with it just now.
Just now?
I felt I needed the power I got
from both Master and Dad...
Otherwise, I couldn't defeat you.
So I tried it at the last moment.
So in all of that you created
the most powerful attack ever.
I can't believe
I thought I could defeat you.
Hadorra...
I regret nothing.
In fact, I'm grateful.
Being at my lowest when I couldn't
defeat you was when my life really began.
It was short,
but it was indeed fulfilling.
Farewell, Dai, the Hero!
For my last wish...
at least let me touch the hand
that defeated me...
before my body crumbles to ashes.
What's this?!
What is that?!
A flute?!
Kilban!
I hope you enjoyed that, my friends.
That melody was a little elegy from me.
To the two who gave everything
to show us a magnificent fight.
This is for them.
Dai! Get away from there!
He's too weakened to move!
It's too late!
Come forth, flames of the Underworld!
Dai!
Well? Isn't my Kill Trap splendid?
How cool!
"Kill Trap"?!
It's a Trap of Death!
Ban Palace is full of
various traps that I've laid.
This is one of them.
The Nine of Diamonds!
It lets me summon the most powerful
flames of the Underworld at will.
It's the ultimate spellcraft.
To be honest, I could have activated it
the moment you entered Ban Palace.
He was waiting!
Waiting for Dai and Hadorra
to be exhausted!
You! You dare defile an honorable duel?!
Hyunckel!
Forget about Kilban right now!
Hurry! We have to help Dai!
It's futile, young lady.
Can't you see it's already too late?
The eight all-consuming flames
gather at the central point
and all living creatures within
are incinerated.
No power can ever escape it.
No!
He gets to die with the Hero,
so Hadorra should be pleased.
Don't assume it'll work out that easily!
Popp!
I figured something like this
would happen!
So long as I'm here,
don't expect your schemes to work!
GIGA STRASH
ULTRA COMBUSTION SLASH
So long as I'm here,
don't expect your schemes to work!
Popp?! Is that you?!
Yeah! Dai's okay!
You dove in just before the trap closed?!
I figured that Ban would try something!
Hadorra and his Royal Guard
may be honorable,
but this is Ban Palace!
Nothing is as untrustworthy as
a fair fight from the Dark Army!
Popp...
It's always that brat...
Oh well.
Kilban disappeared?
Why would he after his trap was thwarted?!
It's no good! My Hyadaruko spell
can't hold it off forever!
Somebody hurry up and do something!
Got it!
Hyadaruko!
It's no good!
My Hyadaruko spell isn't enough!
But Popp's is holding it back!
Popp's Magic Power is
much stronger than mine!
Popp!
Isn't there...
Isn't there anything we can do?!
At this rate, they'll...
Step aside, you two!
You're using Grand Cross?!
This trap can't be broken by normal means!
It has to be blown away
by the greatest power!
In terms of energy output,
no attack can beat Grand Cross!
Popp! Hyunckel's going to use Grand Cross!
Look out!
Here goes, Popp!
Expect this to hurt a little!
Grand Cross!
Impossible!
How could it repel my Grand Cross?!
Hey! Nothing's happened in here!
It had no effect on the inside?
Could it be...
the reason the Reaper retreated...
Don't you see what lovely faces
the humans make?
Even I can't match you
in terms of cruelty.
You're probably the cruelest
in the Underworld.
What an honor.
What do we do?! What can we do?!
Leona, we can't just stand by
and watch them get burned to death!
Leona?!
There's no way!
The Princess knows that!
That's why she remains silent!
There's nothing that we can do!
No!
Even the greatest Aura energy
of Grand Cross was repelled.
That means...
that trap can only be broken
by magical means.
Otherwise it wouldn't explain
why Grand Cross had no effect.
Popp is holding off the flames
inside with his Magic Power.
But, out here, none of us
have Magic Power even close to that.
That means there's only one way
for us to rescue those two.
We have to defeat Kilban,
the one using the spellcraft!
He knows that all to well,
which is why he retreated!
To somewhere deep in Ban Palace.
Finding and defeating him now
will take too long!
He's closed off
our only hope of saving them!
He's right.
Leona and I don't have the Magic Power...
Leona! Use Minakator!
Like in the Cave of Trials, even
incomplete, casting Minakator should...
It's no good... Maam.
Huh?
Don't forget.
In order to stop Ban Palace
I already used Minakator.
This place is already being affected
by my Minakator spell.
Purification Spells have no effect
if the same person casts them twice.
It's just a waste of Magic Power.
How... How can you be so calm, Leona?!
I'm not calm!
But, we have to remain collected
at times like this.
We have to focus
and figure out what we can do.
Our enemy is far beyond us.
They have the minds of evil geniuses!
I'm sorry, Leona.
It's no good, Maam.
Physical power will never work!
If your firsts or my Wave Strike
had any effect on those flames,
Kilban would never have left
without taking us out.
Dai, Popp! Don't give up in there!
They do love their futile resistance.
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
To be honest I was clumsy
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
And it took me forever to get here
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I used even loneliness as a weapon
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
I just want to be there for you
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
To call out your name
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Is harder than any magic spell
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
Even though you're so close to me
aishiteiru
I love you
imasara kizuitanosa
I finally realized it
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
To call out your name
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
Must be the reason I was born
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
I shake off the clinging night
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
Dai and Popp are caught
in Kilban's trap.
The blazing flames of the Underworld
close in on them.
As their stamina ebbs and all seems lost,
a single ray of light shines down on Popp.
Can Dai and Popp escape
from Kilban's Kill Trap?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Hope in the Flames"
The Adventure Continues!