Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE TRAIL OF ADVENTURE, THE PATH FORWARD
Once, the world was threatened
by the Dark Lord Hadorra.
But thanks to the Hero and his companions,
peace was restored.
DAI, THE BOY WHO SEEKS TO BE HERO
Dai, the Hero is here! Yippee! Go, go!
The young boy, Dai
dreamed of being a Hero.
He lived peacefully with monsters who had
been freed from the Dark Lord's thrall.
Hadorra was resurrected
by the power of Dark King Ban,
DARK LORD HADORRA RETURNS
Once again,
the world was thrust into peril.
This is the story of Dai and his friends
as they journey to save the world.
WARRIOR PRIEST MAAM
MAGE POPP
Dai grew in his battles
with the Dark Army.
Today, let's look back at the Best Bouts
between Dai and the Six Legion Commanders.
BEST BOUTS OF THIS SHOW
BEST BOUT #1
THE CROCODINE BATTLE
First is the fight with
the Furfang Legion's Beast King Crocodine.
Persuaded by Zaboera, Crocodine
resorted to using Burasu as a hostage.
PERSUADED BY ZABOERA,
HE TAKES BRASS HOSTAGE
Grampa, wake up!
Don't you recognize me?!
This is the end!
Dai!
You again?!
I've got a Merami of my own for you!
Don't!
Dai?!
Maam, you'll hit Grampa!
But he'll kill you!
Please... He's the only family I've got!
POPP GETS THEM OUT OF DANGER
It was Popp who managed to solve
this hopeless situation.
A magic circle?!
Dark influence, begone!
Mahokator!
Huh? What?
I did... it!
What?!
Impossible!
THE DRAGON CREST
APPEARS ON DAI'S FOREHEAD
And the Dragon Crest
appeared on Dai's forehead.
Use this!
Beast King Anguish Blast!
Aban Strash!
Yes!
If losing was my fate,
I wish I'd fought you fair and square.
Crocodine?
HE NORMALLY FIGHTS FAIR
Crocodine was normally
a warrior who fought fair.
HE PRAISES DAI'S STRENGTH
AND POPP'S COURAGE
He regretted using such dirty tactics
and praised Dai and his friends.
Don't ever lose.
A Hero must always be strong!
BEST BOUT #2
THE HYUNCKEL BATTLE
Next is the one with Hyunckel,
the Dark Swordsman of the Undead Legion.
UNDEAD LEGION
DARK SWORDSMAN HYUNCKEL
Hyunckel is a human who was
raised by the Hell Knight Bartos.
He believed Aban killed his father.
HE BELIEVES ABAN KILLED HIS FATHER
In the fight in the Underground Palace,
Dai and Popp used an attack
they devised to defeat Hyunckel.
THE ATTACK THEY DEVISED
TO DEFEAT HYUNCKEL
Ranarion!
Take this!
Raiden!
With the Soul Shell that Maam discovered,
the truth of Bartos's death was revealed.
THE TRUTH IS REVEALED...!!
...you have a family.
When I realized that, I couldn't kill you.
Sir Hero! I have something I must ask you!
And so I told him.
How I found and raised a human child.
And that, even if he spared me,
should Hadorra die, I would cease to be.
Hero Aban! Please look after my son!
Raise him to be a strong,
righteous warrior!
I ask that you show him real human warmth!
Yes.
And the fight between Dai and Hyunckel...
What?!
Raiden...
Strash!
Just as the fight reached its climax,
FLAZZARD APPEARS
AND ALL HOPE SEEMS LOST
Flazzard appeared
and all hope seemed lost.
However...
Hyunckel!
I can't let any of you die here!
Crocodine, I finally understand
how you felt!
I hope I can apologize to you
in the afterlife.
But for now, for just an instant...
lend me your titan strength!
Stop! Don't do it, Hyunckel!
Hyunckel!
Farewell, Dai and Popp...
Goodbye... Maam...
Hyunckel!
ADDITIONAL BEST BOUT #1
VALGE ISLAND/LEONA RESCUE MISSION
There were many great battles other than
showdowns with the Legion Commanders.
The first is...
Leona was frozen and taken hostage.
THEY SPLIT UP TO DESTROY
THE DARK FLAME AND DARK ICE SPIRES
Dai and his friends split up to destroy
the Dark Flame and Dark Ice Spires.
But Zaboera and Mystban
appeared at the Dark Flame Spire,
while Hadorra appeared
at the Dark Ice Spire.
Aban...
Dai!
As Dai and his friends struggled,
a former enemy came to their aid.
A FORMER ENEMY COMES TO THEIR AID
Wh-Who was that?!
I do!
I-Impossible!
Beast King Crocodine!
And at the Dark Ice Spire...
AT THE DARK ICE SPIRE...
You're...!
Hyunckel's Grand Cross was blocked,
but his will to fight struck Hadorra down.
Die, Hyunckel!
I-Impossible!
He had spent all of his Aura completely!
Even unconscious, he still retains
the last of his will to fight!
Well done, Hyunckel.
You are indeed, a true...
warrior...!
BEST BOUT #3
THE FLAZZARD BATTLE
Back to the Best Bouts.
Next is the fight with Flazard.
ROCK BULLET SHRAPNEL DETONATION
Dai and his friends were helpless against
the Rock Bullet Shrapnel Detonation, but...
Sense it!
The life energy of everyone here!
Something's coming!
A giant evil energy!
This is...
his core!
Flazzard!
Air Slash!
Looks like another dud...
That's my... My core!
It's done.
I've hit...
my target!
MYSTVEARN APPEARS AND FLAZZARD GETS
THE MOST POWERFUL ARMOUR
At the last moment, Mystban appeared.
Wielding the most powerful armour,
Flazzard attacked again.
Hyadaruko!
My spell's not working!
This body is amazing!
Dai faced Flazzard with the completed
Aban Style Sword Technique.
DAI COMPLETES THE ABAN STYLE
SWORD TECHNIQUE...
He can still see...
Slice the earth...
Slice the sea...
Slice the air...
And slice everything...
I was able to do Air Slash.
I know... I know I can slice everything!
Here it comes!
Watch me, Master Aban!
This is... This is a true...
Aban Strash!
He did it!
ABAN STRASH
HELL'S CLAW
BEST BOUT #4
THE BARAN BATTLE
The fourth is the fight against Baran.
Dragon Legion Commander Baran was said to
be the strongest of the Legion Commanders.
DRAGON LEGION
DRAGON MASTER GENERAL BARAN
On his forehead, the Dragon Crest that
appeared when Dai used his hidden power.
DRAGON CREST
Baran is a legendary Dragon Knight
like Dai, and is Dai's father.
HE WAS DAI'S FATHER...
He attacked with overwhelming power,
hoping to recruit Dai into the Dark Army.
GIGABRAKE
His Gigabrake was devastating.
A Dragon Knight's Dragonic Aura
also shields him from any attacks.
DRACONIC AURA
However...
...use that attack at where I aim!
Got it!
Aban Strash!
Right there!
Beast King Redemption Blast!
After blocking this with his Dragonic Aura,
Baran cut off the source of Dai's power,
his bond with his friends...
HIS BOND WITH HIS FRIENDS
HE ERASES DAI'S MEMORY
by erasing Dai's memory.
I shall return to reclaim Dino.
ADDITIONAL BEST BOUT #2
DRAGON MASTERS VS POPP/HYUNCKEL
And now the second side-battle,
Dragon Masters versus Popp and Hyunckel.
BARAN SUMMONS THE DRAGON MASTERS
Baran summoned the Dragon Masters, his
strongest vassals, to help capture Dai.
Land Rider Larhart.
Sea Rider Borahorn.
Sky Rider Galdandy.
Popp pretended to flee,
only to face these powerful enemies alone.
POPP FACES THEM ALONE
AS HE STRUGGLED,
THE ONE WHO CAME TO HIS AID IS...
As he struggled,
the one came to his aid was...
Who's there?!
Great. I'm saved by
the last guy I want saving me.
Sorry to disappoint.
Popp used the last of his strength
to defeat Galdandy.
Hyunckel defeated Borahorn.
And...
Hakendisutoru!
I've got you! You fell for
my final life-risking trap!
What?!
Take a good look at the shape of the Aura
our weapons create!
A cross?!
Grand Cross!
Impossible!
He was hiding a weapon
charged with his Aura?!
W-Where did you hide such a weapon?!
This was the only weapon I had left!
This chain is unbreakable.
It is a symbol of
the bond of the Disciples of Aban!
BEST BOUT #5
THE BARAN BATTLE 2
The last bout is
the fierce battle with Baran.
Baran transformed into the Dragonoid,
the Ultimate Combat Form of the Dragon Knight.
THE ULTIMATE COMBAT FORM
THE DRAGONOID
To protect Dai and his friends,
Popp made a daring decision.
TO PROTECT DAI AND HIS FRIENDS,
HE MAKES A DARING DECISION
Move!
What can a piece of trash like you do?!
Nothing! I know that already!
But I have to fight!
I'm the only one left who can even stand!
That's right...
There's still one thing I can do!
I'll shatter him with one blow!
Th-That's...!
They won't come out!
His grip is just a weak Mage's!
Obviously!
I've got all my life energy
focused in my fingertips!
I can't just let you pull them out!
You're not...!
I knew it! That's...
Megante!
Hyunckel...
Crocodine...
Everyone...
I leave the rest to you.
Popp!
Make something up for Maam, will you?
We've gone through a lot...
It's been fun.
But...
Megante!
Baran withstood Popp's Megante spell
and Dai regained his memories.
DAI'S MEMORIES RETURN
AND THE DEATHMATCH BEGINS...
The deathmatch between
the father and son began.
Doru Aura!
DORUORA
With Baran's spell, Doru Aura,
Dai was slowly driven back, but...
Fall to my Gigabrake!
I'll never abandon Dai!
Impossible! A corpse cast a spell?!
Now!
Aban Strash!
THEY BOTH RUN OUT OF ENERGY AND...
When they were both out of energy,
Baran used the power of a Dragon Knight
to resurrect Popp and disappeared.
BARAN RESURRECTS POPP
Say what you will.
THEY GROW THROUGH UPHILL BATTLES
THEIR ADVENTURE CONTINUES
As they grow through uphill battles,
their adventure continues.
Let's look at the story so far.
THE STORY SO FAR
Dai and Popp went to
the Romos Martial Arts Tournament
THEY GO TO THE MARTIAL ARTS TOURNAMENT
FOR THE LEGENDARY SWORD OF CHAMPIONS
seeking the legendary weapon,
the Sword of Champions.
But Zaboera's son, Zamuza,
was already there.
He was a terrifying enemy who had
turned himself into a Superior Being.
Oh no!
They overcame this peril with the help of
Maam, who had become a Martial Artist.
Dai managed to defeat Zamuza.
But their joy is short-lived...
as the shadow of a new enemy approaches.
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Dai and his friends
learn about Leona's plans
to hold a World Summit
before facing the Dark Army.
Seeking information of a weapon
to replace the Sword of Champions,
they head to Papunica,
where the summit will be held.
Meanwhile, in the Dark Army, the wounded
Hadorra lies in Zaboera's hideout.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The World Summit"
The adventure continues!