nakama tono kizuna wo
With your bonds with your friends
sono mune ni idaite
Embraced in your heart
hikari no you ni isshun ni
Like a flash
In an instant
subete wo kaketeku
You risk it all
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
tachimukatte ikunnda to
You will face it again
kakugo wo kimetanara
If that's what you choose
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even when hurt
Oh tsumazuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
susume kono tabi no hate
Continue on
To your journey's end
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Again and again
To the future you make
Oh Oh
tachiagareru
You're The Bravest
You can stand up
Oh Oh
tachiagareru
You're The Bravest
You can stand up
Fly up to the world
Never let go
Never let it go
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
Fly up to the world
Never let go
Never let it go
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
FATHER AND SON DRAGONS SET OUT
I shall go!
Or does anyone think
Dai and I will not be enough?
Are you nuts?!
That's the greatest tag team in the world!
Why are you willing to help us?
I can explain that.
But first, Hyunckel needs healing.
Hyunckel!
I see.
So you agree with us
that Dark King Ban is a mutual enemy.
Then we'll gladly accept your help.
Dai, go with your father
to the Dark Citadel Gate.
Leona, I can go alone!
Meruru, please heal Crocodine.
Yes.
Popp, Maam, and Crocodine
will take on the Royal Guard.
Okay!
Leona!
Is there anything you need?
No. We will set out once you're ready.
Understand, Dino?
Good grief. He's been pouting ever since
it was decided that they work together.
They've just been standing there
not talking.
Consider it lucky.
At least we avoided a fight
between father and son again.
And temporary as it may be,
Baran is on our side.
Yeah. I still don't believe it.
I've never met him before,
but Dai's father seems different
from what I heard.
I do sense overwhelming power from him...
but he doesn't seem like the violent type.
Last time we fought, it was hardly
the mood for working together.
Totally!
It's all thanks to Hyunckel.
He risked his life to reach
an understanding with Baran.
His being incapacitated
was a high price to pay.
It's better this way.
He always assumes
no one will grieve if he ever dies.
It's a relief to know
he can't take risks anymore.
Honestly, he needs to learn
to take it easy.
Dino...
No... Dai.
There's no need to be on edge.
I will only be helping you this once.
Only until our mutual goal of killing
Dark King Ban is accomplished.
Once that's over,
we are destined to fight again.
Silence will only
complicate things on the battlefield.
If you have something to say, say it.
There's one thing... I want to ask.
What?
My... My mother... What was she like?
Your mother... Soara...
She was beautiful.
And... a kind woman.
Her mere presence
filled everyone around her with warmth.
She overflowed with such light.
I doubt I will ever
love anyone that deeply...
ever... again.
I see.
Let's go!
Toberura!
If there was to be a single exception...
it would be you, Dai.
The Dragon father and son are off.
I know they'll pull it off.
Are you sure?
Huh?
I fear the two of them working together
may instead awaken an even greater evil.
I'm sorry! Just ignore what I said!
Like anyone could ignore what a seer says.
Meruru, don't worry!
We'll do our best out there!
Right!
Besides, we've got not one,
but two Dragon Knights helping us.
If we lose, then it wasn't to be.
Our enemy was stronger than the gods.
So there's no point in worrying, is there?
Popp...
Okay, Maam, Big Guy, looks like we're up!
Facing the Royal Guard alone
won't be easy, but I'm counting on you!
We don't have to win.
We only need to keep them here
while Dai and Baran open the gate.
Okay! Hold down the fort for us, Princess!
Look after Hyunckel, Chiu,
and the other wounded!
I won't bother with cliche parting words.
Give it everything you've got!
We always do!
There they go!
Then let's hurry.
If you slow me down,
I'll leave you behind without hesitation.
It's finally happening.
Sorry Nova.
You wanted to go with them, didn't you?
I did. But I already know
I'm not as strong as they are.
I'll stay and help reorganize the backup.
Thank you.
If it turns out that Dark King Ban
can't be beaten with two Dragon Knights,
then it's all pointless.
But it's better than doing nothing.
Let's just do everything we can!
How can I be so selfish?
She's the one under
the most pressure in this battle.
God of Dragons...
please bless Dai, Popp, and the others.
Okay, time for the main event!
Honestly, I hope I never have
to come to this awful place again.
I doubt you will.
Once the Dark Citadel Gate is open,
we fight Dark King Ban.
We won't leave alive
unless we defeat our enemy.
For now, let's focus on luring
the Hadorra Royal Guard here.
Hmm. If only we had more help.
Huh?
Hmm.
W-What?
There!
-Gomechan?!
-You followed us here?!
Honestly.
You followed us to this dangerous place.
The little guy must not have
wanted to be left behind.
Looks like we've got
a pretty reliable friend.
You're right.
Okay, Gome,
you've been with us from the start!
Stick with us to the very end!
I'm impressed you noticed, Popp.
Well, you know, Maam's butt
looked bigger than usual, so...
POPP
What the hell?!
Don't waste your energy fooling around!
You're the one fooling around, you idiot!
If you two get married,
I know who's going to be in charge.
Why would I ever marry such a...
Such a what?!
You're lucky. You may quarrel a lot,
but you have a powerful bond.
Nothing beats having a family.
I realized that watching Dai and Baran.
If I manage to survive this battle...
maybe I'll find a wife of my own!
Crocodine...
Big Guy...
Let's all... go home alive!
Right! Of course!
Dai, I hope all goes well with your dad.
Leave things here to us!
They're here!
ABAN STRASH
GIGABRAKE
Where's the entrance to Ban Palace?
Where's the Dark Citadel Gate?
I have to find it quickly!
It won't be easy for Popp
and the others fighting alone.
Relax.
This voice... Is that...?
It is.
I'm talking to you through telepathy.
I figured it would be possible
through the resonation of our crests.
Telepathy...
Dai, nothing will start
until we breach the gate.
Focus on fulfilling your objective.
This way.
The queen looks brand new!
I thought Hyunckel
hit them with his attack!
It looks like they can regenerate
using Hadorra's Magic Power.
Hey you! You plan to fight us
with just yourselves?
Talk about overconfident!
Shut up! Watch out
or you'll regret underestimating us!
Hey! Where's that damn pointy bishop?!
I want to get some payback for my friend.
Fenbren is missing?!
Th-This is our emblem!
C-Could it be...?!
There!
What's that?
The bishop moves.
This isn't on Hadorra's orders.
An unexpected turn of events.
How very interesting.
That's...
Sorry everybody...
but this target belongs to me.
Hyunckel!
You shouldn't get up!
Hyunckel, you're not going...
Obviously. To the Field of Death.
Don't be ridiculous!
Your wounds are beyond normal healing.
I'll be blunt. You're not in any condition
to help Dai or the others.
In fact, you're more likely
to drag them down.
If I can't fight,
I'll just serve as a shield.
If I use my body
to block the enemy attacks...
That's crazy!
Miss Amy, where's my weapon?
Quickly. Where's my Dark Armour Spear?
Your spear...
I threw it away.
What?!
Y-You can't stand
on the battlefield either way!
There's no point in having that thing!
So...
I threw it away.
Amy... you...
You can't fight without your weapon.
So just accept it and get some rest!
Please... Hyunckel.
Wait Hyunckel! Where are you going?!
Amy... You have feelings for Hyunckel.
If so, that didn't help.
He'll go even without a weapon.
All you did was take his weapon from him.
Something about him is beyond all reason.
Amy...
Wait! Don't go!
Move.
Why?! Why won't you give up?!
Don't worry. I'm immortal.
No human can be immortal!
You're just a normal human!
Maybe if you were fully healed,
but not now!
You'll die out there!
If it will help Dai and the others,
so be it.
Move.
No.
Don't.
Don't!
Hyunckel!
Leave me.
I love you.
I've... I've always been in love with you.
I can't bear to watch anymore.
To see you keep fighting hopeless battles
which leave you wounded!
Please! Don't go!
Please... stop walking gladly
into death's arms!
It's not like that.
I don't do it gladly.
I'm afraid.
Huh?
The old me was a cursed Dark Swordsman.
My guilt over turning my sword against
my master and fellow students
continues to eat at my soul
and doesn't stop.
It tears me apart.
It terrifies me.
Hyunckel...
That's why I fight.
Only the pain and suffering
I endure in deadly battle
can alleviate my guilt.
It tells me...
that I'm atoning for my sins
in the name of justice!
No...
How...?!
I hid it in the forest near the castle!
Look.
My friend is calling me...
to the battlefield.
W-Wait! Wait!
Amy...
I've never told anyone about that.
Thank you.
But...
you're better off forgetting me.
The bishop Fenbren!
I remember this one.
I sense two sources of Orichalcum.
The larger must be
Baran's Demon Dragon Blade.
So it was the infamous Baran
who scarred my face.
When the others had their wounds
healed by Lord Hadorra,
I chose to leave my eyes as they were.
It cost me my eyesight,
but I wanted to keep this wound...
to remind me of that humiliation!
To keep the flames
of my vengeance burning!
It seems not all of Hadorra's minions
are on the surface.
Leave this to me.
I'm that one's target.
If you wish to waste the life
that I spared, so be it.
This time I'll end things
with a single swing.
That's strange.
This calmness can't be good.
Magic Power?!
Look out!
Take this!
Bagikurosai!
Using Bagikurosai underwater?!
Even though the spell could backfire?!
Dai!
The Orichalcum left the life-signal!
I've got you, Baran!
To defeat a powerful enemy like you,
I figured I had to use my strongest attack
right from the start!
Twin Sword Pinning!
Now I just target your life-signal...
and hit you with this finishing attack!
Where...?!
The flow's changed!
Now!
Got you!
Baran... falls!
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
To be honest I was clumsy
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
And it took me forever to get here
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I used even loneliness as a weapon
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
I just want to be there for you
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
To call out your name
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Is harder than any magic spell
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
Even though you're so close to me
aishiteiru
I love you
imasara kizuitanosa
I finally realized it
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
To call out your name
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
Must be the reason I was born
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
I shake off the clinging night
ai ni iku
And go to see you
ima sugu kimi no moto e
Right now to where you are
Popp, Maam, and Crocodine face
the Hadorra Royal Guard again.
Both sides continue to face off.
Meanwhile, Dai and Baran
conclude their fight with Fenbren.
And beyond the Dark Citadel Gate
awaits one man whose sole purpose
is to fight the two Dragon Knights.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Hadorra's Challenge"
The adventure continues!