Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
TO THE FINAL BATTLEGROUND
It's time to go.
Tomorrow, warriors from around the world
will gather in Carl Kingdom.
The time to begin
our counterattack has come!
Yes!
But where is everybody?
Did their training not work out?
Ah! There they are!
Ow, ow, ow!
Crocodine!
How did your training go?
Well...
we'll just have to see in battle.
Oh! There's Popp, too!
Huh? Aw, I thought I'd be the first back.
You thought wrong!
Looks like you learned
a pretty intense spell there, Popp.
I guess so.
Isn't Sir Matorif with you?
Right. About Mentor...
He said, "I'm tired,
so I'm going to sleep."
Also, "I leave the rest to all of you."
Okay, that leaves three people.
Dai, Hyunckel, and Maam.
You mean two people!
Nice!
That leaves Dai and Hyunckel.
Yeah, those two will probably
take the longest.
Since they need
their weapons restored, too.
Maybe not.
Dai!
Sorry to keep you all waiting!
So, did you master the ways
of the strongest sword?!
Hmm. I'm not sure.
Huh? That doesn't sound reassuring.
Well, I did what I could
in the time we had.
Okay then!
Well, I'm off.
Answer me this before you go.
You're a novice with the spear.
With a sword, you could have matched me.
So why?
Because...
this spear was a parting gift
from a dying friend.
A good answer.
I've never met anyone able to entrust
their life to their weapon like you.
Try to teach that spirit to Dai.
Okay, that's everyone.
Yeah, that's everyone...
Oh!
Hold on a minute!
That's right!
There's one more!
What? What's with those two?
Who else is there?
The Book of Aban!
This is Master Aban's book?
I've never seen it before.
I see... They're right.
We're going to Master Aban's homeland.
We have to bring this.
That's right. Our master.
The one who started all of this.
Without Master Aban,
me, Popp, and Maam...
and even Hyunckel and Crocodine
wouldn't be here like this today!
Master! Let's go together!
This battle will be fought by all of us!
The Reaper.
Wow!
How scary.
I hid my presence and you still sensed me.
No wonder King Ban
regards you with caution.
Finding you was quite a hassle.
I didn't think the legendary Dragon Knight
would be hiding in this remote cave.
What do you want?
You couldn't possibly
be looking to take my life.
What else would an assassin do?
Is that Dark King Ban's will?
He made a promise to me.
Humans are filth
that pollute the Surface World.
He promised to wipe out the humans
and to create a paradise.
He asked that I cooperate
and not oppose him until then.
That's why I served under Hadorra
and fought on the front lines.
Was that promise a lie?
Of course not.
Everything King Ban said was true.
Indeed the humans will be wiped out.
But it won't be just the humans.
The monsters and Dragons and Darklings...
Every creature that lives
on the Surface World will be exterminated.
After all, to erase
the Surface World itself...
is King Ban's true objective.
What?
You fought Abyss Dragon King Veruza,
so you should know.
Deep below the ground
where we stand right now
lies another world.
The Underworld?!
Correct. The land of darkness
that the gods gave to the Darklings.
A world of chaos where
strength is the only rule.
King Ban's true wish is to raise
the Underworld to the Surface World.
This is a secret that not even Hadorra,
his most powerful servant, knows.
Doesn't it sound wonderful?
The Surface World erased,
and humans and monsters and Dragons
all fall to the Underworld.
And only the powerful
and those who enjoy destruction and
slaughter can survive in this new world.
This is King Ban's paradise.
And I am to eliminate
any potential threat to that cause!
You fool!
What you described...
is what people call Hell!
I-It's been fully restored?
The Demon Dragon Blade.
My Reaper Flute neutralizes the senses.
Yet it didn't work.
This man is more than a simple beast...
Dark King Ban.
If that's your intent,
then I have ideas of my own.
Oh no! This is terrible!
Take care, Princess!
May the great gods of Papunica bless you!
Wow, look at how small Papunica is!
"Off to the field of battle!
Farewell dear homeland!"
or something like that, Princess?
You're quite the poet, Popp.
It'll be pathetic if you run away
after saying that.
Oh come on. Do you still think of me
as the cowardly chicken?
It was only way back in the beginning
that I acted like that.
For quite a while back in the beginning!
What?!
That's right.
Huh?!
Anyways!
I'm glad Meruru came
since she can sense enemies...
but why is Miss Amy here?
You always stay back to protect Papunica.
I-I'm here as Her Majesty's bodyguard.
We don't know
what dangers may threaten her.
Besides, I can lend
a bit of a hand in a fight...
If that's all you can do, then you won't
survive the forces of the Field of Death.
Stick to guarding the Princess.
Miss Amy's acting kind of suspicious.
How so?
How so? What do you think?
The whole "for the man I love" thing.
How can Popp be so perceptive
when it comes to other people?
Don't worry, Hyunckel.
The leaders of the world have gathered
powerful warriors there.
It's worth having Amy there
even to just help and heal them.
Princess...
Wow. Powerful warriors from all over!
I wonder what they're like!
Let's hope they're even
half as good as I am.
Powerful warriors...
What's wrong, Hyunckel?
Something worrying you?
Well...
I understand what the Princess is saying.
It's important that
the people of the world stand together.
But...
I don't want to drag too many innocents
into this fight with us.
I've never actually seen his face,
but I've felt the Dark King's
immense presence.
He's not someone
any normal being can stand up to.
True. I know how you feel...
GIGABRAKE
REAPER FLUTE
Is this really the place, Leona?
Yes. This is where Carl Castle used to be.
The Dark Army demolished it,
leaving nothing behind.
Our base should be near here.
So this is...
Master Aban's homeland.
Yes. But this isn't the time
to get sentimental.
That thing's incredible!
It reaches to the top of the clouds!
If that's their stronghold,
it's unbelievably huge!
It looks like the Dark Army is saying,
"We know you're here. Come and get us."
Let's prepare!
We don't know what'll happen!
Who's there?!
Whoa! Wait a minute! It's me!
The Bengana Kingdom
Tank Unit commander, Akhim!
I saw your balloon and came to greet you!
You? We thought you might be an enemy.
What's up? Did you have to shave your head
because you lost the tank unit?
I've always been bald, sir!
I see...
More importantly, have you all seen
what happened to the Field of Death?
Yeah. We saw from above.
Then that will save us time.
General Bowson awaits you
at the base of operations.
I'll show you the way. Please follow me.
Thank you.
Are all the warriors there, too?
No. The warriors aren't
at the base of operations.
Most of them went
to the shipbuilding base in Sababa.
Hey, what's Sababa?
A small fishing port north of Carl.
We're secretly building a large ship
to take us to the Field of Death.
There'll be almost thirty of us
all together.
We'll need a large ship.
Come to think of it, where did Chiu go?
Y-You! Where did you come from?!
Hmph! So what?!
I'm going to infiltrate
the Field of Death,
and gather information
on the Dark Army for everybody!
How am I going to cross the sea?
Don't underestimate me, my friend!
I'm currently worthy
of the title of Beast King!
Ta-da!
This is the Beast King Flute!
Mr. Crocodine gave it to me
as thanks for helping him train!
It's a wonderful item that lures monsters.
If I can beat them,
they become my followers!
With this, I'll eventually form
a mighty legion of good monsters!
Now then, let's blow this at the sky
and get a flying follower.
I-I guess they sometimes come in groups.
Can I beat them?
Wow! It's almost complete!
We'll ride to the Field of Death in this.
Hm?!
What the hell is that?!
The Dark Army?!
You peons are annoying us
from the opposite shore.
Get real!
You've got a lot of nerve
coming here alone!
I would have preferred to come alone.
You'll be fighting all five
of the Hadorra Royal Guard.
We've been waiting for you!
And now all the world's warriors
have gathered.
All that's left is to wait for our ship
to be completed!
An attack?!
No, that's someone
landing with a Rura spell!
Aren't you the mage Fobster?!
I-It's an emergency!
Sababa's been attacked!
A bunch of silver metal beings
attacked the dock!
It's them!
The Hadorra Royal Guard!
Is everyone all right?!
They're strong! They're incredibly strong!
There's no way...
I used Rura to come back and report!
Let's go help them!
Wait!
Rura can't go anywhere
we've never been before!
Then we just need to fly north!
If Popp and I go on ahead...!
Don't bother with that.
I'm all the help they need.
Who are you?
My name is Nova.
They call me the Hero of the North.
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
The Dark Army attacked
the port town of Zababa.
Nova, the Hero of the North goes to help.
Waiting for him there are
Hadorra's Orichalcum warriors.
Nova uses his greatest attack
to fight against Hym.
But no one has yet seen the true terror
of the Hadorra Royal Guard.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Hadorra Royal Guard"
The adventure continues!