Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
BARAN'S RAGE
Popp!
Drop your weapon!
Otherwise, I crush the boy's skull!
You dirty...!
Better hurry up!
If I do, no, if you kill me,
will you really let him go?
I have no interest in this insect's life!
All I want is your head!
What will it be?!
Very well.
Wait!
Don't, Hyunckel! Forget about me!
Shut up!
Just kill him!
I can't do that.
You idiot!
Between me, who's out of Magic Power
and you, it's obvious who can help Dai!
Popp!
Besides, there's someone
who'll be miserable if you die!
Maam...
Her tears are the last thing
I ever want to see!
So please, you have to live!
And go on and make her happy.
I can't make people happy.
All I bring is misfortune.
That's why...
I wanted to bring misfortune
to evil-doers.
That's the only reason
I decided to join your party.
Besides, I'd rather not give Aban another
reason to scold me in the afterlife.
If he hears I abandoned a junior disciple,
he'll reject me for sure.
Hyunckel...
That's the attitude! Don't move!
Don't! Please don't!
Die!
Hyunckel!
Larhart!
Why did you save me?
To use a hostage would bring shame
to the Dragon Masters.
It was unforgivable.
And against a human no less.
Why do you hate humans so much?
Like Master Dino, I was born
between beings of different races.
In my case, it was a Darkling and a human.
My Darkling father died early,
and I was raised by my human mother.
But, when I was seven,
war between Dark Lord Hadorra
and the humans began.
Just because of my Darkling lineage,
the humans discriminated against me.
Not just against me,
but against my mother as well!
Eventually, my mother fell ill
and died a forsaken death.
Master Baran was the only one
who ever understood my pain.
You soft fools.
To feel my pain as your own.
I've never met humans like you.
Perhaps you will be able to understand
Master Baran's pain.
I leave Master Baran
and Master Dino in your hands.
Larhart...
Hyunckel, I have one more request.
Name it.
Will you accept my Dark Armour Spear?
I want you to use it.
It seems the armour favors you as well.
It may have been in battle...
but I'm glad I met men like you...
at the very end.
Larhart, I accept
your will and this armour...
that contains your soul.
It feels like we're doomed.
Do you have a plan, Crocodine?
I was hoping you had one.
If only Hyunckel was here.
Then we may have had options.
He's here!
Hand over Dino.
No!
Do you think you two can stop me alone?
Or do you have some sort of plan?
Of course not.
There's no way for us to stop Baran.
If only... If only we had one more ally!
Speaking of plans...
that Mage came to stop us
on the way here.
I left him to the Dragon Masters
and came ahead.
He means...
Popp?!
To sacrifice such a whelp
was unusually cruel of you, Crocodine.
Or was it the idea of the girl beside you?
Popp... How could he...?
Popp, you went
to stop Baran's forces alone?
That's why you pretended to abandon us?!
You chose to be hated. All for Dai!
I can't believe I actually hit him.
I've been such a fool!
I couldn't realize how determined you were
and called you a coward!
Forgive me, Popp!
You can hit me all you like
in the afterlife!
Have you lost your mind, Crocodine?
My eyes have been opened!
Baran, fight me!
It seems you truly have lost your mind.
Princess, I have a plan. I need your help.
It's too dangerous, Crocodine!
I'm counting on you!
Dragonic Aura!
Unbelievable! He blocked an attack
imbued with my Dragonic Aura!
Baran, use your Gigabreak!
What?!
My tough hide is my only strength!
Only your strongest attack
can take my life!
Well said!
I shall grant your wish!
Take this! My Ultimate Blade!
Crocodine seems to be
proving quite stubborn.
Hopefully Baran will be defeated here.
But I doubt he'll go down easily.
Gigabreak!
Thus ends the Beast King.
What?!
Thank you, Princess!
Now I can fight again!
But my Behoma can't heal
both your wound and stamina at once.
There should be no stamina to heal!
Not even the Beast King can survive
a direct hit with my Gigabreak!
All I need to do is focus
all my power on defense!
So long as I'm not a corpse, the Princess
can heal my stamina with her Behoma!
Hit me as much as you like!
My life or your power!
It's a contest to see which ends first!
A contest?!
You dare mock me...
mock the power of the Dragon Knight?!
I think you hurt his pride
by not dying with one blow!
What an overwhelming Aura!
Crocodine, this is crazy!
You don't know
how long you'll last fighting like this!
I'm well aware that this is crazy!
But it's the only way to stop Baran!
I have no choice!
Let us follow Popp's spirit, Princess!
You're right.
I guess it's punishment for hitting him!
What's wrong, Dai?!
I feel like I'm burning!
I can't sit still!
I have to go.
Someone is calling me.
BLOODY SUKURAIDO!
BEAST KING REDEMPTION BLAST
Crocodine!
Are you immortal?!
No one has ever been hit by
my Gigabreak twice and survived!
Immortality is Hyunckel's thing.
If I keep getting hit
by such an attack, I'm certain I'll die.
But if taking my life
drains your power, it's not a bad trade.
You...! You're not trying to win at all!
You're using your own life
to drain my stamina and Magic Power!
Impossible! The mighty Beast King
Crocodine would sacrifice himself?!
This is the best I can do.
If I can drain your power, it'll help
my friends who will fight you later.
Your friends?! No one is coming!
They'll come!
I know it!
How can he trust the humans so much?!
And that spirit is making him stronger!
Even with the full power of my Crest,
I can't crush him like before!
He need a Behoma!
A Raiden spell?!
That was a warning!
Take another step
and become a charred corpse!
I'm done with this game of cat and mouse!
This time, I will end it!
No! Stop!
No!
Fool! Raiden!
Princess!
What?!
Larhart's Dark Spear?
Why would he interfere?!
What's the meaning of this Lar--
Hyunckel?!
And Popp!
You survived, Popp!
Just barely.
But we managed to take out
the Dragon Masters.
Impossible! You speak lies!
It's not a lie.
How else can you explain our presence?
I see.
So you killed Larhart and took his armour.
No. Larhart gave me this armour
of his own free will.
What?!
He died asking me to save you.
He gave me this armour then.
It was his dying gift.
Liar! Larhart would never
open up to a human!
Baran, Larhart told me of your tragedy.
How Dai's mother, Soara,
was the princess of Arukido.
And how it was the humans
who took her life.
I understand your anger
and grief all too well.
But not all humans are evil!
You yourself know that
more than anyone!
For the woman that you loved
was also a human!
You saw the most beautiful and most ugly
sides of humans at the same time.
Unable to handle it, you hoped to erase
all of humanity from your sight.
But you're mistaken.
Doing that won't erase
your grief from losing her!
If you truly call yourself Dai's father...
If you truly love your son...
then shouldn't you reach out to him
with your human heart, Baran?!
I know that's what Dai's mother
would want!
Baran, Hyunckel's right.
Baran...
What is this unnatural pressure
coming from Baran?
Then I cast it aside!
This human heart and body!
None of your pandering nonsense
will bring back Soara!
To destroy the humans together with Dino
is all that drives me now!
It's all I live for!
If I cannot have that,
then I would rather die!
Something weird is going on with him!
I will reclaim Dino by force if I must!
Even if I must become
a Demon Beast to do it!
Impossible! Look!
His red blood is turning into
Blue Blood of Darklings!
What?!
That's...!
What happened?!
Report. Heyedras stationed
in Teran are disappearing.
Extraordinary energy
is spreading explosively.
Impossible! How can that be?!
I'd heard of it, but it seems Baran
is taking his ultimate form.
Send all Heyedras in the area
to Teran Castle!
Yes, master.
What's happening to him?!
Baran's body...
...Is changing!
Is this the true form of a Dragon Knight?!
Indeed.
The combined power of Dragon,
Darkling, and human.
The Ultimate Combat Form
of the Dragon Knight.
That is this form.
The form known as the Dragonoid!
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Baran's power as a Dragonoid
is beyond this world.
Even Hyunckel and Crocodine together
prove to be no match.
At last, Baran finds Dai,
who lost his memories.
Just when all seems lost,
Popp thinks of one last plan.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Popp's Resolve"
The adventure continues!