Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE DECIDING MOMENT
Take this!
Raiden!
It worked!
We did it! Hooray! Hooray!
As expected, his armour's fine,
but I bet he's burned to a crisp in there.
That's what you get
for underestimating us, right Dai?!
Popp!
Even Raiden didn't work?!
No, it worked.
But he withstood the damage from it!
Even without his armour,
Hyunckel's strong!
I misjudged you two.
If you can do this,
then there's no need to hold back.
Here goes!
Dai, one more!
Too late!
Tomakugutsosho!
Rai...
That binding thing again!
Farewell!
Bloody Sukuraido!
We can't beat him.
Not by sword or by magic.
Dai!
It's over.
Yeah, it must be an exit!
Hang in there, Dai!
No...
Answer me, Dai! Dai!
Don't bother.
Bloody Sukuraido! is a killing attack.
He's finished.
Shut up!
This is all my fault! I got Dai killed!
Join him in the afterlife.
Wait, Hyunckel!
When did you get out?!
Hyunckel, how could you?!
You've struck a fellow Disciple of Avan!
Don't give me that.
He's a student of my father's killer!
You're wrong!
Master Avan wasn't your father's killer!
Spare me the lies!
It's the truth!
This was in a chest in a hidden room.
This is...
a Soul Shell!
They contain messages from the dying!
It's from your father.
The last words of the Hell Knight Bartos!
Dad's last words?! Impossible!
How could that exist?!
This isn't happening.
There's no way he's dead!
He's alive!
In that instant, he leaned his body back
and avoided a hit to his heart!
We can't... beat him...
He can't be beaten by sword.
He can't be beaten by magic.
Not by sword or by magic.
We can't beat him!
Dai...
Listen, Hyunckel,
to the truth your father left behind!
What really happened
the day this Underground Palace fell!
Hyunckel... My son...
Dad?!
My dear son, Hyunckel.
I leave this message
so that you will know the truth.
The day the hero's party
attacked the Underground Palace,
I fought Avan, the Hero
as keeper of the Hell Gate!
But Avan was strong.
I prepared for my death.
And then...
What's wrong?! Strike me down!
Let's not do this.
What?! Will you shame me with your mercy?!
That was clearly made by a child's hands.
It seems unlikely, but you have a family.
When I realized that, I couldn't kill you.
You've beaten me. Not just in strength,
but in heart as well!
Now please open the gate.
The only one I'm here for is Hadlar.
Sir Hero! I have something I must ask you!
And so I told him.
How I found and raised a human child.
And that, even if he spared me,
should Hadlar die, I would cease to be.
Hero Avan! Please look after my son!
Raise him to be a strong,
righteous warrior!
I ask that you show him real human warmth!
Yes.
Sir Avan gracefully accepted.
And then Sir Avan went to face Hadlar.
Soon after...
Hadlar's death cry
echoed through the palace!
And yet... I still lived.
Lord Hadlar!
You survived?!
At my moment of death,
I was saved by the dark powers
of the Underworld god, Vearn!
The Underworld god, Vearn?!
I must now sleep for 13 years to build up
my power and create a new Dark Army!
An army far greater
than the current Dark Army!
But, before I do that,
I need to execute you!
M-Me?!
You're an absolute failure!
With your pathetic sense of justice
and chivalry!
Your human-like warmth makes you weak!
And on top of that, you let Avan
pass right through the Hell Gate!
When I create my new Dark Army,
it will have no place
for a mistake like you!
Well, Avan, enjoy your moment of peace.
When my new Dark Army is complete,
I'll come for you first!
H-Hyunckel...
Dad?!
Dad!
Hyunckel...
I no longer had the strength
to tell you the truth.
And so I hid this message in secret
within this Soul Shell.
Hoping that one day, you would hear it.
Hyunckel, I hope that
you live like a human.
And you must not hate Sir Avan!
If anything, hate this foolish monster
who deemed to raise a human child.
But know that I was happy.
For a brief moment,
this cold corpse of a body felt warmth.
Please let me say this one more time...
Hyunckel... thank you for the memories...
Dad!
Then Hadlar was the one
who killed my father?!
And Avan knew I thought
he killed my father...
and still looked after me?!
Lies...
All lies!
Sword... and magic...
H-Hey Dai?!
Wait! Dai!
Something's wrong.
It's like he doesn't know who I am.
Are you telling me
he's not even conscious?!
Dai?!
Impossible! A direct hit
with Bloody Sukuraido! and he still lives?!
MAGIC BULLET GUN
BLOODY SUKURAIDO!
I remember Master Avan mentioning this.
Sometimes martial artists can keep on
fighting even after being knocked out.
Like their battle instincts keep on going.
That must be what's happening with Dai!
Dai, don't! He'll kill you!
Curse you.
I'll finish you for sure this time!
Stop! You heard what your father said!
The Dark Lord Hadlar is the one
you should really hate!
Stop using your sword for evil!
Enough!
There's no turning back for me!
I'm the Undead Legion Commander
of the Dark Army!
With my body encased in this dark armour,
I am the vengeful warrior, Hyunckel!
Hyunckel...
Here goes, Dai!
Magic and sword...
It's no good!
He doesn't have his usual speed!
This is the end!
Magic... and sword!
What?! My supreme armour!
His sword burns?!
That's the flame of a Mera spell!
No one can encase a weapon in magic!
If anyone could, they would have to be
something beyond human!
Yes! Dai was able to create
a new attack in this moment of peril!
When neither magic
nor sword worked alone, he used both...
in a Magic Sword!
Curse you!
Nice! Do it!
Oh no!
I won't miss this time!
I've gotta do something!
The thunderclouds I summoned...!
Dai, the lightning!
Call down the lighting!
Lightning...
Give it up! I'll finish it with this!
Lightning... Call lightning...
Call down the lightning!
Take this! Bloody Sukuraido!
What?!
Raiden...
Strash!
He did it!
Incomplete or not, it's an Avan Strash
and Raiden double whammy!
Not even Hyunckel can withstand...
Is he immortal?!
We won! We won!
It's no good. I'm finished!
Dai, that's enough!
Maam?!
Dai, it's all over! You've won!
Please... I don't want to see
the Disciples of Avan fighting each other.
Tears?
Maam? Hyunckel?!
What was I doing?
Dai...
Why?
I'm your enemy.
You're not our enemy.
That's my...
You kept it this whole time?
I knew that the time would come
when I would return this to you.
This kindness... This caring warmth...
She's like...
a holy mother.
Dai, are you okay?!
Popp, Gomechan... Did I win?
That's right.
I...
I lose.
Hyunckel.
What are you doing, Maam?!
What if he comes at us again?!
There's no need to worry.
And shouldn't I get healed first?
I'm still casting Behoimi!
It's enough.
Just look at you, Hyunckel!
Losing and then getting a lap pillow!
It's so pathetic it's hilarious!
You're.. Flazzard!
That's right! The mightiest
of the Six Legion Commanders!
Blizzblaze General Flazzard!
What is that guy?!
He's fire and ice stuck together!
What are you doing here?!
Isn't it obvious?!
I thought I'd drop by and kill you!
You know I've never liked you.
A human trying to take all the credit?!
Never in a million years!
If you'd won, I figured I'd kill you
and take the credit.
But it's even better that you lost!
I'll say you all killed each other
and spare you the shame!
You can cry and thank me!
What's this?!
I just gave this extinct volcano
a little wake-up call!
Soon this place'll be
overflowing with magma!
What?!
Curse you, Flazzard!
Whoops! Looks like I ain't welcome!
Guess I'll be bowing out now!
Everybody!
Enjoy your swim in the lava!
It's no good! We can't escape!
If we can make it up there...!
Nobody has that kind of strength left!
Hyunckel?!
I can't let any of you die here!
Crocodine, I finally understand
how you felt!
I hope I can apologize to you
in the afterlife.
But for now, for just an instant...
lend me your titan strength!
Stop! Don't do it, Hyunckel!
Hyunckel!
Thank you.
At long last, my eyes are finally open.
I wish I could help you three out more...
but it looks like this is as far as I go.
Hyunckel!
Watch out! This place won't last!
Maam!
It's coming down! We've got to go!
But Hyunckel's still...!
Farewell, Dai and Popp...
Goodbye... Maam...
Hyunckel!
And so the Undead Legion ends.
Master Hyunckel, at least let this
humble Moruge guide you to the afterlife.
I hear the Underground Palace
was destroyed.
It seems that extinct volcano
suddenly erupted.
An extinct volcano erupting?
Huh. That a shame.
Well, so be it.
He took the new Hero out with him,
so I'd say that wasn't a bad job.
The audacity...
How terrifying it is
to see a man starved for glory.
Okay! Now that Hyunckel's dead,
I guess conquering the Holkia continent
is my job now!
Of course, all I gotta do is find
little Princess Leona and kill her!
Talk about an easy job!
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
Having defeated Hyunckel, Dai and company
along with Baduck, meet Amy,
one of the Papnica Troika.
Together, they head to Valge Island
where Leona awaits.
But the island is already under siege by
their next enemy, the Blizzblaze Legion.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Blizzblaze General Flazzard"
The adventure continues!