Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
HYUNCKEL, THE DARK SWORDSMAN
It's not over!
That stance...!
Avan Strash!
You call this Avan Strash?
Don't make me laugh!
That was just a cheap imitation!
You know the lesson, "Slice the earth,
slice the sea, slice the air.
And what slices everything
is Avan Strash."
Fighting you, I could tell you haven't
mastered the Avan Style Sword Technique!
In other words,
the third skill, Air Slash!
Air Slash?!
That's right...
Dai...
Even if you complete
the Special Hard Course,
you'll probably learn Air Slash
on the seventh day.
The last?
Yes. It's that difficult
of a skill to learn.
But I only trained
with Master Avan for three days.
Even I can't use Air Slash.
It's the greatest
Avan Style Sword Technique.
When Earth, Wave, and Air are mastered,
Avan Strash shows its true ultimate power!
Basically, your attack now
is merely an incomplete imitation!
Even I can use an imitation like that!
Avan Strash!
Dai!
So you two are up next?
We won't let you use
Master Avan's skills for evil!
Three against one...
Then I'll have to use my secret weapon.
As a warrior, I can't use spells.
So Vearn, the Dark King,
gave me the ultimate armour.
A supreme armour that can repel
any and all attack spells!
When I don it, I become unbeatable!
A supreme armour?
I don't see any armour anywhere!
Look closely. It's right in front of you!
Amudo!
His sword is his armour?!
That's right. This Dark Armour Blade
is both the ultimate weapon
and the ultimate armour!
H-He's bluffing! Let's go!
Merami!
It's not working!
How about this?!
Gira!
Dammit!
Popp!
Dammit! I just learned that spell!
Now do you see why I'm unbeatable?
This armour is impervious
to all attack spells.
And no one in the world
can best me at sword fighting.
Don't. I won't fight a woman.
Don't underestimate me!
Even women can risk their lives in battle!
Even more so, if it's for justice!
A likely lesson from Avan.
You learned it too, didn't you?!
Master Avan would never grant
an Insignia of Avan to someone unworthy!
I know that deep down...
This?
How could you?!
I don't need it.
I only carried it around
to find Avan or his students...
so I could kill them myself!
Why?! Why do you hate him so much?!
Because Avan is my father's killer!
His killer?!
This continent of Holkia
was once the Dark Lord Hadlar's base.
The old Dark Army razed towns
and was the cause of many casualties.
Poor thing...
That child was me.
I was raised in Hadlar's Underground
Palace by the Hell Knight Bartos.
The only reason he was allowed to
raise a human child was because
Bartos was the strongest knight
in the Dark Army.
And he was the guardian of the Hell Gate
which led to Hadlar's chambers.
I shall name you Hyunckel
after a legendary swordsman
who once ruled the Underworld.
I couldn't leave the Palace,
but I grew up without questioning it.
Ta-da!
Is this for me?
Yeah!
As my father, Bartos was
the first man to teach me warmth.
He's just like me...
But one day...
Sir Bartos! The Hero is attacking!
He's finally come!
Hyunckel, as guardian of the Dark Lord,
I must fight the Heroes.
It's possible I may die.
Dad...!
You mustn't leave this place!
Should I die,
I hope you'll grow up strong!
Dad!
With the Dark Lord's death cry,
all fell silent.
Dad!
Dad?!
The Undead, unlike other monsters,
cannot maintain themselves
without the Dark Lord's power.
With Hadlar's death,
and the loss of his Dark Power,
my father...
H-Hyunckel...
Dad!
Hyunckel... thank you for the memories...
He crumbled to ashes.
Dad!
It's ironic.
The man who happened to find me was Avan.
You are...?
Hyunckel.
He had no way of knowing who I was.
He must have assumed I was a boy
kidnapped by monsters.
But I knew immediately that
he was the Hero, and my father's killer.
At that moment, I swore
that I'd gain strength and kill him!
That's why I became Avan's student
and learned to fight.
So that I could kill him
with what he taught me!
Stop it!
I know how you feel, but Master Avan...
"Was just fighting for justice"?!
Justice or not, it doesn't change
the fact that he took my father's life!
My father died as ashes.
If that is justice...
then justice itself is my enemy!
Now to finish you off...
My own special attack
that I intended to use on Avan!
A sword from his helmet?!
Take this!
Look out!
Dai! Popp!
This is the attack I developed to defeat
the Avan Style Sword Technique...
Bloody Sukuraido!
Hyunckel, you've gained the skills
of a full-fledged warrior.
And so, I present you with this.
This is...?
Consider it a certificate of graduation.
But you're far from
being a complete warrior.
Your blade seems to have
a strange malice or animosity to it.
Master...
Yes?
Do you know a man named Bartos?
Hyunckel?
Bartos was the strongest knight
of the Dark Army...
and my father!
The malice you sense in my blade is
my hatred towards you, my father's killer!
Wait, Hyunckel!
Hyunckel!
What have I done?
I instinctively fought back!
But if I hadn't,
I'm sure he would have killed me.
What talent with a blade!
It was like a demon's sword!
Hyunckel!
Avan...!
I failed, but I was rescued
by the Dark King's trusted servant,
Mystvearn, the Shadow Vizier,
and survived.
Since then, I've continued to train
as a warrior of the Dark Army.
This attack now far surpasses
the power of Avan Strash!
Your ill-advised dodging
has only increased your suffering.
Let me end it for you!
MAGIC BULLET GUN
IONAZUN
EXPLOSION-TYPE SPELL
He's strong!
Stronger than anyone we've faced before!
Is he really unbeatable?!
No. That's impossible!
Everyone has a weakness,
no matter how strong!
Give it up.
No, I'll never give up!
Even if that bullet contains
a Begirama or Ionazun,
you won't be able to scratch my armour.
We'll see. You never know unless you try!
Is this Manusa?!
Curse your foolish games.
If I use my inner eye to sense
your presence, your Manusa is useless.
Maam!
Right there! If I can hit him there,
an attack spell should work!
It's all or nothing!
Mera!
He dodged it!
You brat!
Look out! Run!
Mera!
Wave Slash?!
You have no power,
yet you insist on troubling me!
Darn it!
You have spirit.
That much is worth praise.
Is Dai really no match for him?!
Sure he's a great swordsman,
but Dai's beaten Hadlar and Crocodine!
I know! It's that mark!
That mark has always allowed Dai
to use extraordinary power!
Dai! Use that power!
Use the power of that mark!
What are you babbling about now?
What's wrong, Dai?!
Get mad! Get mad and fight!
Why won't you get mad, Dai?!
My father died as ashes.
If that is justice...
then justice itself is my enemy!
Dai!
This should keep you from using
your bothersome tricks.
What's that?!
Tomakugutsosho!
This skill uses Dark Aura
to bind an opponent!
Normally, it's used to control corpses.
Darn it!
And now, you're nothing but my puppet.
Dai!
This is the end!
Die!
Bloody Sukuraido!
What?!
Impossible!
Yo, Hyunckel.
Beast King Crocodine?!
Crocodine...
You survived?!
What is the meaning of this?!
Exactly what it looks like.
I won't let you kill Dai!
You there, boy!
Yessir! What?!
Take Dai and escape with that Garuda!
Huh?!
You're still too weak to defeat Hyunckel!
You have to escape!
But...
Some monsters will only obey
my direct commands.
That Garuda is one of them.
But Maam...
Don't worry.
Hyunckel isn't the type
to kill a girl, no matter the situation.
I'll do something about the girl!
Right now, you must escape with Dai!
Do you think I'll just let that happen?!
I'm still one of the Six
Legion Commanders of the Dark Army.
I can take you down with me if I have to!
You can't.
You don't have the strength right now!
I knew it.
Your armour may be
brand new, but I can tell.
Your wounds from your previous battle
haven't fully healed.
Your steel hide is nothing more
than a cracked shield right now!
Crocodine!
No!
Let go!
Not even if it kills me!
Wait! Maam's still...!
Let me go!
Crocodine!
Of the Six Legion Commanders,
I believed that at least you
and Baran were worth respecting!
How disappointing
that you'd submit to a brat!
I merely couldn't stand seeing someone
who beat me lose to someone else.
The argument of the defeated.
How the Beast King has fallen.
If you won't move,
I'll just have to run you through!
So be it!
Why would someone like you
care so much about them?!
They're enemies of our Dark Army!
"Our Dark Army..."
What's so funny!
It never seemed like you were
fighting for the Dark Army.
You always looked like you were
fighting out of hatred for humans.
I was the same.
I looked down on humans.
I thought they were puny,
pathetic creatures.
But fighting Dai and his friends
made me realize...
humans are strong
and compassionate creatures!
They can work together
and can share in joy and sadness!
They're not like us monsters,
who are alone in our strength!
Shut up! Enough of your nonsense!
There's no way a human like you
can't realize their greatness!
Don't you see
that you're lying to yourself?!
That's enough!
Tears?!
Hyunckel... it's good to be a human.
When I'm reborn again,
I hope it's as... a human...
Crocodine...
Moruge.
Is there a problem, Sir Hyunckel?
Oh my! Isn't that...?!
Tend to his wounds.
Sir, I don't see
how he's going to survive.
It doesn't matter. Consider it mercy.
And take this woman
to the Underground Palace.
Huh? Who is she?
A hostage. Throw her in a cell.
Yes, sir!
So long as I have her,
they're sure to come rescue her.
When they do, I'll finish them!
You're awake, Dai!
Popp! Where are we?! Where's Hyunckel?!
He beat us.
The two of us managed to escape.
Where's Maam?!
Hopefully, she's okay.
Our pursuers found us already?!
Hey! Are you hurt?!
You wouldn't happen to be Dai, would you?
How does he know my name?
Who are you?!
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Kindness is the magic of kind people
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
doudarou
I'm not sure
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Even if the place I call home may change
naa kaasan boku wa
Listen to me, Mother
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I will never change those I protect
anata wa nannte iukana
I wonder what you'd say
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
At times I can be cowardly and small
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
Unlike the today that I sought
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
The difference
in their strengths was clear.
Thanks to Crocodine's sacrifice,
Dai and Popp managed to escape.
They begin to form a plan to counter
Hyunckel's overwhelming strength.
The battle to rescue Maam from her prison
in the Underground Palace begins!
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Collaborative Zapple"
The adventure continues!