Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE TERRIFYING CURSE FIELD
Bye-bye little Princess.
Go act tough on your way to the afterlife!
Dai?!
Get away from Leona!
Save it for someone who cares!
If you even touch Leona, you'll regret it!
Dai!
You little brat!
Dai jumped off and charged in alone!
Once we land let's charge in, too!
Baduck, stay here and keep watch.
Huh?
Have the Balloon Ship ready to launch!
Yes, Lady!
I'll regret it?!
Cocky little brat!
Just try to hurt me if you can!
Why you...!
He's fast! Could it be...?!
I'm going to avenge Hyunckel, too!
In your dreams, you snotty brat!
Mahiado!
Dai!
Freeze! Freeze!
What is that sword?!
Magic Sword!
What?!
Oh wow!
Take this!
Fire Earth Slash!
Dammit!
I was right!
No wonder he beat Crocodine and Hyunckel!
In his battles
with the other Legion Commanders...
the little brat's combat skills
have leveled up unbelievably!
This might be...
time for my trump card!
Oh wow! Oh wow, Dai!
You've learned to properly use magic.
I'm a little relieved.
Dai!
Popp, Maam, Miss Amy!
Help everyone!
Hang in there!
Apollo!
A-Amy, help Marin first!
What?!
Sister!
That bastard did all this?!
But it looks like
we've got the upper hand, huh?
Don't let your guard down!
I get it. You're a much bigger fish
than that little princess!
Huh?!
H-His arm grew back?!
Your head is mine!
Everybody, get down!
Blizzblaze Shrapnel Detonation!
Leona!
It hurts! It hurts bad!
You're not the only one in pain, dummy!
Stop crying and help everyone!
It'll take more than that to beat us!
You've already lost.
What?!
That little thing was both an attack
and a signal to my servants...
to begin an infernal battle.
What was that blast?!
Hey! You need my help down there?!
An earthquake?!
What's that?!
W-What in the world?!
Huh?!
What is it?! What's happening?!
The Dark Flame Spire is complete!
The Dark Ice Spire is complete, too!
And now, let's begin
our entertaining showtime!
The shaking stopped!
What was that?! What did you do?!
The Blizzblaze Curse Field!
Blizzblaze... Curse Field?
It's the ultimate tactic that's made
my Blizzblaze Legion unbeatable!
You're all out of options now!
All you can do now is scramble around
until you're all slaughtered!
Get real! You can't slaughter us
with just a little shaking!
Then give it a shot.
Fine! Cry and beg all you like,
but it's over for you!
Gira!
Huh?
What's this?! What's going on?!
My spell... I can't cast Gira!
Mera!
C-could it be...?!
He's nullified our magic?!
I guess you haven't gotten the rules yet.
It's like... It's like
my strength is gone!
C'mere!
Dai!
What's going on?!
How did Flazzard suddenly get so strong?!
That's not it. I haven't gotten stronger.
So what is it then?
You've all gotten weaker!
What?!
That Dark Flame Spire...
and that Dark Ice Spire...
act on the core inside my body...
and encase this entire area
with a powerful field!
Within this field,
everybody but me is weakened
and can't use spells.
Basically, right now, this kid
is weaker than a normal human.
What?!
Looks like you finally get the rules!
Th-That's cheating, Flazzard!
Can't you fight fair and square?!
Save me the sermon.
I don't like fighting.
Winning is what I like!
Slaughter time! Here I come!
It's no good!
My Magic Bullet Gun doesn't work!
AVAN STRASH
FIVE FINGER FLARES
Miss Amy, is your sister alright?!
She's alive. But I can't cast Hoimi!
At this rate, my sister and Apollo
and everyone will die!
Dai, we have to run!
What?! What are you talking about, Maam?!
We have to save the survivors and
take the Balloon Ship outside the field!
It's our only option!
No! I don't want to lose to that cheater!
So long as you survive, you haven't lost!
But at this rate, we'll all be wiped out!
I'll give you a choice.
Want to be frozen solid?
Or turned into a cinder?
No!
No! We can't run!
What?!
Dai, stop being stubborn!
I'm not running!
Damn straight you're not!
Leona!
I just put up the field.
I can't have you running now!
Stop!
Let's make it so you don't even think
about running away!
Princess!
Leona!
There. You like that?
The Princess of Papnica in ice.
Don't worry, though.
She's still alive in there!
I used Legendary Forbidden Magic
to freeze her.
No blow can shatter it
and no spell can melt it.
So what are you supposed to do?
You have to beat me.
Kill me, and the ice melts!
So, do you still want to run?
You can't abandon your little princess
and flee like mice...
Can you?
It's hard being a Hero, huh?!
-Darn it!
-Dai!
There you go!
Just like that!
Come and be killed!
Popp!
Y-Yeah?
Help Miss Amy and get everyone
to the Balloon Ship!
We're running?!
No! We can't abandon the Princess!
At this rate, we'll just be slaughtered!
We have to get out
and wait for an opportunity!
Help us, Baduck!
R-Right!
Sister, hang in there!
Darn it!
How's that?!
Ooh. That's impressive.
You've still got
that much strength in you.
In this field, my enemies' strength
becomes one fifth what it was.
In other words, normally, that blow
would be five times stronger.
Talk about scary.
But...
in here, it'll never amount
to a mortal wound!
Dai, we have to escape!
Don't be stupid!
You saw what he did to Leona!
So long as you're alive,
he won't kill the Princess!
We should escape and formulate a plan!
No! I'm...
I'm...
I'm fighting to the end!
That's right. Come on, big Hero.
What the hell?!
I'm sorry, Dai!
Maam, hurry!
Like hell! You're going nowhere!
How about...
Merazoma!
...this!
Now!
Right!
Why that little...!
What the heck was that explosion?
A bullet from my Magic Bullet Gun.
I threw a bullet with a Gira spell in it.
Flazzard's Merazoma set it off.
That's smart thinking.
Lady Amy, where shall we go?
Head north.
North it is.
There's a rocky coast
where we should be able to hide.
Dancing Flame Army of the Dark Flame Spire!
Knock them out of the sky!
Don't let them off the island!
Wait right there, little Princess.
He ain't the sort of Hero
to abandon you, is he?
Normally, I feel like running
the moment it gets dangerous.
But not this time.
I wish I could have done something
to save the Princess.
I'm sorry.
But...
I know, Maam.
If you hadn't done what you did,
we'd have been wiped out by now.
Yeah.
Everyone, look!
Pursuers!
Get us out of here, old timer!
At full speed!
R-Right!
Hyadain!
Everybody, we're out of the field,
so we can use magic!
Hyadaruko!
Even so, there's too many of them!
We're going to fall into the whirlpool!
I've got this!
Our altitude keeps dropping!
It's all over!
We're crashing?!
Don't give up!
Get us to shore!
Drop the weights!
Over there!
A light came from there and saved us!
Let's go!
We're here.
Who's there? The fools from the balloon?
Uh, yes!
If you're all okay
then feel free to leave.
Huh? Um...
Leave.
Please! You have to help us!
I don't want anything to do with anyone.
Y-You!
Hm?
Uncle Matoriv!
Hmm?
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
Dai and his friends were saved
from Flazzard's pursuers
by Matoriv, a Mage
living as a hermit in a cave.
They work on a plan to break
the Forbidden Magic and save Leona.
Meanwhile, Hadlar and his Dark Army
begin suspicious preparations.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Grand Sorcerer Matoriv"
The adventure continues!