With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
You're The Bravest
DAI AND POPP
I'd rather die than burden Dai
and the others.
Perhaps you're right.
My life belongs to them,
but if it will burden them...
Please! Don't go!
Please stop walking gladly
into death's arms!
You two will be executed
at noon in two days.
Sure! Just kill us already!
We'll choose death
over being used in some scheme!
But warriors of your caliber are valuable.
Especially you, Hyunckel.
Accept this Dark Aura and serve me.
Say he's wasting his time!
Let me think about it.
What?!
Very well.
Hyunckel! You bastard!
You'd sell your soul to Mystban
just to survive?!
I thought...
I thought you were a man
truly worthy of respect!
That you were my friend!
I never thought you'd betray us
at the 11th hour!
Crocodine.
If you consider me a friend...
I need you to trust me no matter what.
What?!
A proud death is fine.
But, I have this new feeling.
Until the final moment...
I want to cling to a chance at survival.
Begone.
I...
What...?
We have to rescue them!
Of course.
But this execution announcement
is clearly a trap.
Knowing that, we must be willing
to expend all of our forces.
I'll do anything!
The world is going to end otherwise!
We must rally our forces
under the Hero once more.
Yes! Once Dai's awake, let's have him
give a speech to everyone!
If he's willing to do that,
I'm sure everyone will
be happy to fight again!
Yes. Dai is everyone's Hero of hope!
-You're right.
-Yeah.
I know he'll give everyone courage!
They all...
still want to make me keep fighting!
I'll go check up on Dai!
Look, Gomechan.
Look how many members
the Beast King Commandos has now!
We even have ten members now!
Emergency! I can't find Dai anywhere!
What?!
Why does everyone
expect me to do the impossible?
My power's not enough.
There's nothing I can do!
Sir Hero!
Hero!
Sir Dai!
Where are you, Dai?!
I can't believe Dai ran away...
You can't blame him. He's still a child.
He lost his father in front of him,
along with his greatest weapon.
If that was on his mind,
why didn't he talk to us?
Because he doesn't understand
what tortures him.
Huh?
He didn't run out of fear of battle.
He fears the weight of his title.
Of not knowing if he can live up to it.
But, as cruel as it is, he's not
a true Hero if he can't overcome himself.
You're wrong!
He's a true Hero!
Hmm.
What the hell?
What's with you?
We might be finished.
I can't believe Dai would leave us.
Oh good grief.
First it's Dai, now we have
"The Uncharacteristic, Part Two."
I never expected to see you
all fragile and weepy.
You never know what life brings.
Stop joking around, idiot!
Don't worry.
There's nothing to worry about.
Just look at me!
The first guy to run from danger
is still standing here.
So it'll be okay.
With Hyunckel, Big Guy,
and of course with Dai.
Popp.
I'll take a look elsewhere.
Perhaps he used Rura to go far away?
Rura, huh?
So I'm in Teran.
God of Dragons!
Please! May the mighty Hero
defeat the Dark King!
Please! Mighty Hero!
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I can't answer your prayers.
The servant of your god told me.
Dark King Ban is stronger than a god.
There's no one who can touch him.
What should I...
What should I do?
For now, I guess you can cry a little.
Popp.
I'll join you.
A moonlight walk could do you good.
ABAN STRASH
MEDOROA
How did you know I was here?
Hey now, don't forget.
I've been with you since the very
beginning back on Dermline Island.
So there's no place
you can go that I can't.
Rura spells are limited
to places you've been.
Besides, back when I was
getting used to using Rura...
I ended up in a place
important to me.
The Dark Forest where we first met Maam.
So I figured the same thing would happen
if you flew off randomly.
This is the place where
you first met your father.
You're not mad?
Hm?
I...
I ran away!
When we all should be working together!
Even though I knew Hyunckel
and Crocodine are in danger!
I ran from the battle!
You're here to yell at me.
"You call yourself a Hero?"
"Coward."
Come on, dummy.
How can I criticize
someone else about that?
When it comes to running,
I'm way more experienced than you.
No one can blame you.
You fought as hard as you could.
You lost your father, and your weapon.
You did... the best you could.
My best isn't enough!
Even with this power,
I couldn't do anything to the Dark King!
I let my father die,
and I let everyone get hurt!
I used to think Heroes were so cool.
I just idolized them.
But then I met Leona.
Then I met Master Aban.
And everyone called me a Hero.
That's why I tried to become
as strong as I could for everyone!
But...
all my power wasn't nearly enough.
Not against Dark King Ban!
And yet, they still think
I can do something.
They still believe I'm a real Hero.
I've had enough.
If they all continue to fight
believing in me...
they'll all end up like Dad...
All of them...
Okay then. I won't try to argue.
But, even if you won't come,
I'm going to fight the Dark King again.
Huh?!
You've always been strong.
But not me.
I was scared of strong guys
and always running around.
And here I am, picking a fight
with the God of the Underworld.
What a surprise.
Popp...
My battles have brought me this far.
Coming this far with you, Maam, Hyunckel,
and the others is my one point of pride.
If I quit here,
all my days of fighting, building up what
courage I have, will have been pointless.
Dai.
Until now, we've always fought
for someone else.
To avenge Master Aban.
To reclaim peace for our families.
Well that's not
our only reason to fight anymore.
It's not only for everyone else.
We have to keep fighting for ourselves.
For ourselves?
Yeah. This is our fight now!
This is... our fight.
You make up your own mind.
I'm going to fight.
Popp...
And I still believe.
I don't care if you're
a real Hero or not.
I believe because you're Dai!
So what about a Hero?!
Who cares about a Dragon Knight?!
For me...
you'll always be Dai!
What should I do?
Why bother asking...
when I've already decided?
Nah, I couldn't find anything.
Popp, couldn't you find Dai?
Quiet please.
The stage is yours.
I had to go cool my head.
Sorry to worry all of you.
Everyone, Dark King Ban is powerful.
The Holy Mother Dragon said
he's stronger than a god.
I can't say that if we fight him
we're going to win.
I'm weaker than Ban.
I have no special weapon.
But I can't just sit back and let him
trample the world by force!
If there's one thing
I have stronger than anyone...
it's this belief!
So, if you will accept me...
please lend me your strength!
Dai!
Hey.
Took you long enough.
Sorry.
Tomorrow at noon, we move to rescue
Hyunckel and Crocodine.
We'll be heading into a trap,
so we must be prepared.
For that, we must obtain
the Great Purification Spell, Minakator.
Minakator?
It's greater than Aban's Mahokator spell.
It can seal the Magic Power of Darklings.
You said Ban Palace
has a protective field.
Yeah. It keeps us from
using Rura spells to get in.
If Minakator works, it will erase
Ban Palace's field,
allowing entry with a Rura spell.
Oh wow!
But this is a spell
not even Aban could attain.
If Master Aban couldn't cast it, who...?
The fifth Disciple of Aban.
Hold it!
Uh, sorry!
But the Disciples of Aban receive
the Insignia of Aban from Master Aban.
There's only four of us!
It's the same! It's an insignia of Aban!
Huh?! Then the fifth Disciple...
These are made by polishing
a rare stone called Kiseiseki,
and concentrating it with magic.
These are heirlooms of Aban's family.
Only he knows how to make them.
These have the power to magnify holy power
and repel dark power.
They work as charms.
Wait... then...
All this time...?!
Yes.
These Insignias have protected you
through all your battles.
I never knew.
I never even considered it.
Master Aban... Master Aban was always...
He was watching over us.
I always assumed we made it this far
through our own strength, but...
Without these Insignias of Aban,
we may have lost some battles by a hair.
Master Aban has always been
lending his strength...
to us.
Aban gave me this as a charm.
Afterwards, he came up with the idea to
give them to his students upon graduation.
Princess Leona.
Uh, yes?!
I would like you to be
the fifth Disciple of Aban.
Me?!
I believe Aban would have chosen you.
And I believe that you
can attain Minakator.
However, it will require
you to pass a severe test.
Huh?! Leona!
Will you accept this, Princess Leona?
Yes.
Leona! This is crazy!
Dai, I'm going to do this.
To be honest, until now...
I've always been frustrated that
I couldn't share your pain.
I should fight like Popp and Maam.
I accept it!
No matter what test awaits!
That way, I will truly be
a member of your party.
That's what I believe.
The test will be to brave
the Cave of Trials.
It's a labyrinth teeming with monsters.
Only there can you bind with
the Minakator spell.
Yes.
But can I become a Disciple of Aban
without his teachings?
Shall I tell you a little bit about Aban?
Yes please.
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
I finally realized it
imasara kizuitanosa
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
Must be the reason I was born
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
I shake off the clinging night
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
When the Dark Lord Hadorra
invaded the world,
the Order of Carl, led by Princess Flora,
fearlessly faced his Dark Army.
Aban guarded Carl Kingdom
with his captain, Roka.
With a fateful encounter with Hadorra,
his destiny was set in motion.
The days of Aban's youth are revealed.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Aban, the Hero"
The adventure continues!