With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE SUCCESSOR OF JUSTICE
So that Underworld combat machine...
dragged Master and Kilban
into a different dimension?!
No one can interfere
with a duel that uses the Judge.
When one is defeated,
they lose their head,
the Judge self-destructs, and only
the winner can return to this dimension.
What must we do?!
I'm asking you what we must do
to save our Master!
Well... I suppose if you want to know,
you have no choice but to ask me.
If you don't tell us, we'll defeat you
and force it out of you!
Here goes, Mystban!
Wait, Dai!
Mystban doesn't know!
Or rather, going over what he just said,
there's no viable way
to rescue Master from the Judge!
It's been used to settle disputes
in the Underworld since ancient times!
There's no way it can be
interfered with from the outside!
In other words, he's just pretending
to know of a way
in order to keep us here and deal
as much damage to you as possible!
That way, even if he loses,
Ban will have more of an advantage!
Don't fall for the enemy's trick!
Believe in Master Aban's strength!
We have to get to the Dark King
as soon as possible!
Leona...
that's cold.
Huh?!
That's right.
I know what you're saying is right.
But to leave without making any attempt...
How can you expect us to do that?!
Maam...
That's right.
Mystban is an enemy
we're going to have to defeat anyway.
I'd expect nothing less
from the Disciples of Aban!
Now, come!
Wait!
Dai!
This is...
Master Aban's Feather!
Leona?!
Why does the Princess
have Master's Feathers?
Don't underestimate me.
Spellcraft and assassinations
aren't all that I can do.
And now...
it's over!
An Aban Strash?!
So this is the original!
Aban's attack. 78 damage to Kilban.
This much damage from a single scratch?
Then, back there...
That's right.
If I had really wanted to,
I could have gravely wounded you.
But instead,
I chose to only break your mask.
Firstly, I couldn't afford
to expend all of my energy back there.
Secondly, I wanted your anger
directed at me alone.
This situation is exactly what I wanted.
I can stay here
fighting you for eternity...
so long as Dai and the others
defeat Ban in the meantime!
Besides,
I've already told my intentions
to my successor, who will lead them.
Your successor?
The only one who can rally everyone
and truly make them a party of justice...
is you.
I leave it to you...
Princess Leona!
Everyone listen!
Master gave me his Feathers
knowing this might happen.
In order to lead
the Disciples of Aban to victory...
In the name of the great Hero Aban,
and justice for the surface world...
I, Princess Leona, now command all of you!
All of you must fight for the Hero!
All of you must fight for the Hero.
Huh?
What do you mean by that?
Listen, Princess.
From this moment forth,
everything rests on getting Dai
to Ban in the best shape possible.
Our party must focus all of our efforts
on this single cause.
The Dark King likely has power
beyond our imagination.
The strike from the Hero's blade
is our greatest weapon against him.
When I faced the Dark Lord Hadorra,
my friends did everything they could
to get me to the Dark Lord's chambers.
Forget about me and just go, Aban!
Sir Aban, good luck to you!
Just get to the Dark Lord already!
My disciples all have kind hearts.
It's a wonderful quality.
But war can be cruel.
At times, we must wipe aside our tears
and focus on achieving victory.
In these times, you must
keep everyone moving, Princess.
I believe you're the only one
with such strength.
Only... me?
You have a firm belief in justice.
And, as a ruler, you already have
what it takes to lead.
Even if at times
it means you will draw ire,
you will do what must be done
to lead the people down the right path.
I believe you are quite brave.
That's why I want you
to have those Feathers.
If some powerful enemy
should attack the others,
I will face that foe just as Hyunckel did.
After that, you must lead the others.
I want you to have those Feathers,
as proof of my faith in you.
Thank goodness.
I...
I thought you were planning
to sacrifice yourself for Dai again.
Well...
Of course not!
I merely brought you with me
so we could talk in private.
I'm not looking forward to dying twice.
Besides, I only gave you
half of my Feathers.
Just half the bunch, for whatever happens.
I apologize for worrying you.
Obviously, there is always
the risk of death.
However... I don't intend to die in vain!
If I'm going to risk my life to fight,
it will be "for the Hero."
Right?
Come! Let's hurry forth!
I'll teach you how to dispel
magical traps on the way.
Yes, sir!
That's right.
Master didn't give me these Feathers
to use as weapons!
He left them to me as beacons with which
to lead the disciples of justice!
Master fights on even now!
We must fight just as he does!
Master is...
Everyone is... fighting for me?
Dad, Mom, and Uncle Matorif...
They all worked together like that
to lead the Hero to victory.
If we want to call ourselves
the Hero's Party,
we have to do what they did.
Otherwise, what is Master
fighting for right now?!
You can shout whatever you like.
Here I come!
Popp!
Princess!
I'll hold him off!
Popp!
I might be a little outclassed here,
but I'll do what I can!
I'm stubborn enough
to figure something out!
I may not be as good as Master or Mentor,
but I can at least do what Hyunckel did!
I've got my own reasons
for why I've got to!
Hey! Don't get the wrong idea, Popp!
Comparisons to Hyunckel
won't sway me to fall in love with you!
Maam!
Don't imitate others
and just show me what you're made of!
Mystban can reflect spells
that come from straight ahead.
But if I have Maam
backing me up with her strength...
Hmph! You're always
cutting me off at the knees.
There you go!
The two of us will handle this!
Princess and Gome, go on ahead with Dai!
Dai!
Popp and Maam are fighting
so I can go ahead.
In that case...
Okay! Let's go, Leona, Gomechan!
To Ban!
MINAKATOR
TOMAKUGUTSOSHO
Stop! Dai!
Are you sure?
That friendship nonsense of yours...
It could lead to their deaths.
Are you sure?
What are you waiting for?!
We fought together all this way
and you still can't trust us?!
Leona!
I'm sorry. I was too harsh.
Lead Dai for us, will you?
Dai!
Right!
You will stop running...
when you hear your friends' screams.
You won't go any further!
And now...
let's show him the combined strength
of the lovers to be, yeah?
Mmm... kiss!
Stop getting ahead of yourself!
Face forward!
It looks like Popp and Maam
have worked things out.
They should be okay.
Yeah.
I wouldn't be worried
if they were facing a normal enemy.
But it's Mystban, the last great pillar!
Listen up! Don't think
you'll be able to go after Dai!
So, how do we fight?
You distract him. I'll finish him!
Oh really?
I guess you don't really
believe in my strength.
That's not it.
I doubt he can reflect a Medoroa spell.
But remember the Mirror of Shahal.
It's best to be careful.
More importantly...
my Refractor Fist
should be able to damage Mystban.
Your Refractor Fist?
Inside Mystban's Shadow Raiment,
I don't know if it was human or Darkling,
but I saw a face like ours.
That means he's not
an evil energy life form,
but a living being with a body!
I see!
So I'll keep him busy with my spells...
...and I'll tear off his Raiment
and hit him with my Refractor Fist!
Got it!
It's simple, but probably
the most effective attack!
Let's go with that!
You ignorant fools.
I could easily go after Dai,
but I said the White Garden
would be your grave.
It would be rude to change locations.
I'll get Dai to return here...
by using your deaths as bait.
Don't make us laugh!
Underestimate us and you'll regret it!
You may be one of the strongest
from the Dark Army, but you won't...
"...win so easily. We'll hold out."
Is that it?
You're the ones making me laugh.
Maybe someone
of Ron Berku's ability could succeed.
But you two will barely
serve as a distraction.
Here is my prediction.
I will kill you two
without taking a single step.
That will stop Dai's progress,
forcing him to come back here.
Why you...!
Don't assume everything will go...
according to your plan!
Tomakugutsosho!
I'm getting tired of your parlor tricks!
It's not an issue
if you know how it works!
Take this!
IORA!
What paltry spells.
Hardly worth absorbing and reflecting.
Yeah! I'm sure they aren't!
I'm using a weaker spell to keep you busy!
Now's your chance, Maam!
Refractor...
Fist!
Did it work?!
But...
Maam!
Popp! Maam!
There's no way my Refractor Fist
wouldn't work on something
with a physical body!
He's squeezing us to death!
Popp!
Forget about us! Get to Ban!
Go!
Oh no! He was letting up just enough
so we could call out!
So that Dai would hear us!
But once Dai comes back, he'll kill us!
There's no point in coming to save us!
My prediction came true.
Dammit!
Don't come!
I'm begging you not to come back!
Hyunckel!
He... He managed to survive!
No! It's...!
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Everyone must fight for the Hero.
Leona's command
brings the heroes together,
only for them to fall into peril
facing Mystban.
Larhart appears, donning the Dark Armour
Spear, and rescues Popp and Maam.
Larhart tells of his promise to Baran
and Dai learns of his father's intentions.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Baran's Last Will"
The adventure continues!