Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE EXTREME ANNIHILATION SPELL, MEDOROA
You're looking much better.
Yes.
Can I get you anything?
No.
I'll bring some fruits.
Th-Thank you.
Yo.
The leaders have finished their meeting.
The showdown is in five days.
So they finally made up their minds.
It's a collaborative effort
between countries, so it took a while.
We'll be gathering in Carl Kingdom,
south of the Field of Death.
Carl Kingdom is in ruins.
We're using the ruins
as a cover to build a base.
Our group will head out the day before.
So for the next four days
I'm going to my mentor's place.
It's not just me.
Maam, Crocodine and Chiu are all training.
You guys make sure to rest up.
I need to get ready too.
Dai.
Are you healed?
Yeah.
We have somewhere to go.
Hyunckel...
Where...
They've all gone.
Huh?!
With the showdown date set,
the Disciples of Aban have all left.
Including Dai and Hyunckel.
But...
His wounds haven't fully healed yet.
Why does he rush into battle so quickly?
He only rests when
he's too wounded to fight.
It's like he's cursed to keep fighting.
They're the only ones
who can save the world.
All we can do is support them
to ease their burden.
That includes Hyunckel.
Sister!
My weapons can recover
from this sort of damage on their own.
But I can fix them if you're in a hurry.
He seems to be
in a really bad mood.
It's probably your fault.
Mine? Why?
You two.
Time to teach you a lesson.
If you think the Sword of Champions
beat you because it's made of Orichalcum,
then I'll knock some sense into you.
I guess it was my fault.
Step outside.
Huh?! You're going to use a sword?
He knows how to fight with a sword?
I said I'd teach you a lesson.
That sword is this world's greatest!
I can't make anything stronger!
Your only hope to fight better
is for you to grow stronger!
What's wrong?
What hope do you have
if you can't match someone like me?
This is no joke... He's strong!
I can't believe someone this good
was still out there in the world.
Very well.
Those weapons will
go to waste in your hands.
Once they're restored,
I'll show you how to really use them...
through actual combat!
That's the Baruji Whirlpool.
Sorry Chiu.
I'll need your help with my training.
Absolutely! I'm glad to help!
Okay!
So, an Orichalcum Superbeing Army...
That's bad news.
It's not their strength that's bad news.
It's also their minds.
Their minds?
The Forbidden Magic of giving life
to inanimate materials
is heavily affected by the mentality
of whoever uses it.
Flazzard was created back when Hadorra
was obsessed with power.
He was a violent piece of trash
who cared only for glory, remember?
I see.
If that Royal Guard
actually cares about a fair fight,
then it means Hadorra himself
has grown as a warrior.
So the members of the Royal Guard
created by the new Hadorra
are each stronger than Flazzard.
Not only that...
until now, you guys have managed
to get by using teamwork.
Now they're going to use it, too.
This'll be difficult.
Mentor, please,
is there anything I can do?!
Hym repelled a spell
ten times stronger than a Merazoma!
A normal flame spell won't work on him!
Not with an Orichalcum body.
What can I do?!
Let's go outside.
Mentor, are you sure you can get up?!
Are you okay?!
Don't worry about me.
Speaking of Flazzard,
he was pretty strong, wasn't he?
Huh?
He used both fire and ice.
R-Right.
The idea was good, but his youth
and inexperience caused him to fail.
Had he used fire and ice simultaneously,
you wouldn't have stood a chance.
Like this.
Can you do this?
I-I don't know.
I've never tried it before.
This is your answer.
Do this, and Orichalcum foe or not,
you'll always win.
After all, this is the Grand Sorcerer
Matorif's strongest extreme spell.
What a spell...
I'll teach it to you.
Well, if I can manage to pull it off.
What do you mean?!
I've only used it a handful of times.
It's too scary.
Mentor's like a walking ball of ego,
and even he's scared to use it?!
Just what kind of spell is it?!
Fire and ice.
They may seem like opposite spells,
but both Fire-type and Ice-type spells
use Magic Power that control heat.
It's just a matter of
whether it's positive or negative.
Push Magic Power in the positive direction
for a Fire-type spell.
Push it in the negative direction
for an Ice-type spell.
When this positive and negative
Magic Power is sparked simultaneously,
it becomes
the ultimate annihilating power.
I'm not sure I get it.
So, by combining the two powers,
it creates an annihilation spell
that will disintegrate anything?
Very good. You've grown quite perceptive.
You're absolutely correct.
It's the Extreme Annihilation Spell.
It's called...
Medoroa.
Medoroa?
This spell is unbelievably hard to cast.
You need the skill to combine Fire-type
and Ice-type spells of exact equal power.
But, pull it off and you're unbeatable.
It doesn't matter
how resilient your opponent is.
This spell will disintegrate
absolutely anything.
And you're going to teach it to me?
Yeah. I will.
This is probably the only spell
that will work on an Orichalcum enemy.
Great! How do I do it?!
What sort of training do I need to do?!
Popp, training for this is simple.
It'll only take an instant.
That's even better!
This spell requires
casting both spells simultaneously.
They must be balanced perfectly.
Those without talent
will never pull it off.
I'm going to cast it at you.
Huh?
Cancel it out with your own Magic Power.
What?
This spell...
can only be cancelled out
by the same spell!
Huh!
If you can't successfully combine
the two spells,
you'll be erased from this world!
What?! That's crazy, Mentor!
Here goes, Popp!
Pull it off if you want to live!
BEHOMA
HEALING-TYPE SPELL
REFRACTOR FIST
O-Oh crap! This is too much!
I'll have to run to dodge it!
That's right! Mentor's not well!
He's been casting Forbidden Magic-level
spells to protect his friends!
He's coughed up blood before!
That spell takes such an effort to cast.
And he's willing to endure it for me!
I can't run away!
This is about more than just a spell!
If I run from this,
I'll have no right to call him my mentor!
Thank you.
Here goes!
Medoroa!
Popp!
Good! Contain it!
Oh no! Popp was always better
at Fire-type spells!
The output of his left hand
is overpowering his right!
Popp! Increase your Ice-type spell power!
Increase the power from your right hand!
Dammit!
Don't vanish! Don't vanish, Popp!
Damn it all!
Oh man, I wish I could train with them.
A princess can't just run off
and abandon her duties.
Maybe I should go.
I'm kidding.
The Baruji Whirlpool became two!
And now it's one again!
Good job, sir!
It's possible!
Theoretically, it's possible!
Are you okay?!
Y-Yeah. Sorry.
You've got your own training,
yet you're helping me.
It's nothing.
I'll make it up to you.
I've got a gift for you.
Huh?! Really?!
What is it?!
Okay, one more time.
Yo! Not bad!
Popp!?
Punching each drop of water that splashes.
Training to increase your speed?
Yes. More speed means more force.
I need more instant destructive power
to damage our new enemies.
W-What happened to your arm?!
Oh, nothing much.
Just training for a new spell.
When I mess up, this happens.
I just dropped by to cool it off.
What kind of spell is it?
You'll find out after I complete it.
This one is seriously strong.
No matter who we face,
I know I'll be able to help.
You seem confident.
Yeah. You can count on me!
We have two days left.
I better try harder!
You're going to have to try a lot harder
if you want to increase your speed.
You're carrying
a lot of excess weight, you know.
What did you say?!
I'm joking! I'm joking!
Are you okay?! Are you hurt?
What the hell was that?!
A trap for grappling training.
We're going to be facing enemies
immune to my Refractor Fist.
That's it. No more gazing at those legs.
Those things are lethal.
Balance...
It's about equal balance.
Not again!
How's that, Mentor?
I know my Fire-type Magic Power
is still a bit strong.
But it's not too far off, eh?
I've never been more impressed
with your skill.
That's the first time
you've ever complimented me like that.
Maybe it's time you retire.
You kids always get ahead of yourselves.
I'm serious, Mentor.
I'll learn every skill you have.
So you don't have to
push yourself anymore.
Try to look after yourself.
Why did you choose to be a Mage
when you became Aban's student?
Huh?
Didn't you consider
being a Warrior or a Hero?
Master Aban told me...
I sense a very, very great potential
for magic from you.
You remind me of an old friend of mine.
That's why I didn't hesitate to be a Mage.
He really had an eye for people.
If you want me to retire,
you better really impress me.
Let me out of here!
I'm the Mystic Legion Commander!
Quiet down in there.
You should be executed, but Lord Hadorra
mercifully granted you imprisonment.
I don't deserve imprisonment!
Learn more remorse.
Hey! Get back here!
If I may, Lord Hadorra...
What is it, Albinass?
That one should be executed at once.
He's nothing but a parasite.
If allowed to live, he will only
be a hinderance to you.
He was the one
who worked to enhance my body.
It cost him his son.
There's no need to kill him.
Let him cool off in his cell.
Yes, My Lord. If that is your command.
The old me would have killed him
without a second thought.
Am I too soft?
No. You are magnanimous,
if a bit too lenient on parasites.
You don't hold back, do you?
Kilban, I have a job for you.
An assassination?
I don't think Hadorra would appreciate
me killing the Disciples of Aban.
It's not the Disciples.
And I'm not even sure you'll succeed.
But at his core, he is still a father.
While he remains silent for now,
there's no telling how he'll move next.
So, eliminate the sleeping Dragon?
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Dai and his friends head to Carl Kingdom
where warriors gather from all over.
As the group approaches the stronghold
of the Dark Army, the Field of Death,
they renew their resolve
to defeat the Dark King.
Meanwhile, on orders from Ban,
Kilban closes in on Baran.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"To the Final Battleground"
The adventure continues!