Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
OFF TO THE DEPARTMENT STORE
What? You want to join Dai's party?
With this last battle with the Dark Army,
we saw that we have much to learn.
We wish to join them and hone our skills.
Both of you wait!
I believe that should be my role!
Amy, you too?!
I will not let you have this!
I will join them on their journey!
Hey! That's not fair, Apollo!
That's right!
How is it not fair?!
-What give you the right?!
-In these matters...
What a handful.
Stop it, all of you!
You three have a duty to protect Papunica!
Besides, I'm going with Dai.
What?!
What did you just say?
Huh? Uh, nothing.
Leona, can I talk to you?
What is it, Dai?
A new weapon?
This Steel Broadsword is on its last legs.
Then it's off to Bengana Kingdom!
Bengana has a department store!
What's that?
You don't know?
It's a huge building filled with stores!
As big as an inn?
Don't be silly. It's as big as a castle!
Wow!
Father took me there once
when I was small.
It was big and huge
and they had everything!
Oh wow!
Dai, would you like to go?
Yeah, I would!
Now you're talking!
Hmm. I think it was like this.
Th-This is...!
Huh? Mentor?
There's no mistake.
It's the Dragon Crest.
If he really is a Dragon Knight...
Aban, your student
is far more than you knew!
So do you know what the mark
that shows up on Dai's forehead is?
My mistake. So you mentioned
you want to journey with Dai?
Uh, yeah. Is that a no?
I guess I'm still in training, so...
Go on. Consider these a parting gift.
The Sorcerer Cape and Shining Staff
I used when I was young.
And this.
Be there for Dai.
Huh?
He's going to hit a major wall soon.
Not as a Hero, but as a person.
When that time comes,
you have to support him.
Understood?
S-Sure.
Man, he was awfully nice today.
These seem pretty cool.
But... well...
This thing's kind of ugly.
Emergency! The balloon on the roof...
What?!
No way!
Princess?!
And Dai?!
Everyone's asleep from the Rariho spell!
Princess! Come back!
Sorry everybody!
We'll be right back, so don't worry!
She always does this.
The moment my back is turned,
she sneaks out of the palace.
I suppose that just means
peace is returning to Papunica.
Besides, Dai is with her.
They should be fine for a few days.
Honestly. After telling us we can't go.
Are you sure about this, Leona?
Isn't this stealing?
It's fine. How is my using
palace equipment stealing?
I guess so.
Oh, right. Shouldn't we have
invited Popp, too?
Popp? Oh, right, that Mage.
Why bother? He doesn't seem too reliable.
It's like he doesn't have much experience.
It probably wouldn't make
a difference even if he came.
Why that little...!
He's a lot more reliable than he looks.
Oh?
Really? He's the type who runs away
the moment the party is in danger.
And who asked you?!
Oh, you're here.
And I was hoping to enjoy
an adventure alone with Dai.
Why you little...!
Bengana is considered
the safest country in the world.
With an advanced military and industry,
it's kept the Dark Army at bay
using its abundance of
weapons and resources
backed by the world's greatest economy.
Let's go!
Go! Go!
Hey! Slow down a little!
This is nothing!
What is with her?!
It's not a big deal.
I'm actually a little relieved.
What?!
Back in Papunica,
Leona has to be a leader for everyone.
So she seemed a little distant.
But now, she seems
more lively and like herself!
So we're here
for her stress relief or something?
Oh! There's a castle!
Don't be silly.
What castle has balloon like that?
Huh?
Go!
Leona, you're going too fast!
So this is a department store?
It's huge! Is it really full of stores?!
Let's go!
This is amazing. It's a hundred times
bigger than my family weapon store.
4F CLOTHES, ARMOUR
3F HOUSEHOLD ITEMS
You can't come here without
checking out the basement!
2F MAGIC ITEMS
1F JEWELRY, COSMETICS
Wait up!
What is this room? It's empty.
We're trapped!
The room is falling!
Calm down. It's called an elevator
and it takes you to each floor.
There's herbs and seeds
I've never seen before!
Two Slime Buns
and one Slime Tapioca please.
Sure thing. That'll be ten gold.
Here.
Are Slimes safe to eat?
It's not real.
It's a snack shaped like a Slime.
Huh? There's something inside.
Congratulations! You found a Small Medal!
What is this thing for?
I dunno.
3F HOUSEHOLD ITEMS
It's super high-quality Horse Manure!
It's so bright, I can't see anything!
Luxuries like these really make
the department-store experience.
Sir. Sir.
Huh? Me?
That's a nice buckle there.
Seriously?
I mean. Isn't it ugly?
Especially the face.
No, it's a wonderful buckle.
I'll pay you 500 gold for it.
500 gold?! That much?!
It won't come off.
Hmm. It's definitely cursed.
ABAN STRASH
HELL'S CLAW
Sirs! See my latest product! Both attack
and defense in this all-purpose helm!
I call it...
The Blockhead Basher!
Come and get it!
No way.
Buy one now and I'll throw in
another one for free!
Okay. Let's go.
Right.
Why don't these sell?
Wow. This is so cool!
Wow!
So cool!
Whoa! 3,800 gold?!
Maybe I shouldn't have touched it.
Dai, feel free to buy anything
less than 5,000 gold.
Metals and cloth
from Papunica sell for a lot.
If I sell these dresses,
it should get us 20 to 30,000 gold.
She's a real princess.
DRESSING ROOM
Hey.
How about this?
What kind of Sage dresses like that?
Huh? Then how about this?
Here!
Meow!
Wear something more serious!
Oh come on.
This actually has pretty high defense.
What about you, Popp?
I'm good. I got a new weapon
and cape already.
You pick something.
In that case, I want that.
I guess this will do.
Are you sure you want that?
It's fine! I'll get used to it!
Okay, let's find Dai a new weapon.
Ow...
You know, I don't feel much stronger.
Oh? What's that?
A Dragonsbane!
Huh? The famous weapon?
Yes. It can pierce a Dragon's hide,
which is said to be harder than steel.
It's a top quality weapon.
But, it's expensive, right?
Huh?
There's no price.
My friends, this is our only piece,
so it will be put on auction.
An auction.
Come on, these things
go for over 15,000 Gold.
You can't buy it
with Mommy's allowance.
Come here, you two!
Dai, Popp, let's buy that Dragonsbane!
Are you serious?!
I have 16,000 gold right here!
Don't bother!
Huh?!
Using weapons more powerful than you are.
Don't waste your money like one of
those fools pretending to be strong.
Are you talking about us?!
Who else is there?
Why you...!
That's enough, Grandmother.
Please forgive us.
My grandmother has a foul mouth.
I merely call them as I see them.
Hmph! What was that?!
They looked like Seers.
Yeah. But the young one
was kind of cute.
You're so stupid.
This country's finished.
All that's advanced is its appearance.
What is it, Meruru?
Grandmother, something's coming.
Many monsters with terrifying power!
What?! I haven't sensed anything yet!
Meruru, it seems you've developed
our bloodline's power.
They're coming! They're close!
What is that?!
A Hydra!
F-Fire! Fire!
Our cannon's aren't working!
Just how tough is its hide?!
17,000!
17,500!
18,000!
That's enough, Princess. Come on.
We're already 2,000 gold over our limit.
If no one else will bid, that's it!
We're fine! I've got this!
19--
Sold! Today's feature item,
the Dragonsbane,
has been sold to the merchant,
Mr. Gopple, for 18,000 gold!
Check it out!
Wow! Good job!
Honestly! What are you doing, Gomechan?!
It's okay, Leona.
I can fight with a normal weapon.
But I can't stand letting those goons
have such a good weapon!
It would be far better in our hands!
W-What's that?!
Look at that!
An army of Dragons!
I see one Hydra, and Dragons...
One, two, three, four, five...
Five Dragons!
Is that the Dragon Legion
of the Dark Army?!
Hey! You bought the Dragonsbane, right?!
Use it to drive them off!
Don't be stupid!
I bought this to make money!
Huh. Pathetic.
That said, with that many Dragons,
we might be in over our heads.
Let's fight! We should fight!
Those Dragons might have
come here seeking us!
And we should buy time
so that everyone can evacuate!
She'll even protect people like that.
Okay!
Princess, you've changed
my opinion about you.
I guess true leaders
prove themselves under fire.
My opinion of you
still hasn't changed though.
Just watch me!
Dai, I'll take care of the Dragons!
You take the big guy!
Okay!
Princess, you evacuate the people in here!
Got it!
Come on people!
We need to get out of here! Now!
Okay! Here I go!
This isn't working!
Let's go, Gomechan!
I guess five Dragons is a little much!
Okay! In that case!
Let me show you how fast I've learned
to flee from all my battles!!
Follow me!
Hurry! Hurry and run!
Mommy!
Mommy! Mommy!
Wait, Meruru! Where are you going?!
I have to help those people.
Don't be a fool!
What can simple Seers like us do?!
Seers...
That's right.
We knew when to run because we could
foresee when the Dark Army was coming.
We've survived
by moving from town to town.
But...
I've had enough!
I'm tired of fleeing towns, knowing
many people will be hurt or killed!
Meruru, wait! Meruru!
Foolish child.
Mommy! Mommy!
Please! Help my mommy!
We have to move this rock!
Wave Slash!
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
An army of Dragons
attacks the Bengana castle town.
Using the power of his mark, Dai faces
a giant Dragon with a hide of steel.
The Seers Nabara and Meruru watch
the battle and are shocked by Dai's mark.
What truth will Nabara reveal?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Dragon Knight"
The adventure continues!