boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
are itsukarada?
Since when was it?
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Being honest became whining
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Standing firm became strength
naa mitsukaranai?
Have you found it yet?
jishin janaku jibun jishin
Not confidence, your true self
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Truly loving myself
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
Is it alright to still believe in that?
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
I smolder because I've actually burned
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
No matter where this journey takes us
tada me wo mihiraite
I'll just open my eyes
yume wo miru
And dream my dream
yume wo shiru
And know my dream
DRAGON MASTER GENERAL BARAN
This is the Dragon Legion's handiwork.
So while we were fighting Flazzard,
they destroyed Carl Kingdom.
The Order of Carl was said
to be the greatest! Dammit!
I have a request.
My brother's corpse should be
around the palace. I'd like to bury him.
My brother was the lead knight
of this kingdom.
The knight Horkins was a hero whose name
was known even in neighboring countries.
He fought off the Dragons valiantly,
but the enemy Legion Commander killed him.
Baran...
I'd never seen anything like it.
My brother matched him
in skill with a sword.
And then he...
You sheath your sword?! You coward!
One shot.
With one shot, he killed my brother.
There. I can't get him out alone.
This shape...
The same shape as Dai's mark.
Serve you?! Destroy the human world?!
You must be joking!
I make no joke about this.
It's what the Dragon Knights
were born to do after all.
What?!
I see you don't know yet.
Very well. I shall tell you
in place of the Dragon Crystal.
Long ago, when the gods
newly created the world,
three races ruled the land.
Specifically, the humans,
Darklings, and Dragons.
These days Dragons
are considered a type of monster,
but they used to be smarter than humans,
and most of them could speak.
But these three races fought
bloody battles for control of the world.
The gods, lamenting this,
decided someone must oversee this world.
The gods of Dragons, Darklings, and humans
convened and came to a decision.
To create a being with the strength of
Dragons, the Magic Power of Darklings,
and the heart of humans.
To create the ultimate warrior.
That is the Dragon Knight.
Thus, if any race should ever
hold ambitions to dominate the world,
it is the Dragon Knight's duty to wipe
them out and administer divine punishment.
In that case,
isn't Dark King Ban worse?!
He's trying to conquer the world!
No. The evil is the humans.
King Ban seeks to wipe out the humans
for the sake of the world.
But...
You must promptly embrace
the proper duties of a Dragon Knight
and offer your power to King Ban.
No! I'm on the humans' side
no matter what anybody says!
I'd rather die than serve the Dark Army
that took Master Aban's life!
I see.
Dragon Legion Commander Baran,
take this!
Aban Strash!
It has no effect?!
I'd rather not harm you,
but if this is how you feel...
I will take you with me by force!
Impossible! How can this be?!
What's going on down there?!
This is...
I sense it. A being with massive power.
What?!
Look! It's Dai!
Dai!
Are you okay?!
That crest...!
Then he's a Dragon Knight, too?!
He's part of the Dark Army!
Dragon Legion Commander Baran!
What?!
Then the Dark Army
has their own Dragon Knight, too?!
Impossible! Only one Dragon Knight
is supposed to exist!
Huh? But...
Correct.
I am the one true
Dragon Knight of this age.
But, while only one Dragon Knight
is supposed to be born,
there was an exception.
And that is you!
It's time to embrace your duties
as a Dragon Knight
and destroy the humans with me!
What?!
I'll never do that!
Don't make me repeat myself!
Things may be all right now.
During childhood, a Dragon Knight
is no different from a normal human.
But as you grow and begin to exhibit
the Power of Dragons,
the humans will begin to fear,
reject, and persecute you.
When that happens,
you will be the one to suffer.
I'm scared! He's scary!
Screw your nonsense! Dai is our friend!
No matter what he is,
we'll never persecute him!
Help you destroy the humans?!
Dai would...
Dai would rather die than do that!
Popp...
Princess, cast Behoma on Dai!
Got it!
I'll... I'll try to deal with him!
It's sad to see someone
overestimate themself.
Betan!
Behoma!
Good! That should heal Dai!
My greatest spell
that took down three Green Dragons?!
You thought a Legion Commander
who leads Dragons to be weaker than one?!
Princess, hurry!
I'm trying, but...!
Your resistance is futile!
My spell!
D-Dammit...
Dai!
I'm taking the boy.
No! You can't have Dai!
You may be the same race, but that
doesn't give you the right to take him!
I do have... the right.
What?!
This boy... is my son.
What?
What did you just say?
I said this boy is my son.
His real name is Dino.
H-He's lying!
Son? Dai is your son?
You're saying you're Dai's father?
Stop lying!
Dai told me he washed up
on Dermline Island as an infant!
Have you got any proof?!
The crest on his forehead is proof itself.
Only one person in the world aside from me
could have the Dragon Crest.
The son I lost 11 years ago, Dino.
Then, yours is the only
Dragon Knight bloodline?
No friends or brothers?
Wait! What about his mother?!
Where is the woman who gave birth to Dai?!
His mother...
Indeed the boy does bear
a resemblance to his mother.
However...
that's no concern to you humans.
Astonishing! So Baran is Dai's father?!
It's father and son Dragon Knights!
Correct. It's the tearful reunion
of a father and son in over a decade.
But don't forget that I'm the one
who set up this emotional moment.
After all, I uncovered the truth
that some coward was hiding.
Why you...!
Silence!
The great Dark King Ban
shall now grace us with his presence.
Contain yourselves.
My king!
Damn you!
Dark King Ban is here.
Well done, all of you.
Raise your heads.
Up close, the pressure from him
is as powerful as ever.
I see things are getting interesting.
Yes. There has been debate as to
whether or not Dai is a Dragon Knight.
Therefore, I went to ascertain
the truth as a neutral party.
Commander Hadorra was dead set against it.
Could he have known Dai's identity?
These dirty little...
Mystban, what do you think
of the boy's power?
I gave Flazzard the most powerful armour
in my army to test Dai's strength.
He possesses all manner
of terrifying power.
To think I could have
two Dragon Knights under my command.
Baran must be rewarded
if he succeeds in recruiting Dai.
Indeed. If he does,
he may take the seat of Dark Commander.
King Ban...!
My decision has been made.
What I was afraid of has come true!
So this is why Hadorra was desperate
to keep Dai from Baran.
However...
it seems things will not go that smoothly.
HYADARUKO
ICE-TYPE SPELL
TOMAKUGUTSOSHO
I'm taking Dino with me.
Don't touch me!
Dai!
Don't you understand? I'm far stronger
than you could ever hope to be.
I still have... my final weapon.
That's right. What Matorif said...
A hero's weapon.
The only weapon I have left
that might work on you...
is what lets me face any powerful enemy.
It's my courage!
My only hope now
is that Dai defeats Baran.
Dino...
Don't call me Dino!
My name is Dai!
It's the name my Grampa gave to me!
I fight the Dark Army! I'm Dai, the Hero!
Dai...
Don't!
He's the legendary Dragon Knight!
But he's evil!
Evil? Don't be so sure.
If the Dragon Knight wipes us out,
it would be humanity's own fault.
But...
I see. Very well.
Then I shall call you
your human name, "Dai."
Dai! I shall defeat you
as a Hero who fights with the humans!
If you will not submit to me,
you shall die!
Popp, here's a Behoma!
Thanks.
But even if I get
my stamina back, I'm useless.
Our spells don't seem to have
any effect on him at all.
Dai, I hope you have a plan!
Any small attack
and he'll kill me for sure.
I'll have to finish him
with my biggest, strongest attack.
I thought you were hiding something,
but I see it's just that.
"Aban Strash," was it?
I assume you unite the power, speed,
and Aura control, of your sword skills
to complete that attack.
It requires spirit,
technique, and strength.
For a human attack, it's formidable. But
you've already seen it won't work on me.
He analyzed Master Aban's greatest attack
with just one hit.
Then I'll have to use that attack.
Please! Power of Dragons
that lies within me!
Awaken!
If I don't defeat him,
all humanity will be wiped out!
Dai showed the crest as well!
Could it be...?
Raiden!
Raiden Strash!
He blocked it?!
Even though Dai's Strash was perfected?!
He's absorbing the energy
of the Raiden spell with his sword!
Impossible!
Impressive that you can control
the Power of Dragons this much.
Normally, a Dragon Knight cannot control
the power of the Crest until fully grown.
You've been blessed
with good teachers and good battles.
For that spirit and courage,
I shall show you...
just how terrifying it is when
a true Dragon Knight controls the heavens!
Gigaden!
Gigabreak!
Dai!
You monster! How dare you strike Dai!
I may not be able to do any damage, but...
Stop!
I shall face that man!
Beast King Crocodine!
Thank goodness! We're in deep trouble!
So this is the Beast King.
With you here it's like having an army...
Big Guy, you're shaking.
Crocodine.
Even you should be aware
of what will happen if you fight me.
I'll probably die.
But, that is something I'm prepared to do.
Big Guy...
Hurry and rescue Dai.
I'll fight with you!
Me too!
-Don't bother.
-Huh?!
I don't know why,
but he's completely immune to spells.
The only way to damage him is
with physical attacks by hand or weapon.
Well done, Beast King. So you realized it.
Get Dai.
Got it.
You heard everything?
I heard enough.
Then why stand in my way?
Why should I not reclaim my own son?
Because Dai doesn't want it.
I see. So you've completely
sided with the humans.
How disappointing. Of all the Legion
Commanders, I respected you the most.
That boy, Hyunckel, wasn't bad either.
With his hate for humans
in that heart of ice.
But, everyone I favor leaves the Dark Amy.
I guess Hadorra just lacks charisma.
That's not true.
I don't know about Hyunckel,
but I was willing to die
for Hadorra or Dark King Ban.
A true warrior
will sacrifice himself for his master.
All that's changed is that
I now support Dai.
And so you would fight me? To protect Dai?
Without Dai, both Hyunckel and I
would have wandered the dark path forever.
He's the sun that brought light
to our hearts of darkness!
The sun?
All living things need the sun!
None can be allowed to take it away!
I may not be strong enough,
but I will still fight!
To move the heart
of one such as Crocodine this much...
What a child.
The sun...
A child of the sun.
Soara...
Why sheath your sword?!
Crocodine,
I see there's no changing your mind.
But if you fight me,
you will learn the terror
of fighting a true Dragon Knight.
The completed Power of Dragons
far beyond that of Dai's!
What is this?! His Aura is staggering,
but he's just standing there!
What's wrong? Won't you fight?
If you won't fight,
I'll just have to claim your head!
I-Impossible!
My axe is the one that shattered!
What's this?!
This is the secret
to the Dragon Knights' supremacy.
The Draconic Aura!
Big Guy!
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Kindness is the magic of kind people
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
doudarou
I'm not sure
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Even if the place I call home may change
naa kaasan boku wa
Listen to me, Mother
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I will never change those I protect
anata wa nannte iukana
I wonder what you'd say
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
At times I can be cowardly and small
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
Baran is Dai's father.
Dai pushes aside his doubts and fights,
but cannot defeat Baran's Gigabreak.
Crocodine joins in,
but fails to even scratch Baran.
Therein lies the secret
to the Dragon Knights' supremacy.
As Dai still stands up to face him,
Baran's Crest shines eerily.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Terrifying Draconic Aura"
The adventure continues!