Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE HADORRA ROYAL GUARD
That was pretty rough.
Hey, you're the first honorable member
of the Beast King Commandos!
You're a Pterrodactyl...
But that's too long,
so I'll call you "Papi!"
Yup, yup.
Hm?
Uh...
You look like you want to join.
Then you'll have to
idolize me as your leader!
Got it?
Is that a fire?
No, our objective is to the north!
My name is Nova.
They call me the Hero of the North.
What?!
The Hero of the North?
I'll go rescue Sababa with my Rura spell.
I don't need the help of
a bunch of amateurs.
What?! Do you know who we are?!
The self-proclaimed "Heroes"
from Papunica, right?
W-Why you...!
That's enough, Nova!
What is it, Dad?
Dad?!
Please excuse him.
Nova is my son,
and Captain of the Knights of Ringaia.
Nova, you disrespect the Hero
and his friends!
What's wrong with stating the truth?
Besides, I can't stand everybody
calling themselves Heroes.
There's only one true Hero
that the world needs to respect!
You bastard! That's our line!
Wait, Popp!
Don't stop me, Dai!
This isn't the time for that!
Will you take us to Sababa with you?
It's better if we all fight together!
I see. You must be Dai.
Yeah.
Huh?!
That's... an Aura Shot!
And he's pretty adept at it!
No thanks. I'll be going alone.
I'd heard the rumors...
but knowing I was being compared
to a shrimp like you irritates me.
I'll protect everyone.
Rura!
Wait, Nova!
Get back here!
That snotty little...!
What a hopelessly selfish Hero.
Please forgive me.
I tried to raise him strictly,
but recently, he won't even listen to me.
Talk about overconfident!
Our Ringaia Army was dispatched to Orzam
to help them from being wiped out.
During that time, the Dark Army
destroyed our homeland.
He still believes he could have
saved Ringaia had he been here.
Baran was the one who destroyed Ringaia.
Even if that boy had been there...
Guys like that don't learn
until they get hurt!
But it's too dangerous
for him to go alone!
He already went off alone!
It's true he's arrogant
and quite self-centered...
but rescuing the port is more important!
Let's go! Leona's right!
Didn't he make you mad?
Who cares who's a Hero and who's not?
Huh?!
It's better to have more strong allies.
It doesn't matter if there happen to be
two, three, or even a hundred Heroes!
It looks like Dai wins this argument!
Honestly, the way your mind works
never ceases to amaze with its simplicity!
Let's go!
Okay!
Dai and I will go ahead
using Toberura spells!
Everybody follow after!
Got it!
Wait, Popp!
I have clothes for you
made from the same material as Dai's.
Thanks, but we're in a hurry, Princess.
Plus, am I supposed to strip here?
It's a type of outerwear,
so just wear it over your clothes!
Huh.
Dai.
I'm sorry. Please look after my son.
Okay!
Oh? Another punching bag to play with?
When will the real Hero
and his friends come?
I guess you need your eyes checked!
What?
The real one is right here.
The real one?
Sir Nova!
Please run!
Th-That's right! Wait until Dai gets here!
Your friend's right.
If you're going to fight, shouldn't you
wait until Dai, the Hero arrives?
Well?
This stuff is amazing!
It's so thin yet still
as tough as Dai's clothes!
Hey! Wait up!
I just learned how to use Toberura
without my crest!
If you insist.
Oh well.
Recently, your power's been increasing
like you're some kind of beast.
It feels nice to still be
better than you at something.
Beast is a bit much.
Don't make me repeat myself!
I, Nova, am the true Hero! Not Dai!
All everybody talks about is Dai...
What's so great about him?!
Stay back, everybody.
Overconfident fools like him...
need a little lesson from me.
I guess you haven't heard
that we're made of Orichalcum.
I see.
Unfortunately, breaking my sword
doesn't hinder my killer attack at all!
What?!
That's...
Hmm.
Aura Blade!
No matter how tough Orichalcum is,
it will break against a greater force!
My sword of Aura is much sharper
than even a legendary weapon!
There they are!
Nova's still alright!
They're finally here.
Nova!
Shut up and back off!
But...!
His Aura is amazing!
He just might...
I said to stay back.
Come on.
Die, you piece of scrap!
Northern...
Grand...
Blade!
Hey! He actually did it!
No...
That actually hurt!
I guess for a human, this would be like
banging your head on a corner!
Not bad.
For a preliminary fight...
that was fun.
HYADARUKO
ICE-TYPE SPELL
ULTRA COMBUSTION SLASH
No...
Impossible! He's not hurt?!
That should have damaged him,
no matter how tough he is!
It's very simple.
Even when you humans
focus with your frail bodies,
you can increase your defensive power.
I merely did the same thing.
I already knew you would aim for my head.
If I just focus all my power here,
I can withstand an attack like that.
They're strong!
They're unlike any enemy
we've faced before!
One thing is clear.
They're not strong only because
they're made of Orichalcum!
They're true pieces of battle!
They're born to fight. All they know
is combat... They're weapons of war.
They're all born geniuses of battle!
Damn it!
Wait, Nova!
Don't touch me!
I'm stronger than this!
My next attack...!
Knock it off!
You're strong enough to know
how dangerous they are!
He's right.
Work with us!
No!
What?!
As the Hero of the North...
I shall defeat them with my own power!
Look around you!
They all need help!
Isn't protecting friends
what a Hero is supposed to do?!
Defeating the enemy
will protect them sooner!
That's not being a Hero!
Shut up!
Nova!
I won't...
I won't let you lecture me
about being a Hero!
Needle...
Thousand.
Nova!
Needle Thousand.
You used it on an enemy that weak?
It would be an insult
to have our guest of honor wait.
Allow me a belated introduction.
We are Dark Commander Hadorra's
loyal servants.
The Hadorra Royal Guard.
I am the queen and leader, Albinass.
I'm the pawn, Hym.
You remember me, don't you?
I am the knight who races across
the battlefield, Sigma.
Remember me.
My name is Fenbren.
I am the Bishop of the Royal Guard,
and the perfect hunter.
What's that?!
And there's one more.
The ship...
is on land?!
He is the rook, Block.
He does not speak,
so I shall introduce him.
Block, that ship is important to them!
Give it back!
You mean...?!
Everybody run!
The cannons' gunpowder must have ignited.
Darn it!
Dai, this could actually be our chance!
While this smoke is hiding us,
I'll use my Extreme Spell to finish this!
Extreme Spell?!
Yeah!
An ambush for an ambush!
Before they can reveal their power,
I'll annihilate them all with my Medoroa!
Popp, what is that?!
I'm going to fabricate Magic Power that'll
annihilate our enemies in an instant!
This thing packs a punch!
Sweet! My clothes don't burn!
An arrow of light?! That's amazing!
I'll explain it later!
After I blow them away!
They're not coming out. Are they dead?
Unlikely. That was hardly
enough to kill them.
I guess I'll drag them out.
Sorry. I still haven't memorized
your names and faces.
I'll end it with this!
Take this!
Not yet!
Nova?!
Not yet! I haven't been beaten yet!
Don't! Normal spells won't work on them!
Magic may not work,
but they should be momentarily frozen!
If I attack in that moment...!
Mahiado!
Now!
Popp!
That was an impressive spell.
Darn it!
Oh no! One of them can reflect spells!
Indeed.
This Mirror of Shahal is the ultimate item
that can reflect any spell that hits it.
And at the same time...
it is the ultimate shield.
This is bad!
Listen up, Popp.
There's one thing I have to warn you
about using Medoroa.
Watch out for counters.
Counters?
The spell Mahokanta can reflect a spell
back at its caster.
There are also legendary weapons
that have the same ability.
If the enemy has one, it's game over.
You'll be the ones wiped out.
It's why I was too scared to use it
back in the day.
I'm fine dying from my own mistake,
but I couldn't stand it
if it took out my friends too.
I get it. Being too powerful
is this spell's greatest weakness.
Now I can't use Medoroa against them...
But it's a silver lining.
If Nova hadn't interrupted me,
we'd be annihilated.
Wait! Where's Nova?!
Nova!
When did you grab him?!
Darn it!
Dai...
It looks like...
you were right... after all.
I guess I'm not...
a real... Hero.
No Hero would be... this pathetic.
Damn it...
Damn it!
Nova!
I guess this was a good lesson.
Your whole body is frozen.
One punch and I can shatter you...
like powdered snow.
Don't!
You cruel bastard!
You're wrong!
I know how he feels all too well!
There are those of us
who would rather die beautifully,
than to live in disgrace.
Right?
Darn it!
Here's a lesson to take with you.
In this world,
there's always someone stronger.
Well... goodbye!
Nova!
At least die gloriously, you loser!
No!
You talk too much.
But you were right about one thing.
There's always someone stronger!
Hyunckel!
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Nova could do nothing against Hym.
Maam, Hyunckel, and Crocodine
arrive just in time.
The Orichalcum warriors' solidarity,
born from their loyalty to Hadorra,
or Dai and his friends' teamwork,
honed by countless battles.
Which will come out on top?
The fierce battle begins!
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Team Battle Begins"
The adventure continues!