With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
THE CAVE OF TRIALS
The Cave of Trials was created by
the God of Humans.
It's a place that contains
all magic that counters evil power.
Queen Flora built this fort believing
we would eventually need to use the Cave.
Why are there monsters
in a cave of a God?
According to this Ancient Tome
King Teran sent us...
the gods did not approve of people
having more power than they deserved.
How far is unknown,
but the labyrinth extends underground.
Deeper levels hold spells
of greater power.
But the paths become
more complex with more traps...
and even more powerful monsters
await down there.
It's not a place for the inexperienced.
But we need to brave it
to obtain Minakator.
Huh. Who knew Carl Kingdom
had such a place.
Ah. So this is Minakator.
"By casting in a group,
Minakator increases in power.
Use Kiseiseki and stand in
a pentagon arrangement
to achieve maximum spell effect."
I guess that's why you need
five Disciples of Aban.
Even so, I'm against this.
Leona's not a warrior.
She's just a normal girl.
And she's Papunica's princess.
She doesn't need to take such a risk.
She could let someone else...
Dai! That's insulting to the Princess!
Women can risk their lives
to fight for what they believe in, too!
Miss Amy...
Dai doesn't want
Leona involved in this fight.
Huh?
If Leona becomes a Disciple of Aban...
that means she'll have to face
that terrifying Dark King Ban.
Yeah. That's a little overwhelming.
We'd rather not face him again
if we had the choice.
I see.
I'm sorry, Dai.
But try to understand that
the Princess wants to be with you all.
Speaking of which...
there's already a girl
who's fighting the Dark King, Dai!
He means you're the exception.
L-Leona!
S-Such thin fabric!
This is a Robe of Carl.
It has the benefit of repelling Malice.
We will need a couple of guards.
P-Please wait!
Please take me with you!
My clairvoyance will help
to navigate the labyrinth!
I want to help you all!
Please!
Very well. That makes one.
Thank you!
We need one more.
I'll--
Right here! I, Popp, will protect you!
Popp...
It will be a terrifying, massive cave!
It would be dangerous with just women.
That look on your face
is much more dangerous!
I'll go for protection.
Sound good. We've never
fought together before either.
Then that makes our party.
You will need to
change into the Robes as well.
Oh man!
I'll be going, Dai.
Leona...
Hey! You don't trust me!
I can do what I set my mind to!
Haven't I always...
since we met?
Huh? What?
I was just remembering when we met.
Oh come on!
Dai?!
I'm off to train while you're away!
I'll protect you against the Dark King!
Okay! Let's all check our weapons
and equipment!
Yeah!
-Nova.
-Yes?
I have a favor to ask.
Maam, aren't you
a little too strict on Popp?
Popp?
He doesn't understand the danger we're in.
The world could end!
Minakator will be most effective
when the five of you form a pentagon.
I'm sure it will be strong enough
to stop Ban Palace.
But why does it have to be
five Disciples of Aban?
All I can use are healing-type spells.
Maam, hold your Insignia of Aban.
Think of the people
you're worried about the most.
Huh?
Hyunckel...
Crocodine...
Oh!
Th-The Insignia is glowing red!
That is the color of
the power of your soul.
The power of my soul?
The Great Purification Spell
requires more than Magic Power.
It requires the will of people
who seek to defeat evil.
Kiseiseki can sense that will
and amplify it.
That glow is proof of that.
Maam, your power is
your loving heart.
My loving heart?
Your ability to care for others
and empathize with them.
That is the source of
all of your strength.
Aban valued such qualities
over strength and skill.
And he granted people with souls worthy of
saving the world with his Insignia.
That's why Dai, Popp, and Hyunckel
should also have unique qualities
that will make their Kiseiseki glow.
Unique colors of their souls.
As do you, Leona.
That's why the Great Purification Spell
must be cast by you five.
Huh. Unique colors of our souls.
What color will mine glow?
It... It won't glow!
That's not possible!
Maam made hers glow
without knowing anything about it!
You're kidding!
My Insignia should glow at least a little!
Glow! Even just a faint glimmer!
Who's there?!
What's wrong, Maam?
I sensed somebody here.
I thought maybe Popp was snooping on us.
That's not possible!
There must be some way to make it glow!
If it doesn't glow, that means I'll
drag everyone down at the crucial moment!
No way! I was properly chosen
as a Disciple by Master Aban, too!
Properly...
Someday I know you will understand.
So, hold onto this
for when that day comes.
Could it be...?!
Is it because Dai and I got our Insignias
before completing our training?!
We weren't properly accepted
like Maam and Hyunckel were.
Could it be that I'm...
unworthy of being a Disciple of Aban?!
N-No way! No way!
That's not possible!
I've risked my life fighting
to come this far!
I'll find a way to make this thing glow!
It'll glow!
I can make it glow too,
right Master Aban?!
This Ancient Tome was left by a Sage
who braved the Cave of Trials long ago.
It includes a map.
How far down is the Minakator spell?
25 floors underground.
The Mahokator spell Aban obtained
is 15 floors underground.
So we're going deeper
than Master Aban did.
We have 30 hours until the execution.
We'll need ten hours to prepare
and get to Hyunckel and Crocodine.
That leaves 20 hours to search.
Mera.
This candle will last for ten hours.
Once it goes out,
we should head back to the surface.
I can cast
the Dungeon Escape Spell, Riremito...
but it won't work in this cave.
Unless the cave's Malice is
somehow repelled, we can't use Riremito.
So we have to assume returning
will take ten hours.
If we can't go down 25 floors in
ten hours, we give up on Minakator?
Yes.
We'll return to the surface and focus on
rescuing Hyunckel and Crocodine.
But...
we have a map and Meruru's abilities.
So long as we watch out for monsters,
we should make good time.
Come, let us go.
How creepy.
And it gets a lot deeper with each floor.
I sense numerous
sources of Malice from below. Be careful.
Wait, Maam!
But this thing flaps around
and gets in the way.
Even so...
Forget it Meruru.
That's the kind of person she is.
That sort of thing has a bad influence
on Popp and gives him a dirty mind!
Really? Popp's had a dirty mind
since I met him.
And this group has its own issues.
We're not on a picnic.
We're entering
the first level of the labyrinth.
Slimes!
The basics.
REFRACTOR FIST
BEHOMA
HEAL-TYPE SPELL
They're weak,
but fighting them all will take time!
We should avoid wasting any time.
Let's go.
What spell can be learned on
the first level?
It says Safe Passage.
We can skip that. I can already use it.
We skip all of them.
All we want is Minakator, 25 floors down.
So Nova's helping him train.
Dai's Insignia was
a provisional one like mine.
So how about him?
You seem much better!
I see you've gotten over it, Dai!
I don't have time to mope around!
We're fighting Ban, the Dark King!
I need to gain any skill I can use,
no matter how minor!
And I'll defeat Ban!
Here goes!
Oh crap!
I'm the only one!
I'm the only one who can't do it!
I have to do something quick!
There's no time!
From here, we'll base your training
on the Book of Aban.
I'll push myself! I'll do it! I'll do it!
The Ancient Tome says the deeper we go,
the stronger the monsters get.
I don't sense any more monsters
on this level.
Let's find the stairs down.
Oh!
What's wrong?!
A vase! I found a vase!
Let's see what's inside!
Come on. Let's find the stairs.
Huh?! Huh?!
You're ignoring a vase in the cave?
Aban Strash!
Yes! I can do it! I can use them both!
That was the projectile type, right?
Yeah.
According to the Book of Aban,
there are two types of Aban Strash.
The Arrow Type, where you cut
a distant enemy by slashing Aura at them.
And the Break Type, where you slash
an enemy directly with all of your Aura.
Arrow and Break...
"Each type has its
advantages and disadvantages.
The Arrow Type can be used quickly,
but has a weaker impact.
The Break Type is powerful
and has speed,
but takes time to unleash each shot.
Using each type of Strash in battle
depending on the situation
requires skill and quick judgement,"
so it says.
I see. I've been fighting without
thinking about that at all.
Had I known that,
I could have fought much better.
It's kind of embarrassing.
Don't be embarrassed.
Look.
What?
I can use Aura Blade.
It's not an Aban Strash, but I can
launch my Aura in an attack, too.
See that?
As adept as I am at Aura Blade,
I still struggle to hit my target
and time my attack so it detonates
at the moment of impact.
Even Sir Aban probably didn't
expect you to master Aban Strash so soon.
That's why he didn't lecture you on
the different types of Strash.
I guess so.
But if I knew how to read...
I could have learned that when Matorif
gave us the Book of Aban.
That's definitely your fault.
But that's why I brought the Book of Aban
to help with your training.
Don't waste your time, Dai.
Thank you, Nova.
Save your thanks for Princess Leona.
She's the one who asked me to help.
You can tell her if she makes it back.
It's fine. I know she'll come back.
You believe in her.
Leona always does what she sets out to do.
She always has.
Come on, Leona! I told you
not to open the treasure chests!
I couldn't help it.
It seems like a waste to
find one and ignore it.
Leona, I bet you buy mountains of stuff
whenever you go shopping, don't you?
Um, but, considering where we are,
I thought we might find a weapon
that could save the world or something.
What have we found so far?
Two Cypress Sticks and 216 gold.
We definitely can't
save the world with these.
Fine! I get it already!
Onward it is, right? Onward!
But it's been almost ten hours.
We're still only 18 floors down.
We should start thinking about
heading back.
I didn't think each floor
would take this long.
Oh! Princess Leona!
Wait!
What? What did I do now?
No! I mean... It's not that.
Then what is it?
Go on, Meruru. Speak up.
It's a premonition... or just a feeling.
Whatever! Just say it!
This floor...
Staying here too long...
feels dangerous.
Huh?!
Head back to the stairs!
-Meruru!
-Yes?!
Next time, let us know right away!
Okay!
To be honest I was clumsy
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
And it took me forever to get here
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
I used even loneliness as a weapon
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
I just want to be there for you
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
Is harder than any magic spell
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Even though you're so close to me
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
I love you
aishiteiru
I finally realized it
imasara kizuitanosa
To call out your name
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
Must be the reason I was born
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
I shake off the clinging night
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
And go to see you
ai ni iku
Right now to where you are
ima sugu kimi no moto e
Dai discovers a potential new attack
during his training with Nova.
Popp becomes more desperate,
being the only hero
whose Insignia of Aban won't glow.
Leona and the others reach the 25th level
where Minakator can be found.
Just what awaits them there?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Sacred Inheritance"
The adventure continues!