With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
VEARN, THE DARK KING
Begirama!
What's that?!
Queen Flora, what was that?
It's stopped.
Huh?
Princess Leona's Minakator spell
was holding it in check,
but the low rumbling
from Ban Palace never stopped.
But now, it's completely stopped.
Then that means...!
Dai and the others must have destroyed
a central part of Ban Palace.
Hooray!
They did it!
-Whoa!
-Yes!
That's the Hero's party!
We're not through yet.
That doesn't mean
the Dark King was defeated.
But Ban Palace
has been left nonfunctional.
Our lands will no longer be attacked
by the Dark Army.
Seeing as it isn't falling...
Ban Palace itself must be made of
material that floats.
It would seem so.
No.
Rather than falling...
it looks like it's rising.
Very slowly.
Little by little.
Dai...
Those Crests on your hands...
That's right, Leona.
He's alive!
Dad is still alive!
Here, in my left hand!
It wasn't just Master or Larhart
who helped me from beyond death!
Dad was...
Dad was right here!
Your father becoming a Crest and living on
inside you sounds too good to be true.
But I can believe it.
I mean, you seem so happy, Dai!
-He's that...!
-Goroa?!
He said he was Goroa, the Drumbler.
Oh, he tripped.
I think that drum monster
is what a Drumbler really is.
He said that Ban gave him power.
But can Ban really transform
such a small monster like that?
It wouldn't surprise me if he could.
His Magic Power is unfathomable.
Let's go! To the top of
the Tower of Supremacy!
But the stairs and everything
were blown away.
There's nothing here.
Look higher.
Merazoma!
Take this!
The back of his head!
This guy's unbelievably tough!
He fought Ron Berku, then me and Maam...
He's been fighting all day!
And yet he doesn't seem tired at all.
You're probably right.
I've hit him
with several mortal blows already.
Yet look.
It's my weapon that's damaged.
I can only assume he's taken no damage.
Exactly.
You can't be hit by attacks,
and I can't be damaged by them.
The fight seems balanced,
but the results are obvious.
He's right. If we fight for too long...
...we'll get exhausted,
allowing Mystban to strike us and win.
We have to uncover the secret
to his invulnerability.
Not even my attacks
can kill him like this.
What now?
This is the dome that was
on top of the Tower of Supremacy.
It looks like the castle above it
was blown away by your Doru Aura.
Doru Aura...
It truly is a powerful spell.
Do you think that
maybe it took out Ban, too?
No. He might have taken
some damage from it.
But he's much stronger than that.
Of course.
Get back, Leona!
-Ban!
-That's him?!
Congratulations in blowing away my castle.
There's no need to hold back any longer
if you're capable of doing that.
I shall erase you here.
This is Ban, the Dark King?!
He's coming!
Ban's always been relaxed,
but now I sense open malice!
Ban's coming at us at full strength!
I can't believe it.
Simply unleashing his Magic Power
creates this much force?!
This is Ban at full power!
When he defeated me last time,
he was barely even trying!
Do I stand a chance against him?
I may have powered up with two Crests,
but my current strength...
Dai.
Let me guess what you're thinking.
"Can I really match him
with my two Crests?"
Twin Dragon Crests.
That is what I call them.
Twin Dragon Crests?
When a Dragon Knight's life ends,
their Crest is passed on to the new life
that resides inside the Mother Dragon.
The danger posed by a Dragon Knight
is largely due to the Combat Instincts
contained within the Crest.
The Dragon Crest contains
the collective skill of Dragon Knights
accumulated over centuries.
And that is passed on to the next Knight.
In other words,
Dragon Knights are born with
the battle skills of past Knights.
They're combat geniuses.
You are the son of Baran, a Dragon Knight.
You have your own Crest.
You have your own strength,
but you did not inherit the skills.
But now...
Baran's Crest
has been passed down properly.
It has given you super combat abilities,
completing the Twin Dragon Crests.
With your innate strength,
and the combat experience of past
Dragon Knights, a Super Knight was born.
In other words, Dai...
you are that Super Knight.
I can no longer predict your power.
You may surpass even the Dragonoid.
I, Dark King Ban,
believe I have nothing to fear
in the Trio of Worlds.
But the unpredictable
cannot be underestimated.
Immediate annihilation!
That is my decision!
GIGA STRASH
KAISER PHOENIX
Immediate annihilation!
That is my decision!
-Leona, stay back for now!
-But...
Heed his warnings, Princess of Papunica.
To approach means death!
After all, nothing can be done
against this strike!
What's wrong?
Aren't you going to fight back?
He's fast! And the impact's
way stronger than before!
But...
Dai! What's wrong?! Fight back!
I see. He must not be able to make
his first strike yet!
Ban once broke his sword.
And his Doru Aura didn't affect him at all.
Dai's freezing up
and can't get a handle on how to fight.
H-How do I fight?
With my sword? Or with spells?
Has fear taken you?
Disappointing, but convenient for me.
Now you die!
-How do I fight?!
-Dai!
You don't need to overthink it!
Just punch him!
I hit him!
He fell! The Dark King Ban fell!
I managed to get in the first hit!
That's right!
Overthinking will just hold me back!
I could never beat him
by fighting normally!
My only option's been to hit him
with my all and find an opening!
Leona was trying to tell me that!
Leona! Thanks for the great advice!
But it's a little improper for a princess
to tell someone to punch somebody!
Oh come on!
I was trying to help you loosen up!
I believed I had him... but I didn't.
Dai's movements...
His unpredictable movements...
I was right.
He's inherited the years of
Combat Instincts from the Dragon Knights!
Dai!
I know! Just attack!
I'll hit him with everything!
All of my best attacks!
Come on, my sword!
Let's start with Earth Slash!
Little whelp! You underestimate me!
It won't break?!
It's working!
Earth Slash!
That's amazing, Dai!
You're evenly matched with the Dark King!
It's working! I can fight!
My Dragonic Aura, power, and speed...
They're all far beyond
what they were with one Crest!
I feel like my body isn't my own!
I knew he was this powerful.
Ever since he unleashed his Doru Aura.
It's likely that Dragon Knights
can only cast Doru Aura in Dragonoid form
because their normal forms can't
withstand the power.
That's why they have to transform
into the Dragonoid form to use the spell.
It's like a built-in safety function.
But he used it just as he is.
Dai's power is equal to
that of the Dragonoid, or even stronger.
What I'm interested in
isn't that power on the surface!
This attack will reveal
what I want to know!
That stance!
Calamity Wall!
Unlike before, this is
my Calamity Wall at full strength!
It's fast! I can't dodge it!
Now what?!
This is Aura!
It's something similar to Aura!
It's blasting upwards
while approaching at high speed!
He passed through it!
Through the force of the Calamity Wall!
These shocks...
King Ban has engaged with Dai.
I suppose I should finish this.
Maam, heal Larhart before he tires out!
I hate to admit it, but he's the only one
who can match Mystban!
I'll buy time!
-Popp!
-Don't!
You don't seem to learn.
You're not strong enough to stop me!
Popp!
I think this is the second time
I've protected you like this.
-You?!
-He's a friend.
He overcame death and was reborn
as our new friend.
Hyunckel! You're all right!
Thank goodness!
I'm sorry.
It's okay. Don't worry.
You moron!
What... What do you mean, "Don't worry"?!
I was... I mean
we were worried sick about you!
If you go off on your own again,
I swear I'll kick your butt!
Forgive me, Popp.
But I doubt I'll need to do that again.
Backup is here
and our enemies are limited in number.
Even if he withstood it
with his Dragonic Aura...
he would have taken heavy damage
from the shockwave.
But...
by shielding himself with a Dragonic Aura
similar in nature to my Calamity Wall,
he passed through
without being affected by the shockwave.
Not only Dai himself,
but none of his friends have ever
shown such skill and inventiveness.
I'm sure of it.
The Combat Instincts passed down
among Dragon Knights
since the time of the gods
have begun to take root within him!
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Dai thwarts Ban's Calamitous Wall
and fights with skills
that rival or even surpass the Dark King.
Meanwhile, Aban and Kilban's duel
grows ever more intense.
Aban grows angry at Kilban's cruelty,
while Kilban remains eerily calm.
Eventually, their duel
reaches its conclusion.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Kilban's Trap"
The adventure continues!