With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
BARAN'S LAST WILL
Ah, Hyunckel!
Looks like you're awake!
Hym... Everyone...
What happened...?
You scared us
when you became unresponsive.
If this weirdo hadn't come,
you might have never woken up.
Mr. Beast kept casting
Hoimi-type spells on you!
I see.
So I managed to survive again.
This guy helped me out, too.
It felt weird to have my body
get fixed by a Heal-type spell.
But I'm back in action!
You now have the body
of a living organism.
Basically, similar to a Metal Slime
or a Metal King Slime.
That's why a Hoimi spell works.
So I'm like those creatures?
You, however, will never fully recover.
What?!
Due to the heavy damage
from repeated battles,
your bones have suffered
irreparable damage.
You can probably walk upright,
but you'll never fight again.
I thought as much.
You're dressed funny,
but you're no ordinary stranger.
No, no. I'm just a member
of the Beast King Commandos.
But it doesn't matter.
I've gained something wonderful in return.
A new friend.
That's right. His wounds
were all because of me!
Crocodine.
Hm?
I know I'll just be a burden...
but could you take me inside that castle
where Dai and the others are fighting?
What?!
You should return to Queen Flora!
I gave everything for this battle.
I have to see it through.
When Dai's blade strikes down Ban...
I want to see it.
Very well then. I'll lend you my shoulder.
Even if I refuse,
you'll crawl there yourself, won't you?
Let's go together.
If need be, I'll be a shield
to protect you!
Hym?
You can use my shoulder.
Until the day you're fully healed
and we can settle things again,
I can't have you going and dying on me.
For now, I'll take care of
all the enemies you were supposed to.
I see. So Hym is his new friend.
Well said!
You were an enemy once,
but you're a monster with noble spirit!
I like you!
You can join my Beast King Commandos!
What?! What is this shrimp babbling about?
I'm not a shrimp! Call me "Captain!"
You better listen to what he says.
He's someone we've all learned to respect.
Seriously?
Pretty much.
Let's see... I don't have a badge, so...
this will have to do.
What is this?! It won't come off!
Of course. It's a Magic Brush.
You bastard...!
Not "you bastard!" Say "Captain!"
I never became
your follower, you bastard...!
Not "you bastard"! Say "Captain"!
Has he reached the others yet?
He should be the greatest help
that they could hope for.
Land Rider Larhart.
So this is... Larhart.
You bear a resemblance to your father.
How did you come back from the dead?!
More importantly, why are you wearing
the Dark Armour Spear?!
This was originally mine.
Why should it matter if I use it?
That's not what I meant! Hyunckel...!
I'm asking what happened to him!!
He carried out his duty and used
all of his strength before falling.
Then...!
Don't worry. That man is immortal.
Oh come on! You scared us!
So you took on that armour
to fight in Hyunckel's place?
Why... Why are you fighting for us?
No. Not for all of you.
I, Larhart, fight for only you.
To pledge my undying allegiance to you,
the successor of the Dragon Knight,
I have come before you...
Master Dino.
What?! To me?!
Yes, sir!
So you want to be our ally?
Not your ally. Your follower.
Follower?!
Tell me to die, and I shall do so gladly.
Tell me to fight, and I will face
even the gods.
You may use me as you see fit
to make the world you desire.
What now? He's my follower.
Hmm...
Mystban!
Oh?
You survived a hit from my Hakendisutoru.
Not bad Mystban,
the heavyweight of the Dark Army.
Why you...!
Come, Master Dino.
Feel free to give me your first command.
Tell me to defeat him.
You shall pay!
A disgraced survivor of the Dragon Masters
would betray us and bare his fangs
against me? What a joke!
I'll tear you to shreds!
Just to be clear, the Dragon Masters
were never part of the Dark Army.
We were direct servants
of the Dragon Knight.
The three Dragon Masters
of the land, sea, and sky!
We never once fought for the Dark Army!
We fought for Master Baran
and Master Baran alone!
To say we betrayed you is the true joke!
Go, Master Dino. Quickly!
But Mystban is powerful!
I should fight, too!
Huh? Hey!
Larhart!
You idiot! You're unarmed!
What's this?
This "tear you to shreds" talk,
how do you intend to do it?
You fool!
Like this!
Look out!
Huh?!
What?!
Satisfied?
Why worry about someone who can't be hit?
B-But...
What just happened there?
An afterimage.
Huh?
What we saw being pierced
was the shadow Larhart left
after moving at high speed.
In other words, an afterimage.
Even so, he's still
not even using his full strength.
He's a monster.
How the hell did Hyunckel ever beat him?!
He's strong.
He could even be
on the level of Ron Berku.
HAKENDISUTORU
GIGA STRASH
Master Dino.
Your mission should be to defeat
King Ban for the surface world humans.
You must head straight
toward that goal without wavering.
I am willing to give my life for that.
That was the wish your father,
Master Baran, left in his last will.
Dad's will?!
When I was resurrected from death
by Master Baran's Dragon Blood...
there was a letter
that had been left inside my coffin.
It was Master Baran's last will,
which he left to me.
"I've given all of you Dragon Blood,
but I doubt the others will make it."
"The chances are slim,
but if you should somehow be resurrected,
I would like you to help Dino
as though you were helping me."
"By that time, I believe
either the Dark King or Dino himself
will have struck me down
and I shall be no more."
Master Baran was already prepared
to sacrifice himself for you.
Dad...
Larhart.
I raised you from a young age.
I know that you feel
strong hatred for the humans.
And yet, knowing that, I still ask you...
Should Dino say
he wishes to protect the humans,
would you please accept and obey him?
I believe that child has the power
to change humanity itself.
This is my final request,
but the decision is yours.
To my other son, Larhart.
He was... like a father to me.
Thank you.
Larhart, you loved my father, too. Deeply.
Master Dino...
All right then. I'll give you an order.
Help Popp and Maam and defeat Mystban!
-Yes, sir!
-And...
I have another request.
Please... don't call me Dino anymore.
Hearing that name is painful.
It makes me remember Dad.
I understand, Master Dai, the Hero!
Let's go, Leona, Gomechan!
Right!
Popp! Maam!
This time, I'm really
leaving things to you!
I'm going to defeat Ban!
Yeah! That's the spirit!
We won't mess up again!
Relax and go on ahead!
I certainly hope so.
I'll give the orders!
You two, don't get in my way!
Oh no! Not another one
of these personalities!
But he's a promising rescuer!
This might just work out!
I may actually
have to consider the possibility...
of fighting at full strength.
My true enemy lies ahead!
And to reach him, everyone...
They've all been wounded...
putting everything on the line...
so that they could leave me with my power!
All of it!
And now I'm going to hit
Dark King Ban with it!
No matter how powerful an enemy he is!
There it is!
So this is... the Tower of Supremacy!
That's right.
Hurry on up, Dai.
I've just run out of wine.
That voice! It's Dark King...
...Ban!
I won't say anything haughty like,
"Well done coming this far."
Your growth and your numerous rescuers...
all of it surpassed my expectations.
Both Mystban and Kilban
are being held off
by your friends at the moment.
I have been left with no one.
Dai.
I welcome you as
an unprecedented challenger.
Climb the stairs of the Tower
of Supremacy and come before me.
I will give you a fitting welcome.
Those are the stairs.
Leona, Gomechan, be careful from here.
Oh? So you're not alone, Dai.
That woman... She's the princess
of Papunica Kingdom.
Well, you can come with whoever you want.
But it seems that Dragon Knights have
a habit of bringing misfortune to women.
Not that it matters, I suppose.
Dai!
What are you waiting for, Dai?
Leona, take this knife back.
Huh?!
This knife you gave me, it's the last one
of the Papunica royal family, isn't it?
That's why I wanted...
What's wrong with you
all of a sudden, Dai?!
Don't listen to what Ban says!
He's just toying with you
before the battle!
I know he is.
Then why...?
I'm not doing this
because I'm saying goodbye.
Just the opposite.
The opposite?
Right now, aside from Master's Feathers,
you're basically unarmed.
I'll be using my Dragonic Aura at
full strength, so I can't use this knife.
So, if you carry it,
at least you'll have a weapon, right?
So you're saying
I should look after myself?
This is Ban we're fighting.
There's no guarantee I can win alone
or even protect you.
That's why...
I want you to fight with me!
If you're going to face danger,
do it with me!
-Sorry. That's asking too much.
-That's not it!
That's not it.
I'm glad.
This is kind of like
the first time we met.
Back then, I attached the knife to you.
And wasn't it the three of us
back on Dermline Island?
Me and you and Gomechan!
You struggled against one Scorpion,
yet now you're fighting the Dark King.
Yeah.
My heart was seriously pounding back then.
We were just going to a cave on my island,
but it felt like my chest would explode.
How about now? Is your heart pounding?
I'm not sure.
My heart's pounding...
but it's different from back then.
My heart isn't dancing.
It's more like it feels tight.
It's not like it was back then.
Dai isn't just an adventurous
young boy anymore.
He's still tiny, but he's a Hero
carrying the hopes of all humans.
He must be feeling
tremendous pressure on his shoulders.
I have to help him.
No. Even if I can't help,
I have to ease his burden any way I can.
So that someday Dai can travel the world
with a light heart once again!
Leona!
Dai!
Hm?
This is an unexpected turn of events.
I never expected it to act on its own.
But, if they were attacked, then they...
What was that?! What just grabbed Leona?!
Was that Ban's doing?!
This is...!
Dai!
Help me, Dai!
Leona!
What is that?!
Is it alive?!
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Dai and Leona race up the Tower
of Supremacy to face Dark King Ban.
But Leona is suddenly attacked
by mysterious tentacles.
Dai follows after, only to reach
the heart of Ban Palace.
There he finds something
even Ban wasn't expecting.
What will happen to Dai and Leona?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Rise, Knight of Destiny"
The adventure continues!