With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
You're The bravest
You're The Bravest
THE BLACK CORE
I hope you're ready for this!
Howl, Vortex Axe!
Take this!
I shall be your opponent!
Don't think you'll beat me that easily!
So this is the power of the Dragonoid!
A truly worthy opponent indeed!
You still don't seem to understand...
Hadorra!
The Dragonoid does not stop
until its opponent is dead.
It's the ultimate battle form
of a Dragon Knight.
Now that I have taken this form,
you stand no chance
no matter how hard you try!
Curse you!
Now you can't use your sword
or Extreme Spells for a while.
He's strong... Too strong!
This Superior Being body was created
based on the Dragonoid's abilities!
It should rival or even surpass Baran!
Why?!
Why can't I do anything to him?!
He's powerful.
Even Hadorra is powerless against him.
It looks like Hadorra
disturbed the beast's nest.
Every animal lashes out
if its nest is disturbed.
They display extraordinary strength
to protect their young.
And unleash harsh punishment.
This is the same.
I suppose that settles it.
Very well.
You're going to detonate the Black Core?
Now that Hadorra cannot win,
this is only mercy.
Don't you agree?
All I do is emit my Magic Power
from this finger and the Core explodes.
When Baran comes in contact with Hadorra...
that's when everything ends.
You would still fight, Hadorra?
You're trying to use
Ultra Combustion Slash with a broken arm?
That's pure futility!
Say what you will!
Simply waiting to die on the ground
would be worse than this pain!
At the very least, I can try!
Very well.
I accept your challenge!
How disappointing it is, Baran.
To come so far yet come up short.
Your final effort
was most impressive, Hadorra.
But fear not.
As you hoped, even in death
you can still defeat Baran.
Here at this very moment.
Shatter into pieces, Black Core!
What?!
Impossible!
I emitted my Magic Power, and yet...
Why doesn't the Core explode?
You underestimated me, Dark King Ban.
Why do you think...
I accepted Hadorra's final challenge?
It was because
I was waiting for this chance!
So I could prevent the Black Core's
explosion with my Dragonic Aura!
Well done, Baran.
So he was prepared for the explosion.
What...
What is that thing?!
What was that thing doing inside of me?!
As a Darkling, you must have heard of it.
This is a Black Core!
A Black Core?!
That's...
That's impossible!
The cursed legendary explosive
was inside of me?!
Who?! Who would do such a thing?!
Who else?
It was your master.
The one who promised you
the surface world,
while ruthlessly intending
to destroy it anyway!
King Ban?!
I see now!
You and Dai were holding back
because of the Black Core!
What happened...
What happened to a fair fight?!
There was no way you could have won
under such conditions!
I sacrificed my own body...
I sacrificed my own life
to have this battle!
Hadorra...
Oh my. How pathetic, Hadorra.
It can't be helped, Kilban.
I didn't expect the power of Baran's Aura
as a Dragonoid to be this strong.
He repelled my Magic Power.
How very impressive.
But as the Core's creator,
all I need to do is approach it
and detonating it should be no problem.
Very well.
I shall go myself
and erase them along with the Core.
King Ban, if you go out there,
it'll just put us to shame.
Right, Myst?
And there he goes.
Baran, what are you doing?!
I'm removing the Core from you
before Ban makes his next move!
Mystban?!
He's here to eliminate us.
Mystban...
Do you...
Do you share King Ban's opinion?!
Are you here to discard me
like a useless tool?!
Was I...
Was I just a pawn to you, too?!
Hadorra...
I have but one answer to your question.
The Dark King's words
take precedence above all.
I see. So that's your answer.
You're already too late, Mystban.
Even with you here I can't be defeated!
Don't be so sure.
I can erase the both of you
without even a touch.
What is this powerful tremor?!
King Ban, do I have your permission?
I grant it, Mystban.
ULTRA COMBUSTION SLASH
GIGABRAKE
That's...!
Mystban's true form?!
With the flash of the Black Core, begone!
The Core has been activated?!
Impossible!
My Dragonoid Dragonic Aura
should repel any Magic Power!
It would take Ban's own
Magic Power at close proximity to...
Could it be...?!
Detonate!
It's going to explode!
Only the Magic Power of
a Black Core's creator can detonate it!
Mystban! Does this mean
your real form...?!
There's no point in asking.
In a moment, you two
will be erased from this world.
Now that you have seen this face,
you cannot be allowed to live.
What is this strange rumbling?!
I'm not sure,
but I have a bad feeling about this!
Hey! Where are you facing?!
Everybody! Gather in one place!
Something's happening
to the Field of Death!
What?!
What's wrong?! Meruru!
A white flash is swallowing everyone!
Everyone is going to vanish!
Even Popp!
No!
Calm down!
Is it connected to this rumbling?
Princess! Emergency!
The Field of Death
has suddenly begun shaking!
It's like... an active volcano!
What?!
Is something happening again?!
Princess Leona!
We must go save the Heroes!
Stop!
Who...?
You!
Oh! You're alright!
We must leave this place immediately!
Hurry!
Yes!
It's no good! The explosion is inevitable!
Goodbye Hadorra. And Baran.
The two men King Ban himself respected.
Your names shall be etched in my heart...
forever.
This shaking.
So Ban Palace is finally going to move?
That's right.
You're covering up already?
Your true face is so much cooler.
So much cooler!
That power should not be unduly exposed.
As you command, my Dark King.
You've done well, Mystban.
It's over.
All of it.
The Hero, Baran and all other nuisances
have all been erased...
along with the Field of Death.
So we're all that's left.
Yes.
Us...
and Ban Palace itself.
Now it is time for
the surface world to be erased.
I'm removing the barrier
around Ban Palace now.
The remaining rocks that covered it
should all fall away.
However, too much remains.
With the explosion of the Black Core,
aside from Ban Palace,
all the rocks should have been
reduced to ash.
Could it be...?
Mystban, have the Heyedras
search for any survivors.
My King!
Survivors! Survivors spotted!
Four survivors on the left wing!
The Disciples of Aban.
They survived? In that explosion?
How very fortunate of them.
Did we make it?
That explosion was unbelievable.
Who saved us?
It was probably Big Guy here.
Who else has the strength to save us
by burying us all alive?
Stop complaining.
At least we're still alive.
I figured that underground
was probably the safest place.
So I dug a hole in the ground
big enough to hide us.
Good idea. It was probably
the only option given that blast.
The Royal Guard are all gone.
It looks like we're
the only ones who survived.
Nice judgment call!
Too late!
But where are we?
This place is nothing like
the Field of Death.
This is probably Ban Palace.
The explosion tore away the Field of Death
and exposed what lied beneath.
Then that thing way over there is...!
That must be Dark King Ban's palace!
It can't be!
Popp?!
You're saying we just flew into the sky
with Ban Palace?!
omoeba boku wa bukiyou de
To be honest I was clumsy
shouganaikurai tomawarishita
And it took me forever to get here
kodokukannsura mo buki ni shite
I used even loneliness as a weapon
tannjun na kotae wo sagashita dannjon
I searched the dungeon for a simple answer
tadashisa yasashisa nagedashite mo
Even if I cast aside
Rightness and kindness
tada hitori kimi no mikata de itai
I just want to be there for you
kimi no namae wo yobu koto ga
To call out your name
ari to arayuru mahou yori muzukashikute
Is harder than any magic spell
konnani mo chikaku ni itanoni
Even though you're so close to me
aishiteiru
I love you
imasara kizuitanosa
I finally realized it
kimi no namae wo yobu tame ni
To call out your name
boku wa kitto umarete kitannda
Must be the reason I was born
shigamitsuku yoru furihodoite
I shake off the clinging night
ai ni iku
And go to see you
ima sugu kimi no moto e
Right now to where you are
The Black Core erased the Field of Death
and exposed Ban Palace's true form.
Popp and the others who survived
quickly go to find Dai,
but find the horrifying results
of Baran and Hadorra's fight.
Dark King Ban makes
his merciless next move against them.
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Inherited Heart"
The adventure continues!