Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
POPP'S RESOLVE
What's happening to him?!
Baran's body...
...Is changing!
Is this the true form of a Dragon Knight?!
Indeed.
The combined power of Dragon,
Darkling, and human.
The Ultimate Combat Form
of the Dragon Knight.
That is this form.
The form known as the Dragonoid!
The Dragonoid?!
Whoa! What unbelievable pressure!
No one's been this imposing before!
Not even Hadorra!
Popp, get into the castle!
No way! I'm fighting, too!
Don't be stupid!
You can sense it, can't you?!
Baran's overwhelming Aura!
Besides, you're out of Magic Power!
You're useless here!
Hey!
Popp! Don't be stubborn!
I'll support these two!
Look after Dai!
If anything happens to us,
take Dai and run as far as possible!
Dammit! Fine then!
Don't any of you die!
Look out!
Popp!
You dare attack the wounded
from behind?! How could you?!
Once I take Dragonoid form,
I become intent only on wiping out
any enemy in sight, like a Demon Beast.
This power is too strong
for me to hold back.
Wounded or whelp,
I cannot spare any mercy.
But can you blame me?!
You pried into the scar on my heart.
This is your own fault!
Curse you!
Crocodine!
Bagi!
D-Dammit!
He's going to wipe us out at this rate!
We can't beat him!
Even if we were at our best!
His power is on a whole different level!
He's truly a super being with the power
of a Dragon and Magic Power of a Darkling!
You've seen nothing of my Magic Power yet!
I'll erase you all in an instant...
with the purification spell
only usable in this form!
With Doru Aura!
W-We have to run!
It's no good! We can't move!
Stop, Baran! Don't give yourself
over to any more violence!
Your words mean nothing now.
Once I take the form of the Dragonoid...
I cannot turn back until you are all dead!
Begone!
Dino!
Dai!
No!
What was that dream?
No, it was far more vivid than a dream.
A vision?!
Dai... Popp...
No!
We can't let Dai and Baran meet!
Dai, run! Get in the castle!
Hey, Dai!
Are you the one who called me?
I am.
Who are you?
I am your father.
But... you don't look like me at all.
You look... like a monster.
Indeed, this form is not human.
It seems you take after your mother more.
I doubt you can become a Dragonoid.
But...
Remove that cloth.
I can tell... I can tell!
You're not lying!
That crest on your forehead is proof.
It's the unspoken bond between us.
While our forms are different,
we are father and son.
I am your father.
My father...
Popp!
Move!
What can a piece of trash like you do?!
Nothing! I know that already!
But I have to fight!
I'm the only one left who can even stand!
Don't, Popp! Don't challenge Baran!
That's right.
I'll kill you!
If you attack me in this form,
I will brutally respond,
killing you and everyone here
except for Dino,
no matter how weak that attack may be.
Meeting Dino has brought out my humanity,
but this is your last chance.
Hand Dino over peacefully.
You're in the way, mister.
Huh?
I finally met my father.
Dai...
What?
You can't have him! Father or not!
I'll never let you have our Dai!
"Our Dai"?
That's right!
Without Dai, Princess Leona would be dead!
If they hadn't fought Dai, Crocodine
and Hyunckel would still be evil!
And... And me...
If I hadn't met Dai,
I'd still be running away.
I'd be a brown-noser.
All talk and useless!
There's no doubt I'd be worthless!
Meeting Dai changed all of our fates!
It's thanks to Dai that we came this far!
Dai is the one who lifts us up!
For Dai to become the enemy of humans...
For Dai to disappear from our lives...
I'd rather die than let that happen!
Then you shall die.
It-It's no good!
He has no humanity left in him!
Dammit!
Popp!
What do I do? I've got no Magic Power
or powerful weapons or items!
All I can do is punch him!
Isn't there anything I can do?!
Think! Think!
If I don't act,
he's going to take Dai away!
Master... What would you do, Master Aban?
How would you fight
at a time like this, Master?
Master!
That's right...
There's still one thing I can do!
HYADARUKO
ICE-TYPE SPELL
BEHOMA
HEAL-TYPE SPELL
That's right...
There's still one thing I can do!
But if I do that...
Don't worry.
I'll end this real quick.
Huh?
Hold on to that bandana, will you?
I've had it since I was five.
It's my trademark.
Me? Why?
Listen! Just don't lose it!
H-He's fighting bare-handed?!
Are you insane, Popp?!
I can't watch
such a pathetic suicide attack.
I'll shatter him with one blow!
Th-That's...!
They won't come out!
His grip is just a weak Mage's!
Obviously!
I've got all my life energy
focused in my fingertips!
I can't just let you pull them out!
You're not...!
I knew it! That's...
Megante!
If you use Megante, you're sure to die!
I know! If I'm unlucky,
I'll be blown to pieces with nothing left!
Just like my master was!
Stop! This is crazy!
I idolized Master Aban, but this was
one trick I never hoped to copy!
You don't know if it'll work on Baran!
Oh it'll work.
The Dragonic Aura may be a mighty shield,
but it can be pierced
by even greater energy!
That's what Baran said himself!
He's taken that much into account?
Plus, I get to die for Dai!
To die for the Hero!
Basically, I get to die
for the future of all humans!
Who could ask for a better reason to die?!
Don't! Please, Popp!
Don't! Don't do it, Popp!
This...
This has happened before!
I get the feeling...
Something really, really sad...
I have to... I have to do something!
I have to do something, but...!
He's trying to rip his arm off!
Leona...
Hyunckel...
Crocodine...
Everyone...
I leave the rest to you.
Popp!
Make something up for Maam, will you?
Dai.
Dai...
If you still have that dumb look
on your face when I die...
I'll be pissed!
See you, Dai.
We've gone through a lot...
It's been fun.
But...
my adventure... ends here.
Megante!
Popp!
No!
Y-You idiot!
I remember!
I remember it all, Popp!
Because I've been so pathetic...
you...
Popp, I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Dai!
Popp!
Has his memory returned?!
But the price was all too high!
What?!
N-No! Even after Popp sacrificed himself!
Does even Megante have no effect on him?!
No. Even I would
take damage from Megante.
But, his lack of experience saved me.
Just as he channeled all of
his life energy and detonated it,
he let his guard down, weakening his grip.
I was able to fly up and shake him off.
Damn it all!
A meaningless death.
C-Curse you!
Baran, why you...!
Gomechan!
Gomechan, don't! Stop!
Begone!
Enough!
No more!
Stop hurting my friends!
Dino...
It seems you really have
regained your memories.
I thought I completely erased them.
It's unbelievable.
If you really are my dad,
why are you doing this?!
Why take my memories
and hurt and kill my friends?!
Silence!
I will wipe out the humans
and their allies!
If you are my son, you will obey me!
No!
You're right that sometimes
humans can be cruel.
They can be selfish, they bully,
and they can discriminate.
But some of them aren't like that.
They can be cowardly, but they
try their best to do what's right.
That's...
That's who Popp was!
He's doing it again!
There's no reason to remember such trash!
I'll erase your memories again!
This time, completely!
He's a monster!
Now forget everything, Dino!
And become my true son!
No! I...
I won't forget Popp ever again!
I'll never forget him!
It's just like last time!
Can we do nothing?!
Popp sacrificed himself and fought...
and I can't do anything!
Please, gods!
God of Dragons! Lend us your strength!
Don't resist!
Your whole mind could be wiped!
I won't give in!
I'm me!
I'm Dai, the Hero!
You still resist your father?! You fool!
You're not...
You're not my dad!
What?!
He struck me while I was shielded
by my Dragonic Aura?!
What?!
Dai's crest is on his fist?!
What?! Impossible! This can't be!
In thousands of years
of Dragon Knight history
for the light of the crest to appear
anywhere other than the forehead...
It's never happened before!
Could it be...?!
The human spirit?!
Is this Soara's will?!
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
With the Dragon Crest on his fist,
Dai unleashes his anger at Baran.
But Baran's flames of rage
are stoked by his son's retaliation.
Teran Kingdom trembles
as the Dragon Knights clash.
The greatest battle in the world
begins now!
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"A Father and Son Clash"
The adventure continues!