Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE DRAGON KNIGHT
I'll draw it away to give you time!
O-Okay!
Come on!
Everybody hurry!
What happened?!
Oh no!
Everybody help!
Yeah, but...
Hurry up with you!
You can lift a rock, can't you?!
Go!
R-Right!
Dragon scales are as hard as steel.
I'll have to target its faces!
Earth Slash!
Dai!
Hyado!
Even its faces are like steel?!
His sword wore down.
I can't win, fighting them one by one.
For this, I'll take them all out
with a single huge spell!
Mighty spirits asleep in the earth,
I now ask you to hear my voice!
Betan!
Yes!
Ouch...
Wow. I guess that's a spell straight from
Grand Sorcerer Matorif for you.
But it used up all of my Magic Power
in the process.
Mera! Mera!
With puny spells like that...
He can't win!
I know! Give that to the boy!
What are you saying?! This is mine!
Dai!
Look!
Green Dragons!
Princess, sorry! You've got to run!
Ow!
Run?! How can we run?!
We're out of time!
Don't leave me!
What a bunch of cowards!
No!
They're done for!
Leona!
Dai?
That crest! It can't be!
IORA!
It's the mark!
We've got the advantage now!
Get out of here!
Grandmother, that crest is...
Huh?
I never thought I'd see it for myself.
The legendary Dragon Knight in battle!
Dai's even more intense than usual today.
Popp, help us out!
R-Right!
Hey!
Raiden!
He won.
Oh wow!
Good going, Dai! That was amazing!
Are you okay?
U-Uh...
What's wrong?
I'm scared! He's scary!
Huh?
I'm... scary?
W-Why is everybody...
Because you're not human.
Seeing your inhuman fighting abilities
has terrified them all.
Who's there?!
Humans can be so selfish.
And after you protected their city.
There!
The Dark Army?!
My name is Kilban.
My rather insulting friends
call me "The Reaper."
Kilban, The Reaper?!
Are you the Dragon Legion Commander?!
I'm not that distinguished.
I'm just a servant.
The Dark Army has been abuzz,
speculating on your identity.
So I was lent some Dragons from the
Dragon Legion and was sent to find out.
As a result, I was able to see
what you really are.
Wait! What do you mean by that?!
Oh, also, the real Dragon Legion
Commander will probably show up soon...
to lure you into hell.
Hope you enjoy it.
He's gone.
What did he mean by... my identity?
Wait. You called Dai
"the Dragon Knight," didn't you?
Indeed.
He must be the Dragon Knight from the
legends of our homeland, Teran Kingdom.
Huh? The Dragon Knight?
Where's Teran? And who are you?
I am Nabara the Seer.
And this is my granddaughter, Meruru.
It's a country north of Bengana.
It's called the Mystic Country.
The Mystic Country.
If I go there...
ABAN STRASH
HYADARUKO
ICE-TYPE SPELL
Sovereign Rock Castle's
footprints end here.
The Field of Death...
Dark King Ban's Dark Army
must be positioned there.
Who's there?!
Are you alright?!
Th-The Dark Army.
What?!
The Dark Army drove
my homeland of Carl to ruin.
Taking down Carl
couldn't have been an easy task.
Which Legion did it?
So this is Teran Kingdom?
It's so pretty.
Yeah, but...
it's kind of shabby.
It's more of a village than a kingdom.
Uh, but, you know, I'm glad
the Dark Army hasn't attacked this place.
To be blunt, it's because
it has no tactical value.
Teran is a kingdom in name only.
It has no military power.
Indeed.
Because of his love for nature
and devotion to the gods,
the king forbade development
of weapons and items.
He said they would bring disaster upon us.
But that also weakened the country.
Everybody prefers
a life filled with luxury.
The population moved to other countries,
and this country was left to rot.
Now there are only about 50 people.
Of course, we were among those who left.
But...
I still love this quiet homeland.
She's a strange one.
Madam Nabara, please tell me!
Where can I find something
that will tell me who I am?!
Whoa. What are you
getting worked up about, Dai?
I'm not worked up!
Dai...
I'm sorry.
But, I have to know! Just who I am!
Follow me.
Talk about decrepit. Is this some ruin?
Look inside.
That's...
That is the Dragon Crest.
Is this the mark
that appears on my forehead?
Yes. It's identical.
Teran worships the God of Dragons.
And this crest is revered and feared
as a sign of the God of Dragons' power.
He who bears this crest
on his forehead is...
The Dragon Knight?
What sort of human is it?
It may not be human at all.
We believe it is a servant of the gods.
According to legends,
the Dragon Knight wields awesome power,
can cast any spell,
and, with the heavens, earth, and sea
as its allies, will destroy all creation.
What kind of being destroys all creation?
It could be our savior or our destroyer.
It is only written that it wields power
like a rebirth of the God of Dragons.
However...
However what?!
There is a forbidden temple
at the bottom of this lake.
The soul of the God of Dragons
is said to rest there.
Then...
Indeed. If you really do have something
to do with the Dragon Knight,
perhaps you can enter that temple
and find some clues.
I'm... going down there.
An underwater temple, huh? Okay!
I'm going alone.
Huh?
But... shouldn't we all go?
No. I want to go alone.
Dai...
All right. At least take this.
I bought it in Bengana.
Okay. Thanks.
I've never wondered who I am before.
I washed up on Dermline Island
as a baby and was raised among monsters.
Grampa Burasu scolded me a lot,
but he cared for me.
The monsters never excluded me
just because I wasn't a monster.
But humans won't accept me
unless I'm also a human.
That's why...
I want to find out alone.
I...
I don't want you or Leona to hate me!
Dai!
Wait!
You idiot!
Worrying about things that don't matter!
I thought we were friends!
I thought we were companions!
I don't care if you're a monster or not!
That... never mattered!
Popp...
So this is...
the Dragon Temple.
How do I get inside?
There's air in here.
Who goes there?
Name yourself.
A talking crystal?!
I am the Dragon Crystal.
Guardian of this temple.
Who are you?
That's what I want to know!
Am I really a Dragon Knight?!
Why do you ask this?
I don't know
where I was born or who I am!
Tell me!
There is no mistake.
You are the Dragon Knight.
Th-Then it's true.
This temple cannot be entered
by anyone but the Dragon Knight.
Your presence here is proof itself.
Just what is a Dragon Knight?!
Is it a human or a monster?
It is neither.
Three gods created this world.
The God of Dragons, the God of Darklings,
and the God of Humans.
The Dragon Knight is the ultimate creature
created by those three gods.
Created?!
Yes. Long ago,
by three great celestial beings.
Why create such a creature?
To...
What's wrong?!
Someone else has entered this temple.
This is impossible. The Dragon Knight...
Who are you?!
The Dragon Legion Commander...
Baran!
Baran?!
So he's the Dragon Legion Commander.
He's the real deal!
And there's something about him...
You must be Dai.
That's right!
This man is also a Dragon Knight?!
Impossible. Two Dragon Knights
existing in the same age...
Are you here to kill me?!
No I'm not.
Huh?!
The Dragon Crystal must have already
told you that you're a Dragon Knight.
So what if it did?!
I want your power.
Serve me!
Together we shall destroy...
the human world!
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
Baran, the Dragon Legion Commander
reveals the Dragon Knight's mission.
For Dai, who seeks to defeat
the Dark King, it is a cruel revelation.
Dai resists, using his Aban Strash,
but it has no effect on Baran.
Baran then reveals a shocking truth...
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Dragon Master General Baran"
The adventure continues!