Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
DAI AND PRINCESS LEONA
Are you Dai, the Hero?
Yep!
Oh wow, you're so tiny!
Talk about undependable!
The royal family of our Papnica Kingdom
has long served the gods.
The latest successor, Princess Leona,
during the month of her 14th birthday,
must partake in a ritual to receive
the blessing of the Earth God.
This island has
a cave into the earth, yes?
Indeed. There is a gigantic cave here.
That is the Ritual Land we seek.
But, as this island has long been feared
as an island of monsters,
no one knows where it is.
It's been 50 years since a member of
the royal family has undergone the ritual.
It just so happened,
when King Romos visited Papnica,
he spoke of Dai the Future Hero
and Brass the Venerable.
I see. So you would like Dai
to take you to the Earth Cave.
Huh?!
The monsters of Dermline Island
will obey Dai, will they not?
The Earth Cave is a dangerous place.
To take the Princess there...
Princess Leona will one day become a Sage.
With the magic I have taught her,
there will be no danger.
Hmm.
Grampa, I don't wanna. She seems rude.
Watch your mouth!
Ow!
If he will be useful,
I will gladly lend him to you.
Go on!
Is this really safe?
Are you sure you won't get lost?
This island is my backyard!
I can walk around it blindfolded!
Oh!
How brave!
Hmph!
Let's go. It's that way.
Take good care of the Princess.
I understand.
What's wrong?
Oh. It's you.
Hey, don't sleep here. Get out of the way.
Bye!
Wow! Amazing!
I'm actually impressed, little boy.
It's Dai.
Is there anything else you can do?
Like magic?
I can't do magic.
Huh? Seriously?! Not a single spell?!
Princess...
I'm sure Sir Dai just hasn't
undergone a Ritual of Magic yet.
I did the rituals.
Grampa wants me to be a Mage, so we did
Rituals of Magic for lots of spells.
Huh. So you've already bound with spells.
But I still can't use a single spell.
I don't have the talent.
So this is the Earth Cave.
It's impressive.
Prepare for the ritual!
Yes, sir!
I'm going to have a look around.
What?!
You can have this.
It's a distinguished knife
of the Papnica royal family.
But Temjin gets mad
when I carry it around.
This is amazing!
If you can't use magic,
you might as well have a decent weapon.
Don't be so gloomy
and work on your sword skills!
You really don't hold anything back,
do you?
Of course.
It's better for everyone that way.
Plus it makes me feel better.
You didn't try to spare
my feelings either.
Huh? That was...
I guess so.
Iruru!
An Evil Scorpion?!
Isn't that your friend?! Get it to leave!
No! That's not a creature
from this island!
Everyone run!
Protect the Princess!
It's like a rock!
Hold on!
Look out!
Gira!
Magic doesn't work?!
Princess Leona!
This knife is amazing!
Your weak point is...
right there!
Princess Leona!
It's the Evil Scorpion's poison!
Grampa said even
an Antidotal Herb can't cure it!
Gomechan! Hurry and call Grampa Brass!
Grampa can use
the cure poison spell, Kiari!
Hang in there Princess Leona!
She's gonna die at this rate!
Darn it! I should've worked on
learning magic harder!
Varon!
Thank goodness!
Cast Kiari on the Princess!
A Magic Cylinder!
Princess Leona...
dies here!
IO!
And never come out!
Dai washed ashore here as a baby.
Since then, he's grown up among us.
So everyone is his friend...
What?!
Princess Leona has been poisoned
by an Evil Scorpion! We must go save her!
How could an Evil Scorpion show up here?
I need to hurry and cast Kiari on her!
What's the meaning of this?!
If you save the Princess,
all of my plans will have been for naught.
What?!
If Princess Leona dies,
without a successor,
Papnica Kingdom will be mine to rule!
That's why I went ahead with this ritual!
So I could say she was killed
by the monsters of Dermline Island!
You were all in on this?!
Only these seven of my trusted servants
and Varon know about this.
Mera!
Gome, summon everyone!
Let's drive them off of this island!
What's that?
Darn it! Another dead end!
You're a servant of the gods, yet
you would kill your master out of greed?!
Unforgivable!
Derupa!
Ah! The Killing Machine!
Impossible! The Dark Lord created
the Killing Machine to kill the Hero!
How can it move with the Dark Lord dead?!
Here's your answer, old man!
Varon's magic power is driving it?!
That's right.
I modified this abomination after it was
nothing more than junk from the last war.
So that it could be controlled
by a human's will!
How could you?!
You're now the ultimate creature!
Wipe them out, Varon!
Everyone get back!
Merami!
Did it work?!
Old fool!
This Killing Machine was created
to exterminate the Hero!
Your pitiful magic can't harm it!
IRURUR/DERUPA
IO
EXPLOSION-TYPE SPELL
Dai...
Princess Leona!
Where are we?
We're underground.
We fell in the gigantic cave.
In the cave?
If I had more strength...
If I could use magic, I could heal you.
I could even get us out of here.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
Did you know?
Most people can't even bind with magic.
Princess Leona...
You've bound
with almost every spell, right?
That's proof you have talent.
But I...
I know you'll learn to use magic someday.
Leona!
If you keep whining,
I won't like you anymore.
Leona! Don't die! Leona!
You won't die.
I swear you'll live!
I won't let you die!
What was that shockwave?!
There you are, old man!
This is goodbye!
Stop!
Grampa!
Dai?!
Varon, the Princess still lives!
That little brat!
What is that?!
Die!
Dai, run! They were planning
to kill Princess Leona!
I can't Grampa!
The poison has already
spread through her body!
She needs a Kiari spell or she'll die!
What?!
Varon, hurry and kill that old man!
That way no one will be able
to save the Princess!
Grampa!
The Princess is sure to die now!
Bagikurosai!
D-Dai used magic?!
Grampa, are you okay?!
Y-Yes!
You startled me!
Even Bagikurosai doesn't work?!
I'm going to kill...
all of you!
Stop!
I won't let you rampage
on this island any more!
Don't make me laugh, boy!
Little fool! Your efforts are futile!
Magic doesn't work! And you
lack the strength to win with a sword!
There's no way for you to beat me!
Dai!
It's over.
Die!
Impossible! He pierced
the Killing Machine's armour?!
He's been targeting the same spot?!
What is that?!
Curse you!
Begirama!
Why?! The Killing Machine
is immune to magic!
There was a crack
in the Killing Machine's armour.
The flames of the Begirama spell
leaked in and hit Varon.
Grampa!
Help Leona!
R-Right!
Bishop Temjin!
What is going on?!
Tell them the truth!
You brat...
Everyone! This boy took the Princess...
What about me, Temjin?
Are you alright, Princess?!
If you have something to say, say it.
It'll make you feel better.
Let a judge at Papnica hear it, too.
Earth God,
I, Leona, priestess
and successor of Papnica Kingdom
come before you to be purified.
So Leona really is a Princess.
Be quiet!
I pledge myself to the Earth God.
Thank you, Dai. You saved my life.
I'm glad you're okay, Princess Leona.
Have you gained some confidence in magic?
I guess so.
When you eventually become a Hero,
come to Papnica.
I'll let you be my bodyguard or something.
Uh... No thanks!
Farewell, Princess!
It's "Leona," not "Princess!"
But...
Next time you treat me like a stranger,
I won't speak to you!
Goodbye, Leona!
See you!
Listen, Dai.
Could you do that again?
That?
That Bagikurosai and all.
Okay!
Bagikurosai!
Begirama!
Perhaps I was seeing things.
Monsters are attacking!
What is that?!
Master, this is bad!
This is bad, Master!
Tons of monsters
just showed up in the city!
-What a pickle.
-Huh?
I didn't think the Dark Lord would return.
Wait. That's all?!
Shouldn't we go back
and take care of them?!
The soldiers can handle those monsters.
We must aim for the future.
The future?
Now that the Dark Lord has returned,
the people will need a Hero.
Let us go visit the new Hero.
Kindness is the magic of kind people
yasashisa wa yasashii hito ga tsukaeru mahou
Then do I have no choice
But to just be a normal person?
jaa boku wa tada no hito de iru shikanaino?
I'm not sure
doudarou
Even if the place I call home may change
kaeru basho wa ne kawatte yuku kedo
Listen to me, Mother
naa kaasan boku wa
I will never change those I protect
mamoru hito wo kaetari shinai
I wonder what you'd say
anata wa nannte iukana
At times I can be cowardly and small
tokiyori yowaki de chippoke de
What would you say to me
As I hesitate to even hesitate?
mayou koto ni mo mayou boku ni nannte iukana
Unlike the today that I sought
sagashite ita kyou to chigatte
I'm sure you'd laugh at my disappointment
ochikonnde shimau boku wo warau no darou
When a terrible calamity
threatens Dermline Island,
a man calling himself a tutor
appears before Dai.
To save the island and the world,
together with
Popp the young Mage trainee,
Dai decides to undertake
a special hard training!
Next time on
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Hero's Tutor"
The adventure continues!