Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
Since when was it?
are itsukarada?
Being honest became whining
honne ga yowane ni nattana
Standing firm became strength
nigenai koto ga tsuyosa ni natta
Have you found it yet?
naa mitsukaranai?
Not confidence, your true self
jishin janaku jibun jishin
There must be something
I've forgotten that I still haven't found
kitto mada sagasetenai wasuremono ga aruhazu
Words I want to say
That I still haven't said
zutto mada tsutaetenai tsutaetai kotoba
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you
mitete kurerunara misete miserunoni
Truly loving myself
boku ga boku wo aishinuku koto
Is it alright to still believe in that?
naa mada shinjitemo iika?
I smolder because I've actually burned
kusuburuno wa chanto moeta karada
No matter where this journey takes us
doko e mukau tabi datoshitemo
I'll just open my eyes
tada me wo mihiraite
And dream my dream
yume wo miru
And know my dream
yume wo shiru
THE DRAGON MASTERS APPROACH
Thank you for coming.
I've been waiting.
It's been years
since we three have gathered.
To require all of us must mean
something big is going on.
Has the time come to burn the world?
My son, Dino, is alive.
Master Dino?!
The Hero Dai, who fights
the Dark Army is my son, Dino.
What a cruel twist of fate.
I've already fought the party he leads.
Their bond of unity was stronger than I
anticipated, and I sustained some wounds.
You were wounded?!
So that's why you came to Argo Point.
This is where the Fountain of Miracles
that heals Dragon Knights is located.
That wasn't my only reason.
He means his wife.
We understand, Master Baran.
You need our help to reclaim Master Dino.
Exactly. My son has
some troublesome allies.
They would risk death for Dai, the Hero.
Especially the two Legion Commanders
who betrayed the Dark Army.
Beast King Crocodine and Dark Swordsman
Hyunckel are not to be underestimated.
You're joking!
No Legion Commander of the Dark Army
aside from you could stand up to us!
You may be the most powerful Dragon Riders
of all Darklings and Beastlings,
but humans can display terrifying strength
when they're prepared to die.
If his allies should resist,
you three must crush them.
In the meantime, I shall reclaim my son.
Yes, Master!
I must prepare for battle.
Wait for me here.
Master Baran is ever the cautious one.
They're just a few humans
and a couple of traitors.
Watch your tongue, Galdandy!
Indeed. They say a lion
does not hold back when killing a hare.
Don't forget his caution has made
our glorious Dragon Legion undefeated.
I get it already.
Soara, this time I shall get Dino back...
from those filthy humans!
The Dragon Legion shall now
head to Teran Kingdom!
When my son, Dino, joins us,
our strength shall be absolute!
Yes, Master!
Follow me!
What a surprise.
With everyone calling you "Princess,"
I wondered who you were.
So you're the ruler of Papnica.
Otherwise, small as Teran may be,
its king would not so easily hear us.
His Majesty will see you know.
He is not feeling well and asks that
you forgive an audience in his chambers.
That's fine.
I'll wait outside.
Call me when you're done.
I see.
So that supernatural storm
was caused by the Dragon Knight.
And this child is the Dragon Knight's son.
It may have been a Psychic Signal
that took his memories.
A Psychic Signal?
Think of it as a mental wave
emitted from the Dragon Crest.
How can we restore his memory?
I do not know.
We merely worship the God of Dragons.
We know of the Dragon Knight,
but not of the full breadth of its powers.
I see.
Then will you let us use this castle
to shelter Dai?
You still seek to fight?
We do.
The people of Teran may think of
Baran's attack as divine will,
but it's an aggression against humanity.
We will fight against aggression.
I see. I had heard of the bravery
of the Princess of Papunica.
Kanar.
Your Majesty!
You will aid Princess Leona.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Tell me, are you the famed Seer...?
Yes. I am Nabara.
And this one?
This is my granddaughter, Meruru.
Come closer.
Huh?
Yes, Your Majesty.
You possess power
beyond that of your grandmother's.
Indeed. Recently, she's been able to
sense things I cannot.
Your power shall soon show you
terrifying and horrible things to come.
What?!
Do not resent your power.
It shall eventually help save humanity.
Trust that that day shall come
and live strong.
Yes, Your Majesty.
What's wrong?!
It's coming! An energy of such wrath!
Straight for this country!
You mean Baran?!
He's coming already?!
That's not all!
Other similar energies... Three of them!
What are you doing?!
Let me out! Let me out of here!
Isn't a prison cell going too far?
But this is the deepest,
most impregnable place in the castle.
But...
Let me out! Let me out!
Young lady, do you know
what "imprinting" is?
Huh?
It's when an animal hatches from its egg,
and assumes
the first thing it sees is its parent.
Baran's reduced Dai to a state
of a newly hatched infant.
If Dai encounters Baran now,
he'll probably accept Baran as his father.
They bear the same mark
as irrefutable proof.
It's cruel, but this is
the only way to prevent that.
We'll take care of the rest.
Please guard the king.
I'm sorry I could not do more.
Dai...
They're headed straight for Teran
from the southeast.
Can you show them, Old Lady?
I think so.
Who are they?!
These are the three sources of energy
aside from Baran?
Could they be the Dragon Masters?!
The Dragon Masters?
The most powerful Dragon Riders
that serve Baran.
With Dragons under their control, they're said
to rival even the Legion Commanders.
You mean he's brought three guys
each as strong as you?!
We may not be strong enough
to hold them back.
Fighting Baran alone was difficult enough.
If only Hyunckel was here.
We're done for. I guess that blows it.
Popp?
Sorry, but I'm not about to
die for nothing.
I'm bailing now.
You guys do whatever you like.
What are you saying all of a sudden?!
I'm saying I'm getting out of here.
If they're that strong, there's no point
in resisting. What a crock!
Popp, do you understand
what you're saying?!
You're the ones who don't understand!
Dai's like this and we're falling apart.
Now we're facing the most powerful Legion.
You'd have to be crazy
to consider fighting now.
I thought fighting for your friends,
even when there's no hope,
was what you
Disciples of Aban believed in!
If Dai falls into their hands now,
the human world will end!
That's right!
I thought you were Dai's best friend!
Are you really willing
to abandon Dai now and run?!
Don't worry about him.
He's not even human.
He's one of them.
Why not give him back to them?
They'll take good care of him!
Very well. Get out of my sight.
We won't enlist the aid of one like you.
Well that's a relief. Thanks!
Popp!
Wait, Popp!
Do not follow him, Crocodine!
We need you here to defend this position.
But...!
Princess...
I've always admired the Disciples of Aban.
If Master Aban was still alive,
I was hoping to learn from him.
I believed Popp would stay with us
because he's a Disciple of Aban.
What happened to your courage, Popp?
Popp...?
Popp...? Who...?
Popp!
Meruru?
Was it all a lie?
When you said Dai was your friend
even if he was a monster!
Were those words...
Those tears... All of it?
I hate you.
I don't like you anymore!
I remember when Maam punched me
and said I disgusted her.
But this isn't like back then!
If I tried to go alone, you'd stop me.
That's why I had to say that.
I'm sorry!
Look after Dai, everyone!
I'll stop them, even if I die trying!
I may not win, but I'll take
one or two of them out with me!
So take care of the rest!
HYADARUKO
ICE-TYPE SPELL
GIGABREAK
Stop right there!
You're not going any farther!
Look who's here to stop us!
Are the others lying in wait?
No, it doesn't seem like it.
Are you insane?! Or just an idiot?!
Victory to the quick!
Galdandy, don't underestimate him!
He wields spells
stronger than you'd expect.
That scrawny wimp?!
Betan!
Be crushed!
Please be crushed!
Thanks for lifting me up!
You're a real help, Ruud!
Dammit! One escaped above!
Such weak Dragons! Pathetic!
You're brave to try to stop us alone.
Master Baran, leave this to us.
We shall catch up,
so you should hurry to Master Dino.
Very well. I leave this to you.
But don't underestimate him.
I said it before,
humans who are prepared to die
can display terrifying strength.
"A cornered rat will bite a cat."
You never know what the desperate will do.
Isn't that what the humans say?
I'm going ahead.
Hold it!
Dammit!
Know your place, boy!
A pipsqueak like you couldn't fight
Master Baran in a million years!
Shut up! Merazoma!
With a single breath...?!
That's not all you've got, is it?!
You thought you could fight
the Dragon Masters with that?!
Are you trying to make me laugh?!
Too frail, boy!
That's enough, Borahorn.
What?
He's nothing more than a fledgling.
Don't make him suffer.
Just drop him on this and end it.
I guess so.
For a toy, he's not very fun to play with.
Galdandy?!
I'll take this toy
if you two don't want it!
He's a juicy human prey! It's no fun
unless we take our time killing him!
As cruel as ever, I see.
They're strong! They're going to kill me!
Dammit! If I'm going to die,
I have to hit them at least once or twice!
Otherwise, what's the point in me dying?!
Whoops. Are you dead already, kid?
I-It hurts! I'm done for!
Please! Just end it by biting off my head!
Weakling!
Oh well. Since you asked so nicely!
Begirama!
I guess you can do anything
if you're desperate.
I don't believe it. That kid killed
Galdandy's favorite Ethereal Serpent.
The rat actually bit the cat.
But his resistance comes at a steep price.
That takes care of their Dragons.
The real fight starts now.
This... This is impossible!
How could you die?!
What the hell?
How cruel! This is too much!
What are you crying about, birdface?!
You've killed tons of humans!
Killed tons of humans?
This Ethereal Serpent, Ruud,
was the only friend I ever trusted!
He was like my brother!
We were always together, no matter what.
How dare you compare my beloved Dragon...
to some filthy little humans!
What are these feathers?!
They won't come out!
I'll slice you to pieces!
So much that
they'll never find your pieces!
G-Get away from me!
That's it! They're all on the ground now!
Betan!
My spell's not working?!
You can't use
such powerful spells anymore.
Your Magic Power is leaking out right now.
You mean...?!
That's right. Those white feathers
drain an enemy's Magic Power!
Dammit!
And these red feathers, drain stamina.
Do you get it?
I'm going to reduce you to
an empty rag doll before I slice you up!
I'll make you fear for your life!
Merazoma!
Then, Merami!
Stop resisting!
It's no good! I feel weak!
I won't let you die so easily.
I'm dragging this out!
Take this and this and this!
Does it hurt?! I bet it does!
He's gone mad. Even we can't stop him now.
The boy could've died painlessly
if he hadn't resisted.
Poor kid.
You're braver than I thought.
That pisses me off!
I've got to fight back! While I still have
stamina and Magic Power!
I have to do something!
Oh! I like that face right there!
I know. I'll do what you did to Ruud!
I'll blow your head off like him!
That's it! That's the look!
Just keep that face!
Who's there?!
Great. I'm saved by
the last guy I want saving me.
Sorry to disappoint.
Even if you face the devil
With logic on your side
tatoe akuma ni seiron kazashite
mukatte mitemo
It may just be a rationalization
sore wa akumade seitouka
sashite chigai wa naikamo
Even now, even now I waver
ima mo ima mo yureteiru kedo
How far will we go?
bokura wa dokomade yukuno
I heard a voice like an angel's whisper
tenshi no sasayaki nimo nita
koe ga kikoeta
Maybe it was an imposter's illusion
It still rang in my ears
hatamata petenshi no mayakashi
hitokiwa mimi ni hibiiteita
Exposed to love and sorrow
ai ni hiai ni sarasare nagara
On the path strewn with pride
hokori mamire michi no tochu
Fleeting moments of cowardice
kiete wa ukabu touhikou
The SOS I held back
nomikonda SOS
I clenched my trembling fist
furueru te wo nigirishimeta
That single little promise
tatta hitotsu no chiisana yakusoku ga
Those trivial little memories
honno sasaina omoidetachi ga
They're still in my heart
itsumade tattemo kono mune wo
As embers that keep me burning
kogashi tsuzukeru tomoshibi ni naru
A single transparent beam of light
tada hitosuji no toumei na hikari ga
Lights the way before me
me no mae wo terashite yuku
There is little that I can do
boku ni dekiru koto wa ikutsu mo naisa
Just keep on to the future
I managed to grasp through my faith
shinjinuita saki ni te ni shita mirai wo
susunde yuke
Hyunckel arrived
just in time to save Popp.
With the best possible ally at his side,
against Galdandy and Borahorn,
they manage to get an advantage.
Larhart watches calmly,
until he finally lifts his ominous spear.
The ferocious battle between Hyunckel and
Larhart, the last Dragon Master, begins!
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"Land Rider Larhart"
The adventure continues!