With your bonds with your friends
nakama tono kizuna wo
Embraced in your heart
sono mune ni idaite
Like a flash, in an instant
hikari no you ni isshun ni
You risk it all
subete wo kaketeku
Time and time again
Against your burning destiny
nanndo mo moeagaru sadame ni
You will face it again
tachimukatte ikunnda to
If that's what you choose
kakugo wo kimetanara
Oh even when hurt
Oh kizutsuite mo
Oh even if you stumble
Oh tsumazuite mo
Continue on
To your journey's end
susume kono tabi no hate
Again and again
To the future you make
kimi no egaku mirai e nando mo
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Oh Oh
You can stand up
You're The Bravest
tachiagareru
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
Fly up to the world
Never let it go
Make you more strong
You're The Bravest
motto Make you strong
KILLVEARN'S TRAP
Calamity Wall!
Dai's completely focused on the fight.
I guess that's a good thing.
But he's completely forgotten about me.
Not a bad idea.
No one has ever done that before.
To try to dodge my Calamity Wall
by standing in its way.
I didn't think of it.
My body just reacted instantly.
I didn't even know I could use
my Dragonic Aura that way.
Come to think of it,
it's just like with my Doru Aura.
It's like I could just do it naturally.
Oh no! Leona! Are you okay?!
Of course I am.
I promised you that
I'd take care of myself.
But you're out of breath...
Don't worry about me!
Just focus on the fight!
R-Right.
But Dai can do this.
I was going to focus on healing him...
but I may not even have a role in this.
I'm not sure about it,
but it looks like you're right, Ban.
I feel something unimaginable
awakened inside me.
It's like when I first gained
the power of my Crest.
I think I might actually be able
to match you in battle.
You still don't understand, Dai.
Your strength nearly matches my own now.
How selfless.
To possess such power, and not think
what you should do with it.
Let me be blunt, Dai.
Your power can decide
the fate of the world.
Even I was ever wary of Baran.
He possessed the Combat Instincts.
An opponent who fights unpredictably
is someone I would rather not fight.
Besides, if someone is that powerful,
I hate to see it go to waste.
Go to... waste?
Dai, you are more powerful
than the Dragonoid Baran.
With the power of your second Crest,
you have gained
the Combat Instincts of all past Knights.
You are more powerful
than anyone I have ever met.
I could say you're the first
to ever get this close to my level.
Just to be sure, let me ask you...
will you be my servant?
That's... Why would...?!
The answer your father gave
to this question was "Yes."
Because he was a pure Dragon Knight,
Baran understood
just how ugly and foolish humans are.
Humans are disgusting, Dai.
They aren't worth lending your power to.
If you fight for them
and happen to win, then what?
Then what?
I would be willing to bet...
should you defeat me and return to
the humans, you will suffer persecution.
I'm scared! He's scary!
They only come crying to you
when they are in need.
Once peace settles,
they begin to complain and accuse.
And you will be
stripped of your title as Hero.
They won't want someone who is not
pure human to stand above them.
That is what humans are.
You're wrong!
We'd never do such a thing!
That is, Princess...
only because you hold
a personal affinity for Dai.
It's no different from Baran's case.
The feeling of one individual cannot
change something as nebulous as a country.
As royalty, you should know this well.
But I am different.
I do not discriminate between races
for those who are strong.
Baran and Hadorra may have betrayed me,
but I still respect them.
So what now, Dai?!
Will you risk your life
for a worthless victory?
Or will you serve one
who understands your true value?
You may be a child,
but the choice should be clear.
What will it be, Dai?!
My answer is...
no!
A child indeed.
You still cling to
the sweet illusion of being a hero.
You're wrong!
Humans...
I know that humans can sometimes be cruel.
I doubt you're lying about what you said.
But it doesn't matter.
I still love everyone.
I love humans.
I love all the creatures of
the Surface World who made me who I am.
Dai...
If what you say is really true...
If it's what the people
of the Surface World want...
Then...
Then I will defeat you...
and leave this world.
I see. A pity.
You truly are a blessing for these humans.
To make the almighty Dragon Knight
say such a thing...
they are quite sinful creatures.
You need to learn a lesson!
That to side with them
was your greatest folly!
Dai... Please win!
Not for anyone else. But for yourself!
I'm not sure how, but you seem to know
what's going on outside.
You're clearly trying to rush this fight.
It looks like we're
nearly done, Kilban!
Aban... I didn't expect
this much from you.
Kilban...
the moment you decided to hold this duel,
you put yourself at a disadvantage.
You only have one way of winning.
To deceive and snare. That's all.
Using your numerous tools and traps,
you immobilize your target
and dispatch them easily.
For a Reaper, it's a sure way of killing,
but over the years,
you've lost the ability to win fairly.
Your strength, skill,
and speed are all top-rate,
but your deciding attacks
lack the drive to win.
That's why you can't mortally wound
someone like me who can match your speed.
You gave in to the humiliation
of your wounded pride.
By using this duel with the Judge,
you already sealed your fate.
That's right.
You lose, Kilban.
You truly are quite fascinating.
As you said, I can't win
without any traps.
If I really wanted to, I could train
and be unbeatable in a fair fight.
I'm strong enough for that.
But I've lost interest in such victories.
Like an insect caught in a spider's web,
seeing a target caught
in a trap is glorious.
The more someone has worked hard, the more
I love seeing them fall into my traps.
Once I've tasted that joy,
killing in other ways seems foolish.
When I can effortlessly finish them off
and grant them peace,
it makes me truly feel
that I'm indeed a Reaper.
I've had it!
I've never met an enemy
as fiendish as you!
Prepare yourself!
My sword suddenly broke?!
No. I felt it hit something.
That's right. It didn't break. It was cut.
As you said,
deceiving and snaring is how I win.
So I set up a snare in secret
while we were fighting.
If you had been more observant,
you'd have noticed the lines
on my hat have been fading.
Could it be...?!
Invisible blades!
Bingo!
The lines on my hat
contain invisible blades
that once drawn will finish an enemy.
They are hidden all around this field!
Only I know where they are.
A cage made of 13 invisible blades.
This is Kilban's final trap!
The Phantom Razor!
And now, it's your turn
to prepare yourself!
ABAGAMU
REAPER FLUTE
Dodge carelessly
and it could end up killing you.
You could at least die to my sword.
A single stab to the heart...
and it will be over.
You called me fiendish,
but you'll thank me when I kill you.
"Thank you for freeing me from this hell."
No! I'm losing consciousness!
What a terrifying trap.
I can't attack or defend like this!
Either way, I'm certain to die.
And now...
I never wanted to use this again,
but I can't let him escape!
Megante, is it?
We can't have that.
The Judge?!
You can commit suicide with that.
Then this Judge was part of your...!
Teaming up with the Judge
is a terrible trap indeed.
Of course I made such preparations.
I even altered it to self-destruct
along with this field if needed.
It can use Megante, too?!
See? In the end, using traps
is the best way to go.
Goodbye then.
W-Wait! Kilban!
You're annoying me.
Vengeance complete.
Whoops, this isn't the White Garden.
This is where Baran died.
It seems the shock
of the explosion shifted my exit.
It appears that
King Ban is fighting Dai.
And Dai is winning.
Oh well. There's no need
to rush to rescue King Ban.
If Dai defeats him then that's that.
I may be obligated to help him,
but I'm not duty-bound to.
I'm not like Myst.
It looks like it's over...
Mystban.
This is truly the final battle.
And the end of you.
And who will end me?
You showing up here changes nothing.
Do you think Crocodine
or that rat can harm me?
Not even Ron Berku or Larhart
could damage my ultimate body!
None in this world can end me.
You or Aban may have had a chance,
but Aban is currently fighting Kill.
Master is...?!
And you are already beyond recovery.
No one can do anything at all!
No. There's one more person.
What?!
He means me.
You can?
It's not like I've completely
joined these guys.
But I made a promise with Hyunckel
that I'd defeat everyone
he was supposed to.
Sorry, but it's time to die, Mystban!
Wait. Seriously?!
He's not someone a puppet
with a tough body can do anything about!
You'd better stay out of this.
Aura?!
Oh?
How's this, Larhart?
Unlike when we met, I'm at full power now.
This is my strength at its best.
A metallic life form using Aura?
Impossible! It's inconceivable!
Here goes!
Hold it!
You can't fight an enemy
without your Captain's permission!
Then give me permission, mister Captain.
Can I beat the pulp out of this guy?
Very well. Go ahead.
Thank you!
-It worked?!
-That's fast!
That's impressive speed.
Added with the hardness of Orichalcum
and the power of Aura...
I may have been severely
underestimating this one.
Hyunckel, that Aura...!
That's right.
Hym's Aura is neither Dark Aura,
nor Dark Fire Energy.
It's Aura of Light.
So it really is Aura of Light?!
But Hym was in the Dark Army!
Even during our duel,
Hym was already emitting Aura of Light.
Going beyond good and evil,
and seeking only to settle things with me,
Hym was no longer evil.
I get it! Aura of Light is the greatest
weakness for Mystban who uses Dark Aura!
No one could defeat Mystban
as easily as Hym.
This is a huge find!
Good going! Keep it up Little Hym!
"Little Hym"?! What the hell is that?!
Giving names like that
is the custom of my commandos!
Can't you come up
with a better name than that?!
Little Hym... Hymmy... Hymster...
Which do you prefer?
Uh... I'll take Little Hym.
That's it then!
Hym's one of the strongest of us and
Chiu's treating it like it's no big deal.
What a fascinating rat.
Is that all?!
Curses! This pathetic puppet!
Now finish him, Little Hym! Or would you
prefer Pawny, since you're a pawn?
Dammit! Call me whatever you like!
Look out, Hym!
I'll tear you all to shreds!
Dark Puppetry Aura Decimation Field!
Don't give me your little tricks!
All Hym had to do was stamp one foot...
...and the Field was shattered!
Come at me like a man, will you?!
Holy cow! Hym's actually amazing!
To be honest, I'm shocked, too.
I didn't imagine Hym possessed such power.
I can win.
I can really win?!
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
I gaze at you from behind
as you begin to walk away
arukidasu kimi no ushirosugata wo nagameru
Tell me, where are you going all alone?
nee hitoridake de doko e yukuno
We act tough and follow our hearts
massugu de tsuyogari na sonna bokura ga
And we began this tale together
hajimeta monogatari
Beyond the horizon something glimmers
chiheisen no mukou de kirameiteiru
We've been seeking something certain
tashika na mono sagashitsuzukete iruno
In the distant sky, dancing in the wind
haruka sora ni kaze ni nori matte
The birds sing as though
illuminating the future
tobu tori wa naiteita mirai wo terasuyouni
The promise that connects us
The adventure we share
bokura wo tsunagu yakusoku to
bokura de tsumugu bouken wo
Again in this world
mata kono sekai de
Enveloped in Aura of Light,
Hym is unaffected
by the Dark Puppetry Aura Decimation Field
and closes in on Mystban.
Meanwhile, Dai continues
to hold an advantage over Ban,
but Dai can't help but feel nervous
at Ban's confidence.
As uneasy air swirls,
can Dai and friends achieve victory?
DRAGON QUEST The Adventure of Dai,
"The Deciding Attack"
The adventure continues!